[narrator]
Previously onSpider-Man.
[Spider-Man] Doc Ock?
You're not getting
away this time!
[Doctor Octopus]
It's going to explode!
The medical lab!
It'll take years to replace!
[Spider-Man] How could I
have been so irresponsible?
[Jonah]
I'm gonna use all my resources
to ruin Spider-Man for this.
If you see Spider-Man,
give him this fan letter.
[Peter] "Dear, Mr. Robertson,
could you please ask him
to come and visit
our little daughter?
She's his biggest fan--"
Yeah, yeah.
My life as Spider-Man is over.
[Madame Web]
You are wrong, Mr. Parker.
You are about to embark
on a period of training
for a mission I require of you.
And you must have
the faith of a child.
Spider-Man!
I'm not going
to be Spider-Man anymore.
You never quit.
I need to do
some web-slinging.
Not without me, you're not!
[dramatic music]
[Spider-Man]
Taina, hide!
I call it the Octobot!
You never learn, do you?
-On the contrary.
-Spider-Man, oh, no!
This time, you lose!
[upbeat rock music]
♪ Spider-Man ♪
♪ Radioactive Spider-Man ♪
♪ Spider blood
Spider blood ♪
♪ Radioactive spider blood ♪
♪ Spider blood
Spider blood ♪
♪ Radioactive spider blood ♪
[explosions booming]
[growling]
♪ Spider-Man ♪
[dramatic music]
My dear Spider-Man,
it's too bad
the effect of the knockout gas
is only transient,
but it will give me the time
to reassert my control
over the Octobot.
Then I will find
a more permanent solution
to my spider problem.
Spider-Man, wake up!
[dramatic music]
Do you see?
This is my newest weapon,
and you will help me
perfect it.
[Spider-Man groaning]
[gasps]
-[snapping]
-Good!
My neuro-neutralizer ray
has inhibited
your synaptic responses.
Now, I finally have
the chance to find out
who you are behind that mask.
Octavius!
I trust our plans
for acquiring
the argon matrix laser
are proceeding
according to schedule.
I have encountered one delay,
the outcome of which
may be to your liking.
Spider-Man?
Yes, I have succeeded
in reformatting
Spider-Man's brain.
Brilliant, Octavius.
Spider-Man shall spend
the rest of his days
in service to the Kingpin.
Don't be too sure.
[Spider-Man groans]
-Where am I?
-So, Spider-Man,
how is your head, huh?
[Spider-Man]
Are you talking to me?
-Who are you?
-You don't know me?
No, I'm sorry.
I'm a little confused.
That's to be expected.
You were accidentally injured
when my neural neutralizer
suffered
an interphase misalignment.
Neuro-neutralizer?
It is a memory-voiding device
to use in our next crime.
-Our next crime?
-Of course.
You mean to tell me
that I'm a criminal?
You're wearing a mask,
aren't you?
Perhaps you should remove it.
It might make you
think clearer.
-[spider-sense tingling]
-Whoa, something's wrong.
-No, I'll keep it on.
-As you wish.
Who exactly are you, anyway?
A scientist devoted to
the betterment of all mankind.
But I have many enemies
who try to keep me
from the resources I need.
You recognize
the importance of my work.
If only I could remember.
[groaning] I want to,
but it makes my head hurt.
Allow me to fill
in the details for you.
[dramatic music]
[Taina] Excuse me, miss,
you've got to help me!
[woman] I'm sorry, little girl,
but the movie's just starting.
Out awful late,
aren't we, little lady?
You can help me!
We have to get Spider-Man
out of the secret lab!
Why, sure,
of course I'll help.
Right after we get
you home to your parents.
-[groaning]
-You seem troubled, my friend.
I'd like to know
what's going on here.
I just can't believe
I'm who you say I am.
Since there is
nothing I can say
that will persuade you,
perhaps this is
the proof you seek.
It's time
we stopped Spider-Man.
He's a blight upon humanity!
Okay, okay,
you convinced me.
I must be some piece of work
for that guy to hate me
so much.
...as I speak.
You must trust me.
Now rest, my friend.
We have a long night
ahead of us.
[thinking]
He seems to make sense,
but I don't know.
Why did I have
that weird feeling
when he reached for my mask?
Who's under this mask anyway?
Maybe if I knew.
I don't recognize the face.
I don't know who I am.
Is there anybody who does?
[Aunt May]
Peter must be awfully busy
to have missed dinner
with us tonight.
He probably got
caught up at work
and forgot
about our dinner plans.
You know Peter,
his memory's the worst.
-So are his manners.
-Shh, Aunt Anna!
I hope he's okay.
[officer]
She won't say where she lives.
She only talks
about Spider-Man.
[Mousie, Jamaican accent]
Officers, arrest this man!
Another deadbeat,
huh, Mousie?
Don't you know it.
I show him to try
to ride in my cab for free!
Hey! [grunting]
Nice moves, Mousie.
In the words
of the immortal James Brown,
"I don't know karate,
but I know ka-razy."
[gasps]
Hmm! No good,
fare-jumpin' so-and-so.
[gasps]
[brakes screech]
Get out of there, girl!
Nobody steals
a ride in Mousie cab.
I'm not stealing.
I'm trying to get help
for Spider-Man.
Ooh, little girl,
you must think
I just rolled
off the coconut wagon.
I do admire your creativity.
For that,
you get a free ride home.
[Taina] Why won't
anyone listen to me?!
Just because
I'm eight years old,
doesn't mean I'm lying!
[brakes screech]
Of course, it don't, girl.
All de same,
that's a pretty wild story.
Spider-Man's really in trouble!
He'd help you
if you were in trouble.
Hold it right there, girlie.
I know what kind of man he is.
[dramatic music]
He once rescued me
from a mugger.
I'd hate to think what would
have happened to the Mouse
if Spider-Man hadn't
been there for me.
But Dr. Octopus
wiped out his memory,
so Spider-Man's not here
anymore for anybody.
You have to help!
You owe him one!
Don't you be telling me
what I owe, girl.
[Taina]
If you don't believe me,
I'll just find
somebody who will.
Now, I didn't say nothing
about not believing ya.
Sit over there
and fasten your seat belt.
[tires screech]
[Taina] I know it's one
of these buildings.
That's them! That's them!
So it is.
You were right.
Well, partner, this casing
for the argon matrix laser
requires a rare metal alloy,
one that we must liberate
from the Wellington Foundry.
The security staff
here is a virtual army,
but it should prove no match
for the combined might of
Doctor Octopus and Spider-Man.
Follow my instructions
to the letter.
Your timing must be precise.
[Spider-Man] Sure thing, Ock,
old buddy.
[Taina]
There's Spider-Man!
This don't look good, girl.
Taina, wait!
[guard]
Whatever you are, freeze!
Did you say squeeze?
[guards screaming]
Break-in at sector five!
Send in the robot tanks!
[Spider-Man]
Ock's scheme is brilliant.
While he distracts them,
I'm free to sneak in unnoticed.
All I have to do is
avoid the alarms.
-[laser blasts]
-[explosions]
[gasps]
Where you think
you're going, girl?
I'm gonna help Spider-Man!
[Spider-Man]
Ock said to stay
above the floor
to avoid their sensor beams.
Now, where would they keep
their precious alloys?
[laughing]
Aha!
This is the alloy,
but how did I know that?
And why do I feel so guilty?
-Spider-Man, don't!
-A little girl.
What's she doing here?
[alarm blaring]
So much for sneaking
in unnoticed.
Another break-in!
Sector 10! Disengage battle!
-[tingling]
-That strange feeling again.
Quick, you have
to get out of here!
-But, Spider-Man--
-You heard the man!
Go, girl, go!
[guns clicking]
Just one of those weapons
could turn me
into spider-paste!
Hello, boys.
So, maybe you're wondering
why I called this meeting.
[explosion]
[groaning]
I believe this is mine!
[Mousie] Time we be doing
the hustle, too, girl.
Come, Spider-Man,
our work here is finished.
The Spider-Man hasturned bad.
Yes, but it's not his fault!
[Mousie] This is
a much bigger problem
than de Mouse thought.
-[siren]
-[Taina] Maybe we need help.
The robbery?
What do you know about that?
-We saw the whole thing.
-Oh, really?
Do you expect
a serious news organization
to rely on a little girl
and a cabbie
as reliable sources?
It's true, mon.
It was the Spider-Man
and de Octopus.
De Octopus got Spider-Man
working for him.
Spider-Man and Doctor Octopus?
Maybe you should sit down
and tell me everything.
Spider-Man is innocent.
He doesn't remember who he is.
A J3 exclusive.
Very reliable sources
tell me Spider-Man has joined
forces with Doctor Octopus
to form a crime duo
that might possibly
be invincible.
-This is terrible!
-Oh, my goodness!
I hope Peter isn't trying
to get pictures of Spider-Man.
That boy is so self-centered
and uncaring.
Aunt Anna, hush.
Mary Jane,
I don't want you involved
with Peter Parker anymore.
[Jonah] And I believe
this is the beginning
of a Spider-Man crime spree,
the likes
of which we've never known.
Spider-Man must be stopped!
-Why, that double-crossin'--
-[click]
He's going to get Spidey hurt!
Not if we get
to Spider-Man first!
Every cabbie in the city
owes de Spider-Man
one way or de other.
It's time for some payback.
Yo, Vinnie.
This is da Mouse calling.
I got a tourist here wants
to find da Spider-Man.
Yeah, well, I'm running
a cab company, not a tour bus.
[Mousie] The guy say
he willing to pay double.
Oh. Why didn't ya say so?
I'll get every cabbie
in the city on it.
[dramatic music]
This is Deepak.
I am not believing
what I am seeing.
Strange vehicle, looks
like Spider-Man is driving!
Yeah, man!
That big old love bus
is trucking uptown!
-[Madame Web] Remember.
-[gasps]
[Doctor Octopus]
What is wrong with you?
Don't you remember
how to drive?
[Spider-Man]
What am I seeing?
Who was that woman?
Am I going crazy?
Come in, Mousie.
Keiji here.
I just lost them near
the south end of Central Park.
[Mousie] Not to worry.
We'll pick it up from here.
[car horn honking]
There they go!
We got them now, girl!
At last, the argon matrix laser
is within my grasp.
[guard] Freeze!
[groaning]
[grunting]
Spider-Man, stop!
You don't know
what you're doing.
Doc Ock is messing
with your head!
You! You were at the foundry.
Who are you?
I'm your friend.
You must remember.
Remember...
What have I done?
Yeah, yeah,
I don't need fan mail.
[Taina]
Spider-Man, is this a dream?
[groaning] My head!
[Doctor Octopus]
What are you doing here?!
I will not tolerate
interference!
Get rid of them!
Run, child, run,
and don't look back!
[groaning]
Why does
she keep following me?
What is she trying to tell me?
[Doctor Octopus]
Did you find the little girl?
[Spider-Man]
No, she got away.
Quickly, we must
go back to the lab.
[dramatic music]
S.O.S.! Mayday!
Cabbie in trouble!
I need help, andale!
At last, my creation
and I are reunited.
How about a little more air?
That little girl,
who is she anyway?
You must remember Taina.
She thinks the world of you.
You cannot let her down.
Think! Concentrate!
Wow!
I make web fluid that load
into these web-shooters.
All I cared about back then was
taking care of number one-- me.
I must mount
the argon-matrix laser
on my Octobot immediately.
-What should we do with her?
-She is of no value.
Get rid of her, now!
[Mousie]
You can't do this!
That little girl
believes in you!
I don't know what to believe.
-Believe in yourself.
-How?
Find de part of you deep
inside that feels true.
If you can remember anything,
try to remember
Taina's love for you.
All these images.
It feels like I want
to remember them,
but then my head
starts throbbing.
I thought I told you
to get rid of her!
Must I do everything myself?
[cabbies] Whoa! Whoa!
[screaming]
Unh!
Thanks.
You must remember.
Mousie, are you okay?
Of course, I am, girl!
Takes more
than a big, bad fish man
to hurt de old Mousie.
I... know you.
Yes, you do.
I've got to remember.
I must try.
I must.
[groaning]
I'm your greatest fan ever.
And you must have
the faith of a child.
Show biz?
[Spider-Man] Taina?
Spider-Man.
[Spider-Man] I remember!
Then you must remember this:
you will never be rid of me!
Look out, Spider-Man!
-[growling]
-[groaning]
And now, Spider-Man,
say goodbye.
[groans]
Oh!
This is so cool!
No. No!
Mother of mercy!
Is this the end of Octavius,
defeated by a-- a child?
Face it, Ock,
these kids today
just have no respect
for their elders.
Spider-Man,
you really are my hero.
You're the hero, Taina.
You're the bravest little girl
I ever met.
-[horn honks]
-How about a lift home, girl?
-Mind if I give her a ride?
-No problem.
Time to get you home.
Good night, everybody.
-See ya!
-Bye-bye.
[Deepak] Good night!
[Spider-Man] If I ever
imagined our little joyride
could turn into all this,
I certainly never
would have done it.
Are you kidding?
Thanks to you, I had
the greatest night of my life!
I should be thanking you.
You made me believe
in myself again.
If there's anything
you ever want--
There's one thing.
Would you take off
your mask for me?
I want to know
who you really are.
But I-- I can't.
Oh, wait, maybe I can.
For you, Taina.
Wow, you're Peter Parker!
Yes, that's who I am.
That is so cool!
Thank you, Spider-Man--
Peter.
You are the best friend
I ever had.
I was thinking
the same thing about you.
I'll keep your secret
for the rest of my life.
Thanks, Taina. Good night.
It'll sure be good to get home.
Oh, no, not this again!
Madame Web, where am I?
You were lost,
but now you are found,
and it's a good thing, too,
because we have a job to do.
It will be
your greatest challenge.
[Spider-Man] Wait!
What kind of challenge
was she talking about?
Oh, well, I suppose
it doesn't matter.
I do know who I am now,
and I'll be ready,
and it's all because
of the faith of a little girl
who's more of a superhero
than I'll ever be.
[upbeat rock music]
♪ Spider-Man, Spider-Man ♪
♪ Radioactive Spider-Man ♪
♪ Spider blood, spider blood ♪
♪ Radioactive spider blood ♪
♪ Spider blood ♪
♪ Spider-Man ♪