[theme music playing]
♪ Spider-Man ♪
♪ Radioactive Spider-Man ♪
♪ Spider blood, spider blood ♪
♪ Radioactive spider blood ♪
♪ Spider-Man, Spider-Man ♪
[John] Surface layer
appears to be igneous.
I'm entering the crater now.
If I'm not out in ten minutes,
start lunch without me, over.
No way, John, you're
treating today, over.
[John] Think anyone
delivers up here, over?
[pickax clanking]
Well, this is a new
one for the textbooks.
Looks like obsidian but,
[grunting]
it's almost like
the rock's bleeding!
[Paul] John, what is it?
Did you say bleeding?
John, what's going
on down there?
Do you copy?
A seismic disturbance!
Get back up here, now!
[John] I copy that!
[rumbling]
[dramatic music playing]
[Paul] John, come in, John!
[rocket roaring]
[shuttle whirring]
[eerie squishing]
Astronauts John Jameson
and Paul Stevenson
are scheduled to land
here at Kennedy Airport,
the first time a space
shuttle touchdown
has ever been attempted
at a commercial airport.
-With touchdown imminent,
-[applauding]
America prepares to
greet its newest heroes.
Congratulations, Mr. Jameson.
What are you
congratulating me for?
I'm just his father.
John's a great guy,
you must've had
something to do with it.
[Peter Voiceover] If you ask me,
the apple fell pretty
far from the tree.
The astronauts are
bringing with them
a treasure trove
for scientists,
but the most promising
discovery, Promethium X.
This new isotope is among the
samples Colonel Jameson found
on the newly
discovered asteroid.
According to preliminary tests
conducted aboard the shuttle,
Promethium X could be more
powerful than plutonium!
You're following this
broadcast, I trust?
Hanging on every word.
[News Anchor] Will this new
isotope be a boon to mankind
or will it turn out to
be a planetary time bomb?
The world is waiting
for an answer.
[car horns honking]
The story of the year
and look where I am!
-[thudding]
-[car horn honking]
[John] O.M.S. engines are armed.
Five, four, three, two, one!
[rockets roaring]
[suspenseful music playing]
O.M.S. burn complete.
[Anchor] The shuttle is now
coming out
of its reentry blackout
and we go live to
the astronauts!
Control, this is Victory.
TAEM interface.
[dramatic music playing]
[Paul screaming]
Paul?
What is that stuff?
Get it off me!
What is it, what's happening?
-Help me!
-[static warbling]
What's going on up there?
[Paul screaming]
Mayday, mayday!
Mission Control, we're in
trouble! Do you copy?
[Anchor] Mission Control has
lost contact with the shuttle.
There's no explanation yet.
John.
[static warbling]
Hang in there.
[John] Mission Control,
we're veering off course,
our landing coordinates
are not valid.
John's the best
shuttle pilot there is,
-if anyone can--
-This bulletin just in.
The shuttle is headed toward
the greater metropolitan area.
Remain calm and wait for
further instructions.
Hello, Aunt May?
Better get down to the basement.
[suspenseful music playing]
Smythe?
I suggest we evacuate,
that shuttle could be
dropping in on us any minute,
with explosive results.
Most unlikely.
The shuttle's trajectory
is taking it this way.
Fort Lee at the Westernmost,
Forest Hills at the Easternmost.
My estimate is that it'll hit
the George Washington Bridge.
Hmm...
[phone beeping]
[phone ringing]
[Rhino] Yeah?
[Kingpin] I have a job for you.
There's something
aboard the shuttle
I want you to get for me.
What shuttle?
[dramatic music playing]
No!
No! Get off of me!
[groaning]
NASA Control is now
estimating that the shuttle
will reach impact in the
Hudson in the vicinity
of the
George Washington Bridge.
Let's go!
We'll take the copter!
Jonah, they're not gonna allow
any air traffic in that area.
Robbie, my son is
on that shuttle.
[Peter Voiceover] I've got
a quicker way to get there.
[helicopter whirring]
[web whooshing]
[News Anchor]
Any motorist in the area
abandon their vehicles.
I repeat, motorists
should abandon their
vehicles immediately!
Yeah, not in this lifetime!
That punk Parker can click
one of these, so can I!
[motorists screaming]
[shuttle whooshing]
-Look out!
-[woman screaming]
Please, show a little faith,
I know my trajectories.
[shuttle whooshing]
[crowd shouting]
Just as I told you.
-[slime squishing]
-[John and Paul grunting]
[Paul screaming]
Gotta make it to the river.
[shuttle whooshing]
[shuttle thudding]
[Kingpin] Rhino,
are you at the bridge yet?
Yeah, what a mess.
[car crashing]
[cars crashing]
We're gonna hit it!
Can't turn!
[car crashing]
[John grunting]
[shuttle thudding]
[shuttle crashing]
[Eddie yelping]
[wires snapping]
[energetic music playing]
[suspenseful music playing]
[web whooshing]
Hey, the shuttle door
has been pulled off!
Colonel Jameson?
-[shuttle rumbling]
-Uh-oh!
[John groaning]
Colonel Jameson!
[alarm blaring]
Good heavens!
Huh?
Where did you come from?
Jersey.
Got a claim check for that bag?
Check this!
-[Rhino crashing]
-[shuttle creaking]
Hey, pal, watch it, or we'll
both be going for a swim!
Just who are you anyway--
-[Rhino thudding]
-[Spider-Man grunting]
[shuttle creaking]
[metal thudding]
[Kingpin] Rhino, did you
get the Promethium X?
Yeah, but--
[Kingpin] Bring it
to me immediately!
The authorities will
be there any minute!
Comin', Boss, comin'.
-[Rhino stomping]
-[Spider-Man grunting]
We'll finish this
some other time.
-[tracer beeping]
-You can count on it.
[dramatic music playing]
What in the world?
-[camera clicking]
-[cars crashing]
[adventurous music playing]
[helicopters whirring]
Spidey saves publisher's son.
Can't wait to see
Jameson's face when--
-[metal clanking]
-Huh?
What was that noise?
Anybody home?
-[shuttle rumbling]
-Uh-oh!
Move, Spidey, move!
[helicopters whirring]
[shuttle splashing]
[sirens blaring]
John, John!
Talk to me!
Black... like tar.
The bridge!
Spider-Man!
Spider-Man?
What's he got to do with this?
[tense music playing]
-[Eddie] J.J.!
-Brock!
You're not gonna
believe this, J.J.!
I saw Spider-Man stealing
something from the shuttle
and I got the pictures
to prove it right here!
So, he was here!
Just give me my
old job back, J.J.,
and these pictures are yours.
I'll take 'em, Brock.
I finally got that
wall-crawling sack of garbage!
[Spider-Man] Well, web-head,
you saved the day
but now what do you have to
show for all your troubles?
Ugh!
Hudson River pollution:
rich, thick, and creamy.
I'll collect my
thank you's later,
right now I wanna find
that big gray goon.
[tracer beeping]
Lost him!
Either my tracer's
been destroyed
or he's in a place that's
built like a fortress!
[ominous music playing]
So, here it is.
What's the big deal?
This is Promethium X,
potentially the most powerful
nuclear fuel in the world!
I can't wait to examine it.
No time, Smythe,
I've got a buyer lined up
and he wants it yesterday.
Looks like a rock to me.
Please do not confuse
this with that.
[News Anchor] Police department
divers have confirmed
that the Promethium X is
missing from the shuttle.
Detectives have
evidence that Spider-Man
was involved in the theft.
-[door creaking]
-Aunt May, I'm home!
Peter, have you heard?
About Spider-Man?
How he saved the
astronauts and now
Jonah Jameson's gonna
eat every word he ever--
Peter, Spider-Man
robbed the shuttle!
What?
[News Anchor] Now live
from Bellevue Hospital.
Mr. Jameson, anything more
on your son and his copilot?
[female reporter] Are they
still on the critical?
[male reporter] What
about Spider-Man?
-Are you sure--
-Spider-Man did it!
I'm sure of it, so sure that
I'm offering a million dollars
to anyone who brings him in.
One million dollars.
[Peter voiceover]
I can't believe this!
How could they get it so wrong?
It's the Spider-Man
justice system,
guilty until proven innocent.
Now there's nowhere
Spider-Man can run,
at last he'll get
what he deserves.
[Peter Voiceover] Thanks,
Aunt May, I needed that.
[suspenseful music playing]
A million dollars on my head.
For once in my life I'm worth
something and I can't collect!
[sighing] No choice
but to lay low.
Well, the one saving grace
is I don't have to
clean you up now.
[costume thudding]
[lamp clicking]
[slime squishing]
[Peter groaning]
-[heartbeat pounding]
-[Peter panting]
[dramatic music playing]
No!
[slime warbling]
[Peter groaning]
[Peter screaming]
[creature growling and hissing]
[trash can clanging]
[wind whistling]
[slime sloshing]
[blow thudding]
[creature crashing]
[power lines zapping]
[creature groaning]
[Peter yelping]
What a nightmare!
For a second I thought I was
going on of my mind?
Parker, how on Earth did you
get in the middle of Manhattan
hanging upside down in a costume
you've never seen before?
[helicopter whirring]
Over there, it's Spider-Man!
-Sure doesn't look like him.
-Well, who else can it be?
He changed his
costume to fool us.
Wouldn't wanna make a mistake.
[Pilot] For Jameson's million,
I'll take that chance!
Whoa!
Unbelievable!
I almost overshot
the whole roof!
I never could jump
like that before.
My webbing!
It's shooting out on its own!
[helicopter whirring]
He's going too low, call
for backup on the street!
-There he is!
-Get him!
-Come on!
[crowd yelling]
[blow thudding]
[Spider-Man voiceover]
What am I doing?
Defending myself, that's what!
[sirens wailing]
[web whooshing]
[car horns honking]
It's amazing, this
suit is augmenting
every one of my spider-powers!
I wonder how strong I am now.
[truck creaking]
I used to have trouble
lifting a Volkswagen.
Uh-oh, my adoring
public is back.
Yo, Spider-Man's hiding
behind the fire engine!
[suspenseful music playing]
I like your style,
but it would be nice
if you were a little
less conspicuous.
You're definitely my kinda suit!
Hey, Sarge!
He went that way!
[policeman] I can almost
taste that million bucks!
[whooshing]
You know, I think I'll keep you.
Yahoo! [cheering]
Nothing on Earth could
do what this does!
Could it have come
from the shuttle?
Peter Parker.
No wait, how about that
guy from Aerosmith?
Ah, maybe something more
traditional, something Italian.
[whooshing]
Buono...
Looks like my life
is going to be
pretty interesting from now on.
Parker?
Is that you?
Lately, I'm not so sure.
I almost didn't recognize you.
You seem so, so different!
You don't know how different.
But, then again, maybe
you'd like to find out?
Hitting on my girl, Parker?
Your girl?
Whatever on Earth gave
you that idea, Flash?
Well, I thought that...
Parker, Felicia I need to talk,
so why don't you crawl
back under your rock?
Not this time, bonehead.
Now, Felicia...
What did you say?
It had something to do with
the contents of your skull.
[chuckling] Well,
this is a twist!
Look who suddenly
developed a backbone.
I've developed a lot
more than a backbone.
Parker!
Flash, don't you have
a class to get to?
Flash!
[Flash] But Felicia...
What's gotten into you?
Just being myself.
You know something, Peter?
You are different
and you scare me.
[somber music playing]
[scoffing] What's
she talking about?
I've never felt so good!
How can I demonstrate
to your buyers
the power of Promethium X
if I don't have the
specially-enhanced control rods?
Get them.
Unfortunately, all control
rods made of Lidium 90
are in a government repository
to which we have no access!
Nothing is inaccessible to me.
[phone beeping]
I have another job for you.
[Aunt May] Peter dear, I've been
worried about something.
Those pictures you're
always taking a Spider-Man?
You really should stop.
Why's that, Aunt May?
Because it's getting
too dangerous, dear!
Don't worry, I can handle it.
[sighing] But there's
that reward now,
everyone's after him, he'll
be like a cornered animal
and you know how
dangerous that--
I'm not gonna listen
to any more of this.
[door slamming]
[sighing] Why's everybody
getting on my case today?
[tracer beeping]
The Jolly Gray Giant, he's back!
Time to take care of
unfinished business.
[whooshing]
[suspenseful music playing]
[grunting]
[crashing]
[sirens wailing]
[Guard] Halt!
You're not authorized
to be here!
[guards shouting]
[blow thudding]
[dramatic music playing]
[Spider-Man] A little far
from the zoo, aren't you?
[laughing]
Well, well, it's the
itsy bitsy spider,
all decked out in
his new threads!
They ain't gonna
look new for long!
Let's get it over with!
I gotta polish my horn.
-[crashing]
-[Rhino grunting]
This'll be over when you tell me
where that Promethean X is.
[blow thudding]
Look, hornhead,
I'm not going around
in circles with you all night!
-[crashing]
-[grunting]
I want an answer, now!
-[crashing]
-[grunting]
This ain't possible,
you can't do this!
I just rewrote the rules!
Now who are you working for?
Know what they would
do to me if I told?
Something like this?
[Rhino grunting]
And I'm just getting warmed up.
The ride ends when you tell
me where the Promethium X is!
I can't!
Well, that's too bad,
big boy, for you.
All right, I give up!
I'd rather go to jail
than the be a snitch!
Who said anything about jail?
Huh?
I don't get it.
You will.
It's like this, I'm through
with not getting what I want!
What're you doing?
I told you, I give up!
That's funny, I give up, too.
I give up trying
to be a friendly
neighborhood Spider-Man.
No, no you can't!
Can't I?
[somber music playing]
I'm not gonna listen
to any more of this!
I've developed a lot
more than a backbone.
You are different
and you scare me.
She was right, I am different.
[Rhino] No, don't!
Don't!
[metal thudding]
I almost did
something back there
that I would've regretted
for the rest of my life
and I have no idea why.
[creature snarling]
What was that?
What's happening to me?
[thunder crashing]
[theme music playing]
♪ Spider-Man ♪
♪ Radioactive Spider-Man ♪
♪ Spider blood, spider blood ♪
♪ Radioactive spider blood ♪
♪ Spider-Man ♪