[Peter] Previously
onSpider-man.
Mariah Crawford was right.
I took her serum too soon.
What are you up to?
Parker's DNA, I will expose
to the neogenic process.
[screams]
No!
I am the vampire bat
who's genes I inherited.
Another victim of plasma drain.
Spider-man.
Your days of
terrorizing are over.
[Newscaster]
Has Spider-man mutated?
Authorities are wondering
if there's a connection
between Spider-man and the
mysterious plasma draining
disease afflicting New Yorkers.
Its Spider-man,
somebody stop him.
Put out an APB for Spider-man.
[Newscaster] It can
only be Spider-man.
[Spider-man] That's Morbius.
[screams]
Debra.
I must feed.
[Man] Get away from her.
[shouts]
Haven't we had enough of
this wall crawling menace?
I must administer this serum.
There, its done.
[Spider-man] Morbius,
he's still out there.
I've got to find him.
[energetic rock music]
♪ Spider-man ♪
♪ Radioactive Spider-man ♪
[energetic rock music]
♪ Spider blood ♪
♪ Radioactive spider blood ♪
[energetic rock music]
♪ Spider-man ♪
[tense dramatic music]
[Spider-man] Dr. Crawford
reversed my mutation
but she didn't cure me.
[engine revs]
I can transform into
the Man-Spider anytime.
Doc Connors says he's found
a way to control my problem.
I sure hope he's right.
[Man] Help me.
[shouts]
[Spider-man] Morbius!
Stop giving into
this blood lust.
You have to or I can't help you.
[groans]
[roars]
The feeding made him so strong.
[shouts]
Where did that flying
blood bank go to?
[groans]
What about Felicia?
Do you think she'll
want you like this?
You shut up about her.
[engine revs]
[shouting]
Cries of a death stalker
are like music to my ears.
You're finished.
He's a samurai on a chopper.
That sword swinging biker
wants to destroy Morbius.
I can't let him do it.
One more round of poison gas
will end your reign
of terror, vampire.
Why are you protecting him?
[Spider-man] Why
are you after him?
He's strength is beyond human.
Great, another
weirdo with accident?
Let's see how you
to react to a dose.
[coughing]
[Spider-man] What the heck?
Garlic?
You sprayed me with garlic?
Are you some kind of nut?
You can breathe?
[Spider-man] Barely.
That gas was made
out of a volatile oil
in the allium family.
You cannot be a vampire.
[Spider-man] Why?
Because you're still alive.
[Spider-man] Hey slow down.
I have no quarrel with you.
[Spider-man] Maybe I've
got a few question.
[roars]
[engine revving]
he's got fangs, too.
Is there a vampire
convention in town?
I'll just let my
tracer do the work.
Then I can track [shouts].
My mutation disease
is flaring up.
Got to get to Connors's.
Who are you, my
dangerous friend?
You know weaknesses of
mine of which I am unaware.
Authorities search for missing
student, Micheal Morbius.
Police think he may have
been kidnapped by Spider-man.
What about this rumor
that Spider-man's
turned into a monster, huh?
All I can say is we're
determined to bring him
in for questioning.
Another missing ESU student,
Peter Parker of Queens,
returned home today.
Well I was tracking Spider-man
and I wasn't able to call home.
I'm sorry for all
the trouble I caused.
I'm so relieved.
I just wish he'd give
up this dangerous work.
It was feared that Parker
might of contracted
the mysterious plasma
draining disease
that is inflicting New Yorkers.
The latest victim, ESU
football star, Flash Thompson,
is said to be recovering
at university hospital
but an eyewitness claims
that he was attacked by
a mysterious assailant.
He had fangs.
Fangs?
I'm perfectly serious.
That's it.
He looked like a vampire.
A vampire?
Great.
I need this like
Spider-man needs vitamins.
[mechanical whirring]
[groaning]
[Spider-man] Doc, the mutation.
Just a few seconds.
I'm almost ready.
How do you feel?
[Spider-man] Better now.
The pains subsiding.
Its too bad
Dr. Crawford had to leave
to fight that plague in Africa.
But her data has shown me how
to control your condition.
Now remember, you must get
these neogenic treatments
every 24 hours or
you'll mutate again.
[Spider-man] No problem.
Just remind me next time
to bring my sunblock.
There's something
I should tell you.
ESU's been getting
nervous about the dangers
of genetic research.
Especially after that
frightening business
with Herbert Landon and
the Brand Corporation.
To alley their fears,
I've beefed the security
in the recombinator lab.
[Spider-man] Do you
think there's a chance
they'll shut down
the Neogenics lab?
Possibly, but if I
can get that grant
from the Toombs Foundation,
it may not matter.
[Spider-man] I've
got to stop Morbius
before he strikes again.
Uh oh, looks like I'm too late.
Wait a minute.
There's more than one
plasma sucker in town now.
I should scan the crowd
for that fruitcake
on the chopper with the
garlic bombs and fangs.
Look, its Spider-man.
He's responsible for this.
Get him!
[crowd shouting]
[Spider-man] Its
surprising how quickly
the public will turn on you
when they think you're a
blood draining monster.
Its Spider-man!
[Spider-man] Something
tells me they don't
want my autograph.
I must find Morbius before
that motorcycle freak does.
If he gets Morbius first, I
won't be able to clear my name.
Looks like Morbius has found me.
Listen to me, Micheal,
you have to end this nightmare.
I can help.
I don't want your help!
When I awoke this
evening, I felt different.
I like this life now.
I cannot be hurt,
cannot be destroyed.
I am immortal!
I have no desire
to be turned back
into a pitiful human.
Now I am so much
more than human.
I am the king of the night.
[shouts]
New strength.
Yes!
[engine revs]
[hisses]
You again.
Who are you?
What do you want with me?
Call me Blade.
And all I want, vampire,
is to destroy you.
[Spider-man] He didn't
get a full plasma drain.
But I still feel weak, dizzy.
[roars]
This time, vampire,
you're finished.
[Spider-man] Stop!
[engine revving]
Why did you do that?
Why?
[Spider-man] I have to help him.
I turned him into a vampire.
You created that creature?
And now you want to save
him after all he's done?
[Spider-man]
He didn't want to be one.
He must be destroyed
and so must you.
I won't make the mistake of
letting you live this time.
[tense dramatic music]
[screaming]
[crowd screaming]
Oh its, Spider-man.
He looks sick.
Don't touch him.
He might have spider cooties.
[Spider-man] Good thing
that awning broke my fall.
Hey, Spider-man!
Can I have your autograph?
If you get the chair,
it will be worth a fortune.
Fame, it always
goes to their heads.
[Spider-man]
Both of them are gone
and my head is pounding.
You're in top form
tonight, Spidey.
Its hard to admit but
I can't do this alone.
I need help.
But can I trust a vampire
hunter to help me?
-[hisses]
-[woman screams]
Blade, you must be calm.
Whether we defeat the enemy
in one battle or by degrees
the consequences
will be the same.
This vampire is different.
Spider-man told
me he created it.
How is that possible?
Many things are possible.
As much as we have
learned, Blade,
we are still chartering the
course through darkness.
All the attacks occurred
near Empire State University.
Why, Whistler?
[Spider-man] Well maybe he
just likes the cafeteria food.
You, here!
[groaning]
Go ahead, do it.
Prove that you're the
protector of those
inhuman things.
[Spider-man] I'm just
looking for some answers.
Who or what are you?
Blade, let's listen to him.
He may be able to
answer our questions.
How could you take his side?
I told you, he saved
that vampire's life.
[Spider-man] Just listen to
me and I'll tell you why.
Continue refitting the
weapons on your motorcycle.
Go, go.
As you request, Whistler,
but I'd keep a close eye on him.
If I were you.
Forgive Blade if
he's not very social.
We have worked by
ourselves for a long time.
[Spider-man] Work?
What is it you do?
Are you garlic wholesalers?
Blade and I are vampire hunters.
[Spider-man] Vampire hunters?
There's always been a
dedicated cadre of people
who hunt Nosferatu.
[Spider-man] Nosferatu?
Isn't that the name
of a German rock band?
No, no.
Its an ancient term for vampire.
In my youth I was
trained to fight them
and now I pass those
traditions onto Blade.
He is the son of a vampire
man who fell in love
with a human woman.
His mother was later turned
into Nosferatu against her will
but she wanted Blade
spared from her dark world.
It was her final act of love.
Blade ran off and soon
discovered that he was blessed,
or cursed, by
being part vampire.
Not all vampire, the
transformation was not total.
He has the quickness, the
strength, the agility.
But is unaffected by sunlight
and he is immune to the venom
of his bloodsucking brethren.
No he aims to destroy
all those condemned
to a life as a freak of nature
and he yearns to find
his mother again.
[Spider-man] I know what
it means to be different.
Its not an easy thing.
I found Blade and I raised him.
I focused his anger
to where it belonged.
Protecting innocent people
from the vampire scourge.
He can match any
Nosferatu in a way
that no human never could.
[woman screaming]
[Spider-man] Are you saying
there are more vampires
out there?
Every country in the
world has those who carry
the mutant gene responsible
for this disease.
[Blade] You've told
him too much already.
No, Blade.
He must know.
The diseases symptoms
include deadly reactions
to certain plant life,
alloys, and ultraviolet rays.
Vampires bodies burn
iron too quickly.
They need to steal
plasma to get it.
[Spider-man] Well that
sounds like Morbius.
Who?
[Spider-man] The vampire
we've been chasing.
He's the result of an experiment
with a machine called the
Neogenic Recombinator.
A machine that can
create vampires?
Yes, that would explain
his territorial proximity
to ESU.
You must show me
where the machine is.
I have to destroy it.
[Spider-man] Whoa, whoa,
wait a minute, fang face.
I need it to make
Morbius human again.
I won't let you
protect him any longer.
Blade!
[explosion]
If Spider-man can
transform Morbius back,
maybe he can help you, too.
You know that as you age you're
becoming more vampire like,
you crave plasma.
The serum you give me makes
those cravings go away.
Yes but its losing
its effectiveness.
This machine could help
you become human again.
I must remain a vampire so
that I can locate my mother
and I'll destroy anything
that gets in my way.
I am and will always
be a vampire hunter.
Then you must learn how to
act out of what is right.
Not to satisfy your
uncontrollable lust for revenge.
[Peter] Unlike the
myths about vampires,
its not a simple piece of
garlic that Blade uses,
its combined with rare
bacteria.
Telephone, Peter.
Its Mary Jane.
Oh, thanks Aunt May.
[Peter Voiceover] No,
I've been dreading this.
Young love.
[screaming]
[Peter Voiceover] She looked
at me with such horror
when I was Man-Spider.
Stay back!
[Peter Voiceover] I'm
afraid to ever bring
that monster into
our life again.
Hi, I uh, I've been
meaning to call you
since I got back.
But uh.
No excuses, Peter.
The police want to
meet at Lehman Hall
with friends of students
who've taken ill.
You should be here.
We could talk
afterwards, over dinner.
[Peter Voiceover]
Maybe I can get a clue
to Morbius' whereabouts.
Okay, I'll meet you there.
[Lee] I'm glad you all came
because we have a very
serious situation here.
Spider-man, Morbius'
disappearance.
The plasma disease,
this vampire story.
I just know they're linked
but I can't find the thread
that connects them all together.
Well better late
than never, tiger.
At least you showed.
Sorry I was--
-Parker!
-Lieutenant Lee.
You always find
Spider-man fast enough
to get pictures of him.
Why don't you tell me
where I can find him?
It doesn't work that way.
What's with you?
You're protecting your
income while innocent people
are being hurt.
No, I'm not trying to--
By the way, I understand
you and Ms. Hardy here
were an item before
Micheal Morbius showed up.
You seem to be
benefiting all around.
That's not true.
Felicia, wait.
I'm not finished with you.
Well then book me or let me go.
But I don't have
to listen to this.
Fine, you can go.
Just remember, I'm watching you.
[crying]
Felicia.
Oh, Peter.
I miss Micheal so much.
This is tearing me up inside.
[Peter Voiceover]
I feel terrible.
It was my blood that
turned him into a vampire.
I'll do whatever I can
to bring Micheal back.
I promise.
Mary Jane, are you okay?
I'm fine.
Harry, how would you like
to take a gal to dinner?
I had other plans but
I just canceled them.
Well sure, I'd love to.
This is a game you
cannot win, Mr. Parker.
I drain away the very
marrow of your being.
No, Felicia cannot
see me this way.
Can you walk me
to my car, Peter?
Sure.
No problem.
[tense dramatic music]
[electronic beeping]
How does it feel, Morbius?
Its only artificial sunlight
but it will do the job.
I had only planned to
destroy the Recombinator.
How fortunate I get to
destroy you as well.
[tense dramatic music]
You have underestimated
my powers, friend.
What an amusing toy.
[tense dramatic music]
I fed well tonight.
I'm now stronger than you
and Spider-man combined.
There are others
like me, Morbius.
You will never be safe!
And soon, thanks to
the Recombinator,
there will be many more like me.
The whole world will
become vampires.
Then you and your kind
will be the freaks.
The hunted.
[Spider-man] I came out
tonight to hunt Morbius.
I didn't expect to find this.
[screams]
Get it off me!
[shouting]
[Spider-man] Spidey's first rule
of vampire hunting, never
let em see you sweat.
[shouts]
No!
-You okay?
-Yes.
Your webbing almost
held him this time.
[Spider-man] I borrowed
some vampire repellent gas
from you and mixed
it into my webbing.
But I watered it down
because I want Morbius alive.
I thought it would hold
him a little longer.
Good try, Spider-man
but you've got a lot to learn
about catching vampires.
It's time I taught
you a few tricks.
[Spider-man] I have no choice
but to work with this hunter.
I have to get that
Recombinator back.
My life depends on it.
Stay alert, web slinger.
Its gonna be a long night!
[tense dramatic music]
[energetic rock music]
♪ Spider-man ♪
♪ Radioactive Spider-man ♪
[energetic rock music]
♪ Spider blood ♪
♪ Radioactive spider blood ♪
♪ Spider-man ♪