[upbeat rock music]
♪ Spider-Man ♪
♪ Radioactive Spider-Man ♪
♪ Spider blood
Spider blood ♪
♪ Radioactive spider blood ♪
♪ Spider blood
Spider blood ♪
♪ Radioactive spider blood ♪
[explosions booming]
[growling]
♪ Spider-Man ♪
[siren wailing]
Lieutenant Lee, he's up there.
[Lieutenant Lee] Well,
what are you waiting for?
Hit the lights!
Cletus Kasady, come out now!
[Cletus laughs]
Come out, and nobody gets hurt.
[Cletus] Nobody gets hurt?
Man, what fun would that be?
-Look out!
-Grenade!
[Cletus laughing maniacally]
[newscaster]
If you're just tuning in,
police have wanted criminal
Cletus Kasady
surrounded in his home.
How can one man hold the entire
NYPD at bay like that?
Jonah, Kasady's not a man.
He's a monster.
He's done things
even the Post wouldn't print.
Well, his capture will
make our front page,
if we get good photos.
Peter Parker's already on
his way to the crime scene.
Good, I hope he's using
the fastest route he knows.
Chief, we'll need a distraction
in about a minute.
You got it.
Terri, you like your job?
-What?
-Kasady loves his.
Be careful.
[helicopter whirring]
-[lasers zap]
-[explosion]
[Terri]
There's our distraction!
Move it!
[device beeping]
[gasps]
-[Terri grunts]
-Lieutenant Lee!
[grunts]
[Terri gasps]
I was raised in this place.
It was a real house of horrors.
It still is, man.
You'll see.
[laughing]
[loud thudding]
Man, you stay away from me,
or--
It looks like raw V-9
fragmentation plastique.
Exactamentay! [laughs]
And in 30 seconds, I'll be
meeting you all-- [yelps]
Thanks, big mouth. Now, I know
how much time I have.
-Freeze!
-[guns cocking]
Give it a rest.
He'll never get
far enough away.
We're all gonna go kablooey!
[thinking] The blast radius
of this quantity
of raw V-9 plastique
has to be about 200 meters.
Where am I gonna find that
much clear space around here?
There's only one safe place:
the sky.
But can I throw it high enough?
[explosion]
[laughing]
Rest in pieces, Spider-Man.
Don't count him out!
He's gotten out
of worse than that before.
[Spider-Man groans]
Once again,
our hero triumphs,
the cheers of a grateful city
ringing in his ears.
Something's ringing in my ears.
-Hey, look.
-What?
[man] Come on!
It landed right near here.
Let's see what it is.
It might be worth something.
[woman]
What are you doing?
[woman screams]
-Help me!
-Oh, get it off me!
[both screaming]
Kasady, I hope you get
a real good shrink
and a real long sentence.
Uh-oh.
I've seen this happen before.
No spider-sense?
No danger?
So, this has got
to be Madame Web.
You don't surprise me anymore.
This time, I knew it was you.
I see nothing clever
in that, Spider-Man.
You've always been
awfully good
at deducing things
that were
pathetically obvious.
Gee, thanks.
Don't tell me you
teleported all this way
just to insult little old me.
No, to warn you.
The evil
you will soon confront
will be unstoppable,
unless you learn
to overcome fear
and rely on unlikely allies.
Remember, a warrior
keeps his friends close
and his enemies closer.
Wait! Come back!
What do you mean?!
What evil?!
Why does she always do this?
She wants to make
a warrior out of me.
Warrior? Me?
Heck, I'm still fighting acne.
I wanted to be a warrior,
fighting injustice,
fighting
for the innocent people.
I guess-- I guess that's
why I became a journalist.
[thunder rumbling]
-[lightning crackles]
-[screeching]
When I break this story,
it'll be Pulitzer time.
[screams]
[Spider-Man] I won't let you
won't ruin Connors' life.
But I'll show you
the Lizard himself.
J. Jonah Jameson.
You're history, Brock,
outta here, fired!
[Brock] When the alien symbiote
joined with me,
we-- we had the power
to do anything we wanted!
But first, we had
to destroy Spider-Man
for-- for all
that he had done to us!
Now there's no more us,
only me,
all because of Spider-Man.
[chuckles]
I know
who he is behind that mask,
but that's my little secret,
and I'm gonna keep it
until my other half returns.
When I become Venom once more,
we will destroy Spider-Man.
No, not "we," Eddie.
This Venom thing never existed.
It was
a stress-related delusion
brought on by Spider-Man's
terrible persecution of you.
Ha! He persecuted me,
all right.
He humiliated me!
-He made me lose
my job, my health.
-[sneezes]
My apartment, my symbiote.
-[rocket rumbling]
-[snarling]
I hate that slimy little--
Hatred's not going to help.
You have so much potential,
and together, we're going
to get you through this.
Do you have to go, Dr. Kafka?
Our time's up, Eddie.
We'll continue this tomorrow.
[Cletus]
Man, what a dump!
No pool, no stereo, and
weirdoes everywhere you look!
Aren't you gonna give me
some therapy, beautiful lady?
[laughing]
Good night, Eddie.
Good night, Dr. Kafka.
-Ashley.
-Don't I get a goodbye kiss,
or are you afraid
I'm gonna bite?
Hey, you! Shut up!
Hey, man, [chuckles]
I could eat you for breakfast!
Oh, yeah?
I'd give you indigestion, man.
[thunder]
Mordo, I need you.
Mordo!
Yes, Master Dormammu.
I am yours to command.
The symbiote is finally back
on Earth, just as I planned.
Now go
to Ravencroft Sanitarium
and contact Eddie Brock.
It is time for him to play
his part in our affair.
[thunder]
[Brock]
You can't be real!
I want to be well.
Leave me alone!
I am not a delusion, my boy.
I've merely come
to you in my astral form.
I want to restore to you
that which is rightfully
yours, the symbiote.
How do you know about that?
My master, Dormammu,
knows everything.
You need only swear
to serve him,
and the symbiote will
be yours once more.
He can make you whole again.
Hey, you in there, whoever
you are, forget Brock.
If this Dormammu guy
can get me out of here,
I'll do whatever he wants.
Whatever.
Buzz off, laughing boy.
Why are you hesitating, Eddie?
Don't you miss the symbiote?
And don't you want
to get out of here
and destroy Spider-Man?
Okay, okay.
You got a deal.
Just tell me what I have to do.
My master, it is done.
Excellent.
Now, we are poised to obtain
the last piece of the puzzle
at Stark Enterprises.
[Debra] Peter, do you really
think that they can make
an interdimensional probe?
Well, if anyone can, Debra,
it's Stark Enterprises.
This could be one of
the most important
scientific breakthroughs
in history.
Well, it could create a gateway
to whole new worlds,
other dimensions.
Yeah, and it could also
accidentally let something
get through to us
that shouldn't.
-[Dr. Connors] Debra! Peter!
-[Debra] Dr. Connors.
Come on, the demonstration's
about to start.
Debra Whitman, Peter Parker,
this is Jim Rhodes,
head of security
for Stark Enterprises.
Miss Whitman, Mr. Parker.
Now, there's
a real cheerful guy.
I don't think cheer is part
of his job description.
[Dr. Connors] There's
the interdimensional probe.
Just think, a machine
that might allow us
to transcend the limitations
of space, perhaps even time.
If it works,
Tony Stark's a genius.
That's Ardon Broom.
His electronics company
is a supplier
to Stark Enterprises.
[thinking]
If that's not Baron Mordo,
then I don't stick to walls.
He must be here
to use this technology
to transport Dormammu
to our dimension.
[Stark] Good day, and welcome,
scientists and scholars.
Today, we are here to begin
a new era in technology.
Our plan is to actually
teleport solid matter
instantaneously from New York,
where all of you are,
to our labs here
in Los Angeles.
We're gonna be using
an interdimensional gateway
built expressly
for that purpose.
Incredible.
[guard]
Brock, you've got a visitor.
-A visitor?
-[woman] Eddie Brock?
Yeah.
Do I know you?
Don't you recognize us?
Eddie?
How about now?!
[both groan]
-[Venom growls]
-[alarm wailing]
[growling]
[laughing]
Together again!
We knew it wasn't a delusion.
-[gasps]
-Do you believe us now, Doctor?
Eddie, is that you?
There's no more Eddie,
and no more symbiote.
Only Venom!
Eddie?
Please, don't go!
[Cletus]
No, give it to me!
I want the power.
I deserve the power.
[Venom growls]
The symbiote could have
bonded with anyone,
but only the rage and
frustration of Eddie Brock
could have created Venom.
You are truly unique.
That is why I need you.
How did you make us one again?
At a place
called Stark Enterprises,
my assistant, Baron Mordo,
secretly gained access
to the ground-control system
for the space probe to which
the symbiote was attached.
[computer beeping]
I ordered Mordo to guide
the probe back to Earth.
From there,
it was a simple matter
of locating the symbiote
and hypnotizing
its hosts into submission.
What do you want
from us in return?
You must get something for me,
something very important.
[Stark]
Scientists and scholars,
a new era in technology,
an interdimensional gateway.
[laser buzzing]
Just think, this is an actual
gap in reality as we know it.
[spider-sense tingling]
-[explosion]
-[crowd gasps]
-Something's wrong.
-[alarm beeping]
Suspend all activities!
Deactivate the probe!
[people screaming]
What is it?
[growls]
Venom!
[laser blasts]
Peter? Where does
he always disappear to?
Come on,
it's not safe for us here!
We want the probe!
Rhodey, don't let that thing
get near the probe!
-Stop him!
-Security position alpha omega!
[growling]
[Venom]
You think you can stop us?
[groaning]
[Spider-Man]
Maybe not them, smiley.
-[groans]
-But I can.
I did it before, and so
help me, I'll do it again.
We remember.
That's all we could think about
as we traveled
the endless reaches
of outer space!
[Venom growls]
[groans]
He's gotten even stronger
since last time,
if that's possible!
No loud noises to help you!
This time will be different
from last time!
This time, Venom will win!
[growls]
Spider-Man's destruction will
bring us great happiness.
-[growls]
-[laser zaps]
Happy hour's over,
bright eyes.
Thanks, I owe you one,
whoever you are.
The name's War Machine.
[Venom]
This wasn't your fight!
It is now, little man of iron!
-[lasers zap]
-Wrong!
Iron Man's the other guy,
but thanks for the compliment!
[groans]
I'm taking care of things
here while he's away.
You got a problem with that?
No job is worth what
we're going to do to you.
We will crush you
like a tin can.
[Venom roars]
A bizarre creature is
attacking Stark Enterprises.
The most incredible thing
about this creature
is that it bears a striking
resemblance to Spider-Man.
Spider-Man?
I'm going down there myself.
The creature seems to have
all of Spider-Man's powers,
but it calls itself Venom.
Eddie!
[growling]
-[lasers zap]
-Aaah!
[Dormammu] Mordo!
My master.
Venom is facing
formidable foes.
There is a chance that
the probe will be lost to us.
[Dormammu] Mordo,
I leave nothing to chance.
The probe will be secured,
if not by Venom alone,
then with someone else.
Someone else?
When I ordered you to retrieve
the symbiote from space,
I did so not only
because of its strength,
but also because it
was about to reproduce.
The symbiote can do that?
It can, and it has.
There is now another.
But to be effective,
won't the second symbiote
need as its host
someone as fanatical as Brock?
[Dormammu] Yes.
-[Cletus laughing]
-Perhaps even more so.
[laughing]
Sorry, nobody's allowed
in here right now.
[guard groans]
[loud crash]
Who are you? [giggles]
What in the name of--
[Mordo]
It is my master, Dormammu,
who confers this gift
upon you, Kasady.
-Gift?
-Remember?
You wanted the same power
that I offered Eddie Brock.
This is it?
But to enjoy it,
you must first swear
to serve Dormammu forever.
No problem, man.
He sounds like my kind of guy.
Let me have the power.
What do I do?
This is a symbiote,
a living organism.
It must bond with you.
And then I get
to be like Brock?
Similar, but different,
as different
as you are from Brock.
Once you bond, it will reflect
your hatred for humanity,
your lust for destruction.
-I'll take it!
-It must take you.
Come on.
What are you waiting for?
I am yours, man.
[giggles]
We're gonna wreak glorious
carnage throughout the land!
Carnage, eh?
I like the sound of that.
You promised us carnage.
Deliver it!
[Mordo laughs]
[Cletus screams]
-What's wrong?
-Kasady is gone.
There is only Carnage!
[Spider-Man] War Machine,
he reacts to loud noise!
[War Machine]
I've got just the thing:
a concentrated
sonic disrupter blast.
Aah!
[Spider-Man] Whatever
you do, don't stop!
[Carnage laughing]
Who are you?!
Your offspring.
Offspring?
Yes. Yes!
We recall replicating.
Our flame-headed friend
sent us to get this.
Call us Carnage!
[Spider-Man] Carnage?
There's another symbiote?
Sorry to interrupt the reunion.
We hoped
we'd run into you again.
You know me?
Kasady!
Think of the damage
we can do now, man!
[cackling]
[War Machine]
If you want that probe,
you've got to go through me.
With pleasure!
Well, what are you
waiting for?!
Why did Dormammu send you?!
Didn't he trust us?
-[Ashley] Eddie!
-Ashley.
You're just a sentimental
old fool, Dad.
And we've got to do
everything ourselves.
[Ashley screams]
No!
The party's
not over yet, freak.
Ohhh!
-[cackling]
-It wasn't that funny.
[growling]
Whoa!
[groaning]
I don't give up that easily.
We'll make you sorry
you didn't!
Will you--
will you be all right?
Eddie, let me see
your face for a minute.
You've got your power back.
Are you still going
to fight injustice?
[growls]
[groaning]
We could leave you now.
We've done our job,
but we want a bonus.
Dad? Ha ha!
Ready for
some father-son quality time?
Between the two of us,
there won't be enough
left of Spider-Man
to fit in a matchbox,
but we'll try, won't we?
[upbeat rock music]
♪ Spider-Man, Spider-Man ♪
♪ Radioactive Spider-Man ♪
♪ Spider blood, spider blood ♪
♪ Radioactive spider blood ♪
♪ Spider blood ♪
♪ Spider-Man ♪