[Peter] Previously on
Spider-Man.
Are you related to
Richard and Mary Parker?
The last time I saw them, they
stood where you stand now.
[man in blue] Wolfgang,
the KGB are onto us.
You must make it out!
This weapon is more
dangerous than ever.
-[gun clicks]
-I'll take that.
[Spider-Man] The Chameleon!
Welcome to my temporary base,
Spider-Man.
For years, there was a
rumor of a doomsday device,
created by a German master spy
who planned to take over the
world, I intend to do the same.
[Spider-Man] No!
I've been betrayed!
[man] The infamous Kingpin.
[man] Drop your weapons!
This complex will be rubble!
[Kingpin]
Head for that stairway!
[explosion booming]
-Time to leave.
-My men and I thank you.
There are pieces of the puzzle
I'd like to share with you.
But you'd best hear it
from Professor Omar Mosley.
He knows the story of
The Six Forgotten Warriors.
My parents were never traitors.
Now all that remains is
for the world to find out.
[theme music playing]
♪ Spider-Man, Spider-Man ♪
-♪ Radioactive Spider-Man ♪
-[gunshot booming]
[weapons whooshing]
-[explosion booming]
-♪ Spider blood, spider blood ♪
♪ Radioactive spider blood ♪
♪ Spider blood, spider blood,
-[explosion booming]
-[creature roaring]
[monster roaring]
♪ Spider-Man, Spider-Man ♪
[suspenseful music playing]
[Spider-Man] I've
got to find them
or the world will
be in great danger.
I've got to find
The Six Forgotten Warriors.
I still can hardly
believe the story
Omar Mosley told Robbie and me.
[suspenseful music playing]
Mr. Robertson!
You got my message.
-I came as fast as I could.
-I'm glad you did.
[knocks]
Robbie, come in!
[Robbie] Omar,
this is Peter Parker.
The one I told you about?
Mr. Robertson says you
have a story I should hear.
Yes.
I've kept this
all these years.
This is where the story begins.
That shield!
It looks just like the one that
belonged to Captain America!
The story of The Six American
Warriors began in 1942,
the dark days of World War II.
A scientist named Dr. Reinstein
created a serum to turn
a normal human into what
he called a super-soldier.
It is time to
unveil the volunteer
for this top-secret experiment,
Private Steve Rogers!
-[suspenseful music]
-[water splashing]
-[electricity buzzing]
-[suspenseful music]
Rogers is the is
merely the first ever
new breed of super-soldiers;
gentlemen, meet
the new champion on the
Allied Forces, Captain America.
-[dramatic music]
-[spectators exclaiming]
In the name of the fatherland
I will destroy this
American war machine.
[blows thudding]
It is going to explode!
-[explosion booming]
-[people shouting]
[dramatic music playing]
When the German spy sabotaged
the super-soldier experiment,
Dr. Reinstein was lost.
With him went the secret of
to the super-soldier serum.
The only known copy of
it had been in that lab.
A team of scientists tried
to re-create the formula.
They wanted to make an
army of super-soldiers.
But because of wartime
chemical shortages,
only five more doses
could be synthesized.
So, five young
volunteers were found
to become America's new heroes.
However, the new process was
discovered to be unstable.
Miraculously, no one was hurt.
The process was
obviously too dangerous
to ever be used again.
And yet, there was
an amazing result.
Each volunteer was
affected differently.
One's muscle strength
was so increased,
he became incredibly fast.
The other gained the
ability to control her mass.
She could will herself to
become lighter than air.
Another was able to
create sonic shock waves
-[rubble rumbling]
-with his vocal cords.
The final two came closest
to duplicating
Captain America's powers.
However, the five
new heroes discovered
that their powers
weren't permanent.
They would wear
off after a time.
The scientists
deduced that some day
those powers would
cease altogether.
So, to ration their use,
they created ring devices
to turn the powers
on only when needed.
Only Captain America's
powers were permanent,
since he was the only one
who took Reinstein's formula.
He was the true super-soldier.
Soon the others took names
to suit their new identities.
They became The Destroyer,
Miss America, The Thunderer,
The Black Marvel
and The Whizzer.
With the Cap as their leader,
they were to be called
The Six American Warriors.
Miss America?
The Thunderer?
With those names they expected
to be taken seriously?
Yes, and they were.
Well, it was a
different time then.
[Peter Parker] The Whizzer?
[Omar Mosley] For his speed.
Uh, how do you know all
about this, Professor Mosley?
Way back then I was the
Black Marvel's chauffeur.
I was what you might call a
sidekick to the Black Marvel.
His real identity
was Dan Lyons.
The purpose of
The Six was to destroy
pith-com spies
and saboteurs.
Then one night, The Six stumble
onto the most devious plot
the Axis powers ever hatched.
It began as an attack on
a German spy rendezvous,
but it turned into
more with the discovery
of a unique matchbook cover.
[boards clattering]
[explosion booming]
-[man grunting]
-[men yelling]
-[bodies thudding]
-[dramatic music playing]
It was Cap who examined
the cover and found on it
a microscopically
reduced film negative.
[suspenseful music playing]
It contained information
leading to a deadly weapon
designed to defeat
The Six American Warriors
and the country as well.
[suspenseful music playing]
-[water roaring]
-[dramatic music]
[thunder rumbling]
[helicopter engine roaring]
-[thunder rumbling]
-[dramatic music]
[helicopter engine roaring]
[helicopter rotors whirring]
[suspenseful music playing]
[keys clicking]
Excellent, thanks to
your work I have reached
phase one of Project Doomsday.
Herr Dr. Groitzig, you are
now of no further use to me.
Dispose of him.
[shield whooshing]
Stay back!
Leave him alone.
[gunshots booming]
-[shock waves roaring]
-[weapons whooshing]
[Whizzer whooshing]
We know about project Doomsday.
We're here to pull the plug.
-I think not!
-[weapon whooshing]
This energy vortex will
keep you trapped forever!
-Cap!
-Stay back!
All of you!
We are evenly matched,
you cannot escape.
Maybe, but I can see to
it that you're not around
to activate this atrocity.
-Something
-[Miss America exclaiming]
[Spider-Man] Captain
America sacrificed himself
so that the Doomsday
device would never be used.
Do I have the guts to make
that kind of sacrifice?
Pray that I never
have to find out.
The machine's advanced
power source was perpetual.
Cap and the Skull would
remain in stasis indefinitely.
-Now what do we do?
-We can't just
keep this our little secret!
Can't we?
After much arguing,
The Five decided they
could keep it a secret.
They divided the six
keys among themselves.
Except for the Black Marvel,
who, by luck of the draw,
took the remaining two.
And they all vowed to find a way
to one day free Captain America.
What happened to them?
Of course,
they then got distracted
by the business of
winning the war.
But when the war ended,
they received a rude shock.
They were ordered to disband.
The war department feared
their dwindling powers
would prove to be a liability.
[Miss America]
Now what do we do?
[Black Marvel] I plan to
devote my life to research
that might some day save Cap.
Cap is gone for good!
I'll never abandon Cap!
I'm gonna protect the
site to my dying day!
[Omar Mosley] When they
couldn't reach an agreement,
they all moved on,
the war became part of history,
and the warriors, they were
forgotten as things are.
In time,
The Six Forgotten Warriors.
I decided to help Dan Lyons
in his scientific pursuits
to save Captain America.
I went to college and
became a scientist.
He put me in charge of
one of his companies
that was doing research
on vortex phenomena.
But Dan died, and so
I started teaching.
Professor Mosley was the
hardest teacher I ever had,
but we became friends,
and years later,
he confided his story to me.
What about the keys?
-Where are they?
-They're in a safe place.
The Six kept their
identity secret.
Today they could be anywhere,
if they're still alive.
[Peter Voiceover] I get it now.
When My parents found Groitzig,
he wanted to disable
the Doomsday device,
but he needed the six keys.
My parents must have found
the secret identities
of the American Six for him.
But someone stopped them
before they could get
Groitzig out of the country.
And Groitzig spent the next
20 years fearing for his life.
Omar, this Doomsday device,
what is it?
Only The Red Skull knew that.
But what I do know is
someone is after the keys
to the Doomsday complex.
And if they get them,
the world is in dire peril.
[Spider-Man] That
someone is the Kingpin.
He has everything he needs
and I have no way to stop him.
I'm stuck waiting to see
what he throws at us next.
[man snarling]
You once worked for my
arch enemy Silvermane.
-Are you the traitor?
-No, I swear it ain't me.
Well one of you has
betrayed me once
and may try to betray me again.
But I'm warning you,
the information inside this box
should make me powerful enough
to squash all my enemies.
Look, it's all here!
The owners of the keys.
We've already infiltrated
every database in the country.
If these people have cars
or even a dog, we'll find them!
Distribute the information
they will need to
find those keys.
This is what I'm looking for.
Six statues of six
ancients gods of war.
But you said you wanted keys!
These are keys.
The base of each statue
contains a pin tumbler key
of a very advanced design.
Go and bring them to me.
Bring me the keys to our
future ownership of the world.
-[birds twittering]
-[kids laughing]
[light music playing]
You can't make the
superhero's head
smaller than his hands, Bobby.
Maybe not when you were
drawin' comics, Mr. Frank.
But this is what's happenin'
in comics nowadays.
But it doesn't look real.
So what?
Nothin' you ever drew back
in the '40's looked real.
Like that goofy
Whizzer character.
Nobody ever took him for real.
-[Rhino roaring]
-[wall clattering]
I'm lookin' for a Whizzer.
Mr. Frank, what's
he talkin' about?
Whizzer, you got
somethin' I want,
and you're gonna give it to me,
or you ain't gonna
live to see 100.
[Spider-Man] How can
I stop the Kingpin?
If only I could, whoa!
Did I just see
The Vulture chasing
after an old woman
who was flying?
Stay away from me!
-[whooshing]
-[suspenseful music]
[woman screaming]
[dramatic music playing]
Out of web fluid?
Not now!
One cartridge left, gotta move.
Made it!
Whoever you are,
you're safe now.
Not on your life, son.
That feathered freak
stole something in my bag
that could destroy the world!
It didn't happen to
be a small statue, did it?
-How do you know about--
-Don't worry!
I'll get it back, Miss America.
I can't fight The Insidious
Six on one web cartridge.
I could go home,
but I've still got
some spare web
cartridges at Aunt May's.
[Nick] Your promises
to your old pals
have put them in
great danger, Keene.
What do you mean, Nick?
The Whizzer, Bob Frank,
has been attacked
and his key stolen.
So has Miss America,
Madeline Joyce.
I could've prevented this
if you had told me
the whole truth!
I thought by not revealing
their identities,
it might keep them
out of harm's way.
You were wrong.
-Yes, again.
-[door latch clicks]
We'll talk later,
Fury, over and out.
Keene, you're still here.
You can join us for lunch.
May, you must let
me have those items!
I can't wait any longer!
What on earth is
he talking about?
Keene, not now.
If you don't,
we're in great danger.
You don't know what's at stake.
Ben told me and
I made a solemn vow
to him not to let you have them.
-[May exclaims]
-[clattering]
Marlow, we're here for that key!
Now fork over that key,
or The Shocker here
takes care of the ladies.
Get back!
How did you find me here?
Kingpin can get information
from anywhere he needs to.
Even S.H.I.E.L.D. headquarters.
[Spider-Man]
I've had it, frog face!
Stay out of this, wall crawler!
[Spider-Man grunting]
-[blows thudding]
-[Spider-Man grunting]
[weaponized fluid splashing]
[Spider-Man grunting]
Look out!
I gotta get him outside
to protect my family!
May, they've come for it
and they'll tear your
place apart to find it.
Tell me where they're hidden.
Here, In the basement,
under the furnace.
[suspenseful music playing]
Uh-oh, that's it
for the webbing.
[grunting]
No, stop, stop!
Freeze, web lamer or
I spread your lady!
No, don't!
I give up.
Who the heck are you?
I'm called The Destroyer.
And if you want this,
you'll have to take it from me.
[Scorpion] That's it!
I'm through playing around!
Ah, it's a placebo.
[Scorpion] Come on,
let's get outta here!
Are you all right?
I have to deactivate.
You can't stay here.
Look at this poor old house.
You've got to come
to my house now,
where you'll be safe.
You too, Mary Jane.
No!
I intend to wait
here for my husband!
[Anna] Fine.
Come along, May.
Are you okay?
Yeah, but he's not
in such great shape.
He's coming around.
Did they get the statue?
Yes.
I should never have
tried to use my powers.
I failed again.
Mr. Marlow?
What do you have
to do with this?
I'm one of the group
who called ourselves--
The Six American Warriors?
That was a long time ago.
But what brought you here?
This house.
Ah, it all goes back
to over 50 years ago.
It was in the late 1930's.
Ben Parker and I always
wanted to be heroes.
It was all we thought
about when we were young.
Well, almost all
we thought about.
Nora Sharp was also
on both our minds.
We were both head over
heels in love with her.
At first, Ben had
the inside track.
But then the war started
and I was chosen
to be in a project
which would turn me
into a real superhero.
Against orders, I told Nora.
She was enthralled.
Ben couldn't compete with it.
He was just a regular,
decent guy.
[crowd chattering]
Then Nora and I married
during the war.
Did she love The Destroyer
or Keene Marlow?
All I knew was
I was in paradise,
but paradise never
lasts for very long.
It was not until 1946,
right after the war ended,
when I told Nora my
powers weren't permanent.
She begged me to give
up being a superhero,
but I couldn't!
I was hooked on
the thrill of it!
Even after the war,
I continued to work in
secret for the government.
Then one night,
I let my beautiful wife down.
I saw a bank being robbed.
I activated my power.
It was an impetuous
fool hardy thing to do.
[guns firing]
My wife was caught
in the crossfire.
How ironic.
I've become The Destroyer,
all right.
The Destroyer of lives.
Ben Parker was as
devastated as I was.
From that moment,
we both knew that
with great power,
there must always come
great responsibility.
So that's how Uncle Ben
learned that lesson.
I gave my ring and
my costume to Ben
to keep hidden
somewhere in his house.
Hidden from me,
so that I'd never be
tempted to use them again.
But I also gave him my key
to the Doomsday device.
Fury knew about that.
When he heard May Parker
was selling the house,
he urged me to stop her.
I appreciate you
telling me all this,
more than you could know.
Now rest here for a few minutes,
there's something I must do.
[Peter] This will
only take a second.
What a sad life
Mr. Marlow has had.
[Peter Parker] No kidding.
My worst fear is that
I'll end up like Marlow
and jeopardize
Mary Jane's life.
Why do I do this?
Why do I still have to
put on this costume?
What is it, tiger?
What's the matter?
I just want you to know
I love you, M.J.
Fury says the damage
made on this house
will be taken care
of by S.H.I.E.L.D.
-Fair enough.
-You've been awfully silent.
What's on your mind, Spider-Man?
I was thinking
you were a real superhero
in World War II,
but for the rest of your life
you've been a regular person.
Did you miss being a costumed
crime fighter at all?
Just between us,
costume cronies?
I missed it more than I would
miss the very air I breathe.
Being a superhero
is a wonderful gift,
one not to be taken lightly.
I was afraid you
were gonna say that.
The worst part about
it is I agree with you.
[theme music playing]
♪ Spider-Man ♪
♪ Radioactive Spider-Man ♪
♪ Spider blood, spider blood ♪
♪ Radioactive spider blood ♪
♪ Spider-Man ♪