[Mary Jane]
Previously onSpider-Man.
[prison guard] He was doing
special effects
with Miranda Wilson,
but Beck got sloppy
and a camera copter crashed.
[brakes screeching]
[Mary Jane] When Spider-Man
opened the door of her car,
Miranda Wilson was gone!
Now the producers want
to finish that film,
and I got the job.
Congratulations!
-[director] Action!
-Help!
Mary Jane!
Can you help me find her?
This way!
[Miranda] He became Mysterio
again to save my life.
Why are you doing this?!
I require your body.
At last!
My face restored!
-No, Miranda!
-What went wrong?!
The machine was
never designed to work.
This was the only thing
that kept you alive.
[Spider-Man]
What's that noise?
Get out of here!
[explosion]
Mary Jane,
all this has made me realize
just how precious you are to me.
I'm flattered, but I'm already
in love with Peter Parker.
Mary Jane, there's something
I've got to show you.
[gasps]
[upbeat rock music]
♪ Spider-Man ♪
♪ Radioactive Spider-Man ♪
♪ Spider blood
Spider blood ♪
♪ Radioactive spider blood ♪
♪ Spider blood
Spider blood ♪
♪ Radioactive spider blood ♪
[explosions booming]
[growling]
♪ Spider-Man ♪
[sirens wailing]
You see, Mary Jane, it's me.
Peter?
But this is impossible!
Here, let me prove it.
Wait, Peter, there's
so much I have to ask you.
Fasten your seat belt.
Don't worry, Mary Jane.
I'd never let anything
happen to you.
Believe me.
[gasps]
So, what do you think?
How could you have
kept this from me so long?
It makes me wonder what other
little secrets you're hiding.
How'd you like to take
a lifetime to find out?
What?
What are you saying?
I lost you once because
I didn't act quickly enough.
I'm not gonna make
that mistake again.
Mary Jane, will you marry me?
Mary Jane!
Why did you do that?
To prove to myself
that you'll always
be there for me
when it really counts.
You will, won't you, Peter?
Yes. Yes, I will.
Then of course I'll marry you.
[Peter] This is
the happiest day of my life.
If only I had a ring.
Wait a minute.
Now, it's official.
Family heirloom?
Well, I wouldn't want
it appraised by Tiffany's.
[screech]
-[ominous music]
-[growling]
[keys jingling]
[electronic humming]
Did you see?
He isthe one.
Yes.
Now that we have found him,
he must be ours.
[Aunt Anna] You're what?!
If only Peter's Uncle Ben
had lived to see this day.
Peter, Mary Jane,
getting married.
Peter Parker,
you're too young
for the responsibility
of marriage!
Where will you live?
How will you live?
Well, we hadn't thought of--
Besides, I've just gotten
my Mary Jane back
from heaven knows where.
She's in no condition to make
such an important decision.
Aunt Anna,
I may have partial amnesia,
but one thing has
remained constant.
My love for Peter.
Our minds are made up.
By this time next month,
we'll be
Mr. and Mrs. Peter Parker.
Oh, Anna, isn't this amazing?
Yes, that would be
one word to describe it.
[knocking]
Who is it?
[Peter]
Uh, Dr. Connors?
It's Peter
and Mary Jane Watson.
Blast! Why now?
Do you really think he'll do it?
Dr. Connors will do
anything for you, Peter.
Peter, Mary Jane, couldn't
it have waited till morning?
Uh, maybe you're right.
We'll come back in the--
Sorry, doctor, but this is
much too important for later.
We didn't realize you were
in the middle of an experiment.
No matter,
now what's so important
that it can't wait
till tomorrow?
Dr. Connors, you've been
more than a teacher to Peter.
More than a friend, too.
You're the closest thing
he has to a father.
And since neither Peter
nor I have any male relatives--
close ones that is--
We were hoping that you--
We were hoping
that you'd consider
giving the bride
away at our wedding.
Your wedding?
I'm honored.
But are you sure?
-What's wrong?
-Don't worry.
-It's probably just a brownout.
-[spider-sense tingling]
No, it's more than that.
What is this?!
Who are you?
We want you!
[Peter] If only I could get
a chance to become Spider-Man.
[glass smashes]
Nice diversion, MJ.
It might not be
so bad having someone
in on my little secret.
-Aah!
-No, don't hurt her!
This cannot be our father.
See how he fears for the female.
He is our father.
I feel it in my blood.
Bah, I do not believe
that we owe anything to a human.
Better listen to the lady,
scale-boy!
Unh!
This human is strong!
See?
They are full of surprises.
[Spider-Man]
Doc, are you--
[groaning]
[gasps]
MJ, get out of here!
You are going nowhere!
Gecko, Monitor, come!
Yaah!
We must return to
our realm with our father.
[growling]
MJ! Doc Connors!
Wait a minute, MJ's ring.
-The spider tracer.
-[tracer beeping]
Bingo.
She's coming in loud and clear.
There!
[Gecko]
Even if he is our father,
why do we not destroy
the useless human female now?
Because Gila has a soft spot
in her heart for humans.
No, Monitor, unlike you,
I think all living creatures
should be treated with respect.
[chuckles]
An amusing concept.
We are stronger than all humans,
therefore we should
be their leaders.
[Gila]
Our father disagrees.
We must follow his will.
If he is really our father.
Who are you?
What do you want from us?
All your questions will
be answered soon, Father.
Why do you think Dr. Connors
is your father?
It is in our blood.
We can feel it.
You see, once, we crawled
on our bellies in the dark.
No past, no future.
Then something happened.
We began to grow,
to think with the knowledge
of the father
who gave us his blood.
We share it.
That is how we know
he is our father.
You gave us life, Father.
Now you must fulfill
your destiny, and ours.
What destiny?
[Gila]
To lead us into the future.
To tell us our true purpose.
They're as crazy
as they are ugly.
You didn't create them.
I don't think
it's as simple as that.
In my impatience to make
a scientific breakthrough
and re-grow my arm,
I combined my own DNA
with the DNA of a lizard.
In doing so,
I turned myself into a monster.
In seeking
a more permanent solution,
I began experimenting with
my own mutated body chemistry.
The experiment failed.
I was furious!
If I'd been thinking clearly,
I never would have
let the fluid
go down the drain.
That fluid must have
been what they drank.
They will learn that their
existence is a pure accident,
and I can't lead them anywhere.
They will not be pleased.
Dr. Connors, your arm!
-[growling]
-Monitor, look!
Run, Mary Jane,
before it's too late!
Tell my wife and son,
tell them I love them!
Ohh!
-[screams]
-Whoa, MJ, it's me.
Peter!
Oh, wake me up.
Tell me this is a nightmare.
Don't worry, I'm here now,
and everything will be okay.
Dr. Connors claims
it-- it was all a result
of that accident
he told me about.
I was afraid Neogenics
was at the bottom of this.
Look, MJ, follow this tunnel
back a short distance.
You'll get out of here safely.
-What about you?
-I've gotta find Doc Connors.
You have to let
somebody else go.
No, I have to go.
This is what I do to make
a difference in the world.
Is this the way
it's always going to be then?
You risk your life
against insane odds
while I sit back and worry?
I'm sorry, I have no choice.
If you think I'm just going
to wait, Peter Parker,
you don't know me at all.
[growling, hissing,
and shouting]
-Hold him!
Don't worry, Doc,
the cavalry's here!
You've got to hold off
that transformation.
-[groaning]
-Try!
-[screaming]
-I don't like the sound of that.
[lizards growling]
I like the sound
of that even less.
Come on Doc,
let's get out of here
before the party
gets too crowded.
No, Father, don't leave us!
[doorbell rings]
Mary Jane,
what are you doing here?
It-- It's your husband.
Curt?
What's happened?
There was this experiment,
and he...
He's turning into--
The lizard?
You know?
Come inside, quickly.
Curt said I should
watch this tape
if anything happened to him.
He left specific instructions.
Margaret,
if you're playing this,
then all my attempts to control
the lizard have failed.
You must now take extreme
measures, my darling.
First, take Billy to stay
with your sister, and then,
in the safe, you will find
a kind of genetic neutron bomb,
harmless to all life
except that which has been
mutated by Neogenics.
I know this is hard for you,
Margaret,
but you must use this on me.
You must destroy the lizard.
Are you really going
to destroy your own husband?
No, but he's right.
I must destroy the lizard.
We need someone familiar
with Neogenics to help us.
We need Peter Parker.
Uh, Margaret,
Peter's out of town,
on assignment
for The Daily Bugle, I think.
Oh, dear.
But he's always told me
that Debra Whitman
was smarter than he is
any day of the week.
Debra, of course!
This way.
I sense the blood.
And soon
it will stain the ground.
Monitor, that's our father
you're talking about!
That remains to be proven!
Eeny-meeny-miny-mo.
This way.
How can you be sure?
Stick with me, Doc.
I make these kind
of executive-type decisions
all the time.
Uh-oh, visitors!
Well, the gang's all here.
Let the party begin.
[groaning]
Father, we don't
want to hurt you.
Speak for yourself, Gila.
[growling]
[roaring]
Connors! No!
Ha ha!
Oh, please, not this!
Not now!
[growling]
No!
This is not the way!
Yes, it's all clear to me now.
I am your father.
I once thought
that it was my lot in life
to improve the human condition,
but I was rejected
by the humans, defeated!
[growling]
Debra! Are you all right?
I got the wind
knocked out of me.
Doc Connors, come back!
-[explosion]
-[Debra] Peter!
[roaring]
[zapping]
[gasping]
Curt.
Is he... ?
He'll be okay.
Oh, thank heaven!
I was nearly destroyed by him!
The humans
cannot be reasoned with,
and they will
not let us coexist with them.
They must be destroyed!
[Gila] No!
We cannot act like savages.
Our father has spoken.
Doc Connors!
You're making a mistake!
This isn't the way
any living beings should behave.
Fool! I am no longer
that weakling Connors.
Father, the human insults you.
There is but one fate for him.
No! Leave him alone.
She is a traitor
to our father's will!
-Take her too!
-Wh-What?
No! No!
May I dispose
of them for you, Father?
Yes, do what you must.
Come on, Flash,
don't be such a slug.
Let's go party!
This isn't like you, Deb.
We've partied every night
for the last two weeks.
I can't believe I'm saying this,
but I need to study.
Well, I don't.
Yes, you do.
Drowning your sadness
in parties
isn't going to change the fact
that Michael Morbius is gone.
And running away
from the very science
that turned him into a vampire
won't bring him back.
Now, do you wanna go to
the library with me and study,
-or not?
-Not.
Suit yourself.
[sobbing]
[Mary Jane] Debra?
Your roommate said
we'd find you on campus.
Mary Jane, Mrs. Connors,
what's wrong?
There's been
a Neogenics accident.
Curt desperately
needs your help.
[Debra] If what you're
telling me is true,
this device is intended
to work like a neutron bomb.
Instead of exploding,
it would irradiate its target.
Curt wants me
to destroy him with this.
What I need to know is,
do I have
any other alternatives?
Maybe I can adjust
the bomb to neutralize,
as opposed
to destroy the target.
At least, I can try.
It's no use. These chains were
stolen from above.
[Spider-Man] What are
they going to do with us?
-They'll put us in the games.
-The games?
I had hoped
our father would come
and put an end to the games,
but instead...
[crying]
Gila, don't give up.
Listen, I know
how you came to be.
You and the others evolved
into what you are now
based on Doc Connors' DNA.
You got it
from a fluid that accidentally
washed into the sewers.
An accident?
Is that all we are?
-I'm sorry. I shouldn't have...
-[lock clicks]
Time for the games!
Something tells me
we're not talking checkers here.
[Gila] An accident?
We are nothing but an accident?
-[spider-sense tingling]
-Uh-oh!
[roaring cheers]
Our people are ready, Father.
Unite them around
a shared hatred for mankind!
My people!
Behold the human.
They are weak, these humans.
You must never fear them.
We will overcome them together!
[roaring cheers]
Release the centurions!
Great, this is exactly why I got
out of professional wrestling.
From the look
of these footprints,
there must be thousands
of these creatures,
whatever they are.
We may have to detonate
the device right in their midst.
You seem so strong, Margaret.
This situation scares
the heck out of me.
Oh, I'm frightened, all right,
but I love Curt.
I'd do anything for him.
In a strange way,
all I've had to endure for him
has shown me my own potential,
made me see
how strong I really am.
Mary Jane,
you don't have to do this.
No. Just like you,
I must do this.
[roars]
[Spider-Man] You've got
to be faster than that
if you want a little thing
like world domination.
[roaring]
Hey! Thanks, pal.
You were lucky, Spider-Man.
Your opponent was unworthy.
Oh, you noticed that,
too, huh?
Now you will fight someone
who is your superior.
-[growling]
-[groaning]
[crowd cheering]
Listen! What's that?
It's coming from over there.
Good, it sounds like they're
all in there together.
The device is primed.
All you have to do is press
this button to activate it.
[roaring]
Uhh!
-Aaah!
-[groaning roar]
[gasps] Curt!
Oh, Peter!
-[roars]
-[groaning]
-[crowd cheering]
-Oh!
We must do it, now!
Mary Jane!
Get to the center
and press the button!
An accident gave us a chance
to live as the humans live.
To love, to laugh.
But instead we have chosen
stupidity, brutality.
[roaring]
[Spider-Man]
Can't give up!
For both our sakes!
We could have been
better than them,
but instead, we have
chosen to act as animals.
What?!
So we have chosen,
so shall we be!
[pained roars]
What's the matter?
With all my superpowers,
I was helpless.
It took three normal women
to save the world.
Anything wrong with that?
No, but I was hoping
to be the only one
to wear the superhero costume
in the family.
Of course, it'd probably
look better on you anyway.
Thank you, Mary Jane.
You've given me my life back.
No, Margaret.
It's you who've helped me.
More than you'll ever know.
Debra, you were brilliant.
I guess I'm not as finished
with science as I thought.
Ah, alone at last.
Mary Jane, this whole thing
only proves to me
how dangerous being Spider-Man's
wife is going to be.
Are you sure you want to keep
wearing my ring?
Bet your life on it, tiger.
It will take a lot
to be Spider-Man's wife,
but I learned something today.
If anyone can do it,
it'll be Mary Jane Watson.
[upbeat rock music]
♪ Spider-Man, Spider-Man ♪
♪ Radioactive Spider-Man ♪
♪ Spider blood, spider blood ♪
♪ Radioactive spider blood ♪
♪ Spider blood ♪
♪ Spider-Man ♪