[upbeat rock music]
♪ Spider-Man ♪
♪ Radioactive Spider-Man ♪
♪ Spider blood
Spider blood ♪
♪ Radioactive spider blood ♪
♪ Spider blood
Spider blood ♪
♪ Radioactive spider blood ♪
[explosions booming]
[growling]
♪ Spider-Man ♪
[dramatic music]
[cackling]
[screaming]
Dad? Dad.
-Harry.
-No, no.
Don't leave me, not again.
[cackling]
Spider-Man!
Oh, please save my father.
Oh, no, stay back! [yelling]
[cackling]
You're next, boy.
-[cackling]
-Nooo!
Nooo!
[heavy breathing]
[heavy sigh]
[dramatic music]
[gasping]
Hello, young Osborn.
It's about time you got up.
There's lots
we have to do together.
[cackling]
[dramatic music]
[Green Goblin] Turn here.
But, but that's the way to--
Yes, I know.
[cackling]
Go to the ground floor
janitor's closet.
[beeping]
[Osborn] I'm going crazy.
You can't be real.
When you see your father again,
you'll know just how real I am.
Now, push up
on the spigot in the sink
and then rotate it
all the way around.
[dramatic beat]
See? if I were just a figment
of your imagination,
how would I know
about this room.
Wh-Where are you?
How are you
communicating with me?
Good question, boy.
I wish I had an answer.
It's all Spider-Man's fault.
That was the woman I loved!
I'm taking you down,
Goblin,
even if it means I go with you!
[struggling] Now!
[Green Goblin]
Osborn needs me!
You'll pay, Osborn!
If I have to chase you
forever, you'll pay!
Not if I can help it!
Something's wrong!
Aaah! No, not you!
Not now!
No! Help me!
Aaah!
[Green Goblin]
He put me here.
I thought I'd be
trapped alone forever.
I searched desperately
for someone who could hear me,
and I found you.
M-m-me? Why me?
Maybe subconsciously
you were looking for me.
All I know is that I need you
to get me out of this limbo.
Turn this valve, Osborn.
No! Why should I do
anything for you?
Because I know
where your father is,
and I'll tell you
if you do as I say.
Turn the valve
for his sake boy.
Do it!
-[hissing]
-[coughing]
[pained screams]
Night after night,
it's the same thing.
I get one punk off the street
and ten more take his place.
After I lost you, I promised
I'd make the world
a better place.
I just wish I could
make a real difference
in one good person's life.
[sobbing]
Ma'am, it's dangerous
to be out here this late.
Let me get you a cab.
No, no, no, thank you.
I need to be here right now
with my late husband.
I feel so alone, so helpless.
I just know a crime
has been committed,
but I can't prove it.
[Frank] Why don't
you tell me about it?
My friend Mae has been a dear
to stay with me
through all this,
but she's asleep upstairs.
I'm convinced her nephew,
the one I told you about,
knows where Mary Jane is.
For some strange reason,
my niece often confided in him.
What's the boy like?
He's very secretive.
Oh, and he's brought
so much misery to poor Mae.
Ugh, I wouldn't be surprised
by anything he'd do.
But I can't actually
accuse Peter of anything
without proof.
Hmm, then let me see
what I can do.
Wait, why are you helping me?
Let's just say
because I need to.
Liz, I'm finally
starting to believe
that Mary Jane is gone for good.
And I don't think
I'll ever get over it.
Me, neither.
How's Harry been coping?
Well, I tried to get him
to come out with us,
but he just wanted to sleep.
Hey, how about we cheer him up
with a late-night pizza.
You know, that
just might do the trick.
Come on.
Hey, Liz, give me a hand.
I can't carry the pizza
and open the door.
And I thought you photographers
had to be as coordinated
as Spider-Man.
-[spider-sense tingling]
-Danger!
-Liz, no!
-[grunting]
[explosion]
She's okay, just shook up.
Liz and I were saved by
my spider strength, but Harry--
[cackling]
The Goblin, he's back!
That maniac!
I knew Norman had lost it,
but would he blow up
his own son trying
to get back at me?
Now, do I get to see my father?
All in due time.
But I did what you wanted!
I destroyed Spider-Man.
The only thing you destroyed
was Harry, you creep!
[groaning]
Aaah!
[grunting]
Ooh!
I don't know how you got back,
and I don't care,
but I've been waiting
for this for a long time.
You're all mine, Norman.
Harry?! [coughing]
Harry's the Goblin now?
How did he get
the Goblin's power?
And how did he find out that
Peter Parker is Spider-Man?
You fool!
Why aren't you going
after Spider-Man?
I ran out of bombs!
Oh, we ran out of bombs,
did we?
Then go get more! Hurry!
[newscaster]
The police have confirmed
that one person
is missing in the blast.
Harry Osborn, son of the
industrialist, Norman Osborn,
who vanished four months ago.
Right on track, Chip.
Where there's Peter Parker,
there's trouble.
[newscaster] The criminal,
known as the Green Goblin,
was reported to be in the area
shortly
after the conflagration.
Frank, somebody must
have wanted to get
that Osborn kid real bad.
Yeah, but if he's still alive
then I want to find him.
Maybe he'll tell me
what he knows about Parker.
[Chip] I've got
an alternate address on Osborn.
Let's have it.
[horn blows]
I think I'll do this
as plain old Peter Parker.
The Osborn Estate guards
know me as Harry's best friend.
If they spot me inside, I'll
just say I'm looking for him,
which I am, sort of.
Okay, Harry, where are you?
What's this?
Well, well.
Harry's clothes
and his laptop in sleep mode.
He must have thought
it was off.
Nice.
Addresses for half a dozen
Goblin hideouts
across the city.
Norman set himself up
to be a one-goblin crime wave,
and now his son's
inherited the arsenal.
Lucky for me, Harry's a novice.
This list will lead me
right to him.
-Time to change back into--
-[spider-sense tingling]
Maybe not.
My spider-sense tells me
I'm being watched.
[Frank] You got a positive I.D.
on this guy, Chip?
Just like you thought, Frank.
It's Peter Parker.
Perfect. I'll keep on his tail
and see what he's up to.
I wish I knew
who was watching me
and where they are.
But I can't let
them slow me down.
There's too much at stake.
Well, this place is
on the Goblin's list,
but it doesn't get
the Good Housekeeping
Seal of Approval.
Ah, very clever, Norman.
[blows]
Okay, kid,
turn around real slow.
The Punisher, but why?
I'm looking
for Mary Jane Watson.
-You are?
-Yeah.
And three names keep coming up.
The Green Goblin,
Spider-Man, and Peter Parker.
So tell me,
what's the connection?
-Great.
-Talk to me, Parker.
I have only one thing to say--
trick or treat!
Come on, spider strength,
don't let me pass out.
Okay, smart boy.
Now you're gonna
tell me everything,
about Mary Jane Watson,
about Harry Osborn,
and about the secret identity
you've been hiding
from the world.
I think I know who you
really are, Peter Parker.
[dramatic beat]
The way I figure it, Parker,
you're really the Green Goblin.
What? That tranquilizer must
have gone to your head, too.
You took all these pictures
for The Bugle.
You're obviously
obsessed with Spider-Man,
and I'm told you're in love
with Mary Jane, too.
When she decided
she liked Harry better,
your mind snapped and you became
this Green Goblin character,
and you kidnapped her.
Brilliant deduction, Holmes.
But absolutely wrong.
[groans]
Goblin gloves!
Hope I can make 'em work.
I'm not here to play games, boy.
That's too bad.
Love to stick around for
the rest of your babble, but--
[groaning]
Now, if I could just
get this thing to start.
Whoa!
[laser blasts]
No wonder Norman went crazy!
Trying to steer this thing
would make anyone nuts!
Battle Van, stinger missile,
hone in on heat signature.
Fire.
Great!
[helicopter buzzing]
No!
Come on, up, up!
Whoa!
Uh-oh.
[groaning]
Now that I've seen how agile
you can be on that thing,
I know I'm right.
What's this, Parker?
[explosion]
What the devil?
[cackling]
Well, what do you know.
That must be me up there!
[laser zaps]
Harry's too high.
But I've got to reach him
before the Punisher does.
And he will try to get to him
because he's got the disk now.
[sighing] At least
I still have the printout.
But which one do I go to first?
You reading this, Chip?
It's from the disk
I took off Parker.
[Chip] Looks like
a complete list
of Goblin hideouts
across the city.
Parker's tied
into this some way.
How?
Chip, can you plot me
the most expedient course
to all these locations?
[Chip] Already on it, Frank.
[dramatic music]
You allowed yourself
to be chased across the city
like some stray dog?
While I'm trapped
in another dimension,
you're out there
ruining my reputation.
I'm not you!
Can't you get that
through your head?!
Ah, you have a temper.
I like it.
It looks like there's a little
of the old Goblin spirit
in you after all.
Maybe more than you realize.
Now, go to Oscorp.
There you'll find a new battle
glider your father built.
With it,
you can defeat Spider-Man
and that gun-crazy goon.
Then you'll tell me
where my father is?
Yes, yes,
just as I promised you.
But I want Spider-Man
destroyed first.
Now, go, go, go go!
[bang]
-[tracker clinks]
-[cackling]
Why am I letting the Punisher
beat me to the punch?
All he did was run down
the list of Goblin hideouts.
I have the benefit
of knowing
that the new Green Goblin
is Harry.
And like any good Osborn,
ultimately he'll end up
at his home away from home--
Oscorp.
[Green Goblin] The computer
sequencer will load
the battle parts automatically.
With this glider,
you will soon be invincible!
I don't care
about invincibility.
I just want to see
my father again.
[Spider-Man] I'm sorry, Harry,
but your father is gone.
Why are you doing this?
This isn't like you.
Don't listen to Parker!
He pretended to be your friend,
but he really wanted
to hurt you all along.
Yes, yes.
You betrayed me before Peter!
You stole Mary Jane away!
I can't trust you!
The real Green Goblin's
my friend.
[Spider-Man]
Who is he talking about?
With his help, I have a chance
to get my father back, see?
See?
Harry has
completely flipped out.
Harry, your father was
the Green Goblin.
He's lying, isn't he?
[gasping]
Your whining simp of a father
doesn't exist anymore.
I am the ultimate evolution
of Norman Osborn.
Smarter, stronger,
able to be more ruthless
than he ever was!
-[sobbing]
-There's nobody there, Harry.
You're talking to yourself.
Harry!
I'm Sorry I had to tell you,
but you've got
to snap out of this.
[sobs turn to cackling]
Sorry? [cackling]
Sorry for what?
For helping me find
my true destiny
as the new Green Goblin?!
[cackling]
It all makes sense now.
I'm the only one
who could hear him,
because I'm his son!
At last, I can earn his respect!
[cackling]
This isn't exactly
what I was hoping for.
[crashing]
How did you get in here?
I hit him with a tracer
on his last stop.
And I want answers.
[Spider-Man] Sorry, but I've
still got a Goblin to catch.
Battle Van, stun rockets,
minimum spread.
Bye-bye!
Battle Van,
heavy detonator pack,
ten-second delay.
[beeping]
[Spider-Man] You know,
I'm really getting tired
of that guy blowing things
up around me.
[Chip]
Frank, he's headed for
the George Washington Bridge.
[dramatic music]
No, not here again!
But it makes sense.
It's where I ended
his father's career
and where he wants to end mine.
[cackling]
Harry, we've been
friends a long time.
It doesn't have to end this way!
Friends?
Is that what we were, Peter?
-You could have fooled--
-[boom]
Missile on target.
Look out!
So, you led your friend
here, did you?
Thought you'd betray me
once more.
Guess again, traitor!
[intense music]
-[tires squealing]
-[honking]
Get away from here!
You'll never be able
to stop him!
[cackling]
You know, Harry,
I'm beginning to think
you are a son of mine.
[cackling]
Time this just right.
-[groaning]
-[dramatic music]
[gasping]
Harry!
No, not again.
It can't have happened again!
Blast!
He failed, failed!
What?
I don't believe it.
How can she be there?
How?
I searched all over,
but they're both gone.
I can't believe it.
It's the same way
I lost Mary Jane.
[Harry] ♪ Spider-Man
and the Punisher ♪
♪ Sittin' in a tree ♪
♪ MJ, MJ, MJ, and me ♪
[chuckles]
Your friend Osborn here
is a few pumpkins short
of a full pie.
So you're gonna have to tie up
a few loose ends for me, kid.
Once and for all,
where is Mary Jane Watson?
Oh, boy, now what do I do?
[doorbell rings]
No, that could be Aunt Mae.
She can't she all this.
The shock might--
Peter?
Mary Jane.
I don't understand.
It's you-ouuu!
Where were you all this time?
I-- I don't know where I've been
or what's happened.
I just knew
that I had to find you.
I love you, Peter.
And I love you.
[moans]
I have a promise to keep, kid.
[doorbell rings]
Mary Jane!
You brought her back to me.
Oh, thank you! Thank you!
Mae! Mae!
[gasp] Oh, my!
Mary Jane's come home!
War Journal Entry 81498.
Don't know how
all this happened,
maybe I never will,
but for the first time
in a long while,
I feel human again.
[Spider-Man]
Don't worry, Harry,
I'm taking you to get some help.
[Harry] Is that you
under there, Peter?
I don't know
what's real anymore.
All I know is MJ is back,
everything will be better again.
[Spider-Man]
Will it, Harry?
Oh, well, Spidey, enjoy
some good luck for a change.
Mary Jane is back.
And maybe this nightmare
is over at last.
[upbeat rock music]
♪ Spider-Man, Spider-Man ♪
♪ Radioactive Spider-Man ♪
♪ Spider blood, spider blood ♪
♪ Radioactive spider blood ♪
♪ Spider blood ♪
♪ Spider-Man ♪