[Kingpin] Previously
onSpider-man.
[Explorer] The pyramid
of the Toltecs.
[News Anchor] According to
Langdon the Tablet of Time
once held the secret
of eternal life.
This is business.
Crime has taken over
your entire life.
I must have the tablet
in my collection.
[Spider-man] Mega-Slayer.
[robot whooshes]
[missile booms]
[Man] We're being followed.
Your stop, Ms. Kingpin.
Get Connors!
-[wall cracks]
-[Lizard growls]
I must have that tablet.
Connors too.
We'll lay a trap at ESU.
[light buzzes]
-Dr. Connors, I presume.
-[knuckles crack]
[laser hisses]
[Spider-man] Let go
or we'll suffocate!
I don't breathe. [laughs]
[upbeat electronic music]
♪ Spider-man ♪
♪ Radioactive Spider-man ♪
-[explosion booms]
-[upbeat guitar music]
♪ Spider blood, spider blood ♪
♪ Radioactive spider blood ♪
♪ Spider blood ♪
[webbing hisses]
[missiles whooshing]
[Venom growls]
♪ Spider-man ♪
You see, web head,
I don't need to breathe anymore.
Too bad you do.
[Spidey coughing]
I almost forgot what I came for.
Sorry I can't finish this.
But here's a going away present.
[machine thuds]
[dramatic music]
[tires screech]
-[Alisa] Hello.
-It's me, Tombstone.
I got Connors.
Perfect.
Nobody suspects I was involved?
[Tombstone]
Your alibi is airtight.
Get back and enjoy your date.
[Alisa] I will, if
he ever shows up.
[Spider-man] I'm
choking and I can't see.
But wait, I know this place,
I shouldn't need to see.
[webbing hisses]
[fan whirs]
Amazing how a little
fresh air can make me feel
so much stronger.
No sign of Tombstone anywhere.
For a walking Mount
Rushmore he's fast.
Oh no, the Coffee Bean.
I'm supposed to meet Alisa
Silver there for dinner.
I lost Mary Jane because
of my web slinging,
I can't let it ruin
another relationship.
-[tires screech]
-Hammerhead!
What's he doing here?
[dramatic music]
Freeze, all youse.
Get the girl.
No!
Stop!
Let me go!
[dramatic music]
[Spider-man] Yo, chrome dome,
the lady didn't
finish her latte.
[webbing hisses]
[gun blasts]
-[Hammerhead thuds]
-[Spider-man whooshes]
[dramatic music]
[driver yells]
[concrete roars]
Great, now I'm going to be
turned into a life sized
Spidey statue minus the life.
[dramatic music]
From Spider-man to speed
bump in 10 seconds.
[Spider-man] I need an anchor.
-[webbing hisses]
-Anchors away.
[dramatic music]
[doors squeals]
What the heck is going on?
First Doc Connors is kidnapped,
-now Alisa Silver.
-[sirens blaring]
Who's next, Aunt May?
I better get home and change
into my spare costume,
before I turn into Tombstone Jr.
[dramatic music]
He's got her!
Silvermane's got my wife.
Perhaps I can use the
Mega-Slayer to rescue her.
No, you and your robot have
bungled too many jobs of late.
Hammerhead says he has plan
that will sure her safe return.
You trust him over me?
I trust myself.
I am giving Hammerhead
this one chance.
[monitor buzzes]
If he fails I will have him.
[Hammerhead] Perish the thought.
[Wilson] Hammerhead,
who is this girl?
Leave me to introduce
Alisa Silver,
better known as
Alisa Silvermane.
His daughter?
I told you I had a plan.
My father won't be pleased
when he finds out
what you've done.
Good, now Silvermane
will it feels like
to have the life of a loved
one hanging in the balance.
[Curt] It's incredible.
You made an exact duplicate
of the top of the
Toltec pyramid.
Yeah, right here
in the Big Apple.
Now check this out.
[bricks scraping]
A crude, solar powered grid.
This will amplify the power
of the Tablet of Time.
[Silvermane] Precisely, doctor.
[Curt] Who are you?
I'm an old man who
wants you to harness
the life giving
force of the tablet
to make me young.
You don't know what
you're dealing with.
I can't.
You can, doctor, and you will.
[dramatic music]
[Curt thuds]
[lights clicking]
You won't be seeing your wife
and son again until you do!
[phone ringing]
Boss, Hammerhead's
double crossed us.
Hammerhead?
What are you talking about?
He kidnapped Alisa from ESU.
He's taken my daughter?
I'll [groans].
You okay?
The Kingpin.
He's behind this.
Let me go size him up
for one of my coffins.
No.
If Kingpin touches a
hair on Alisa's head
he'll suffer pain worst
than anything I'm feeling!
[dramatic music]
[Peter] Alisa, Doc Connors,
their lives are on the line.
Easy, Parker,
you won't get anywhere
unless you concentrate
on the task at hand.
If my new adhesive holds on
Aunt May's nonstick frying pan,
it might hold on the slick
armor of the Mega-Slayer.
[tracker clinks]
Okay, Smythe, now I'm
ready for our little date.
-[dramatic music]
-[Mega-Slayer whooshes]
Why can't I meeting
Meg Ryan up here
instead of that hunk of tin?
Or at least Faye Wray.
You were supposed to
bring Dr. Connors.
Where is he?
[Spider-man] You know
everything, smart guy,
didn't you know
he was kidnapped?
You're lying!
And I'm tired of your insolence.
I want Connors now.
[grappling hook whooshes]
[Spider-man]
Now I've made him mad.
[Mega-Slayer whooshes]
[missile booms]
If Smythe doesn't have
the doc, who does?
[dramatic music]
[phone ringing]
Fisk, I have your wife,
you have my daughter.
Let's set up a meeting.
[dramatic music]
[display beeping]
[Spider-man] Smythe, listen,
I don't have Connors.
[gargoyle crumbles]
[dramatic music]
-[beam blasts]
-[Spidey thuds]
[dramatic music]
Smythe, I have reached an
agreement with Silvermane.
There's going to be a trade.
[Spider-man] I don't get it.
Why's he leaving in
such a big hurry?
[Mega-Slayer whooshes]
-[tracker clinks]
-Yes!
My new adhesive works!
Run away as fast as
you want, Smythe,
I'm still gonna be right on
your big, fat, mechanical tail.
[dramatic music]
I wonder how much Smythe
pays to park that thing
here in the city.
[grate squeaks]
[dramatic music]
[Mega-Slayer thudding]
Margaret Connors,
and Alisa.
Why did Smythe take her?
She's just a lab assistant.
Must've been some
kind of mistake.
[Mega-Slayer thudding]
[Alisa grunting]
[Smythe] Let's make this
simple and painless.
Fine, we send them
all at the same time.
[dramatic music]
Check out the tablet, Professor.
I want the real deal.
Smythe, order in your robot now.
[metal squeals]
It's a double cross
just like I figured.
[missile thuds]
-[computer beeps]
-Do something.
The robot's power
cells are damaged.
I can activate the reserves
if you let go of me.
[dramatic music]
[lasers blasting]
Don't hit the old
man's daughter.
[door thuds]
Please, help me.
-[car booms]
-[metal clangs]
[Spider-man] Doc.
[Spidey thuds]
[electricity fizzes]
Good night, sweet prince,
and flights of angels
sing thee to thy rest.
Only problem here is I
don't know who to root for.
[dramatic music]
[laser whizzes]
[arm thuds]
[cans rattle]
No!
Don't bother with
Spider-man, get my wife!
[Mega-Slayer thudding]
Come on.
[dramatic music]
[gas hisses]
[Hammerhead] Okay,
boys, let's nail 'em.
[lasers blasting]
[missiles roaring]
It's about time I broke
in Kingpin's new toy.
[Mega-Slayer thuds]
Alisa.
[Alisa yelps]
[Alisa] Help.
[Tombstone] No, you
might hit the girl.
[dramatic music]
Now I'm really confused.
What could Hammerhead
want with Alisa?
[Margaret] Curt,
we don't have time.
Please, Margaret, I need this.
[Tombstone] That's mine.
And so are you.
-[doors creak]
-[lasers blast]
[Alisa] Let me go!
[helicopter squeals]
[webbing whooshes]
-We're losing power.
-[Alisa screams]
[helicopter thuds]
[dramatic music]
[Spider-man] Hey, brick brain.
-[webbing whooshes]
-[gun clatters]
-[Hammerhead yells]
-[dramatic music]
Are you all right?
I'm fine.
But you've got a problem.
-[gun blasts]
-[Spidey grunts]
[dramatic music]
[helicopter whirs]
Are you sure you do not know
where they were holding you,
my dear?
No.
I told you I was blindfolded.
Now, please, get me home.
Of course.
Take her back.
And if anything happens
to her this time,
you'll pay with your lives.
I am never going to go
through another nightmare
like that again.
Ever.
You've botched another
important operation, Smythe.
We also lost the girl.
-And the tablet.
-What?
Spider-man got the jump on me.
Then the girl
blasted that web-head
and then took off with
him in the chopper.
You incompetent fools!
-I'll have--
-Hello.
What's this?
It's one of Spider-man's
tracking devices
stuck to the Mega-Slayer.
Perhaps I can reverse
the homing signal
and use it to find
him and the tablet.
And Connors as well.
Really?
Then do it.
Who would have thought
that Spider-man
would ever prove useful to me?
No.
Unmasking Spider-man
is a privilege
A lucky break for you,
Spider-man.
Silvermane, the crime boss?
I've read about him
in the Bugle's files.
He's Alisa's father?
I liked her.
You've fallen head over
heels into this one, Parker.
[dramatic music]
[metal whirs]
[laser blasts]
It works.
You've done it!
But the exact solar power
factor is still in question.
You're stalling.
I think you know
what you're doing.
Go tell my father we're ready.
[watch ticks]
Connors is finished.
It's time.
Yes, time.
That's what this
is all about... time.
Time to rebuild my empire
and destroy the Kingpin's.
[Spider-man] That's Silvermane?
He's the old man I
rescued from Doc Ock.
If I had known who he was,
I would have handed him over
with a ribbon and bow attached.
Now comes the time
for rejuvenation.
Put the tablet in place, Doctor.
[tablet whirring]
[Spider-man]
He's out of his mind.
That thing can turn
DNA into linguini.
Please, Alisa, don't let him
do this, it's too dangerous.
Doctor, this is the greatest
gift I can give my father.
And nobody's going to stop me.
Lock him in the lab.
No, you can't, it's not ready.
You can not do this.
-You mustn't.
-[door whirs]
Tombstone, the sun's
coming into position.
Open the ceiling!
-[remote beeps]
-[ceiling whirs]
[Spider-man] The Mega-Slayer.
A nice distraction.
Now if I can take
advantage of it. [grunts]
[Mega-Slayer thudding]
[laser blast thuds]
[webbing whooshes]
[Mega-Slayer thuds]
Destroy the robot.
[dramatic music]
[Mega-Slayer thuds]
[Tombstone thuds]
[remote beeps]
Your persistence will
be rewarded, Spider-man.
After my transformation
you will have the honor
of being the first
person I destroy.
[Smythe] The robot's
badly damaged.
-[computer beeping]
-What are you doing?
Rerouting remaining battery
power to down link arrays.
At least we can watch
what's going on.
Hammerhead, get over there
and bring me that tablet.
Power of the Toltecs,
give me the wisdom of
your wisest shamans,
the strength of your
strongest warriors,
and the invulnerability
that will carry me
into the next millennium.
-[light buzzing]
-[dramatic music]
[Silvermane screaming]
Let me out.
You don't know
what you're doing.
No.
No!
[remote beeps]
[metal clangs]
[Alisa] Father?
Yes, Alisa, it is me, the way
I was before you were born.
Strong, fearless,
powerful enough to strike fear
into the hearts of my enemies.
Enemies like Spider-man.
[Spidey grunting]
Now, I want to see
who's behind the mask.
[Lizard bangs]
[Alisa gasps]
Oh no, not again.
Are you another one
of Kingpin's flunkies?
Is that the best you can do?
[tail whooshes]
[wall thuds]
[dramatic music]
[Spidey thuds]
[fist thwacks]
[laser blasts]
[Alisa] Are you all right?
Better than all right.
I feel wonderful! [grunts]
[Alisa] What's happening to you?
Dr. Connors, where are you?
I think I can reactivate
the weapons system.
Smythe, look.
No, no, I don't
wanna be like this.
Make it stop, please.
Somebody help me!
[Spider-man] He
wanted his youth back.
He got it.
-Father!
-[infant cries]
-[fist thwacks]
I shoulda finished
you off before--
-[laser blasts]
-[Tombstone grunts]
[dramatic music]
-[electricity buzzes]
-[Mega-Slayer thuds]
[Spider-man] They
don't make Mega-Slayers
like they used to.
[webbing whooshes]
[dramatic music]
[both thudding]
Tombstone, open the
skylight all the way.
But the whole place'll go up.
Exactly.
We'll annihilate them all
for what they've
done to my father.
-[light hissing]
-[dramatic music]
[baby crying]
[Spidey groans]
[Margaret] Help!
Help!
[dramatic music]
Spider-man, where's Curt?
[light throbs]
[Spider-man] I
think I can guess.
[light beams whooshing]
[pyramid rumbles]
[webbing whooshes]
[building thunders]
Don't you understand,
we barely escaped.
Yes, but Silvermane
is no longer a threat.
There'll be another threat.
And then another,
as long as you cling
to your precious power.
I've made up my mind,
I'm leaving you.
But, Vanessa, I love you.
I used to believe that.
Now I see clearly.
All you really love
is being the Kingpin.
The Kingpin of crime.
[door creaks]
[dramatic music]
[Hammerhead] You
sent for me, boss?
Thank you for obtaining
the tablet for me.
Hey, no problem.
-It was my--
-Now dispose of it.
What? But.
I said, get rid of it!
The sight of it sickens me.
What happened?
Silvermane should've
listened to you.
He kept getting younger,
until he turned into a baby.
Curt, I'm so thankful.
The tablet's healing energy
seems to have
transformed you back.
And the tablet itself?
Gone, probably destroyed
at the explosion at
Silvermane's place.
If only we could've saved it.
The tablet might've
cured you too.
[Spider-man] If only.
Got yourself a
real bargain there.
A real bargain. [laughs]
[dramatic music]
♪ Spider-man ♪
♪ Radioactive Spider-man ♪
[upbeat guitar music]
♪ Spider blood, spider blood ♪
♪ Radioactive spider blood ♪
♪ Spider blood ♪
♪ Spider-man ♪