[Kingpin] Previously on
Spider-Man...
[chuckles]
New York's leading
philanthropist, Wilson Fisk.
Thank you, Mr. Osborn.
Dig a hole for your
final resting place.
-Huh?
-[explosion booms]
I wanna know who that is.
Name's Hobgoblin!
[Spider-Man thinking]
This clown's out maneuvering me
every step of the way.
How do I nail this
flying lunatic?
You failed me,
you failed to tell me
Spider-Man would get involved.
Pay up and I'll take
another shot at Fisk!
You're fired!
I'll take the wing as payment.
How convenient.
All of your men, Fisk.
Why should I do that?
Why do you want me
as your roommate?
This is the man's home now.
I just hope you two
bachelors don't ruin it.
-Aunt May!
-[man chuckles]
-What on--
-That kid, perfect!
[evil laughter]
-[explosion rumbles]
-[groans]
All we can do is give her time.
[Harry] What do you
want from me?
Your Dad's loaded.
You kidnapped my son!
This is what happen's
when somone tries
to double cross me.
What are you suggesting?
We can get Fisk together.
I need a better weapon.
[evil laughter]
I know that laugh anywhere!
Different wings, same jerk.
[Hobgoblin] Let's see
what this baby can do.
[evil laughter]
Spider-Man!
You're right on time ...
For your funeral.
[explosion rumbles]
[theme song playing]
♪ Spider-Man, Spider-Man ♪
♪ Radioactive Spider-Man ♪
♪ Spider blood, spider blood ♪
♪ Radioactive spider blood ♪
♪ Spider-Man, Spider-Man ♪
[debris falling]
[Spider-Man thinking]
Where are the skyscrapers
when you need 'em?
Can't get airborne.
[evil laughing]
Maybe I can use that
truck for cover.
[groans]
Hope Rat-Man and Cockroach-Man
aren't already in here.
[evil laughter]
[Hobgoblin] Bombs away!
[evil laughing]
Where's he getting this stuff?
I've heard of country's
with smaller arsenal.
[slicing sounds]
[groans]
Think you're smart, Spider-Man?
You're not as smart
as these smart bombs!
Happy trails, Spider-Man!
[evil laughing]
[sirens in the distance]
[man] Did you see it?
He never had a chance!
[man]
Who's gonna pay for all this?
[crowd bickering]
[Spider-Man thinking]
Ugh, first he knocks me
out of the air
and now he's taken
over the ground, too.
At least I've still got
the sewer.
Hey!
You can't get rid
of me that easily.
Not after what you
did to Aunt May.
[dramatic music]
[static]
And police
still have no leads
in the kidnapping.
John Osborn was taken from
his Manhattan apartment
by a masked man calling
himself The Hobgoblin.
Osborn's father,
industrialist, Norman Osborn,
has refused to comment.
What did the Hobgoblin
want from you?
You can't just
come in here and--
Why was he here?
[stammers] I can't tell you,
it's personal.
Hey!
You better tell me,
it's personal for me, too.
Look, this is all
been taken care of.
What are you saying?
Don't tell me you
made a deal with him.
You trusting the Hobgoblin?!
I had too!
I could lose it all,
my company, my inventions.
-Everything!
-What about your son?
I said everything.
Look, you, don't judge me.
I know what I'm doing.
This will all be
over by midnight.
Midnight, huh?
Then you can expect to
see me, one minute after.
Just to make sure.
-How is she?
-Peter, there's no change.
Mary Jane I really
appreciate you staying.
Peter, you don't
have to thank me.
It means a lot to Aunt May
and to me.
I hope some day you
forgive me, Aunt May.
This is all my fault.
Fisk!
Boss!
Hmm, where is everybody?
Hmm. [evil laughter]
Yeah.
-[Kingpin] Comfortable?
-Huh?
I see you have a fondness
for the trappings of power.
Oh, not just the trappings.
I like the prestige
and the influence, too.
It seems you want what I have.
You read me like a book.
Speaking of books, I've
got to balance mine.
It's time I got paid.
I've got something
to show you first.
We can get Fisk together!
Oh, that!
I was just getting what
I could for myself, Fisk.
As I always do.
It's just good business
and you like the way I
do business, don't you?
[Kingpin] What I like is of
less consequence
than what I demand.
I demand loyalty.
As of now, you are terminated.
No!
I've worked too hard to
have it end this way.
Guards, I never want
to see him again.
[evil laughter]
He must not get away.
As if anyone could stop me!
[evil laughter]
Come on, come on!
Yes!
The measure of a man is
how he handles defeat.
So let's see how
you handle yours!
[guards clamor]
Where'd that come from?
Shut the portal.
Another of Osborn's
toys no doubt.
Where do you think
you're going, Smythe.
We've gotta get out!
Retreat?
From him?
You'd rather be buried here?
[evil laughter]
Run!
It's our only chance.
Yes!
Well, what do you know
I finally got him.
Well, really the worse for wear
but the important thing is,
it's mine now!
All mine.
[evil laughter]
Mine!
Oh, every inch of
optical fiber,
every bite of information,
all mine.
Well? What are you waiting for?
[stammers]
My father paid the ransom?
I'm free to go?
Free? Nothing with
me is ever free.
You're mine now
and so is all of this.
Look at it, it's a worldwide
network of illegal information.
See? Instantaneous contact
with any place on the planet.
Oh, but I don't just
observe in here,
I control the information
and the better I control it,
the more money I make!
Everything's wired
to this panel,
power, water,
security, everything!
I can stay here forever.
Then what do you
want from my father?
Revenge.
And now that I have you,
I'm going to get it.
[screen ringing]
Evening, Osborn.
You were supposed
to come back here.
What went wrong?
Nothing went wrong,
your wings
a true marvel, Osborn.
It helped me destroy
the Kingpin,
just like you wanted
from the start.
Then why aren't you here?
I've rethought
our arrangement.
Now that I've got
the Kingpin's empire,
I want Oscorp, too.
All of it, not just
your inventions.
Are you out of your--
Why you--
I'll expose your identity
for all the world to--
Harry?
Say hello to your
old man, junior.
[muffled yelling]
[evil laughter]
This town has a new
Kingpin, Osborn,
and it's me!
Hobgoblin!
Come back, Hobgoblin!
You filthy, rotten, lying--
I believe the word you're
search for is traitor.
Ironic isn't it?
You started this by
double crossing me
and now he is
double crossing you.
But he said you were--
That report was
greatly exaggerated.
Much like your IQ, Osborn.
Only a fool would bring
this down on himself.
It was because of you two,
trying to bleed my company dry.
You left me no choice.
Enough.
Recriminations are useless.
I suggest we attend to
more important matters,
like eliminating the Hobgoblin.
And how can we
possibly do that?
There's a secret
tunnel that leads
back to my headquarters.
We used it for our escape.
Therefore, we have
a way back in.
All we need from you
is a weapon
that can stand up to that wing.
A weapon?
I just might have something,
or perhaps I should say,
someone.
[Spider-Man thinking]
Aunt May,
I wish I could be there
with you right now.
It's midnight and I don't
see your son anywhere.
You were right.
I never should have
trusted the Hobgoblin
but I got one ace up my sleave.
I'm suppose to trust you?
We both want the Hobgoblin,
don't we?
Oh, I want him, all right.
This is it?
There's a tunnel inside
that leads to his hideout.
You better not be playing
games with me, Osborn.
'Cause if you are,
I know where to find you.
[dramatic music]
[Spider-Man thinking] Huh?
This doesn't look
like the entrance
to a criminal stronghold.
This is a different story.
[groans]
Here goes nothing.
He's on his way.
Brilliant strategy,
using one of our enemies
to fight the other.
This should be quite a show.
[Spider-Man thinking] I wish
I had some idea of where I am,
but with all these
twists and turns,
I haven't got a clue.
Well, no where to go now
but up!
You need land mines?
Sure I know where
you can get 'em.
But I want double
the commission. [evil laughter]
Good news, Merrick,
I'm gonna help you
get rid of those extra mines
but I want half the profit
or they can rust
in your warehouse.
Spider-Man!
But how did you--
No matter.
Welcome to my new kingdom.
Wherever you are,
here let me give you
a proper greeting.
[Spider-Man] Stuck?
How about a kick start.
[metal clanging]
No!
Look what you made me do.
All flights have been canceled,
Red Baron.
[Harry] Watch it, Spidey,
those discs of his
are razor sharp.
[Kingpin]
Only a few more minutes,
a few more!
[Spider-Man groans]
Get out here, face me!
[evil laughter]
Careful what you wish for.
End game, Spider-Man.
It's all ruined,
I've lost everything!
You still got your life,
for the moment.
My last one.
Where's Harry Osborn?
You want him? You got him!
Catch that, wall crawler!
[evil laughter]
[Smythe] The plants working.
Of course,
you expected something less
from the Kingpin?
Good, you're OK.
I'll be right back,
on second thought.
Lets go before this
place collapses!
Come on.
Spider-Man and Osborn
are in the elevator.
The web slinger must not
be allowed to escape.
Can't this thing go any faster?
I hadn't asked.
No more Spider-Man.
Easily worth the price
of an elevator,
wouldn't you say, Smythe?
Next time
we'll take the stairs.
No, they made it to the tunnel!
Then you know
what you have to do.
As soon as I get you
out of here, Osborn,
I'm gonna go back
down this tunnel
and find out where
we just came from.
Maybe not!
Now I'll never know
where we were.
It worked,
exactly as planned.
Ever hear the phrase,
heretic victory?
You're wrong, Smythe,
we're going to rebuild it
bigger and better than before.
The main thing is,
it's mine again.
I'm sorry but there's
no improvement.
Peter, where are you?
What's wrong with him?
He took a fall.
He'll be OK.
What about the Hobgoblin?
-Gone.
-Then it's finally over.
No way is it over,
I've got a lot of questions
and I know you've
got the answers.
Maybe I do but that
wasn't part of our deal.
Still playing games,
huh, Osborn?
Like the games you played
with the Hobgoblin
and with your own son's life.
Let go of me!
What do you know? You think
I don't care about Harry?
The fact is I do but my
work was all consuming.
I was always away, do you
know what that's like?
Missing his birthday parties,
his baseball games.
Never being there when he
was sick and needed me.
But none of that meant
I didn't care about him.
It was just a matter
of making choices.
Maybe, I made the wrong ones.
Oh, what--what happ--
It's payback time, Osborn.
No!
Harry!
Osborn!
You OK?
[coughs]
Dad?
We're OK.
I guess he finally
made the right choice.
[Hobgoblin laughs evilly]
So you're here too,
how convenient.
[Spider-Man] Yeah, for me!
[Hobgoblin laughs evilly]
Let's get this over with!
I can't out maneuver him.
[evil laughing]
[screams]
That was for Aunt May!
How is she?
She's still the same.
Where have you been?
I, uh, I had to take
care of something.
More important than this?
That's what's wrong
with you kids today!
You can't seem to make
the right choices.
[sighs]
Thanks for staying, Mary Jane.
I know your busy
moving out and all, so.
-I'm not moving, Peter.
-You're not?
I thought I wanted to
but after this,
now I'm worried about
leaving my own aunt alone.
So I can wait.
Peter?
Aunt May!
Oh, we were so
worried about you.
Oh, it was such a shock.
Don't worry,
the Hob Goblin's gone now.
The Hobgoblin?
Who's talking about that--
It was your apartment, dear!
-I've never seen such a mess.
-Oh...
I don't think you're ready
to live on your own yet.
I think you're right.
And, Peter? When you saved
that nice Mr. Fisk's life,
you did the right thing.
Uncle Ben would have
been very proud.
[Hobgoblin] Don't forget me,
Spider-Man.
I'm not going to forget you.
♪ Spider-Man, Spider-Man ♪
♪ Radioactive Spider-Man ♪
♪ Spider blood, spider blood ♪
♪ Radioactive spider blood ♪
♪ Spider-Man ♪