[upbeat rock music]
♪ Spider-Man ♪
♪ Radioactive Spider-Man ♪
♪ Spider blood
Spider blood ♪
♪ Radioactive spider blood ♪
♪ Spider blood
Spider blood ♪
♪ Radioactive spider blood ♪
[explosions booming]
[growling]
♪ Spider-Man ♪
[dramatic music]
Peter, is that you?
No! No! Mary Jane!
[laughing]
I just know
it's your fault she's gone!
I blame you, Peter Parker!
You! You! You!
She doesn't mean it, dear.
Anna's delirious
over the loss of Mary Jane.
[Peter] Anna Watson was
closer to the truth
than Aunt May realizes.
You know, Parker, I don't think
I've made you suffer enough.
-[Peter] No!
-[cackling]
Let her go, Osborn.
This is between you and me.
I'm not Osborn!
I am the Green Goblin!
[screams]
Mary Jane!
She was the woman I loved!
You'll pay Osborn!
There's no Osborn anymore,
Parker!
There is only the Green Goblin!
[laughing]
[screams]
[Harry]
My father's vanished.
I'm sure the Green Goblin's
kidnapped him again.
Now the Goblin's
taken Mary Jane, too!
Why?
How can I live my life
without the two people
I love the most?
[Peter] It's Spider-Man's fault
they're both gone.
This costume's gotta go.
It's the only way I'll ever
be able to live with myself.
Who needs Spider-Man anyway?
[Jonah] We need Spider-Man
right here on the front page.
Pictures of Spider-Man
at the scene
of that Watson girl's
disappearance.
Jonah, Spider-Man would
never hurt that girl.
He protects people.
I've never felt protected
by him.
We need those photos.
Call Parker.
I did, but he said
he doesn't want his career
tied to Spider-Man anymore.
What?!
The nerve of that kid!
In my day, you did what
your editor told you to do
and you liked it!
Those were the days.
When I was a reporter,
I'd have solved a mystery
like the Watson disappearance
before lunch.
Did I ever tell you
about the time--
Sorry, Jonah,
but I've gotta run.
My son Randy is starting
in the all-star game
in less than an hour.
You know, I miss
those days with my own son.
You should cherish
this time with your family.
You're a lucky man.
That's one thing
we can agree on, Jonah.
I am a lucky man.
Taxi!
-[tires screech]
-[door locks]
Hey! Hey!
What's going on here?
[coughing]
Stop the cab!
Let me out!
[dramatic music]
[helicopters whirring]
-Well, I almost made it home.
-[sirens]
The heat's onto us, Mastermind.
What do you want us to do?
Are you talking to me?
Mastermind, we gotta
get outta here!
Why are you calling me
Mastermind?
C'mon, Mastermind,
you gotta shake off
that knockout gas
the guard fired at ya.
Yeah, we can't
let them take us alive.
[sirens]
What do you want us to do?
[Spider-Man]
If I'm gonna quit,
it looks like they're
gonna throw me
one heck of a party.
And what's party
without snapshots?
Mastermind, it's Spider-Man!
Shoot him
with your stun blaster.
Are you crazy? No!
[groaning]
I feel like
I was kicked by a mule.
[engine revving]
[helicopter whirring]
-[groans]
-We gotta get outta here!
I'm not gonna go anywhere
until my head stops splitting.
Okay, Mastermind,
you're the boss.
Mastermind?
Your name's as hokey
as your costume.
You gonna call your men off,
or do I have to make you?
No, don't web me!
Drop your weapons.
Mastermind's been nabbed.
Repeat, drop 'em.
[engines stop]
You've gotta be
one heck of a leader
to have so many men wanna
take the fall with you.
Who are you?
Robbie?!
Eh, we took all our orders
from Mastermind.
He planned the whole enchilada.
Mr. Robinson
got the info we needed
from confidential Bugle files
and their secret informants.
That's impossible!
I'd have known!
[pounding]
Mr. Robertson's fingerprints
are on this weapon.
Ballistics prove it's been fired
and lubricant
from the mechanism was found
on his hands.
I remember getting in the cab,
and then there was
the knock-out gas.
Mysterious cabs? Knock-out gas?
Mr. Robertson,
this is a court of law,
not a Saturday morning
cartoon show.
Without proof,
we can't be expected
to believe anything you tell us.
Your Honor,
we the jury find the defendant
guilty as charged.
Sentencing will commence Monday.
Oh, Robbie.
[Peter] Is this another life
Spider-Man has ruined?
My dad is a good man
who believes in the system,
and this is how
the system repays him.
Robbie Robertson is
the most decent man
I have ever known.
And I intend to use
every resource available to me
to overturn this verdict.
If there's anything
the two of you need
in the meantime, it's yours.
But what could you do now?
What could anyone do?
[Jonah] I'm telling you,
Governor, you have to help!
Someone's framed him.
No, I don't know who,
but I'd stake
my reputation on it.
[click, dial tone]
Hello?! Hello?!
Useless!
And none of you are any better!
Why haven't
you brought me anything?!
-Parker!
-Sorry I'm late, Mr. Jameson.
Sorry, nothing!
Why aren't you working
the Spider-Man angle?
It's clear he set Robbie up!
No it isn't, boss.
Did you ever think
that maybe Robbie
was working with Spider-Man
and Spidey betrayed him,
that Robbie could be guilty?
No, Leeds, not for a second.
Now either you find
me something I can use,
or you can find
yourself another job.
Got it?
Right, boss.
Got it.
Ned Leeds is right
about one thing.
Spider-Man did betray Robbie.
After all the times
he stood up for me,
I helped put him behind bars.
I'm worried about you two.
What are you gonna do
while I'm gone?
We're fine, Robbie.
We're gonna hold it together
until you come home.
Why should we have
to hold it together?
It's Spider-Man's fault
you're in here!
Randy, Spider-Man was just doing
what he thought was right.
He's a good man at heart.
Oh, yeah, Dad?
If he's so good,
where is he to help you now?
Robbie says he woke up
with the blaster in his hand.
But if he's innocent,
why would he fire it?
Wait a minute.
[clicking]
The gun's firing,
but for no reason.
Robbie's been set up!
And whoever's behind it
is a master of deception.
Yes, all is going
according to plan.
Now, what remains
is for Robertson
to be sentenced to the proper
correctional facility.
And how on earth can
you control that?
You forget, I am a man
of unlimited resources.
I have my methods.
[officer] Alan, Richard,
Empire State Penitentiary.
Edelman, Matthew,
Robertson, Joseph,
New York State Pen.
-[power fails]
-Huh? What the heck is that?
You see?
All it takes is
a little ingenuity
and 25 million dollars' worth
of digital equipment.
[power resumes]
I don't know what that was,
but it's over now.
Robertson, Joseph,
Rooker's Island.
But wait-- wait a minute.
You just said he was going
to New York State Pen.
Couldn't have. It says
Rooker's Island right here.
Huh, I must've heard you wrong.
Okay, next.
Good, now the rest
is up to Burch here.
Are you ready?
I'm ready.
Hi, Miss Grant.
I've gotta show Jameson
something right away.
Wait, Peter. Mr. Jameson's
in a really bad mood.
News of Robbie's
sentencing has just come
over the wire service.
He's been given 15 years
in Rooker's State Penitentiary.
Parker, how dare you show
your face around here
without bringing
in some hard evidence.
Why, in my day--
Actually, Mr. Jameson,
I do have something.
-What?
-Look!
That stun blaster
that Robbie fired,
he's not pulling the trigger.
Good start, Parker!
You're not as lazy as everyone
around here says.
Thanks, Mr. Jameson.
I'll get right...
This is too important a clue
to leave to an amateur.
I'm going to investigate
this myself.
Just like the good old days.
Jigsaw Jameson is back,
and he's gonna get to the bottom
of this puzzle.
[both] Jigsaw Jameson?
JJ, something tells me
I better keep an eye on you.
Taxi!
[Spider-Man] I hate
being in this suit again,
but there are a lot of
dangerous creeps out there now,
and you may be too rusty
to handle them.
Still, I have
to admire your guts.
Take me to 10th and Bensonhurst.
Now, hurry!
Yeah, okay.
814 reporting in. We're going
to 10th and Bensonhurst.
I still can't believe it!
Jigsaw Jameson,
but you're a big CEO now!
What are you doin' down here?
Same as before.
I need information.
So the person I come
to is Jimmy Mills,
the best beat cop I ever knew.
Oh, baloney, I'm gettin'
too old for this stuff.
But since you're askin'
about high-tech weapons,
Joseph Nails is your man.
Joey Nails? He used to stooly
for me years ago.
He's big time now,
owns some fancy supper club
on the Upper East Side.
It's called Baby Joe's.
Wait here.
[dramatic music]
So do you still remember
how to make a Newshound Float?
-What?
-You shove him in the river
and toss him a life preserver.
Jigsaw, what are you doing here?
Hello, Nora.
I'm back on the crime beat,
and I'm here to see Joey Nails.
No, nobody sees Joey
just like that anymore.
He'll see me.
I want to talk
about old times, and new.
Sure. Sure, Jigsaw.
Have a seat.
What the devil?
[grunts]
Yeah, I've taken delivery.
We'll be ready to ship them
to you tomorrow.
Ciao, baby.
Well, Jigsaw Jameson.
You never write, you never call.
You're too big
for your old friends now?
Only for two-bit crooks
like you, Nails.
Hey, no fair.
I'm strictly legit now.
Oh, yeah? Then what's
with the fancy chair?
This just for haircuts?
Everybody's got enemies.
But what do I got to fear
from a geezer like you?
Plenty! For one thing,
I can smell a warehouse storage
record from a mile away.
Hey! Put that down!
It's none of your business!
[groans] Whoa!
Not bad for a geezer, huh?
I always could get
the drop on you, Nails.
-Thanks for the info.
-[growls]
Well, there's Jameson.
Hey, what's this?
Judging by all the attention
Jameson's getting,
he's definitely on to something.
Who are you working for?
Talk!
I'd rather go to jail
than squeal on my boss.
I like breathing.
I don't have time
to convince him.
I'd better stay
on old JJ's tail.
[dramatic music]
I wonder
what we're doing here?
Bingo!
I mean, the place
seems quiet enough.
-[spider-sense tingles]
-Or maybe not.
Guys, pipe down, will ya?
[grunting]
-[straining]
-[groans]
[beeping]
[grunts]
That move made me captain
of my college wrestling team.
Yeah, well,
now I'll show you the move
that won me first prize
at my gun club.
[Jonah]
I knew you were in on this.
And after all these years,
I finally realized something.
If you want it done right,
you gotta do it yourself.
Don't you get it?
I was trying to keep
those goons from hurting you.
Yeah? For all I know,
you're just trying
to keep them from fingering you.
When I think of all the times
Robbie tried
to convince me you were
one of the good guys.
-How you framed him like that?
-[spider-sense tingles]
Goodbye, scum.
[Spider-Man] We've gotta get
to a safer place.
This rat-trap
is liable to come down!
It looks
like we hit the jackpot.
Okay, Spider-Man, let's
finish this once and for all.
Unh!
Didn't you ever think
that if Robbie Robertson
thought I was okay,
there might be something to it?
That's just
like the blaster Robbie
was holding in the picture!
This is a remote control unit.
And I'll just bet
it operates the blaster.
This proves
that Robbie was set up.
That tunnel probably
leads to the river
where they secretly ship
the stuff in.
Spider-Man, I'd give anything
to settle your hash right now,
but I've got a judge to see,
and a man's life to save.
Well, I've gotta give
old fuzz-head credit.
He never gives up.
But there's more
important things to do here,
like find out
who's behind all this.
This technology is incredible.
For my money,
there's only one guy
who can afford all this:
Wilson Fisk, the Kingpin.
But why would
he do this to Robbie?
If I can tap into the Kingpin's
computer network,
maybe I can find the answer.
Great, I can't get
to any of the files on Robbie
until I crack the access code.
I'll have to use every hacker's
trick I've ever learned.
[dramatic music]
Come on.
P-R-O-G?
Yes, I'm in!
Now to get some answers.
I was right! The Kingpin
did arrange Robbie's kidnapping
and set him up to take the rap
for that crime.
Robbie's prison
assignment was changed
from New York State Pen
to Rooker's.
But why?
[guard] Robertson.
-[cell door sliding]
-What is it?
Say hello to one
of your new roommates.
Hello, Robbie. How are you?
What?!
Richard Fisk?
Of course! The password!
"Progeny" means offspring,
as in son.
Fisk has only one son--
Richard.
He's been incarcerated
at Rooker's, too,
ever since that time he
tried to frame Peter Parker.
But why would he want
access to Robbie?
Could it have been
something that he did
for somebody else?
Rooker's. Oh, no!
I have to hurry!
Robbie may be in real danger!
This can't be a coincidence!
And neither is this.
Hey, homie, good to see ya.
-Tombstone!
-[laughing]
Straight arrow,
your son's developing
into quite the little criminal.
At least I'll have the pleasure
of seeing the Robertson name
go down in flames.
-[Robbie groans]
-[laughing]
I'm gonna take you down
once and for all!
And how do you plan
to pull that off?!
Simple, I'm not afraid
of the police!
-[alarm bells ringing]
-No!
[groaning]
Ugh!
[screaming]
You okay?
I'd hate to think you weren't
glad to see me
after all the trouble Fisk
went through to get ya here.
You did this to me!
Why?! How?!
Hey, take it easy, man!
Fisk just did me a favor
for helping him out
of a few scrapes here in prison.
With his connections,
he brought the whole thing off
without a hitch.
What do you want from me?
You!
[laughing]
Hope I'm not too late.
And I also hope it's easier
to break into prison
-than out of one.
-[spider-sense tingles]
Hey, it's Spider-Man! Get him!
So much for
the element of surprise.
-What's goin' on out there?!
-It's Spider-Man!
He's probably coming
for his buddy here!
He's not gonna get him!
I've worked too hard for this!
[inmates shouting
and cheering]
Hey! Hey hey hey hey!
-We're runnin' out of time!
-Get us out of here!
The prison supply copter
is out in the yard.
And Spider-Man will
be our distraction.
How ironic.
[Tombstone]
Come on, straight arrow,
now you and me are gonna
be wanted fugitives.
[inmates shouting]
[grunts]
[guards groaning]
[shouting]
Robbie!
It's Spider-Man!
Shake him loose!
[dramatic music]
Ugh!
We're going down!
Do something you fool!
Do something!
Great idea. Why don't you
start by surrendering?
You're not gonna ruin
my plans again!
Aaaah!
[both screaming]
Ugh!
Oh!
It can't end like this!
Hang on!
This is our only chance!
Unbelievable! It worked.
[explosion]
And so you see, Your Honor,
it was all a clever charade
to fool us
into believing
that Robbie was involved.
Joseph Robertson is
cleared of all charges.
-Robbie.
-[all cheering]
Yeah!
Thank you for everything, guys.
It's great to be back.
You see, Robbie?
It wasn't Spider-Man
who helped you
when you were in trouble,
it was me.
I'll never forget what
you've done for me, Jigsaw.
I had to do something.
it would've been too much work
to replace you.
I hope you'll change your mind
about taking pictures
of Spider-Man, Peter.
I've never been
more convinced in my life
that Spider-Man is a true hero.
I know his job's not easy,
but he's exactly what this city,
this world, needs right now.
I hope he never gives up.
Okay, Mr. Robertson,
consider my mind changed.
Thanks, Robbie.
I needed to hear that.
More than you'll ever know.
[upbeat rock music]
♪ Spider-Man, Spider-Man ♪
♪ Radioactive Spider-Man ♪
♪ Spider blood, spider blood ♪
♪ Radioactive spider blood ♪
♪ Spider blood ♪
♪ Spider-Man ♪