[upbeat rock music]
♪ Spider-Man ♪
♪ Radioactive Spider-Man ♪
♪ Spider blood
Spider blood ♪
♪ Radioactive spider blood ♪
♪ Spider blood
Spider blood ♪
♪ Radioactive spider blood ♪
[explosions booming]
[growling]
♪ Spider-Man ♪
I'd like to fire
the nitwit who decided
this year's fundraiser should
be a pirate masquerade.
-I look ridiculous!
-I don't know, Jonah.
I think you make
quite a dashing rogue.
Parker, take one more
picture of me in this getup
and you're fired.
[Peter] Aye, aye, sir.
Attention, swashbucklers.
I'd like to point out
our main attraction tonight.
This is actual treasure
recovered from a Spanish galleon
that sank off
the coast of Florida.
It's here on loan from
the George Cocteau Foundation.
Let's give Mr. Cocteau
a round of applause.
[applause]
-[spider-sense tingling]
-Shiver me timbers.
[guests screaming]
I guess the same genius
behind the pirate theme
came up
with this brilliant stunt.
-[clang]
-Jonah, this isn't a stunt!
It's for real!
-What?!
-[clang]
[woman]
Help! Somebody help us!
Help!
Everybody get out of here, now!
And miss the story of the year?
Not on your life.
[intense music]
What are these things?
Some kind of robots?
Not even you can stop
my new automatons!
Mysterio, I should've guessed.
After all,
this robbery does play
like a grade B horror movie.
But this time,
you're going to end up
on the cutting room floor!
Oh, really?
Unless these guys can fly,
you're all mine, Mysterio.
No, they can't fly.
But neither can he!
Jameson! Oh, no.
Ta-ta, Spider-Man!
[laughing]
Hope my tracer connects
with something
in all that smoke.
[Jonah] Who are you,
what do you want?
Oof!
[barriers slamming]
I forgot how well Mysterio
prepares for a crime.
But he forgot something, too.
[spider-sense tingling]
Hold it, buzz head!
Another Mysterio trick.
And you fell for it
you Neanderthal!
-Get us outta here!
-Hang on.
[groans] They're empty!
Your blundering is gonna
get us sliced into fish bait!
[intense music]
[Jonah] Aaah!
[robotic whirring]
[Spider-Man]
That'll stop them.
-What if they can swim?
-No way.
It's life
that provides buoyancy.
Or hot air.
Which means you'd never drown.
-Why you--
-Uh-uh-uh! Be nice.
I just saved
your life, remember?
You just saved face, that's all.
I think you wanted
to steal that treasure,
-but Mysterio beat you to it.
-Yeah, right.
I'd love to listen
to you rant, squid lips,
but I've got another
fish to catch,
and he comes
with his own fish bowl.
If my tracer connected
with Mysterio,
I should be able
to pick up his whereabouts.
-[beeping]
-Yes! Got him!
He's not far.
[intense music]
[webs whooshing]
Spider-Man, how did he--
Blast!
[wind blowing]
This snow job
won't stop me, Mysterio!
The source
of this holographic illusion
has to be around
here somewhere.
And if I remember
what I saw before it kicked in,
there's a hydrant right here.
There. Holocube destroyed,
illusion gone.
But now,
where's that creep hiding?
Okay, Spidey,
you're a native New Yorker.
What's wrong with this picture?
An exclusive club,
an overpriced hair salon,
a trendy restaurant,
and a neighborhood deli?
Give me a break, Beck!
You've gotta go
another 30 blocks
to find a good deli
above 66th Street.
You mustn't do this!
I can't go to prison, not now!
No, let me go!
No!
[guard]
How come this Quentin Beck guy
rates a high security cell?
Oh, he's a tricky one.
He calls himself Mysterio.
He used to be a special effects
guy in the movies
until he messed up
on the Brooklyn Bridge
a couple of years ago.
He was doing
special effects on a movie
with that actress,
Miranda Wilson.
Remember her?
It was an action picture.
Beck was supposed
to rig the scene
with spectacular explosions
and stuff.
But Beck got sloppy
with the explosives,
and a camera copter crashed.
It's a good thing
Spider-Man showed up.
He saved the pilot.
[brakes screech]
[Mary Jane]
And he caught Beck.
And as for Miranda Wilson,
when Spider-Man opened
the door of her car,
there was nobody there.
Miranda Wilson was just gone.
Anyway, now the producers
want to finish that film.
-They have two scenes left.
-Really?
And because I resemble her,
I just got the job taking
the place of Miranda Wilson.
Oh, great! Congratulations.
Where are they going to shoot?
Wonder Studios?
Of all places.
This place was Mysterio's
base of operations.
[roars]
He rigged it with all kinds
of deadly traps and devices.
[roars]
Mysterio's safely in jail,
and the studio
is open for business again.
So why does it
still make my skin crawl?
I'm happy for you, MJ.
But are you sure this
is the right thing
for you to be doing now?
Tiger, I see this
as my big break.
I need it.
For my career and for my sanity.
Peter, is that you?
Spider-Man!
I thought I heard Peter.
Look out!
Mary Jane!
Peter, help me!
You'll never know how strange
it is to be gone for so long,
and then to return
with no memory
of where you've been.
All I have are strange dreams.
Weird images
that flash in my head.
Sometimes I think
if I don't do something,
I'm gonna go crazy.
Fine, I just hope
this action adventure movie
doesn't suddenly
become a disaster film.
[man]
Five minutes, Miss Watson.
I'll be right out.
[ghostly man's voice]
Mary Jane!
Who-- Who's there?
-No, what's wrong with me?
-[loud bang]
Is this another dream?
[gasps]
Am I going crazy?
Please, stay where you are.
Wait a minute, I know you.
Yes, Mary Jane.
I've come back to make up
for having left you
so many years ago.
And-and-and this house,
it's never clean!
Lousy kids leave
everything in a mess!
Forget it, I'm outta here!
[gasps] Daddy?
[voice reverberating]
Yes, my dear.
Come with me, don't be afraid.
Where's the Watson girl?
I need her now!
I gave her the five-minute
warning ages ago, JS.
She probably
just has the jitters.
I'll go get her.
Why would she lock her door?
This isn't right.
[straining]
Mary Jane!
She's disappeared.
Not again!
What's this?
[creaking]
Mysterio must've
built these tunnels.
But why?
[Mary Jane] Father?
Where are we going?
Mary Jane, wait!
No! Father, don't go!
-[rumbling]
-[screams]
Aaah!
My father, he came back!
He was going to explain
what happened to me!
Oh, Spider-Man.
Am I going mad?
I hope not, Miss Watson.
Maybe you're just tired.
Uh-oh.
I'll just bet I know who was
really behind that apparition.
[Spider-Man]
Always got a trick or two
up your sleeve, huh, Beck?
Who's there?
Spider-Man,
lovely of you to drop by.
Get over it, Beck.
I saw some
pretty bizarre things today,
so I came to check and see
if the man I put
behind bars was real.
Or just another robot.
Ow! It's me all right,
in the flesh.
-It isyou.
-Well, duh.
Then who created
the illusions I saw
in the catacombs
under Wonder Studios?
Catacombs, no!
Spider-Man,
stay away from there.
If you go back, you'll
face your worst nightmare.
What are you talking about?
Give me some answers!
Oh, forget it.
This was a waste of my time.
Well, I did slip
a spider-tracer on you, Beck.
Just in case.
And you thought
I was just trying
to pull your face off.
Nice try, wall weasel.
But you can't trick a trickster.
You have, however,
provided me
with the one thing
I needed most.
A tiny battery to power
my ticket out of here!
[water roaring]
[noise subsides]
[director] Okay, doll, the ship
is sinking, and it's on fire.
Anyone else would be
panic-stricken, but not you.
You're Super Agent Tiffany West.
You got it, honey?
Whatever you say, JS.
-[man] Scene 72A, take one.
-[clack]
And action!
Let's have
that hurricane effect now!
Hey, somebody turn
down the water!
It'll put out the fire!
Aah!
Oh, no! Mary Jane!
Help! Help!
Help!
Mary Jane!
[intense music]
How could she survive this?
[Mary Jane's father]
Thank goodness
I found you again.
Quickly, my child.
You must follow me to safety.
What's happened to you?
Where are you taking me?
[Mary Jane's father]
Just a bit further.
Then all your questions
will be answered.
[groans]
Return to your world
if you wish to live!
How do you manage to be in
two places at once, Mysterio?
Bravo, Spider-Man.
This time, I think you'll find
there's a bit more to Mysterio
than smoke and mirrors.
Oof!
Looks like
our little visit is over!
No, stay out of this!
Oh, good, I was just
beginning to think
one Mysterio wasn't enough.
Tough choice,
but I guess I'll go with the one
who prevented
my untimely demise.
[short-circuiting]
Are you ever for real?
You don't have time to find out.
Come this way!
Why should I trust you?
Because the automatons
that you've already faced
were nothing compared
to what's in store for you!
I acquired
this deadly technology
from Wilson Fisk, the Kingpin.
[Kingpin] Alistair Smythe
was brilliant with robotics,
but as he's no longer with me,
his technology is mine to sell.
[Mysterio]
Very impressive, Mr. Fisk.
It's exactly
the technology I need.
The simulacra
specifications are yours,
if you can meet my price.
And not just money.
You must use this technology
to destroy Spider-Man.
No, I have other concerns
besides Spider-Man now!
Then I suggest you drop them
and attend
to that annoying arachnid,
or forget about this technology.
I had prepared
for your destruction,
when I was arrested trying
to steal the treasure
to pay off Kingpin.
But my surprise for you
is still in operation.
[laughs] My design
for your ultimate destruction.
[Spider-Man]
But if you want me destroyed,
why are you going to help?
[Mysterio]
I have my reasons.
What about Mary Jane?!
Can you help me find her?
Only if you help me.
Looks like I have no choice.
-[spider-sense tingling]
-[groans]
[groans]
The Lizard, here?!
[roaring]
It isyour worst nightmare,
Spider-Man.
Deadly automatons
that I designed
to mimic
your most powerful foes!
[groans]
-Remember.
-[roaring]
They're only machines.
Real comfort.
[groans]
Mysterio's right,
this isa machine.
And it has
certain vulnerabilities.
Open wide.
[roaring]
[circuits crackling]
Quickly, Spider-Man,
this way!
Toro! Toro!
I can't believe I'm having
to thank you for your help.
This isn't over yet,
Spider-Man.
There's something down there
that's more important to me
than eliminating you.
[Mary Jane's father]
Just a bit further.
Aah!
-Father?
-[woman] What's the matter?
Don't you have a hug
for your dear old dad?
[Mary Jane]
Miranda Wilson?
Very good, you've got brains
as well as beauty.
[gasps] No!
[Spider-Man]
Okay, break it to me easy.
Where are we now?
I was going to stage this
as the scene
of your final sacrifice.
[spider-sense tingling]
[roaring]
[growling]
[groans]
[roaring]
I made them too intelligent
and strong!
[growling]
And I see you've improved
on the originals, too.
But they're still
only machines.
Try to make that work
to your advantage, Spidey.
Flame needs gas to feed it.
Gas, that's it!
Okay, slobber jaw,
right here!
You too, needle mouth.
You were programmed
to make me your prime target.
[explosion]
I hope that's
the last of the robots.
-[scream]
-Mary Jane!
Why are you doing this to me?!
You possess something I require.
-Your body.
-[gasp]
You see, there was nothing
magical about my disappearance.
-I merely fell off the bridge.
-[splash]
Something had gone
terribly wrong.
I was a woman renowned
for my great beauty.
And now it had been destroyed.
I couldn't let anyone
see me this way.
I crawled through the sewers
like the rats that live there.
Miraculously,
they led me to some catacombs
beneath the studio.
Without medical treatment,
my condition steadily worsened.
But then I was discovered
by Quentin Beck.
He had gotten out of prison
and come back
for equipment he kept here.
He became Mysterio again,
so he could steal the money
and buy robotic machinery
needed to save my life.
Quentin made me self-sufficient
by directly hooking my mind
to these new machines
and illusory devices.
Beck must really care about you.
Who could care about somebody
that looks like this?
But soon, this device
will give me back
what he took from me.
My youth and my beauty.
Correction,
your youth and your beauty.
It will put
my mind in your body.
Unh! No!
When I learned they were
going to complete my film,
I knew it was just a question
of luring
my lookalike down here.
My father.
How did you--
Once I knew you were cast,
I simply accessed city computers
to find out everything
I could about you.
[Spider-Man] But now,
your haunting days are over.
[Miranda]
Hoping for this day
was the only thing
that kept me alive!
No, Miranda, you mustn't!
To the contrary, Quentin.
-[machine powers up]
-I must!
-[crackling]
-At last, my face,
my body restored to me!
Quentin, what went wrong?
I'm still trapped
in my own body.
-[groaning]
-Quentin!
I can't fix it.
There's nothing to fix.
The machine was never designed
to work, was it, Beck?
[Quentin]
Miranda, what you wanted was
a scientific impossibility.
Why did you do this to me?
You said it yourself.
Hoping for this day
was the only thing
that kept you alive.
Don't you see, Miranda?
I love you.
No, it's impossible, Quentin!
I'm a hideous monster!
All I wish is to be with you.
Always.
And so you shall.
-[rumbling]
-What's that noise?
[Miranda] Get out of here,
both of you!
I've just overloaded
the energy source
to this complex!
[Spider-Man] You've gotta
get out of here, too!
No, I'm staying.
So am I!
[noise intensifies]
There goes my film debut.
Up in smoke.
Let's go.
[sirens]
[Mary Jane] Wasn't it
cruel of him to lead
Miranda on like that?
Hope is something
you've gotta have.
It kept me going
when you were gone.
-Uh...
-Mary Jane,
all this has made me realize
just how precious you are to me.
Uh, I-- I'm flattered,
Spider-Man,
but I'm already in love
with a great guy-- Peter Parker.
Mary Jane, there's something
I've got to show you.
[gasps]
[upbeat rock music]
♪ Spider-Man, Spider-Man ♪
♪ Radioactive Spider-Man ♪
♪ Spider blood, spider blood ♪
♪ Radioactive spider blood ♪
♪ Spider blood ♪
♪ Spider-Man ♪