[Spider-Man]
Previously onSpider-Man.
The astronauts are bringing
with them Promethium X.
Help me!
[crashing]
[Kingpin] Rhino, did you
get the Promethium X?
-Yeah.
-[Kingpin] Bring it to me!
[crashing]
Where did you come from?
Could it have come
from the shuttle?
Spider-Man robbed the shuttle.
I'm offering a million dollars.
[Peter thinking]
For once in my life,
I'm worth something,
and I can't collect.
[splashing]
No!
[growling]
[Spider-Man thinking]
I don't know how I got here,
and I'm in a costume
I've never seen before.
Nothing on Earth could
do what this does.
I've developed a lot
more than a backbone.
Parker, you scare me.
[Spider-Man thinking]
I am different.
Go!
[Spider-Man thinking]
What's happening to me?
It's a symbian, an organism
that thrives by
bonding with another!
You've got to get
that suit off.
[Spider-Man] I can't.
I have some things
I have to take care of first.
[Shocker] I am invincible!
[zapping]
Say good-bye to
your friendly super hero.
This Spider-Man
plays for keeps.
[Spider-Man thinking]
What have I done?
What's this costume doing?
I've gotta get it off!
I guess Conners is right.
[dinging]
Stay away from me!
I'm not like you!
It's over.
[groans]
[Venom] Spider-Man!
Enjoy your
fame while it lasts.
[theme song playing]
♪ Spider-Man, Spider-Man ♪
♪ Radioactive Spider-Man ♪
♪ Spider blood, spider blood ♪
♪ Radioactive spider blood ♪
♪ Spider-Man, Spider-Man ♪
[grunts]
You thought it was over,
didn't you, Spider-Man?
You made a fool of Eddie Brock
whenever you could.
You cost me my job,
my reputation,
[sneezes]
my health, my apartment.
You just won't stop 'til
you ruin me, will ya?
You can't do this.
I already have.
[strains]
[man] You're fired!
I'll get even with you if
it's the last thing I do!
You rejected the symbiote, only
wanted to make you stronger.
Well, surprise, surprise.
Now, we're one.
Now, you're gonna pay.
From now on, we're poison
to you, Spider-Man.
That's why we call
ourselves Venom.
[growls]
[Spider-Man thinking]
I feel great.
Boy, am I glad to be
back in my old clothes,
and that full moon is
perfect for my date tonight
with Mary Jane.
Huh?
Down there, I don't believe it.
It's the Rhino!
Finally found you.
[laughs]
We've got a score to settle.
You shoulda stayed in
black 'cause I'm gonna
dirty you up bad.
Sorry,
they tell me the blue
really brings out my eyes.
[crashes]
[stomps]
Last time, I kicked your
hide all over this town.
Is your learning curve
a flat line, or what?
[Shocker] His might be.
Mine isn't.
[Spider-Man thinking]
Rhino and Shocker,
how'd they get together,
computer dating?
Ow!
[crashes]
[groans]
[Shocker] This time,
it's maximum voltage
at minimum range.
[Venom] Back off!
He belongs to us!
[bangs]
[growls]
[Shocker]
What are you doin', you?
No!
How am I gonna
fight both those creeps
at the same time?
Huh?
Whose webbing is that?
[Venom] Need a hand, pal?
Eddie Brock?
-How did you--
-Get up here?
Same way you did, Spider-punk,
or do you mind if we just
call you Peter Parker?
What did you say?
Oh, you're quite
the bully when you wanna be,
aren't you, Parker?
Problem is Eddie Brock isn't
the same guy he once was.
Why don't we introduce you
to our better half?
We call ourselves Venom.
[growls]
We're your old clothes,
Kid, your hand-me-downs.
The symbiote that
Peter Parker tried to destroy,
Eddie Brock has embraced.
We've bonded.
The symbiote,
it's still alive!
How, how did it find Brock?
You don't understand, Brock!
It doesn't just bond with you.
It takes over, makes
you do what it wants.
-You've gotta separate from it.
-Separate?
We're made for each other.
Brock's rage
and vengefulness
made us a perfect breeding
ground for you, Parker.
Brock,
you've got to get rid of it.
Why?
We're now part of a life force
that has existed since
the dawn of time.
Imagine what you've
turned down, Parker.
Think of all this knowledge.
We've seen thousands of worlds,
millions of civilizations,
learned many secrets,
always with but one goal
above all else, to survive,
and now we're sharing those
secrets with Eddie Brock.
We're thrilled to be together.
No, Brock, Brock!
Surprise!
[crashes]
He never
triggered my spider sense!
Such low range weapon.
Here, have some of mine.
Now, don't worry.
We're not gonna finish
you yet, Parker.
Listen to me, Brock.
You've got--
Stop calling us that!
We are Venom now!
We wanted you,
but you spurned us.
Now, we have big plans.
You know nothing about us, but
we know everything about you.
You'll see us everywhere,
even in your nightmares.
[growls]
Brock, come back!
[Spider-Man thinking] Venom,
Brock, I have to find him.
Doc Connors was right.
That alien takes over its host,
but since it tried to bond
with my DNA and failed,
it could even block
my spider sense.
Now what do I do?
I've gotta track 'em down.
Maybe I can find a clue
in his old apartment.
If that symbiote nearly
drove me nuts, I can imagine
what it's doing to a pumped up
lunatic like Brock.
[dramatic music]
Pumped up, that's it.
Brock likes to work out
by himself all the time,
and that might give me
just the lead I need.
[roars]
[Peter thinking]
Get a grip, Parker.
You're starting to lose it.
Uh, Atlas Equipment?
My name is Eddie Brock,
and I need to double check
the address you
sent my weights to.
OK, yes, that's right.
Thank you.
Here are those clippings
you wanted on Brock.
Why do you need them?
Uh, a school project.
Thanks, Mr. Robertson.
[Jonah] Hey, everybody,
look who's here.
[indistinct chatter]
Colonel Jameson,
what a surprise.
How're ya feelin'?
The prognosis is
that John's going
to make a full recovery.
In fact, NASA can't
wait to get him
back in command of
another shuttle.
Is that right, son?
Sure, so long as I
can shake the memories
of the crash
and the black alien ooze.
Dreams go away.
You'll be fine.
He'll be fine.
That satellite is being
launched tomorrow night,
they've named it
the John Jameson probe
in his honor.
[Peter thinking] That black
ooze isn't a dream.
It's my worst nightmare.
Spider-Man is finished.
I'm through.
There's nothing I can do.
Somewhere, he's out there,
and my spider sense
can't detect him.
He could strike at any time.
[Venom] Nice Spidey jammies.
Brock!
Wonder what people would do
if they knew
who Spider-Man was.
Hey, let's go ask
Jameson about that!
[growls]
[swooshing]
[yelling]
Look up there.
Two Spider-Mans!
[growls]
Brock, the more you hate me,
the more the symbiote
can control you.
Who said we hate you?
Fact is,
we're your biggest fan.
Look, streamers!
Now it is a party.
[growls]
Disappeared!
[Venom] Revenge is
a human trait we enjoy.
We'll have our revenge
against you and the ones close
to you, like your poor
Aunt May or Mary Jane Watson.
-We know all about them too.
-You leave them alone!
[yells]
[swooshing]
[yelling]
You won't believe it!
Two of 'em!
His webbing's stronger
than mine,
stronger than me!
Quite a crowd!
Perfect time for an unmasking.
No!
[muttering]
[man in mask]
Check it out, Dude.
His mask is off.
I'm Spider-Man.
This is my chance to ID
that wall-crawling rat bag.
Gimme that!
Quick, somebody, what do I do
to make this thing zoom in?
Come on, hold still so I
can focus in on your face.
Ready for your closeup,
Mr. Parker?
When the world finds out who
you are, you're history, pal.
Think of all the lovely
folks you'll leave behind,
like Mary Jane.
She'll be so lonely.
Maybe we'll have to
keep her company.
How does that sound, Tiger?
If you
try anything with her.
Come on, hold still.
Blast, hold still.
Oh, clumsy us.
We almost dropped you.
[snapping]
This'll have to do until I
get my spare mask at home.
[murmuring]
I was supposed to meet
Mary Jane tonight,
but what if Venom
gets to her first?
Mary Jane, Mary Jane,
Mary Jane.
Oh, sorry I'm late.
That's OK, Peter.
I ran into someone who says
he's a friend of yours.
Don't you just love
the theater?
I know you do.
I hear you're
a wonderful actress.
Oh, thank you.
[grunts]
What are you doing?
We have to go.
[Venom] But you'll miss
the curtain, Petey.
What's wrong with you?
We're going to miss the show.
Brock's a weirdo, OK?
I'll explain later.
Just keep walking.
[Mary Jane] Why?
Nobody's there.
Peter, what's gotten into you?
[growls]
[sighs]
I've gotta take you home.
Peter, tell me what's going on.
Lost him.
Who are you talking about?
Mary Jane, do you trust me?
-What are you--
-Do you trust me?
Yes, I think I do.
Then just do as I say,
and don't ask me
any questions, please.
[Mary Jane] OK.
[groans]
[May] Home so soon?
Uh, we had to leave.
Really, why?
[doorbell rings]
Hey, buddy.
Real quaint, homey.
[May] Who is it, dear?
Eddie, Eddie Brock, ma'am.
An old, dear friend of Peter's,
and you must be Aunt May.
Heard so much about you.
Eddie and I have to have
a little talk, Aunt May.
Be seein' ya, ma'am.
What a nice man, so polite.
She won't see you again.
[Venom] How would you stop us?
[creaking]
Brock!
[Peter thinking]
He'll never stop torturing me!
I've got to fight, and I
know just the way to do it.
[gasps]
No, no!
Like the way
I decorated your new place!
You dare!
[crashes]
[screams]
That's it, follow me, come on.
[growls]
Blast, where'd he go?
We'll crush you like a worm!
-[cracking]
-[screams]
Happy landing.
[grunts]
We're going to turn
out your lights.
This party is over!
[growls]
We'll catch you
wherever you go!
There's no place on Earth
that we can't find you.
It'd be nice if there were
a couple hundred more
cars to this train.
[growls]
Now where is he?
[Venom] Ticket, please.
Sorry, big guy,
but I think we're about
to reach your stop.
He won't let that stop him.
[engine roars]
[horn honks]
[Venom] Look, Parker,
we're booked for a round trip.
Next time, I'm flying.
The military base launch pad.
We're here.
[yells]
Finally, I made it.
Now the hard part begins.
And as the countdown draws
to a close, let me say
that it is an honor
to have the very first
space launch in the New York
area be named
for NASA's brave
shuttle commander,
Colonel John Jameson.
[cheering]
One minute and counting.
Mark.
[Spider-Man thinking]
Bingo, the John Jameson probe.
Fitting since this
all started in space.
[growls]
Not too smart, Spider-Man.
Nowhere to run,
and nowhere to hide.
[growls]
Come on, come on,
launch this thing!
[growls]
[Venom] Got ya!
No, got you.
[yells]
Hope this launch doesn't
fry my molecules,
but if I'm gonna go,
at least I'll take him with me.
Start the engines, come on.
-Say aloha!
-[engines roar]
[NASA Technician] We have
main engine ignition.
[screams]
[Venom] The noise!
What have you done?
You tricked us!
[screams]
Yes, it worked.
The roar of the rocket forced
the symbiote off Brock.
[NASA Technician]
We have liftoff.
What?
[Security Personnel]
Security launch control,
I have intruders in
the gantry elevator.
Let's sweep
the perimeter fence.
[engines roar]
I did it.
I beat the most relentless,
unforgiving opponent
I've ever faced.
[romantic music]
[Mary Jane] Peter,
are you listening to me?
Huh?
Oh, sorry, I was just
admiring the stars.
You were saying?
I said, looking up at the sky
on a night like this,
it's easy to believe
that we're not alone.
I wonder what's out there.
That's exactly what
I was wondering too.
[growls]
♪ Spider-Man, Spider-Man ♪
♪ Radioactive Spider-Man ♪
♪ Spider blood, spider blood ♪
♪ Radioactive spider blood ♪
♪ Spider-Man ♪