[theme music playing]
♪ Spider-Man, Spider-Man ♪
♪ Radioactive Spider-Man ♪
♪ Spider blood, spider blood ♪
♪ Radioactive spider blood ♪
♪ Spider-Man, Spider-Man ♪
[train horn blaring]
I can't believe it!
A date with Felicia Hardy.
Finally!
Sure, I'm only taking her to
a science exhibit
as her physics tutor,
but after that
Spider-slayer business
I didn't think she'd
let me see her again.
[man on speaker] Who's there?
Peter Parker, I'm here to--
[gate opens]
[Peter thinking]
Relax, Parker.
Felicia's just a simple,
sweet, regular girl.
With a front lawn
the size of Central Park.
So, when is this place
applying for statehood?
Maybe I should have
worn a suit.
Or at least a new shirt.
Come in, Mr. Parker.
I'll announce you.
[Peter] Yep,
definitely a new shirt.
[metal crushing]
[radio static]
Camera three,
negative function.
Please investigate.
Wow.
Aunt May's whole place
could fit in this one room,
and there'd still be
space for the Jets
to hold a scrimmage.
Security, code red!
Parker.
How sweet, you brought flowers.
Thank you.
Oh, it's nothing.
So, where's your mom?
Parker, she's out
buying a new yacht.
Well what happened,
the old one get wet?
Shall we take the convertible?
It's kinda chilly out,
but I'll keep you warm.
I'll get a jacket,
if it's all the same to you.
No!
Let me go!
Felicia!
-[gasps]
-[groaning]
Let go! [screams]
Help!
No!
[Peter groaning]
Four metallic arms?
Yes, that's what I saw.
I keep telling you.
Did you notice anything
else about him?
Couple extra heads, maybe?
Look, I don't care whether
you believe me or not.
Felicia's gone.
You should be out
looking for her.
My daughter, where is she?
What happened to her?
Who are you?
Mrs. Hardy,
I'm Agent Ford, FBI.
I have bad news.
Your daughter's been kidnapped.
Kidnapped?
We found this note out front.
It says ransom
instructions will follow.
That signature.
Doctor Octavius.
-[Hardy] You know him?
-Well, that explains it.
The Hardy Foundation
refused to grant money
for his outlandish experiments.
He must want revenge.
[Peter] Dr. Octavius?
Otto Octavius?
It can't be.
When I was 10, Uncle Ben
enrolled me at science camp
and the man who ran the
camp was Dr. Otto Octavius.
He was a genius.
Had a real gift for teaching.
I remember once, I tried
an experiment of my own.
-It blew up in my face,
-[children laughing]
and the other kids
started laughing at me.
But then Dr. Octavius said
something I'll never forget.
Their laughter is meaningless.
Science is the important thing.
It justifies all that
we do in its service.
[Peter] What could
have changed him?
Where did he take Felicia?
[grunts]
What do you want from me?
Who are you?
Who am I?
What's in a name? Mmm?
An octopus by any other name
would still be as deadly.
[screams]
Please.
I've never done
anything to you.
No, of course you haven't.
That's what they all say.
No one's ever done
anything to Dr. Octopus.
It started with my colleagues.
They ridiculed me.
Those mindless fools
could not comprehend how
a cold fusion reaction could
be generated in a battery.
So I approached
The Hardy Foundation
for funding of my experiments.
They promised to grant
me the money I needed.
I knew I would master
fusion power eventually.
But it wasn't quick
enough for your mother,
great friend of
science that she was.
She cut off the grant.
I had to move my laboratory
to a miserable basement.
I could no longer
afford vital safeguards,
but I was determined.
Nothing would stop me.
[grunting]
And I paid the price.
Dr. Octavius vanished
in that explosion,
and Dr. Octopus was born.
[maniacal laughter]
This is J. Jonah Jameson,
President and CEO of
J3 Communications.
I have a message for
Dr. Otto Octavius.
Felicia Hardy's
family and friends
are deeply concerned
for her safety.
We're prepared to
meet your demands,
but we need to
know what you want.
Please, call me here
at the J3 studio
as soon as this
broadcast is over.
We want Felicia back.
We'll do anything you ask,
as long as she isn't harmed.
I will personally
guarantee that.
[phone ringing]
[man] Cut to station ID.
Jonah, if it's him, whatever
you do, keep your cool.
Don't I always, Robbie?
And try to keep him
talking as long as you can.
Stop fussing, I've seen
enough crime movies.
[man] You're on, JJ.
Jameson here.
This is Dr. Octopus,
accepting your generous offer.
I'll switch us off the air.
No.
I insist we keep it on the air.
I want the whole world to
know how I've been treated.
What about Miss Hardy,
is she OK?
Sometimes sacrifices must be
made in the name of science.
If anything happens
to her I'll--
[Octavius] You'll what?
You're not in a position
to do anything.
Don't count on that,
you six-armed squid!
No, Jonah, no!
[Jameson] You're a
symbol of everything
that's wrong with this country.
[Peter] J. Jonah Jameson.
The great communicator.
You should be put away
for the rest of your--
You dare talk that
way to a scientist?
Scientist?
You're just a coward who
kidnapped a helpless girl.
Coward am I?
We'll see who the coward is.
I want you personally to
deliver the ransom money to me.
What?
Come alone,
unless you're the coward.
I'll fax you
the instructions later.
He wants me to bring it.
[car screeches]
Hello?
Octavius?
Where are you?
Show yourself!
[screaming]
Face to face at last.
I trust we're alone.
The FBI promised to stay clear.
Now show me the girl.
Sorry, I don't take requests.
If you've hurt her!
She's in perfect condition.
But as for you...
[Spider-Man] Hands up!
All of them.
[Jameson] Spider-Man,
what are you doing here?
That's simple,
you brought him, didn't you?
Me? I never.
You web-headed foul-up!
Hey, it's nice
to see you too, pickle puss.
You really think
your spider powers
can compare with
the shattering impact
of my unbreakable
hydraulic tentacles?
[Spider-Man] It was a thought.
Don't waste your time thinking.
It may very well be the last
thought you'll ever have.
Your pathetic acrobatics
are no threat to me.
Listen carefully.
Now that I have twice
as many hostages
I want twice the ransom,
and I want it in 24 hours.
You're won't get
rid of me that...
They're gone.
I really blew it this time.
Who asked you to help?
If you'd kept out of it I'd
have my daughter back now.
I don't think he would have
released her, even if we--
Oh, now you're
a mind reader too?
For all I know, you might be
working with that lunatic.
I used to defend
you against Jonah.
Told him the city was
better off because of you.
Maybe I was wrong.
Coming from Robbie, that hurt,
more than anything Octavius'
tentacles could do to me.
The worst part is,
they may be right.
Listen to me,
sinking into self-pity.
That's not gonna get them back.
And if spidey can't do it,
maybe Peter Parker can.
This video just arrived.
[Felicia] Oh.
Felicia.
What's he done to you?
Time's running out.
I'll be calling you
at 10 o'clock.
Two minutes from now.
Robbie, I have to talk to you.
Not now, Peter.
It's about Dr. Octopus.
Listen, kid, we
don't have time--
You don't understand,
I know him.
He was my teacher.
We're professionals.
We know how to deal
with these situations.
But I think I know
how to get to him.
No, no, wait.
let's hear him out.
We're tampering with
the most important
thing in Octavius' life.
Science.
Unless we understand that,
Felicia and Mr. Jameson
will be...
[phone ringing]
Let me talk to him.
Hello, Dr. Octavius?
This is Peter Parker.
I was one of your students
years ago at science camp.
[Octavius]Hmm, Parker?
[Peter] You probably don't
remember me,
but you taught me how
important science is.
I've read every paper
you've published.
Sustained fusion-fission
reactions.
Neurochemical fusion.
[Octavius] What about
fusion potential
of the super-collider?
You never wrote that.
You were testing me,
weren't you?
[Octavius] And you passed.
Do you know about my
cold fusion battery?
Of course.
I'd give anything
to see that battery.
Then you're the perfect one
to bring me the ransom.
And after that,
I'll show it to you.
[Peter] Usually it's
the spider that traps the fly,
not the octopus that
traps the spider.
An abandoned rocket
assembly plant.
What a perfect hideout
for a loony scientist.
-Peter!
-[Jameson] Parker!
Don't worry, everything's
going to be OK.
I'll believe that
when I see it.
Is that the money?
Excellent.
Now, let me show you
the purpose this will serve.
What about Felicia
and Mr. Jameson?
Them, they can hang
around for a while.
Fusion energy,
billions of kilowatts.
Enough power to lift mankind
from the depths of poverty.
A power I will control.
Think of it.
A battery only twice
the size of this
could replace a dozen
nuclear power plants.
Yes, but when you exceed this
size it becomes unstable.
-The last time it--
-You're right, Mr. Parker.
It blew up.
But there was a dividend.
The explosion that
destroyed my laboratory
also welded these
arms to my spine.
A neurologically
augmented exoskeleton.
It responds to my thoughts.
A melding of metal
to flesh and bone.
Incredible.
Reminds me of Flash Thompson,
all hands.
They let me do my work
four times as fast,
and they are the greatest
weapons imaginable.
Dr. Octavius, you've been paid.
Now release
Felicia and Mr. Jameson.
Release them?
Don't insult my intelligence.
But you've got your money.
A good first installment.
You promised to let them go.
What? A broken promise?
Sound familiar?
That's one of the perks
of power, my student.
Listen and learn.
[Peter] I'm no
longer your student,
and there's nothing
more you can teach me.
Oh, no?
[Felicia] Peter!
Even Parker
didn't deserve that.
[sobs] You--
You heartless freak!
Freak?
I'm merely the victim
of an accident,
and anyone
can have an accident.
[Spider-Man] Don't touch her!
Spider-Man!
You're making a career
of interference.
Some career.
No salary, no vacation.
And talk about on-the-job
health hazards.
Clinging to walls won't help.
My tentacles will turn
you into a blood smear.
I've got to find
a way to immobilize
at least some of those arms.
A dynamo.
Dynamos make electricity
by spinning a coil
between the poles
of either a magnet
or an electromagnet.
What's the matter, doc?
Stuck on that dynamo's magnet?
You lamebrain!
You've started
the assembly test line.
When the rocket
engine's overhead,
it will fire on top of us.
Double jeopardy, Spider-Man.
If you manage to
turn off the dynamo
you'll face the full
fury of Dr. Octopus.
And if you don't, perhaps
you'll live long enough
to see your friends'
molecules fry.
Well that's what
I love about life.
Choices.
Hurry!
[Spider-Man] I'm going as
fast as I can, Miss Hardy.
How does it feel to
know that you could
change things, Spider-Man,
but be helpless to do so?
[Spider-Man] About
as bad as I'd feel
if I had a name like Doc Oc.
An electromagnet!
If i can just
find the controls.
[Octavius] Let me give you
a few last thoughts
to contemplate
before I put
an end to your puny--
I really hate to interrupt
a megalomaniac
when he's on a roll,
but here's web in your eyes.
Come on, drop me.
Come on!
Perfect.
Now if I can just
get Oc over here.
[groaning]
You six-armed neanderthal.
Why don't you get over here
and fight like an octopus?
No fool am I, Spider-Man.
I won't fall for
the same trick twice.
Besides, I can wait,
unlike your friends.
[computer beeping]
[alarm blares]
[screaming]
Spider-Man!
Do something!
[Spider-Man] Octavius is right.
I'll never get past him
to shut off that dynamo.
Unless...
Get away from that.
[Spider-Man] Tell you what,
let's make a trade.
My friends for
your life's work.
[snarls]
It worked like a charm.
[Felicia screaming]
[gasp]
Hang on!
[Jameson screaming]
[engine whirring off]
Oh, how can I ever thank you?
Well this seems like
a pretty good way.
Oh, no, Peter!
Peter!
Peter?
[Peter groaning]
Are you OK?
Sure, fine.
Some date, huh?
That's one way of putting it.
You wanna give it another try?
Well Parker, you have
to understand something.
I don't usually
allow myself to be
taken hostage on a first date.
I respect that.
[lightning]
Stone walls do
not a prison make,
nor iron bars a cage.
Not against
the genius of Dr. Octopus.
[maniacal laughter]
[theme music playing]
♪ Spider-Man Spider-Man ♪
♪ Radioactive Spider-Man ♪
♪ Spider blood, spider blood ♪
♪ Radioactive spider blood ♪
♪ Spider-Man ♪