[upbeat rock music]
♪ Spider-Man ♪
♪ Radioactive Spider-Man ♪
♪ Spider blood
Spider blood ♪
♪ Radioactive spider blood ♪
♪ Spider blood
Spider blood ♪
♪ Radioactive spider blood ♪
[explosions booming]
[growling]
♪ Spider-Man ♪
[dramatic music]
Boojums, I'm afraid.
I may have to help destroy
one man I love
or betray another.
[cat meowing]
[blasting]
Either way, I can't
avoid hurting somebody.
[Spider-Man]
Are you all right?
Yes, now that you're here.
[Spider-Man] A guy
could get the wrong idea
and think a certain someone
likes him.
-[hissing]
-It's me, Felicia.
You're still the man I love.
Felicia, will you
help me find peace?
I've been given a device
that will end your misery.
No! There's got
to be a better way!
[Spider-Man]
Michael, come back!
[Black Cat]
I blew it, didn't I?
[Spider-Man]
No, you did the right thing.
Since when did
my new powers come
-with so much responsibility?
-[meows]
[Spider-Man] Will I ever
see the Black Cat again?
She seems to have soured
on the superhero life.
Maybe I should have
been more encouraging,
made her my partner
from the beginning.
I sure could use her help now.
Vampire hunting
isn't my forte.
[ominous music]
[whooshing]
[keys rattling]
-[Miriam] I need your plasma...
-Aah!
...to sustain me
on a long, long journey.
-[weapon blasting]
-[groans]
[Blade] Drop the human now,
night stalker!
[motorcycle engine roars]
-[tires screech]
-[groans]
[chains clanking]
[groaning]
[screaming]
Sunlight!
[Blade] Nothing can protect
you this time, vampire!
You can't stop me, not now!
[loud blasts]
[groans]
No! It can't be!
Noooo!
[thinking]
Where are you, Michael?
Is it wrong for me to hope
you're still alive?
[gasps]
Sorry, Spider,
but I can't face you,
not until I sort out my
feelings for you and Michael.
[Spider-Man, thinking]
I don't get it.
Morbius hasn't attacked
anybody for days.
If he's out there,
he must be starving.
Hey, buddy, you okay?
-Rrr! Stay away from me! Go!
-[frightened gasps]
I am so weak,
but I will not destroy you
or anyone else,
just to feed myself,
even if it means--
Morbius, I am Miriam.
I, too, am a vampire.
And I have come
a long way for you.
Miriam, how did you find me?
Once you became a vampire,
you gained a psychic link
with me and others
just like us.
I need your knowledge
of the machine
that can turn humans
into vampires.
No! I cannot.
Look into my eyes.
Let me enter your mind.
No! Stay away!
Your mind has told me enough.
Now I know how to get the rest.
Oh, this is frustrating.
Michael is on the loose,
and it's all my fault.
But how can I help him?
Landon and his thieves
took all my equipment!
Easy, Deb.
How were you supposed
to know the foundation
that funded you was bogus?
-Right, Clay?
-Yeah.
After Landon
gets out of the hospital,
the cops'll make him tell us
where the Recombinator is.
-Then we can do something.
-[power shuts down]
-[Debra] Hey!
-Look!
Where is
the Neogenic Recombinator?
[under mind control]
He... took it.
Who did?
Herbert Landon.
[wind whistles]
Wh-- What are you?!
Sleep, human!
Herbert Landon,
open your mind to me.
Show me where the Recombinator
is and how to use it.
[whooshing]
-[electricity crackling]
-What?!
The Neogenic Recombinator
is gone!
[moaning]
[gasp] Spider-Man!
[Spider-Man]
What happened here?
[Terri] Three of them,
barely conscious,
severe plasma depletion.
-Morbius!
-He started attacking again,
and that makes him
Public Enemy Number one.
Listen, I think there's
still a chance to save him.
Forget it, webhead.
He's too dangerous.
When I find him, I'm going
to stop him for good.
[Black Cat]
Sorry, Michael,
but I can't let you hurt
anyone anymore.
You must be stopped.
Cat, where have you been?
Out trying to catch Morbius.
I had no luck.
I need Whistler's help.
Wait! We both have
the same goal.
Why can't we work together?
I told you,
on this I want to fly solo.
[Spider-Man]
It was my blood sample
that did this to Morbius.
Sorry, Cat,
I have a stake in this, too,
no vampire pun intended.
Whistler, your weapons
are our only hope
of catching Morbius.
My weapons are best suited
for annihilating vampires.
Are you prepared
to destroy him?
No! Can't we
just stop him somehow?
[thinking] She seems
almost afraid for Morbius.
He save me and Spider-Man
in Landon's lab.
He deserves our help.
That must be it.
She must have sympathy
for his plight.
Well, the fearless vampire
hunters are all here.
I guess I know why.
We're assessing our options.
I still think we can stop
Morbius without hurting him.
And I think you're dreaming.
He has to be stopped
once and for all.
Whistler has just what we need.
[electronic beeping]
[Spider-Man] Cat, why are
you so interested in Morbius?
Someone close to me once
became a victim of vampirism.
This isn't the time
to talk about it.
[Terri] Where is
Blade these days?
He was tracking down
a dangerous vampire
in Eastern Europe, but I have
not heard from him in days.
I am most worried.
You were wise
not to try to have
a relationship with him.
It would have been hard on you.
Tell me something I don't know.
[Terri]
Kishi Electronics?
What would Morbius
be doing here?
[Whistler]
The readings are strong.
Nosferatu!
Put the guard down, Morbius!
[hissing]
-You're not--
This is
a computer printout
of the plans
for the Neogenic Recombinator.
Aah!
What do you have to do
with the Recombinator?
[Miriam]
I possess it,
and now I have the parts
I need to activate!
This sunburst grenade will
end your plasma-draining days!
Stay back!
You will not harm her!
This locket
that she once possessed
has proven to me that she is
Miriam, my mother.
-Blade?
-Look into my eyes.
See that I tell the truth.
Yes.
Yes!
[Whistler] Blade, she is now
an evil stalker of the night.
That is why I shall take
her away and cure her.
No way! She's got to pay
for the crimes she's committed.
This from you, Terri Lee?
You'll have to fight me first.
[groans]
[Miriam] You are strong.
I can't wait to see
what your plasma does to me.
[Black Cat] No!
[thud]
Mother!
Weakling! Yaah!
[groans]
Morbius!
[crash]
[weapon blasting]
Blade, stop!
We can work together.
You've never been much
of a team player, Spider-Man.
Neither am I!
[coughing]
[motorcycle revving]
Please, for both our sakes,
-don't come after me!
-[glass shatters]
Are you okay?
No. I'm disappointed in Blade.
-I taught him better than this.
-[Morbius groaning]
He's had no plasma
for too long.
Good, then we've done our job.
He wasn't responsible
for those last attacks,
and he just saved my life.
We have to help him.
Even if I thought it was
a good idea, what could we do?
[Spider-Man] Whistler,
what about that serum,
the one I once saw you give
to Blade to keep him human?
Couldn't we give him that?
He has to want to be human.
That's the only way
it will work.
Whistler, I believe
that now he does. Please.
This is against
my better judgment,
but let's get him
back to the theater.
The serum
appears to be working.
It seems odd to me
to be saving one of them.
-Will he be all right?
-I'm hopeful.
Saving him gets us nowhere.
The vampire locator is gone.
How will we find
Miriam and Blade now?
[Morbius]
I can find them for you.
I can sense her presence.
That's how I found her
at the factory.
She is evil!
I have been in her mind.
She plans to-- She--
It's almost dawn.
He can't do anything
until he's slept.
We ought to do the same.
Then what?
Blade will never let us
lay a finger on his mother.
[Spider-Man]
Then he is our enemy, too.
Blade is merely a lost child,
bonding at last
with the mother he never knew.
Surely, you all
can understand that.
I guess I can.
I never knew my parents,
either.
You all must help me
explain to him
that once a vampire,
always a vampire.
But I think
you can count on him
to do what's right in the end.
I certainly hope you're right.
Our lives depend on it.
Thank you for coming.
I am sorry about last night.
But my mother says
she wants to be human again.
What makes you think
you can trust her?
I had hoped you
would understand me.
You were the one
who showed me the beauty
of feeling with my heart.
I understand,
but I'm so scared for you.
As long as I have your love,
I am strong.
But I must go now.
And as before, please
don't try to follow me.
Don't worry.
I probably couldn't
keep up with you anyway.
[Peter, thinking]
I've gotta go.
Oh, it's torn.
Thanks a lot, Blade.
Luckily, I have a spare.
[Harry]
Peter, is that you?
[Peter] Harry? I don't
have time right now.
Pete? Huh.
I could have sworn
I heard something.
What on Earth?!
Pete, can I come in?
Look, Pete
this won't take long.
I just-- That's weird.
[Black Cat]
How is Morbius doing?
As well as can be expected.
He will always burn
with the desire for plasma.
My formula isn't a cure,
but it can keep
those urges in check.
What is the attraction
you women have to vampires?
Detective Lee loves Blade.
-You love Morbius.
-[Morbius moans]
What am I missing?
Fangs, maybe?
Michael?
Felicia, I do not
know if I can rely
on the serum
for the rest of my life.
Maybe if someone were by
your side giving you strength.
Someone like me?
You would do that for me?
I will do that for you.
[metal can skittering]
Hey, man, check it out!
You need help
with something, mama?
Yes, I need you, my children.
[Recombinator blasting]
[screaming]
Terri, you coming in?
I can't.
I'm not strong enough.
I'm sorry.
[Spider-Man] Don't be.
-I understand.
-[engine starts]
[motorcycle engine roaring]
[loud rock music]
Mother, I am so glad
to have you with me again.
Yes, I was so lost without you.
For years, I have
sought out the family
that I was denied when
I was turned into a vampire.
At last, my quest
will be fulfilled.
Oh, soon you will be human.
Then you can make
a new life for us both.
Is the Recombinator ready?
[Miriam] It is ready.
I've tested it.
What do you mean, tested it?
What is the meaning of this?!
It is useless to struggle.
Unlike you, these are full
vampires, stronger than you.
My true goal's
not to change myself,
but to create that family
of which I spoke,
a family of vampires!
And I will be their mother,
as well as yours.
Never! I trusted you!
Blade, you must forsake
your humanity.
But you are the one
who gave me my humanity!
That was long
before I'd seen the wonders
of the eternal night!
Join me! This is the way
you will become a vampire,
not the halfling
that you are now!
[Morbius] I sense
that Miriam is near.
We will save time
if we look separately.
Oh, nice suit, man.
Mother, you can't do this!
[Spider-Man] Right.
[roaring]
[Miriam]
Help me, my children!
Tonight the whole city
will be mine!
[Spider-Man] Incredible.
She's used Landon's knowledge
to turn the Recombinator
into a vampire creator!
[Spider-Man] Come on!
We've got to stop Miriam!
Morbius, cover your face!
We must not let them get away!
It does not matter.
I have no desire
to fight anymore,
not against my own mother.
You, here? But how?
Don't stop now!
You must go on!
I believe in you, Blade!
Your real mother is trapped
in that vampire's body,
and she needs
your love to rescue her.
You are right, Terri Lee.
Come, my vampire children.
Now these four will join us.
Not on your afterlife!
[screaming]
My family!
My beautiful children!
Lost to me again!
I must find her.
She must realize
that I am her only child
and that only I can save her.
[motorcycle starts]
[Whistler]
I must go prepare new weapons
and serum for him to use.
Will you be all right?
Oh, yeah.
I feel giddy with delight.
[Spider-Man] We've lost her.
I'm going after her.
-I'll go with you.
-No.
I've learned
that with this great power
comes a greater responsibility.
I have to use my power
where it's needed most,
and that's not here
with you, Spider.
I've finally made
a hard decision.
I'm going to leave.
[Spider-Man] Why?
Why can't I be with you?
Because you must stay here
and take care of this city.
-It needs you.
-I need you!
I won't let you go.
You will,
because I'm asking you to.
Do this for me, please.
Someday, I will explain.
For now,
just remember I love you.
[Spider-Man] Cat!
[motorcycle engine roars]
[tires screech]
What do you want, vampire?!
To join you, to give
some purpose to my life.
You'll find her faster with me.
She and I are
telepathically linked.
Do as you like.
Okay, that went well.
We shall follow him.
He will grow accustomed to us.
Perhaps if we are lucky,
someday he will be our friend.
Are you sure you want this,
my darling?
Yes, my love.
[Morbius] Then, let us go.
[spider-Man] So here we are,
dazed and totally confused.
Yeah, we're a regular
lonely hearts club.
[police radio beeps]
[dispatcher]
One-Adam-Zero-Zero.
There's a 911 in progress.
I guess it's time
for me to get back to work.
You take care of yourself.
Yeah, you too.
What did I do wrong?
Now Black Cat's left me,
Felicia's gone,
and Mary Jane's still missing.
Well, at least there's nowhere
to go from here but up.
[upbeat rock music]
♪ Spider-Man, Spider-Man ♪
♪ Radioactive Spider-Man ♪
♪ Spider blood, spider blood ♪
♪ Radioactive spider blood ♪
♪ Spider blood ♪
♪ Spider-Man ♪