[announcer]
Previously onSpider-Man.
Sorry Commander but I got
a problem only you can solve.
This scientist
holds the key to one
of the greatest powers
known to mankind.
I must band together
the Insidious Six.
Who will be your sixth
forgotten warrior?
Since the last
Mysterio, Vulture.
[Peter voiceover]
These passports belong
to my parents?
This is Keene Marlow.
[Spider-Man] I'm gonna find out
just who this guy really is.
Huh? S.H.I.E.L.D Headquarters?
No matter what,
Richard and Mary Parker's name
must not be cleared.
[Spider-Man] What?
Your parents were
spies for Russia.
I want to go to Russia.
Spider-Man's going where?
If you send Peter,
then I want to go too.
The man who gave me your name
told me to show you this.
Now that Groitzig's been
taken I fear for my life.
[explosion booms]
Take Lentz.
[dramatic music playing]
Destroy this place.
[beeping]
[theme music playing]
♪ Spider-Man, Spider-Man ♪
♪ Radioactive Spider-Man ♪
♪ Spider-Man ♪
♪ Spider-Man, Spider-Man ♪
♪ Radioactive Spider-Man ♪
♪ Spider blood, spider blood ♪
♪ Radioactive spider blood ♪
♪ Radioactive spider power ♪
♪ Spider-Man, Spider-Man ♪
[suspenseful music playing]
[gong ringing]
[bomb beeping]
[groaning] Robbie?
What now?
[Robbie] Look.
There's enough
plastique on this thing
to take out four city blocks.
Give it to me.
This is a K-8
incendiary device.
I know what to do.
[Spider-Man] Really?
Are you sure?
[Robbie] I'm sure.
[Spider-Man] Where did
you learn how to do that?
I was in the bomb disposal
unit in the service.
Never thought what I
learned would come in handy
in the regular world.
You're full of
surprises tonight.
For instance,
what are you doing here?
I might ask you
the same question.
[sirens blaring]
I'd love to continue this chat
but neither of us needs
to spend the night
in a Russian jail cell.
[man] Good work, Silver Sable.
My wild pack and I
are expensive
but we always get results.
Now I, too, have a job to do.
Leave me.
Who, who are you?
Ah, you desire to
face your captor?
Then I won't disappoint you.
Not you!
[hooded man snickering]
[anticipatory music]
[Peter voiceover] A beautiful
morning in downtown Moscow.
What did I hope
to find here anyway?
For all I know
my parents really were
traitors to America.
No, I can't even think
that for a second.
Huh?
Robbie, leaving early?
This is the second time
he's tried to lose me.
What's he up to?
Going somewhere?
Peter!
What's the big
idea Mr. Robinson?
Look, there are things
I have to do here
that could be dangerous.
Jameson will have my head.
I'm going with you whether
you like it or not.
[Boris] Robbie,
my old tovarich!
How are you being?
Just great, Boris.
Peter, this is My good friend
Detective Boris Pushkin.
[speaking Russian]
Uh, how do you two
know one another?
I used to work for a wire
service here years ago.
Yes, friend Robbie
saved my life once.
Boris, there's no
time to reminisce.
I need that information
about Groitzig.
Can you believe it?
That German scientist had
been living right here
in the city under an assumed
name since World War II.
How exactly did you find out?
Groitzig's daughter came
to us after the kidnapping,
hysterical.
Since his retirement from
the telephone ministry
Groitzig had been living with
his daughter and her husband.
My old friend if you could
just give us her address.
It's important.
I'm afraid I cannot
do that, officially.
I understand.
Explain their presence
here immediately!
My name is Robertson--
I am the Chief of Police.
We know who you are.
Ah, Komisar Kragov.
I was simply telling them
how our new democracy
results in less crime
than in America, and--
This democracy is
hard enough to swallow
without licking the feet
of Western journalists.
Get them out of
here immediately!
Out! Out!
American dogs!
And, good luck, my friends.
[suspenseful music playing]
Who, who are you?
[man] Illyena, close the door!
No! We're here to help
find your father.
I'm Joe Robertson,
a journalist from New York.
I'm Peter Parker,
a photographer.
Parker?
Did you say Parker?
-Yes.
-Come in, quickly.
Are you related to
Richard and Mary Parker?
How do you know
about my parents?
The last time I saw them,
they stood where you stand now.
That was 20 years ago.
You must take us to
America with you.
[Richard] Wolfgang,
the KGB are onto us.
They found out that we've
only been posing as traitors.
We're really loyal
to our country.
[Mary] We barely got back
here in time to warn you.
We'll never get out
of Moscow alive.
You must make it out.
The rest must be told.
The Red Skull forced me to
create the doomsday device.
This weapon is still there,
in New York City
after all these years
and it's more
dangerous than ever.
[Richard] Wolfgang, this box
contains all the information
we've discovered about
the doomsday weapon.
It's up to you to get this
back to the free world.
If you can.
I... I will try.
[Mary] We have a little boy
a little younger than you.
We love him so much.
If anything
should happen to us.
My father knew the KGB was
behind their plane crash.
Now, my father
has been kidnapped
by someone who's after
this doomsday weapon.
Is there anything
else your father said
that might help us?
Yes, the six warriors.
He just kept repeating,
"I must find the six warriors."
Illyena, have you ever
seen this symbol before?
Da! Da!
There is something
that I must show you.
My father wanted to get
this to your countrymen.
It was what your
parents gave him.
Hopefully, this will lead
you to the answers you seek.
I'll take that,
my darling wife.
Karl!
I don't understand.
Kid, be careful!
[engine starting]
[tires screeching]
[Peter voiceover]
I can't let that creep
get away
with the only proof
that can clear my parents.
-[beeps horn]
-[man laughing]
Looks like I got what
I came for eh, comrade?
[muffled grunting]
[Spider-Man] The chameleon?
Here?
[gunshots banging]
Uh-oh.
[explosion booms]
Close one.
Well, score another clean
escape for the chameleon.
No, there he goes!
Hold on a minute.
Why didn't he morph into
someone else to hide himself?
He's trying to lead me
into a trap, that's why.
Well, I'm not gonna
fall for it this time.
I'm staying up high
until I scope things out.
What is this place?
It looks like some kind of city
maintenance yard and warehouse.
Uh-oh.
Welcome to Russia, Spider-Man.
I'm gonna blast
you from Red Square
back to Times Square.
[Spider-Man grunting]
Is there no place on Earth
where I can be rid of
your meddlesome presence?
Doc Oct?
Shocker, Vulture!
Here in Russia?
Did you guys come over
on separate flights
or did you get one of those
super-villain package deals?
[dramatic music playing]
[Spider-Man grunting]
I always wanted to send you
and your big mouth to Siberia.
Yeah, only now it ain't so far.
Now let's play Russian
roulette for real Spider-Man.
I say we play
Russian ice hockey
and we use Spider-Man
as the puck!
No!
The kingpin will
reward us handsomely
for bringing Spider-Man
to him alive.
[Kingpin] Welcome to my
temporary base of operations,
-Spider-Man.
-[Spider-Man groaning]
I must say, this is
an unexpected treat.
If I were you Kingpin
I'd cut down on the treats.
Joke while you can, Spider-Man.
Soon, I will be
far more powerful
than even I dared to dream.
You hatch a different crackpot
scheme every week, Fisk.
What makes this one so special?
There is no reason
not to tell you
as your annoying antics
will shortly end.
For many years in
the spy underworld
there was a rumor of
a doomsday device,
A device left by German
spies in New York City
at the end of World War II.
I thought this was a fairy tale
but with the reappearance
of Wolfgang Groitzig
I realized that the
stories could be true
and the weapon might
still be intact.
The device had been created
by a German master-spy.
Who called himself
The Red Skull.
He planned to use it
to take over the world.
I now intend to do the same.
World domination?
Kingpin, now you sound
like a Saturday morning
cartoon villain.
I assure you,
my victory will be real.
Ironic, isn't it?
If not for your photographer
friend, Peter Parker
Groitzig's daughter
might never have revealed
the existence of this.
The first real clue
I have found
to the doomsday device's
location and operation.
[Peter voiceover] Great.
I've handed the
most powerful weapon
in the world to the Kingpin.
How could things
possibly get any worse?
And now, let us see who
you are behind that mask.
Huh?
[dramatic music playing]
-[coughing]
-[Shocker] What's going on?
[all coughing]
I've been betrayed.
By someone.
[Spider-Man coughing]
[Silver Sable]
The sleeping gas has worked.
Wild pack, initiate our
plan for garbage removal.
Oh, my aching head.
Now where am I?
One thing's for sure,
I've got to start
hanging around
with a better class of people.
[Silver Sable] Hmm,
the arachnid one awakens.
Do I know you?
I'm called Silver Sable.
The paid mercenary?
Tell me, how did you
infiltrate my headquarters?
Simple.
One of your men is a traitor.
What?
Working with us
and against you.
Which one?
Sorry, trade secret.
Besides, that's what you get
for conspiring with petty,
low-life criminals.
Eh, watch who you're
calling petty?
I'm not one of them.
Why am I all trussed up?
Your reputation is no better.
Oh, and I suppose
yours is spotless?
I am not a criminal.
I'm merely a
professional for hire.
Which means you just work
for whichever creep
pays the most.
I think I prefer
these guys over here.
Their dishonesty
is more honest.
I have my reasons
for doing what I do.
And you've done
well, Silver Sable.
The infamous Kingpin.
Such a waste.
You could have been useful
to me in my new world order.
The doomsday device
is my birthright!
For trying to take it,
you must all be eliminated.
I think not.
[grunting]
Sable!
I would not do
that if I were you.
Drop your weapons.
Release my men now.
Do it.
Now this is more like it.
Now, if you all don't mind.
[Kingpin]
Turnabout is fair play.
And before I was
rudely interrupted
I was about to unmask someone.
I might as well begin again,
with you.
The Red Skull?
Huh?
The German war criminal?
After all these years?
This cannot be.
Just as I suspected.
Nothing but a pitiful
pretender.
The true Red Skull would have
had the power to break free.
Komisar Kragov.
The Chief of Police.
Why are you doing this?
Because Kragov is
only my assumed name.
I am really the son
of The Red Skull
who will bring his
father's dreams
of world domination
to fruition.
Now there's a nice
family business for ya.
The world shall be dominated,
but by me.
[Kingpin yelling]
Uh-oh.
Give up.
The odds do not favor you.
I've been beating...
worse odds all my life.
[Kingpin yelling]
That must have triggered
the release circuit
on my shackles.
Spider-Man free?
Get him!
I've got to get that box.
[both grunting]
[dramatic music playing]
Hey.
[growling]
At last!
Fine, have your precious box.
It will do you no good
where you are going.
[alarm ringing]
Within seconds
this entire complex
will be reduced to rubble.
and you with it.
Help us!
They just don't build these
fortresses like they used to.
Evacuate immediately.
[Spider-Man grunting]
[Kingpin]
Head for that stairway!
Somebody help us.
[Spider-Man grunting]
[Spider-Man groaning]
Kingpin managed to keep his
fat fingers on Groitzig's box.
No matter.
I have all I need
to insure my control
Of the doomsday device,
don't I, my comrades?
Soon the world will
once again tremble
beneath the iron fist
of The Red Skull.
This way, hurry!
[Dr. Octopus laughing]
[Spider-Man] Hurry!
My webbing can't
hold it forever.
Move it.
Now that's what I
call an e-ticket ride.
Oh?
And it isn't over yet.
Wild pack, defense frame.
These guys don't
talk much big guy,
but something tells me
they're gonna give you
one heck of a fight.
Fighting is a waste of time.
Look around you.
Hey, this place
does look familiar.
Good heavens.
I've seen photos of it.
It's Chernobyl.
The nuclear reactor
that went into meltdown?
What a clever hideout.
No doubt we were
shielded from radiation
while we were underground.
Well we ain't shielded now.
So what?
You fool.
If we do not leave here we
will be poisoned by radiation.
My employer kept aircraft
in those hangars.
Then it is time
to take our leave.
Vulture!
Unbelievable.
My men and I thank you
for saving our lives.
Why do you do it?
Why do you work for
slime like Kragov?
-You judge me harshly.
-Well.
Maybe someday you'll find out
that I'm more than I seem.
Come, we must also be off
before the radiation
poisons us as well.
No kidding.
One dose of radiation
a lifetime is enough.
[Peter voiceover] Now there are
two madmen racing to control
the most dangerous
weapon ever created.
I still don't even know what
this doomsday device is.
For all I know,
it was television
and it was released in 1945.
Peter, there are a few
more pieces of the puzzle
I'd like to share with you,
but you'd best
hear it from someone
else when we get home.
He was a teacher of mine
when I was in college.
Professor Omar Mosley.
He knows the story of,
the six forgotten warriors.
[Peter voiceover]
Why do those words
send a chill down my spine?
[Mr. Jameson] I can't believe
what I'm hearing.
I spent all that money
to send you to Russia
and you come back with nothing?
Parker, this is the last straw.
I'd fire you if you
weren't a free-lancer.
From now on, you'll make no
money off of this newspaper
unless you have
the photo of the century.
You hear me?
Loud and clear, Mr. Jameson.
[Peter voiceover]
I'm sorry, J.J.
But on this trip I had
something more important
to worry about
than your newspaper
and I think I did
the job I had to.
[Aunt May] And so that's it?
After all these years
we finally have an answer?
Yes, Aunt May, my parents
were never traitors,
Never Russian spies.
They were loyal to this
country and died as heroes.
Oh, Peter, I feel
like a great weight
has been lifted off me.
Off us both.
I'm so glad you
found out the truth.
From the bottom of my heart,
I thank you.
Now all that remains is
for the world to find out.
I'll do everything in
my power to make that happen.
And so will Spider-Man.
[theme music playing]
♪ Spider-Man ♪
♪ Radioactive Spider-Man ♪
♪ Spider blood ♪
♪ Radioactive spider blood ♪
♪ Spider blood, spider blood ♪
♪ Spider-Man ♪