[theme music playing]
♪ Spider-man, Spider-man ♪
♪ Radioactive Spider-man ♪
♪ Spider blood, spider blood ♪
♪ Radioactive spider blood ♪
♪ Spider-man, Spider-man ♪
You know, Parker,
you're unpredictable.
This is not the direction
I want us to go.
But I thought
you lived this way.
[Felicia] No, I mean
direction in life, Parker.
I don't want us
to start dating.
[Peter] Well what's
wrong with us dating?
We study together all the time.
That's different.
That's because I need
your help in science.
You're the only man I know
who can remember
everything about protons
and neutrons and alpha
rays and gamma rays.
I guess I simply glow on
the subject of radiation.
I don't know why, it
must be in my blood.
Precisely.
You're a natural student.
But dinner with
you would be a date
and dates are for boyfriends.
Please don't be
offended, Parker.
But, Felicia, why can't you
think of me as a boyfriend?
[Peter thinking]
Spider sense, danger.
I have enough men asking me out
but a good tutor,
that's hard to find.
Parker?
Peter?
He walked away from me.
Who does he think he is?
[Peter] After being rejected
all evening by Felicia,
it sure pulls through
the old spirits
to finally get into
a little action.
Now, who is that little creep?
Some mugger after my money?
Heck, if I could find any
on me, I'd split it with him.
Well it shouldn't be too
hard to keep him in sight.
-[exploding]
-Whoa!
I should have
stuck with Felicia!
[web whipping]
[mimicking kissing]
Web fluid, I love you.
If those explosions
were accidental,
then I'm the Human Torch.
Aha, just as I thought.
They don't look like they're
headed for night school.
It's not nice to rob
jewelry stores in
Mr. Spider-man's neighborhood.
Can you say,
"I'm going to jail"?
[robber] He has the jewelry.
Who cares?
Let's get out of here!
[Peter] Well if
it isn't a meeting
of the diamond
lovers of America.
[robber] It's Spider-man!
[Peter] What?
Spider-Man?
Where, where?
Oh, I just get so flustered
when I meet a celebrity.
I just don't know what to say.
How about you just say goodbye?
[Peter] I'm way ahead of you.
[robber] Stay still, will you?
[Peter] Actually no.
[shouting]
[robber] Get him!
It's three against one!
[Peter]
As far as I'm concerned,
that means you're outnumbered.
Good thing I remembered to
set this up ahead of time.
I hate to use so much
expensive webbing
on yo-yo's like them.
Too bad that
little troll got away.
I wonder who he was.
Peter, these photos
are terrific.
In all my years as editor,
I've never known a photographer
as resourceful as you.
Oh thanks, Mr. Robertson.
I don't know how
you get these shots.
Me neither.
You're always in
just the right place
at just the right time.
Tell me, Parker.
What's your secret?
A good telephoto lens
and a lot of luck I guess.
That so?
Sure there isn't something else
that you wanna tell us?
Well, I'd like to get my
paycheck today,
if you don't mind.
Parker, you really tick me off.
I'll find out how
a young squirt like you
gets those photos
sooner or later.
Better make it later.
Bye!
[Peter thinking] He's got no
use for me,
he hates Spider-man.
I'll bet he can't
even stand himself.
Although
that would make sense.
[elevator bell dings]
Well what do you know?
The little creep.
Sorry, he almost
spotted me last night.
I just ain't had any breaks
tailing that Parker kid.
Gargan, you're worthless.
Ah gee, Mr. Jameson,
don't call me names.
People have been making
fun of me all my life.
Yeah.
I can see why.
Parker must know Spider-man.
That has to be how
he gets those photos.
How hard could it
be to follow him
to Spider-man's hideout?
So that's what
old fuzz head is up to.
Is this a private party or
can any wall crawler join?
Hey, what do you
think you're doing?
I got a message
for your pal, Parker.
Tell him if I catch him
following me again,
snapping his little pictures,
I'm gonna do this to him
and that's if I'm in
a good mood.
As for you, prune face,
get off my case, you hear?
[male]
I'm warning you, Jameson.
Get off my case, or else.
[gun firing]
[Peter] Mr. Jameson.
Huh?
Yeah, I hear you.
Wonderful.
Til next time, kiddies.
That ought to throw
flat top off the trail.
It won't happen again.
That spider freak making
me look ridiculous.
People are always trying
to make me look ridiculous.
You are ridiculous, Gargan.
But how would you like
to get back at him
and make a real
name for yourself?
Me, get back at Spider-man?
I'd kill for the chance.
Then you're on.
I've one trick up my sleeve
that will get that
wall crawling wimp
out of my hair forever.
Give me the genetics lab
at Empire State University.
I wanna talk to
Professor Stillwell.
[Farley] I made all
the preparations.
So this is
the neogenic recombinator.
Yes.
And this is the battle suit.
Beautiful, isn't it?
It ought to be considering
what I paid for it.
All right, let's get going.
[whirring]
Doc, what are you doing to me?
I feel strange.
Easy, it's the radiation.
Radiation?
Ain't that stuff dangerous?
Not for someone with your
limited intelligence.
Gargan, this is what
you said you wanted.
Don't chicken out on me now.
I ain't no chicken,
Mr. Jameson.
I just gotta know
what's going on.
Stop, stop!
Stillwell, what's
wrong with him?
He'll be OK.
The neogenic recombinator is
restructuring Gargan's DNA
to match the genetic
code of a scorpion.
I chose to use a scorpion
because it's a natural predator
of the spider, see?
It's working.
[whirring]
Spider-man will at
last meet his match.
[growling]
This is J3 Bravo.
I got a spider sighting.
Heading due south.
I copy that, J3 Bravo.
We finally found him,
Mr. Jameson.
Oh, man, I've got three
science papers due Friday,
I have to study all
night for a big exam
and I'm still batting
zero with Felicia.
[Jameson] Get ready, Scorpion.
I hear you.
If I didn't have web
swinging to help me relax,
I'd be wound up tighter than--
Now what?
Who the heck are you?
A real hero, you freak!
This is a joke, right?
Whoa! This is not a joke.
If you wanna join
the Fantastic Four,
you're in the wrong place.
Highly corrosive acid.
Why do I get the feeling
he's not into male bonding?
Where'd he go?
Look, I'm stronger
and faster than you.
[laughing]
[shouting]
Gotta get this creep
away from these busy streets
before some innocent
bystander gets hurt.
Hey, pal, let's go talk
this over some place
where it's just you and me.
[laughing]
That's it, Gargan!
Don't let up, get him!
Who's doing this fight,
me or you?
[Peter] Who are you talking to?
Wouldn't you like to know?
[laughing]
[shouting]
[man] Oh, my God!
You're dead meat, little man!
[grunting]
Go, go! Get him!
No, you're doing it all wrong!
Did you expect your
crummy webs to stop me?
The thought
had crossed my mind.
[yelling]
Yes!
Good move!
Excellent!
[laughing]
-[screaming]
-[man] Look out!
[Peter groaning]
[laughing]
How about that?
I beat Spider-man!
Taken out by the one,
the only, Scorpion!
Quit stalling, Gargan!
Unmask him!
What's happening to me?
No, no!
What are you waiting for?
Unmask him now?
I've become a freak, a monster!
Lower me down.
I'll unmask him myself.
[Scorpion] You tricked me!
You never said
this would happen.
[Jameson] What are you doing?
What do you think?
Getting as much distance from
that lunatic as possible.
No, go down, go down!
I am, when I get back to base.
Fire me if you want to but I
have a family to think about.
[sirens blaring]
Jonah, check the main feed.
Oh, no.
[yelling]
What have I done?
You?
What do you mean?
Robbie, I helped
create that thing.
You what? Why would
you do such a thing?
I did it for Julia, my wife.
Years ago, a crime
boss wanted me
to back off a story
but I refused.
One night,
a man came after me.
A man in a mask.
He aimed at me,
but he hit her.
Now I've sworn to
keep this city safe
from people who
hide behind masks
and think that
they're above the law.
That's exactly what
your creation is doing.
You've got to stop him.
You're right, Robbie.
I made a horrible mistake.
Every bone in
my body is killing me.
I'd love to rest
up but I've gotta find that
green goon before
he levels all of Manhattan.
Stillwell, do something!
Gargan's going berserk!
I know.
The genetic realignment is
making him mentally unstable.
Professor Connors was right.
Neogenics is too experimental,
too dangerous
to use on a human being.
[crumbling]
Stillwell, fix me!
Make me like I was!
I can't.
The process is
regenerating exponentially
like a nuclear chain reaction.
It's too far out of control.
Not again.
[groaning]
You lying...
[crashing]
You, this is your fault!
You want me to stay this way
so I can destroy Spider-man!
Ah, Gargan, what are you doing?
I'm gonna let you
live just long enough
to find out.
[Officer] Can we get
a shot at him?
[Officer 2] Negative,
he's got a hostage.
Stay back!
No, really, Aunt May.
Everything's OK.
I just won't be home for lunch.
But, Peter, I've invited
Anna Watson's niece, Mary Jane.
Oh, right.
I'm sorry, I forgot.
I can't make it home right now.
The traffic, it's terrible.
In fact, it's really crawling.
Look, Aunt May,
I've really gotta go.
All right dear, but don't
stay out too late.
You sound like you're
catching a bug.
[Peter] I certainly hope so.
What?
Nothing, Aunt May.
I'll be careful. Bye.
Did I just see Joe Jameson
with the Scorpion
or should I start
wearing glasses again?
That's the Oscorp
nuclear reactor.
Why are you heading there?
'Cause radiation
made me this way
and I'm gonna use
it to change me back
into who I was.
I'll punch a hole inside,
get at the radiation.
I think it's in the
middle somewhere.
[growling]
Gargan, you're insane!
You'll unleash radiation
on the whole city!
Not my problem, pal.
And quit calling me names.
Green ball
in the center pocket.
I'd ask what you're
doing here, Jameson,
but something tells
me I don't wanna know.
A nuclear reactor?
Why don't villains ever
pick bakeries to invade?
[screaming]
[cracking]
[alarm blaring]
Uh-oh.
What's that alarm?
Scorpion just activated
the neutron absorbing
control rods
behind that door.
Now they're automatically
being removed
from the nuclear chamber.
They control the rate of
the chain reaction
inside the reactor.
Without them,
the nuclear fission
in the chamber increases.
If we don't get them
back in, then the heat
will make that thing blow
and we'll all turn into
walking night lights.
How can we stop it?
[Peter] The console,
the red button.
I'll bet my web shooter
that's the emergency shutdown.
Trust me, it's always
the red button.
What do you know
about stuff like this?
Hey, who do I look like?
The Tick?
[slamming]
Gotta get to the core.
[groaning]
[Peter] Hold it, Scorpy.
You don't realize
what you're doing.
Oh yeah?
I'm doing this!
[beeping]
What were you up to?
You heard the man.
I've got to hit that red button
or the reactor will melt down
and the city will be
destroyed by radiation.
Who cares?
Long as I get what I'm after.
[screaming]
Look, if we continue
to meet like this,
tongues will begin to wag.
[shouting]
[slamming]
What are you made of,
adamantium?
I'm gonna crush you now.
Oh yeah?
It just so happens I
like to start each day
with a warm hug.
Who am I kidding?
Everything's going black.
-[striking]
-[groaning]
You gotta be nuts, mister.
Why would you risk
your puny life
to save his?
Because you're a greater evil
and heaven help me,
he's the only one
who can stop you.
Huh, did I hear right?
J. Jonah Jameson's on my side?
He can't stop me if
I squash him first!
Scorpion! You're nothing
but a worm, an insect,
a silly sap.
I told you before.
Don't call me names!
Now this gives me an idea.
So you don't like names, huh?
Well that's too bad, frog face,
'cause to me, you're
nothing but a two bit,
no account, second rate,
sewer breathed baboon
with the brain of a pigeon
and the face of an eel!
Stop it!
[zapping]
[whirring]
Jameson, get down!
[groaning]
Oh, my aching head.
[Peter] Hey buster,
I'm hurting more than you.
I'm suffering from
double vision.
Get it, double vision?
I knew I never
should've left Brooklyn.
[Peter] Oh never mind.
Thanks, JJ, for backing me up.
I guess things
will be different
between us now, huh?
No way.
This doesn't change
a thing between us.
I still won't rest until
you've been unmasked
and eliminated.
Fair enough, pickle puss.
And I won't rest until you
shave that stupid mustache
so we're even.
Oh, and fuzz head.
Thanks for saving my life.
[groaning]
Jameson saving me
is like Moriarty
saving Sherlock Holmes.
Life sure is full of surprises.
Well, Stillwell's
in the hospital.
Scorpion's in jail.
Old Jonah's probably
writing a nasty editorial
against Spider-man.
[tires squealing]
Well, at least things ought
to be quiet for a while.
Hey!
Parker, I've been
looking all over for you.
You know, you really made
me angry the other night,
-walking away like that, but--
-But?
I guess you were
trying to tell me
that sometimes I'm
a little difficult.
I can deal with that.
You know, Parker,
you're unpredictable.
I find that interesting.
No kidding.
Does this mean we can
have dinner together?
No, maybe lunch. Ciao.
Maybe lunch?
I think she's
starting to like me.
Yep, life's definitely
full of surprises.
[theme music playing]
♪ Spider-man Spider-man ♪
♪ Radioactive Spider-man ♪
♪ Spider blood spider blood ♪
♪ Radioactive spider blood ♪
♪ Spider-man ♪