[upbeat rock music]
♪ Spider-Man ♪
♪ Radioactive Spider-Man ♪
♪ Spider blood
Spider blood ♪
♪ Radioactive spider blood ♪
♪ Spider blood
Spider blood ♪
♪ Radioactive spider blood ♪
[explosions booming]
[growling]
♪ Spider-Man ♪
[dramatic music]
[gust of wind]
What do you mean
you want to end
our relationship?
Just what I said.
I don't have time
for your games anymore.
'Cause right now, I have
everything I ever wanted.
Mary Jane loves me,
and I love her.
This big battle you say
you're training me for,
I'm not interested.
My life is complete.
Complete, is it?
Ha! Have it your way,
Spider-Man.
One day you will yearn
for the wisdom of Madame Web.
And that day will come soon
when the two-headed monster
rises from the Netherworld.
[welding torch sparking]
[Green Goblin]
Osborn, aren't you
finished yet?
[Norman]
Almost, be patient.
This inter-dimensional spot
technology's extremely
delicate.
Miniaturizing
the device to this size,
I can't guarantee
its stability!
[moaning]
[cackling as Green Goblin]
Spare me your warnings, Osborn.
Turn it on!
With this technology
in my hands,
I'll make your enemies topple
like toy soldiers!
Even Spider-Man
and the mighty Kingpin
will be dirt under your feet!
[As Norman]
But what about Spider-Man?
He knows
about our connection.
[As Green Goblin]
Indeed, Spider-Man is
the only man on Earth who knows
that the Green Goblin
and Norman Osborn are allies.
[glider engine starting]
That knowledge
will cost him dearly!
[glider engine roaring]
[explosion]
-[guards screaming]
-[tires screeching]
[maniacal laughter]
There wasn't much fight
in those two.
You just can't find
good help nowadays.
He's certainly taking
his own sweet time.
Usually a couple
of explosions like that and--
-[bang]
-Ahh!
Finally.
You?!
I thought you were--
I'm not.
But you'll soon be!
[laughter]
You can run, Osborn,
but you can't hide.
Not when I know your address.
[dramatic music]
[thinking]
No sign of the Goblin here.
Or here at Osborn's mansion.
But, somehow, I don't think
this is the end of it.
Just call me Mr. Psychic.
-[spider-sense tingling]
-Whoa!
What was that?!
No sign of anything.
-[spider-sense tingling]
-My spider-sense, again!
[warping sound]
Still nothing.
There's something wrong
with my spider-sense.
Well, busted
Spidey-sense or not,
I promised to meet
Mary Jane at The Coffee Bean.
And, since there's
no sign of the Goblin...
[spider-sense tingling]
There it is again!
Hope this isn't my mutation
disease returning.
I don't think
I could deal with that.
Yes, yes!
Take off your mask
and reveal your secret identity
to your greatest enemy.
[maniacal laughter]
At last, Spider-Man's
greatest secret
-is mine!
-[spider-sense tingling]
What?! The Green Goblin's
greatest foe, a mere boy?!
Impossible!
[moaning]
Wait!
That's Peter Parker,
the friend of my son, Harry!
[laughs maniacally]
Shut up, Osborn!
I'm trying to think.
He must have been
using Harry to...
get to you!
Well, two can play
at that game, Peter Parker.
And the Goblin plays for keeps!
Hey, my spider-sense
stopped blaring.
Must've been
some kind of glitch!
Mary Jane, I never thought
you and Peter would
ever get together.
Me neither, Liz.
Hm, so how's
Harry Osborn handling
you not being
his girlfriend anymore?
Mm, not well.
He doesn't realize I wasn't
happy in our relationship.
He thinks Peter betrayed him.
Oh, poor Harry.
You know,
he's a real sweetheart.
I kinda feel sorry for him.
Sorry for who, Liz?
Sorry for any girl
who has to put up with you
being late all the time, Pedro!
I'll get you your usual.
Am I that late?
Yes, but that's
right on time for you!
It's one of
your little idiosyncrasies
I've come to love.
Ooh, you used the L-word.
I like that!
So, Liz was talking
about Harry Osborn?
Uh-huh.
His birthday party's
tonight, remember?
Tonight?
I completely forgot.
Maybe we shouldn't go.
We have to go!
Harry's made a point
of inviting both of us.
His father's throwing
a big dinner party.
Norman Osborn
is throwing a party?
Is he back to normal?
This is perfect!
I can observe Osborn
without him knowing
that Spider-Man is watching.
Now, remember, Peter.
Try to be sensitive
to Harry's feelings.
This might be tough for him.
[door bell rings]
[Debra]
Oh, look who's here.
Whoa!
I didn't think
you'd show up here, Parker.
Score one for bad taste.
[Debra] Flash!
[Mary Jane]
Happy birthday, Harry.
It was nice of you
to invite MJ and me,
considering everything.
Look, friend.
I only invited you
because my dad insisted.
He told me to show
a little backbone.
Come on, Harry!
Don't be like that!
His dad insisted?
[Norman]
Ah, Peter Parker's here!
Now the party can really begin!
I'm so glad you could make it.
Put 'er there.
Osborn's never been
this friendly to me before.
His grip,
it's getting tighter!
He'd break my hand
if not for my spider-strength.
[Norman]
Oh, I'm sorry, Peter.
Was I squeezing too tightly?
I forgot how delicate you are.
Dinner is ready to be served!
I hope you enjoy the stew.
It's almost as if
he knows I'm Spider-Man.
-[dramatic music]
-But how could he?
I understand you're seeing
Mary Jane now, Peter.
I'll bet you two
have been conspiring
to get together for some time.
Uh, Mr. Osborn,
you've got it all wrong.
You know,
I saw another one
of your spectacular
Spider-Man photos in the Bugle.
How do you get
those fantastic angles?
Mr. Osborn,
Peter never gives out
his treasured trade secrets.
Not even to me!
You know, Harry,
your friend and I
share a little secret.
Don't we, Pete?
Tiger, what is
he talking about?
I-- I wish I knew!
Maybe we should let
your friends in on our secret.
Over dessert, perhaps?
He does know I'm Spider-Man!
But how?!
Uh, will you excuse me
for a moment?
Make sure
it's only a moment, Pete!
The party's just begun.
I've gotta do something
before Osborn flips out
and reveals my identity.
I need a little diversion.
I've got it!
Maybe if I heat up
the chemicals
in my web cartridges,
that might do the trick!
Sorry, I, uh...
I felt a little ill
for a moment.
Only a little?
So, just what was this secret
you were talking about,
Mr. Osborn?
Peter, I think it's time
we shared our little secret.
-[explosion]
-[Debra] It's a fire!
[Peter]
Outside, quickly!
[man] Fire!
Party's over, but
I still owe Osborn a dance!
Peter, where are you going?!
Mr. Osborn's still in there!
I've gotta save him!
No! You can't!
Dad!
-[spider-sense tingling]
-Parker!
you've been a thorn
in my side for too long!
You pestered me as Spider-Man!
[moaning]
[as Norman]
You hurt my son
as Peter Parker.
[moaning]
[maniacal laughter]
Well, it all ends tonight!
[glider whooshing]
I don't have
my web-shooters on!
Problems, Parker?
-Uh-oh!
-[explosions]
It's a good thing nobody can
see us here in the backyard.
I guess clothes
really do make the man!
[groaning]
It's some kind
of super hard metal.
I can't break it!
And away
we go!
-[maniacal laughter]
-[intense dramatic music]
[Peter]
Madame Web was right.
The monster with two heads,
two identities, has struck!
I've never been
so vulnerable before!
Awake down there?
As befits an adversary
of your caliber,
I'm granting you
a demise with dignity!
Just keep talking, Osborn.
I need the time!
You'll have
a burial at sea, Parker!
Isn't that charming?
[Peter] Gotta get
to my web-shooter!
Did it!
Norman would be so proud of me.
He'll never believe
how easy this was!
Believe this!
Huh?!
If this is going to work,
I can't be a millimeter off!
What?!
No!
Now let's try this
little tango again, shall we?
-[dramatic music]
-[Green Goblin groans]
I underestimated him.
Time for Plan B.
The Time Dilation Accelerator!
He must've miniaturized it!
[warping sound]
I'll bet he used it
to spy on me
to find out I'm Spider-Man!
You know, Parker,
I don't think
I've made you suffer enough!
You've been a guest at my home,
and now it's high time
I visited yours!
No!
He's going after Aunt May!
With Ohn's technology,
that psychopath can be in
Forest Hills in micro-seconds!
I'll never reach
Aunt May in time!
[Mary Jane]
So, when the firemen came out,
they said all they found
was something strange
smoldering in the fireplace.
And Mr. Osborn?
We figured Peter
took him to a doctor.
But why wouldn't he call?
Oh, that's Peter Parker
all over!
Thoughtless and irresponsible!
Ah, if I didn't like May Parker
as much as I do--
You're wrong about Peter,
Aunt Anna!
He's wonderful.
I love him!
Aunt May!
If he's hurt her...
[intense dramatic music]
No spider-sense.
Does that mean
he's already been here
and gone?
She's okay.
I thought for sure--
[spider-sense tingling]
Shh!
She's sleeping so peacefully,
I couldn't disturb her.
I think I'd rather pay a visit
to your other co-conspirator!
[evil chuckle]
Nighty-night, Parker!
What is it?!
Who's there?!
It's just me, Aunt May.
I thought I'd
better check on you.
Oh, Peter.
Thank heavens!
I must've been
having a nightmare.
Did you have fun
at Harry's party?
Well, the party's
still going on.
Oh, how nice for Harry.
Good night, dear.
Sweet dreams, Aunt May.
Another of my co-conspirators?
Who could that nutcase mean?
[Norman] I'll bet you two
have been conspiring
to get together for some time.
Mary Jane!
Osborn accused us of
conspiring to get together.
She's the Goblin's
next target!
I still say
you're asking for trouble
by dating
that strange young man.
Lady, you don't
know the half of it!
[Mary Jane
and Aunt Anna scream]
Run, Aunt Anna, run!
[coughing]
The Goblin's Knockout Gas!
She's okay, just stunned.
-But where's Mary Jane?
-[maniacal laughter]
Osborn!
[laughing]
No!
[dramatic music]
I know the Goblin's
luring me into a trap,
but I can't give up!
Not with MJ's life at stake!
[glider whooshing]
[Green Goblin] I held
the curtain for you,
Spider-Man!
I wouldn't want you
to miss the show!
Let her go, Osborn!
This is between you and me.
I'm not Osborn!
I am the Green Goblin!
Well, does Osborn know
that you are about to destroy
the only person
his son Harry cares about?
Harry?
[as Norman]
She hurt Harry
with you.
The two of you
plotted together.
No, you're wrong!
We're Harry's friends.
You attacked Harry
to get to me.
The Goblin told me so.
Oh, yes, the Goblin
takes care of me.
He makes life better for me.
He's the only one.
Nobody else loves me.
They all hate me!
Now, while he's Osborn!
I gotta make this count!
[as Green Goblin]
Quit whining, Osborn!
How can I make a man out
of you if you're going to--
-Osborn!
-What?!
[groaning]
[dramatic music]
[both grunting]
-[Green Goblin] Aah!
-[Spider-Man] Whoa!
[as Norman]
Help me! Please!
Pull me up, I'm falling!
-Ah, thank you.
-Osborn?
[laughs maniacally]
Not Osborn!
Goblin.
-[zapping]
-Goblin!
-[spider-Sense tingling]
-What now?!
Oh! Aah!
Mary Jane!
I've gotta get to her!
Fast!
[laughing]
[grunting]
[Mary Jane coughs]
Mary Jane!
Ahh!
Ah, no matter.
As long as I get
my portal device,
I'll be just fine.
No!
-It's okay, my love.
-[moaning]
Everything's going to be fine.
[engine starts]
[Mary Jane moaning]
Peter?
Is that you?
Spider-Man!
-What-- ?
-[clicking]
I thought I heard Peter.
[spider-sense tingling]
[Spider-Man] Look out!
[screaming]
Mary Jane!
[warping sound]
-[water splashing]
-No!
Where did she go?!
Mary Jane?!
Mary Jane!
[glider engine roaring]
[sing-song]
Where are you,
my little machine?
[intense dramatic music]
[deep breath]
I can't find her.
So help me, I can't find her!
[coughing]
Mary Jane!
[maniacal laughter]
What's wrong, Spider-Man?
No quick comebacks,
no clever one-liners?
You think this
is a game, Osborn?!
It's not!
That's the woman I loved,
and you're about
to learn what that means.
For the last time,
I'm the Green Goblin!
[buzzing]
The circuitry must be damaged.
No matter.
Fool!
My glider's almost out of fuel!
I'm taking you down, Goblin!
Even if it means I go with you!
No!
Osborn needs me!
Nothing can keep me
from you, Goblin!
This can!
[buzzing and crackling]
My precious machine!
I've got to make you work!
You'll pay, Osborn!
If I have to chase you forever,
you'll pay!
Not if I can help it!
Eureka!
Something's wrong!
[wind gusting]
[screaming]
No!
Not you!
Not now!
I can stick to the ground.
You can't!
[Spider-Man
He's created an imbalance
between the gravitational pull
of this dimension
and the vortex!
If it continues to increase...
[straining]
It's pulling me in!
I can't turn it off!
Sound like you've got
a problem!
Aaah!
[grunting]
Help! Help me!
[as Norman]
Oh! Where am I?!
What's going on?1
Spider-Man! Help me!
Why on Earth should I do that?
-Aah!
-No.
As much as I hate him
for what he's done,
I can't let this happen!
Revenge is never justified.
Nothing will bring
Mary Jane back.
Hang on, Osborn!
-I'm coming!
-Hurry!
I'm losing my grip!
Quick, take my hand!
I'm trying!
[groaning]
[laughs maniacally]
Osborn, take my hand!
It's your only chance!
There's no Osborn anymore,
Parker!
There is only the Green Goblin!
-[laughs maniacally]
-[spider-sense-tingles]
[grunts, screaming]
[electrical bolts zapping]
[panting]
It can't end like this!
[shouting] Madame Web!
Yes, Spider-Man?
Can you bring them back?
I'll do anything you want!
I can't.
Can't or won't?
This is the path
you chose for yourself,
to do things on your own.
Once that decision is made,
there is no turning back.
It is yet another thing
that you have to learn.
Learn?!
I am tired of you
and your riddles
and your lessons
and your supreme arrogance!
Don't you ever,
ever,
enter my life again!
Do you hear me?!
As you wish.
I shall leave you for now,
but you are
still the chosen one.
And, when the time comes
for the ultimate battle,
I will return
and send for you.
That
you cannot escape.
It is your destiny.
For so long now,
I've tried to be
there for everyone.
Tried to live up
to the responsibility
that comes
with this great power.
But when push came to shove,
I failed the people
who needed me most.
The woman I love is gone.
Gone. Forever.
Where am I? Peter?!
Somebody, please!
Help me!
Help meeee!
[upbeat rock music]
♪ Spider-Man, Spider-Man ♪
♪ Radioactive Spider-Man ♪
♪ Spider blood, spider blood ♪
♪ Radioactive spider blood ♪
♪ Spider blood ♪
♪ Spider-Man ♪