[upbeat
rock music]
♪ Spider-Man ♪
♪ Radioactive Spider-Man ♪
♪ Spider blood
Spider blood ♪
♪ Radioactive spider blood ♪
♪ Spider blood
Spider blood ♪
♪ Radioactive spider blood ♪
[explosions booming]
[growling]
♪ Spider-Man ♪
[Felicia] What's wrong?
[Spider-Man]
I'm sorry, Felicia,
but this just isn't
going to work.
Spider-Man can't
have a girlfriend.
It'd be too dangerous,
for both of us.
I know.
Even so, I had to let
you know how I feel.
-[loud rumbling]
-[dramatic music]
[man] What's that?!
Retrieval team, on your mark,
T-minus five, four, three, two.
-[loud crash]
-Go!
Coordinate your movements
precisely according to plan.
[cutting torch crackling]
Ah, accurate timing
is a thing of beauty.
[loud rumbling]
[sirens wailing]
[Spider-Man] Felicia, I--
Duty calls?
I understand.
You should go.
Be careful, Spider-Man.
[lasers zapping]
[Spider-Man]
Hey, boys, what's your hurry?
[explosions boom]
- [loud rumbling]
- Uh-oh.
Move it, web head!
Move it!
[dramatic music playing]
[loud crash]
I thought I'd seen everything,
but this really takes the cake.
I'm sorry the manufacturer
raised the price
on that medicine, Robert.
If it helps Mama get better,
it's worth it.
Tell you what, I'll give
you this one at my cost.
Let your mother know
we're all pulling for her.
Thanks, Mr. Jackson.
We really appreciate that.
[door bell jingles]
Can you believe it?
That kid used to be
in trouble all the time,
then his mama got sick.
Now, he's really trying
to turn himself around.
Yes, ladies and gentlemen,
it's Robert "The Rocket" Farrell
slashing up the sidewalks.
Will the curb be a problem?
No way!
He's too stoked to be stopped.
Radical aerial!
The crowd goes wild!
Yeah!
He shreds the stairs
like a pro,
and then,
for the grand finale--
-[loud rumbling]
-Huh?
Unbelievable!
[Spider-Man] Uh-oh.
Gotcha.
Flying flakes!
[Spider-Man groans]
Whoa!
Felt the breeze on that one.
The cops can handle him.
-I've got
a bigger fish to catch.
-Oof!
[man] Ohh!
[Robert] Incredible!
-[siren wailing]
-[cop] Freeze, kid!
Long time no see, Farrell.
This time,
you're in real trouble.
[Spider-Man] Okay,
rocket runts, party's over!
Blast!
What a lousy time
to run out of webbing.
No extra cartridges.
No captured bad guys?
For this, I left Felicia?
[Felicia] You were right
to call, Mrs. Farrell.
I can't thank you enough
for coming with me, Miss Hardy.
I-- I just didn't know
who else to turn to.
Robert's one
of the brightest students
in the Hardy Foundation
science program.
I'm sure the police
have made a mistake.
There's something
I have to tell you.
Before he got involved
in your science classes,
Robert used to be
a very bad boy,
and if he's gone back
to his old ways, I just--
Shh, now, just take it easy.
Take it easy.
You know how being upset
affects your health.
[Mrs. Farrell] Oh, Robert.
Mama!
Baby, I was
so worried about you.
Miss Hardy kindly
posted your bail.
I tried to tell them
I didn't do anything,
but they think I'm a thief.
Maybe that's just what I ought
to do, then I'd show them.
No son of mine is going
to become a criminal.
It would destroy me, Robert.
Don't ever talk that way, son.
Don't even think that way.
[Peter] Too bad
those rocket raiders got away.
Ah, well.
It's nice to be able to
drown my frustrations
as a crime fighter in my work
as a science teacher.
It doesn't pay anything,
but sometimes, there's
more to life than money.
-Hi, Mr. Parker.
-Hey, sir.
-Good morning, Mr. Parker.
-How's it going?
Hey, guys,
it's great to see you, too.
Has Robert gotten
his gyro-coaster working yet?
Yeah. All you have to do
is switch it on.
[Peter, thinking]
Incredible.
When I told Robert to read up
on the latest theories
of gyroscopic stabilization,
I had no idea he'd assimilate
them so thoroughly.
I'll bet he knows more about
this subject now than I do.
I thought I saw our favorite
science tutor come in.
[Peter] Oh, hi, Felicia.
[Felicia] Parker?
-Is something wrong?
-Uh, oh, no, no.
Nothing's wrong.
Well, that is,
nothing that wouldn't be fixed
if you'd go out with me
tonight.
A date?
That's sweet, Parker,
but there is someone else
I'm seeing these days.
Thanks anyway, though.
You really are a good friend.
[thinking]
Friend? Unbelievable!
As long as she's
in love with Spider-Man,
that's all Peter Parker
will ever be.
Now I'm competing with myself.
Felicia, where's Robert today?
Uh, Peter, something happened
last night with Robert.
We'll talk after you teach
your class, and then--
[man]
Excuse me, my dear fellow.
I'm looking for Felicia Hardy.
You found her.
Miss Hardy.
We spoke on the phone.
My name is Phillips.
Jason Phillips?
Mr. Phillips.
How nice.
Uh, this is Peter Parker,
one of our tutors.
Mr. Phillips wants to donate
a lot of money to our center.
I promised to show him around.
Uh, yes, and perhaps
we can discuss
further matters
later over dinner?
How nice.
That sounds delightful.
I know that, Robert,
but I still think
you should keep up
with your science class.
We've been
through all that, Mama.
-You need my help
here a lot more.
-[door bell jingles]
[man]
She needs help all right,
the kind of help
we can give her.
See, lady, all kinds of things
can happen in this world.
[loud crashing]
-Get outta here!
-[man laughs]
-Whoa!
-Robert!
[man laughing]
[men cheering]
Why are you doing this to us?!
Why?!
We want you to pay us to
protect you, okay, store lady?
If you don't come up
with ten times this amount,
we might have to have
a neighborhood bonfire
and use your store as fuel.
Mama, you better go
lie down and rest.
Yes, I must.
Let me clean this mess up.
Thank you, Robert.
You're such a good boy.
[Peter] Hey, guy.
What happened here?
Nothing.
Just a small earthquake.
Miss Hardy told me what
happened to you last night.
Is there anything
I can do to help?
No.
We can fend for ourselves.
And I don't have time for
that science center anymore.
But I thought science was
an important part of your life.
What you don't realize, Dukes,
is that brothers like me
don't need science.
We've got to think more
about how to survive,
any way we can.
Now leave me alone.
I have work to do.
[thinking]
I seem to be striking out
all over these days.
He's making a big mistake
if he thinks education
isn't a key to survival.
There's got to be some way
I can make him
understand that.
But how?
[both groan]
Hey, watch where
you're going, punk.
-Uh, I'm s-- sorry.
-Now, beat it!
Raiders, I congratulate
you on our latest triumph.
Thanks to our precision
and timing,
Spider-Man was
hopelessly outmaneuvered,
and, as usual,
the police were useless.
A new ring?
-Yeah, like it?
-Interesting.
However, I recommend
you hold off
buying any more jewelry
with our earnings,
since our next target will
be the Diamond District,
and all your purchases
will be on the house.
[laughter]
The credo I live by
as a master thief
is the same one I believed in
when I was
an aeronautical engineer:
timing is everything.
Fortunately, I gave up
government work just in time
to use
this top secret technology
for more lucrative ventures.
-[laughter]
-Sounds like a good idea, boss.
Incredible.
Hope they won't miss
a few pieces of equipment.
[camera beeping]
Everyone wants me
to get back into science?
Cool.
I'm with that.
But this time,
it's going to pay.
[knock on door]
- Hi, Mama.
- Oh, Robert,
I am so glad to see you
working on your project again,
not going out into the streets
and getting yourself
into trouble.
Science is your real future.
No kidding.
Well, I'm gonna go lie down.
-Keep up the good work.
-Don't worry, Mama.
I will.
[rockets whooshing]
Great!
The gyros, the magnetic wheels,
and boot clamps,
they all really work!
I can cling to buildings
by magnetically attaching myself
to their infrastructures.
Yeah!
Desk Sergeant,
I have a silent alarm,
East Side Jewelry Shop.
[thinking] See, Mama,
I do know what I'm doing,
and this stuff is gonna make
all our problems go away.
-Oh, Robert.
-Mama.
No son of mine is going
to become a criminal.
It would destroy me, Robert.
Hey, wait a minute.
What am I thinking?
This is really whack, man.
It's wrong.
[siren wailing]
[cop] You take the back.
I'll cover the front.
No. I've got
to get out of here.
[reporter] We've just picked
up a crime in progress,
and we're here to bring
you all the action, live,
as a costumed crook is
making a dramatic escape
from the East Side
Jewelry Shop
on, get this,
a rocket-powered skateboard!
[Spider-Man] Another one
of those Rocket Raiders?
This time, I won't
let him get away.
I've got to lose
that nosy news chopper.
Uh-oh!
Get out of my face!
Help! I'm stuck!
[elevator starts]
Oh, no! Help me!
[reporter] An amazing drama
is coming to an incredible
conclusion at the Hotel
Excelsior construction site.
[Spider-Man, straining]
I can't stop it!
You've got to!
My boots
are magnetically sealed,
and I can't shut
down my power supply!
[Spider-Man]
There's only one chance.
[Robert] Don't leave me!
No!
[relieved sigh]
[female reporter]
Continuing our live coverage.
[Spider-Man] I never realized
this finger was so powerful.
[power supply buzzes]
[helicopter whirring]
[Robert] Back off!
What?
That costume, that material,
it's Robert! Oh!
[Spider-Man]
Hey, put the missiles down!
Haven't you had
enough for one night?!
I guess that's
his way of saying no.
Yeah!
There has been a flaw in my
meticulously worked-out plan.
Punch up the security video.
As I suspected.
That little weasel came in here
and stole our technology.
But why do I know that face?
Look! That's the twerp who was
caught with some of our loot.
Farrell, eh?
We've got to eliminate him
before the police
make him reveal where he got
his technology, my technology.
-[loud rumbling]
-[dramatic music]
[horns honking]
[Spider-Man]
He's fast, but he can't outrun
-my spider tracer.
-[bang]
[tracer beeping]
[truck horn blaring]
Whoa!
[loud crash]
Nice work, Spidey.
The new kid in town
just took you for a ride.
-[horns honking]
-[monitor beeping]
Wow.
What a night.
-Huh?!
-So you're the newest creep
to hit the Big Apple?
Spider-Man?
How'd you find me?
I left you sucking
diesel exhaust.
[Spider-Man]
A little bug told me.
But what's with breaking
into jewelry stores?
Wasn't getting arrested once
enough to teach you your lesson?
The lesson is to survive, man.
It's not an easy thing
down here.
I bet when you take
off that mask and go home,
you don't come
to this neighborhood.
See, I didn't steal anything,
but everyone thinks I did.
So what's the point of
playing by the rules, man?
-Tell me that, spider guy.
-[knocking]
-Robert? Are you there?
-[Spider-Man] Felicia Hardy?
Spider-Man.
What are you doing here?
It's Robert's mother,
she had a relapse.
When she saw Robert in costume
on TV, she recognized him.
No!
Where is she now?!
[Felicia]
She's at my house.
There's a doctor with her.
[Robert]
I've got to get there!
[Jackson, on loudspeaker]
That's the building.
Go in and get him.
[groans]
[both groaning]
[Spider-Man]
Get out of here!
I'll hold off
these rocket rejects!
[loud rumbling]
[Robert] It's that overgrown
Hula-Hoop again.
Ah!
Robert, get in!
[screeching]
[Jackson] I want my
technology back, skate punk!
[tires screeching]
[Felicia] It's gaining!
Aaah!
You can't outrun him!
I've got to keep you
out of this!
[Felicia] Robert!
[men groaning]
That big Ferris wheel thing
is trying to crush Robert!
Not if I can help it.
[lasers zapping]
Whew!
Finally lost him.
Huh?!
Time to remove the one gremlin
in my carefully timed
machinery.
[lasers zapping]
I've got you now,
you little gnat!
-[Robert] Thanks, man.
-[Spider-Man] Don't mention it.
[loud crash]
[electricity crackling]
Wait a minute.
That voltage cable could
be just what we need.
I'll bet the gyroscopes
he uses are electrically driven.
That's how they
can be precisely timed.
[Spider-Man] Good thinking.
One big jolt of electricity
might short-circuit
the stabilizers.
[Robert]
That could ruin the timing
and make the big wheel
roll out of control.
-[Spider-Man] It's worth a try.
-[Robert] I'll keep him busy.
[Spider-Man]
Robert, over here!
[electricity crackling]
Aah! My gyroscope!
The timing mechanisms,
they're ruined!
Aaah!
[Spider-Man] It worked!
Got to save that guy
before he gets hurt!
Aaah!
[Robert]
Well, how do you like that?
My smarts helped
to get us out of that one.
I guess it pays to know
science stuff after all,
and to use
what you know responsibly.
[thinking]
Looks like the big wheel
steered him in
the right direction after all.
Well, the police picked up
that Jackson Weele character,
and he's confessed
to everything.
I think they'll go
much easier on Robert
when he goes to trial.
That's wonderful,
but something even more
wonderful's going on in there.
I knew I was wrong, Mama,
but since everyone
thought I was a thief,
it just seemed like
the easiest way to help out
was to become one for real,
but I couldn't
go through with it.
I'm not a crook,
and I guess I really am
a scientist at heart.
Yes, and you're my son.
Oh, I am very proud of you.
You and I, hm, we're a team,
and we'll get
through everything together.
Okay, store lady, we're gonna
make an example out of you.
Time to light this place up.
[Spider-Man]
Did somebody say something
about making
an example of someone?
[Robert] Your gangbanging
days are over.
[groans]
Aaah!
Ohh!
Well, I always did want
to hang with the homeboys.
[orchestral music]
[Jason] I look forward to us
doing this again, soon.
Jason, I had
a wonderful time, but--
Felicia?
What's wrong?
Is there someone else?
No, I suppose not, not anymore.
Yes, let's have
dinner again, soon.
[Spider-Man] Looks like Felicia
has found a new friend.
Aw, well, I suppose
it's all for the best.
[blows kiss]
Sweet dreams, Felicia.
It's hard to let you go.
[upbeat rock music]
♪ Spider-Man, Spider-Man ♪
♪ Radioactive Spider-Man ♪
♪ Spider blood, spider blood ♪
♪ Radioactive spider blood ♪
♪ Spider blood ♪
♪ Spider-Man ♪