["Spider-Man Theme Song"
by Joe Perry playing]
♪ Spider-Man ♪
♪ Radioactive Spider-Man ♪
[guitar break]
♪ Spider blood ♪
♪ Radioactive spider blood ♪
[guitar break]
♪ Spider-Man ♪
[Spider-Man] Look at them
down there. I'll bet each one
has somebody close.
I feel so distant.
I have nobody,
except you, of course.
You're always here for me.
You're rock solid.
And best of all,
you laugh at all my jokes.
Bruce, you're a heck of a guy.
But I do wish I had someone
a little prettier to talk to,
like maybe Felicia Hardy.
[gentle jazz music]
You're a good dancer.
I love surprises.
What do you think of this one?
[Spider-Man]
Then there's Mary Jane Watson.
Tiger, you just took
the jackpot again.
Care to walk me to class?
[Peter] Sure.
[Spider-Man]
What am I thinking?
How can anybody commit to a guy
who sneaks off to
crawl on walls?
Hey!
Ow!
I'm losing my grip!
What was that?
I never slip.
[gasping]
Got it.
Oh, weird.
Must've been some
kind of glitch.
Oh, no.
It's happening again!
I'm losing my spider powers!
[Spider-Man screams]
I'm sticking again,
but it's too little too late!
[loud crash]
What's wrong with me?
International smuggling
revenues are up 14%,
theft up 43%.
Fellow crime lords, we are
having a most profitable year.
[men laugh]
So it would seem, for now.
But what about the future?
[Kingpin] The future?
[yelps]
[groans]
You dare do this to me?
Kingpin, you're losing
control of your territory,
and soon, that's going
to cost us all money!
The crime cartel is
losing respect for you.
-[grunts]
-[electricity crackles]
Losing respect, Silvermane?
Who dares defy me now?
Owl?
Maybe you, Hammerhead?
At this very moment,
I've begun an operation
which will exterminate that
wall-crawling vermin forever!
Spider-Man is finished!
[lasers buzz]
[device beeping]
[phone beeping]
Greetings from the Kingpin,
Chameleon.
In 15 minutes, a helicopter
will land in the main yard.
Warden Davis?
What are you doing in there?
-[belt beeps]
-Warden?
No! [stamemrs]
It can't be!
[Chameleon] Ah, but it is.
The Chameleon's loose!
Help!
[Chameleon] Mac Gargan,
this is your lucky day.
Quentin Beck, follow me.
Shocker?
Get a move on.
[Shocker] The Shocker is alive.
[explosion booms]
The Scorpion, too.
Alive and stinging.
And I can resume my
leading role of Mysterio.
Now, let's disappear.
[guard] Nobody here.
Come on.
[Scorpion]
Not bad, bubble head.
Not bad.
Impressive, but why
not try this instead?
It's called a key.
Is it dinner time already?
[Chameleon]
Doctor Octopus, I presume?
[explosion booms]
[siren wailing]
[guns firing]
[Kingpin] Welcome, Chameleon,
Mysterio, Rhino,
Scorpion, Shocker,
Doctor Octopus,
my insidious six.
Your insidious six?
Who are you?
Why have you brought us here?
[Kingpin] I am your new leader.
All of you are my
ultimate weapon.
I ain't nobody's
weapon but my own.
[Shocker] Watch your mouth.
Yeah,
that's the Kingpin talking.
The Kingpin?
No kidding.
-[Mysterio] Look!
-[Scorpion] Spider-Man?
-Here?
-Get him!
[loud crash]
Ooh.
What do you know?
All this time, Spider-Man
was really a robot.
Neanderthal, that wasn't
the real Spider-Man.
It was an obvious fake!
[doors clack]
So, you're the Kingpin, eh?
While I'm grateful
for the early release,
I have no time for
childish games.
This is no game, I assure you.
It is a demonstration of
what is going to happen
to the real Spider-Man.
First, we will draw him out
and then close in
around him like a noose.
Supposing I have
a plan of my own?
[Mysterio]
And I might have one, too.
Solo efforts, I presume?
[Mysterio] He who travels
fastest, travels alone.
Look where you all wound up
when you worked alone, prison.
Gentlemen, we need each other.
With your talents, together,
we're sure to
defeat Spider-Man.
But you must all
agree to follow me.
To the end of the Earth, boss.
A man like me could
learn from you, Kingpin.
[Mysterio] The plot
seems clever enough.
The climax ought
to be intriguing.
I'd kill for a chance
to work for the Kingpin.
Doctor Octopus?
I am no petty hireling.
I am a scientist.
I can provide you
with the finest laboratory
in the world
and with unlimited resources.
Spider-Man won't
know what hit him.
[Spider-Man]I seem
to have my powers back,
but now, I'm worried about
those six escaped creeps.
[sighs] Can't find a trace
of them anywhere.
No bank robberies,
no jewel thefts...
not even any fresh graffiti.
They must be up to something.
I've been searching all night.
Now, it's almost morning.
If I'm not back before
Aunt May wakes up,
she'll be worried sick.
No.
Not again!
[screams]
[groans]
What's happening to me?
I left my clothes
on that high ledge.
Can't get to them now.
I've got to hide.
It'd be too easy for some
super villain to grab me
and take my mask off.
[Aunt May] Peter,
where have you been?
Out jogging.
Wearing a blanket?
Are you all right, dear?
Yes, Aunt May.
-Fine.
-You look pale to me.
I've just been up all night,
uh, studying.
Well, why don't you
just lie down and rest?
I'll bring some
breakfast for you.
Uh, oh, thanks, Aunt May.
You're the greatest.
[sighs]
I hope rest is all I need.
[groans]
[yawns]
Wow, I feel fantastic!
Yes, my spider powers are back,
at least for now.
Morning, dear.
I'm sorry I let you
sleep like that,
but you really must
have needed it.
Sleep like what?
Why, you slept all day
yesterday and all night.
What?
You mean it's Thursday!
Well, I tried to wake you
a couple of times,
but you kept turning over
and going back to sleep.
Ah, I'm late
for Dr. Connors's class!
Peter, your breakfast!
-Peter!
-[door thuds]
Oh, dear me, that boy.
[man] Neogenics,
the new science
of genetic exploration
and manipulation of DNA,
invented by Professor
Farley Stillwell
here at this college.
It's one of the most important
achievements of this century.
The Toombes Foundation
might be giving
Empire State University
grant money
to continue our research
if we can convince them
how important neogenics is.
That's up to all of us.
You are ESU's best
science students.
Consider this a contest.
Whoever conceives the most
original neogenics experiment
gets the job as my
research assistant
if the Toombes grant
is awarded to ESU.
I'm going to win this, Debra.
You'll have to beat me
out first, Michael.
Nice of you to show up, Parker.
Good luck to you all.
-Thank you.
-[Peter sighs]
[Peter thinking] Great.
First, my powers go
wonky, now, this.
A little late, huh, Peter?
What's the matter?
Get wrapped up watching
cartoons this morning?
Not in the mood, Debra.
I had thought you would be
my main competition, Parker,
but you will be lucky to
make it to the starting line.
Don't forget, Michael,
the tortoise beat the hare.
In my country,
we eat tortoises.
Peter!
Hi, Felicia.
Felicia, what a splendid name.
Allow me to introduce myself.
I am Michael Morbius.
Uh-huh.
Charmed.
Please excuse us.
What B-movie did he come from?
The Revenge of Dracula's Ego.
-What's up?
-I need you to escort me
to the opening of my mother's
new science center tonight.
Hah. Wait a minute.
Are you asking me for a date?
Parker, you're the
only one I know
who can explain these boring
science exhibits to me.
Whoa, hold on,
answer the question.
Is it a date?
All right, all right.
You can call it a date
if you want.
Great!
I'll be there!
Naturally.
Meet me at The Coffee Bean
at 6:30.
Careful, Felicia.
I don't think he's
had his shots.
Flash, what do you want?
I want to know
what Parker's boss
is doing calling those crooks
the Spider-Man Six,
that's what.
The Spider-Man who?
J. Jonah Jameson
is not fooling me.
Spidey's a hero.
He's not any crime boss.
It's some kinda setup.
What are you talking about?
What's the matter, you been
asleep for the past 24 hours?
[John]
And here, we see it live,
just as I've always warned you.
Spider-Man leading one
of his criminal band,
the Spider-Man Six.
It's a setup, I tell ya.
What do you think, Parker?
Parker?
Where are you?
[Peter thinking] I go to
sleep for one lousy day,
and I wake up
in the Twilight Zone.
[Spider-Man]
Hold it, horn head.
You didn't fill out
a withdrawal slip.
-[Rhino groans]
-The spider has landed.
Get ready
for the Rhino's charge.
[loud crash]
[Spider-Man groans]
[Spider-Man]
Aren't you a handsome gent?
[gun fires]
-[Spider-Man groans]
-Eat acid, Spider-Man.
[acid sizzling]
[Spider-Man] Sorry,
I'm on an acid-free diet.
-[acid sizzling]
-Too many of them.
Got to get clear.
Uh-oh!
-Bad move, Spidey!
-[horn wailing]
Bad move!
[Spider-Man] You're getting
predictable, Mysterio!
[Mysterio]
Can't have that, can we?
[Spider-Man coughing]
[explosion booms]
[Mysterio laughs]
Too bad you didn't predict--
[door thudding]
Hey! He's mine!
Nonsense.
You merely softened
him up for me.
Make way for the Scorpion!
Back off, you pea-brained,
uncoordinated,
absurdly dressed
excuse for a man!
Who are you calling
absurdly dressed?
[Doctor Octopus groans]
[Doctor Octopus]
Take your hands off me!
Cease this mindless fighting.
Spider-Man will escape!
[Peter thinking]
Oh, no, not this.
Not now!
My powers are gone!
I'm dead meat.
Still got my web-shooters.
They're my only chance.
I hate this pathetic gunk.
[Spider-Man screams]
[Spider-Man groans]
Almost tore my arm off!
I better not use webbing again
without my spider-strength.
[loud crash]
[Spider-Man groans]
I can get him!
Huh?
Where'd he go?
[loud clunk]
[Peter thinking]
It's a good thing
I kept my clothes
in a web sack with me
this time.
I have to find out why
I keep losing my powers.
[man]
It's incredible, Spider-Man.
Your DNA structure is changing.
[Spider-Man] Changing?
Into what?
Can't say yet,
but I'll help you find out.
I owe you that much for what
you've done for me in the past.
You were not born with your
spider-powers, were you?
[Spider-Man] No.
I won them on a quiz show.
[man] Amazing.
These patterns imply
neogenics is involved,
but how could that be?
[Spider-Man] That was
the category I chose.
I need to conduct
some more tests.
[Spider-Man] Fire away.
[Peter thinking]
I can't tell him the truth
that neogenics might be
the reason I became Spider-Man.
It was an early experiment
of Farley Stillwell's
that I was watching.
Nobody noticed a small
spider climb down
into the path of
his radioactive ray.
[Farley] The future
of genetic engineering
lies in unraveling
the mystery of DNA.
[Peter thinking] That spider
changed my life forever.
-[chomps softly]
-[Peter gasps]
[groans]
[Spider-Man]
Doc, what's going on with me?
I need to do more tests
to be sure,
but your DNA may have
mutated permanently.
For all I know,
your powers will be gone.
Enough!
Scour the city.
Find that wall-crawling
worm at all costs.
[Peter thinking]
So, it's over, just like that.
I'm not Spider-Man anymore.
Now, I'm just normal.
I guess I'm finally free!
No more danger,
no more secrets.
Time to study,
go out on dates!
Oh, no.
Felicia!
Now, where could an inane
arachnid aberration
such as you be going in
so much of a hurry?
Out of my way, Octopus!
You didn't say please.
Now, must I repeat my question?
No, I'll tell you.
I'm headed for
Peter Parker's house.
He's this newspaper
photographer,
always shooting Spider-Man.
Parker?
Yes, I know who he is.
I figured I'd follow him.
Maybe he'll lead me
to the wall-crawler.
Hmm, good plan.
Too good for a clod
such as yourself.
Follow me and see how
a master would do it.
I don't know where Peter is.
Frankly, dear,
I'm getting worried.
Well, if he gets in soon,
please have him call me.
Thank you, goodbye.
[Felicia thinking] I'd worry
if he was ever on time.
What do you got
in the purse, honey?
-I take all major credit cards.
-[gasps]
[Felicia] No!
-This does not belong to you!
-[grunts]
Let go of that or I'm gonna--
[siren wailing]
[indistinct radio chatter]
[Felicia] Are you all right?
Yes, of course.
Ah, it is you,
Parker's girlfriend, huh?
I'm not Parker's girlfriend.
I'm not even sure
I want to be his friend.
Felicia,
you shouldn't be out alone
at night in this neighborhood.
You know something, Michael,
you're right.
How would you like
to keep me company?
I would be delighted.
Naturally.
Tell me, what do you
know about science?
-[doorbell rings]
-Peter?
Oh, can I help you?
Allow me to introduce myself.
I am Doctor Otto Octavius.
A doctor?
It's about Peter, isn't it?
I knew he looked ill.
Where is he?
[stammers]
Uh, Peter collapsed
on the street.
Fortunately, it
was near my clinic.
Good heavens!
Take me to him.
But of course.
Aunt May!
No dinner for me tonight!
I'm late! Aunt May?
[Peter thinking]
She's always home
at this time of night.
Why do I think if I still
had my spider-sense,
it'd be going crazy right now?
Aunt May?!
Aunt May!
[Peter reading] " Parker,
if you ever want to see
your Aunt May again, tell
your friend Spider-Man
he's wanted at 636 Battery
Street immediately."
Aunt May.
[Peter thinking] Even
without my powers,
I can't fail her now.
[Aunt May] Doctor, tell me more
about Peter's condition.
Well, it is precarious.
Oh, dear.
When can I see him?
Soon.
We have the best doctors
attending to him
at this clinic.
How ironic, the Kingpin
built this clinic
to patch up his men.
Yet look how perfectly
it serves our little charade.
[Scorpion] I think the old bat
is sweet on the Doc.
[Shocker]
Here comes Spider-Man.
Hmm.
Never seen Spider-Man
come in on foot before.
He must have some
trick up his sleeve.
[device beeping]
Excuse me, my dear.
I am needed in surgery,
but I'll be back.
What a nice man.
[Spider-Man screams]
[groans]
[Peter thinking] Oh, no!
[Mysterio]
No more illusions, Spider-Man.
We're real.
And we got you at last.
Oh, you poor dear.
Ready for the end, my pretty?
[laughs loudly]
["Spider-Man Theme Song"
playing]
♪ Spider-Man, Spider-Man ♪
♪ Radioactive Spider-Man ♪
[guitar solo]
♪ Spider blood, spider blood ♪
♪ Radioactive spider blood ♪
♪ Spider-Man ♪