[theme music playing]
♪ Spider-Man, Spider-Man ♪
♪ Radioactive Spider-Man ♪
♪ Spider blood, spider blood ♪
♪ Radioactive spider blood ♪
♪ Spider-Man, Spider-Man ♪
[Beyonder] We have
traveled a long way,
through time and space,
Look at what has happened.
Now where'd the Beyonder go?
And where am I?
5th Avenue? It can't be!
How long have I been gone?
What's happened here?
Aunt May!
No! All of Queens,
Astoria, Forest Hills,
all just destroyed!
Aunt May...
You're Aunt May exists
no longer in this world.
I've had it with you, Beyonder!
I want some real answers!
Who's responsible
for this devastation? Who?
You are, Spider-Man.
What?
[Beyonder] You are.
What kind of sick joke are
you playing now, Beyonder?
Whoa, Spider Sense. Danger!
Ho ho! Nice shot,
brother Goblin!
Stick with me, boy,
by the time we've
leveled Manhattan,
I'll have made a real
Goblin out of you! [laughs]
The Hobgoblin and
the Green Goblin together,
destroying the city?
Have they gone
completely insane?
[man] This is J3
Emergency Radio,
broadcasting from
the Daily Bugle building.
We continue our
report on Spider-Man's
war against the city,
I just hope the
National Guard will rescue us
from this criminal siege.
Sorry, this program is
canceled due to low ratings.
Huh?
There was no one left
in the city to listen.
-[Jameson groans]
-[Hobgoblin laughs]
Let go of him, you--
[grunts]
Our boss wants the
microwave broadcaster
on the roof of
J3 Communications.
But it seems to have a
substantial security system.
[Robbie] Don't Jonah!
Don't help them!
-No!
-Talk,
or I'll give your right
hand man his severance pay.
I can deactivate the security
system with my palm print!
Excellent!
We don't need you anymore.
[screams]
Gotcha!
Hey, what's the big idea,
Robertson?
I'd do a lot more if I could,
Jonah was right all along!
I don't know what
you're talking about!
I'm talking about the
destruction of this city!
And those Goblins you've
sent to attack Jonah and me!
The Goblins? In the Bugle?
All right, now you're gonna
pay for what you've done!
Why did you do that?
Let's see: You level Manhattan,
destroy Queens,
why would I be mad at you?
But we did what you told us to!
What? I never told
you to do anything!
Goblin, this Spider-Creep must
be the other one the
boss warned us about!
The other one?
Yes, I think you're right!
But a good Goblin never falls
for the same trick twice!
[Spider-Man coughs]
We have what we need here,
finish the job, Hobgoblin!
With pleasure.
[laughs maniacally]
Uh-oh!
I can't believe it.
The Bugle, destroyed!
My life's work, ruined!
Oh, quit whining!
Thanks so much!
You! I was right
about you all along,
but I never dreamed
you'd go this far!
I'd love to hear your whole
tirade, but not right now!
Hey!
Now I see what's been taking
those idiot Goblins so long!
I wondered when you'd
turn up again, dear clone.
And in my costume no less!
[grunts] That voice!
He sounds like me!
Oh, how I despise you!
And for that reason,
you must be obliterated!
You see, I really,
really, hate clones!
He looks like Carnage,
but he has my costume.
My voice!
[laughs maniacally]
He's squeezing me so hard!
I can't breathe!
What? No!
Where?
[groans]
Beyonder! What's wrong?
Are you all right?
No, he is very, very weak.
How could he be,
with all his power?
Because he's not in
our home dimension.
His power is diminished
the longer he stays here,
in this unfamiliar reality.
We must rest,
and let my life support
system rejuvenate
you as much as it can.
Madame Web, tell me what's
going on! I need your help!
You must help yourself,
but that does not mean
you will be alone, look.
Am I going mad?
This, is the one that's
supposed to be our leader?
Give me a break, I should be
in charge of this group,
I'm the real Spider-Man!
I don't know what
kind of mind game this is,
but I'm the real Spider-Man!
The real Peter Parker!
Guess again.
See, Pete old buddy? We're
just as genuine as you are!
But, how can that be?
Madame Web says that we're
each from different dimensions.
Reality is like a river,
that splits off into many
parallel tributaries.
These Spider-Men
are from parallel realities,
each as legitimate as yours.
They're all you,
with some slight differences.
But don't let these
worry ya Pete,
they're just a little souvenir
from my last fight with Doc Oct.
You mean to tell me that
you all share my life,
and my spider powers?
[clears throat] Well, uh,
not quite all of us.
I don't have your life,
or your powers.
So who are you then?
You wouldn't believe
me if I told you,
let's just say,
I'm here to help.
Although I'm not prepared
for anything like this.
We were all kind of caught
in the middle of things,
I'm having a little
mutation problem right now.
Whoa, I don't think I even
wanna hear your story.
All of you must hear
the Scarlet Spider's story.
For this is his
reality we're in,
and that monster you encountered
was his twin, behold!
My name is Ben Reilly,
I'm related to this
reality's Peter Parker.
How?
I'm his clone, or,
maybe he's my clone,
we're not sure.
This dimension's Peter Parker
had it pretty rough.
He had already lost Uncle Ben,
then Aunt May passed away.
That nearly unbalanced his mind,
but then Parker's
path crossed with
a brilliant scientist,
an expert in genetic cloning,
his name was--
Miles Warren!
Ah, I see you've met him,
well he cloned Spider-Man.
To make matters worse,
the clone escaped.
I thought I was that clone,
I tried to stay out of
Peter's life
by taking on a new identity.
I dyed my hair,
changed my name to Ben Reilly.
But I had no memory of
where I really came from!
Warren had robbed me of my past.
I understand what you've
been through, Warren created
a clone in my reality
who had the same problem.
Peter, I've come back to you.
Mary Jane!
[crowd cheers]
Oh!
Mary Jane, what's the matter?
I'm not the real Mary Jane?
That is so, my dear.
Why didn't you just
tell me I was a clone?
The cloning process
has proven unstable.
You're coming apart.
Mary Jane! No!
It's too late.
Warren! Warren,
where the blazes are you?
Forget it tiger, I want
you to know just one thing.
If any part of me is anything
like the real Mary Jane Watson
she loves Peter Parker more
than anything in the world.
More than anything!
No!
Mary Jane! Mary Jane!
I might make some
startling advances!
I hate him for what he did.
So did my world's Peter Parker,
but he hated me,
the clone, even more.
When I became a costumed hero,
the Scarlet Spider,
I really made him angry.
But the next big blow came
from Dr. Curt Connors.
He discovered according
to our genetic structures,
it might be Peter
who was the clone, not me!
That news pushed Peter Parker
over the edge.
Now he hated me with a passion!
This is starting to sound
like a bad comic book plot!
It gets worse.
I was trying to stop one of
the Kingpin's crimes,
he had created some kind of
inter-dimensional transporter
which would make him
invincible as a criminal.
No sooner had I arrived,
then my other showed up.
I thought he was there to
help me, but he wasn't.
He wanted me out of
the picture, permanently.
Then, from some other
dimension, it appeared.
That's the Carnage symbiote!
Drawn by Peter's hatred,
it bonded with him somehow,
and drove him completely insane!
So this reality we're
in is your reality.
But what does it have
to do with the rest of us?
What's our stake in this,
or yours for that matter?
Behold, look into the future,
tell me what you see.
[Spider-Man] A portal
has been opened!
The dish stolen from
J3 Communications
is magnifying
the incendiary device
attached to the transporter,
and it's about to go off!
No!
[orchestral Spider-Man
theme playing]
Spider-Carnage will link
a matter disintegrator bomb
to Dr. Ohn's time
portal device.
The blast will be magnified,
and will enter other dimensions.
It will not only
destroy this reality,
but every reality
across space and time.
I have already seen it happen.
If this has already happened,
how are we standing here?
When the destruction
reached my home dimension,
I used all my powers
to roll back time.
It taxed me to the extreme.
We are now in this
reality's past.
Spider-Carnage has not
detonated the device yet,
You must stop him.
Wait, you can transcend time,
why don't you just
go back to the past
and prevent any of
this from happening?
Although Madame Web
and I are beings
who can pass through
different realities,
we are powerless-- [groans]
We cannot stay in
this one reality
to keep anything
we change stable.
It takes all this machinery for
us to remain in your dimension
for as long as we have.
And once we leave,
it will be as if
we had never been here at all.
The Beyonder decided
that Spider-Men
from other realities would have
to find a way to stop this one.
In other words,
only he could stop himself.
My companion Madame Web traveled
to your dimensions to
prepare you for this task.
You were all tested,
but only one of you
proved worthy to be
the leader of this team. You.
Me?
Yes, you.
I object!
I think I should be the--
Silence!
We took you to our dimension,
and created the Secret War
to test you,
and see if we were right.
Behold!
Spider-Man! Get out of here!
No! We have to get the
Lizard back! He's my friend!
We've gotta help the rebels!
The robots are pounding them!
Hold on, Doom.
We're not your pawns!
You can't possibly control the
God-like abilities
you've stolen!
You might place us
all in grave danger
if you don't give that power up!
Who amongst you has ever wanted
to give up their super powers?
I have, 'cause I've learned
time and time again,
that with great power,
there must also come
great responsibility.
We were right.
It's up to all of you now,
even my survival depends
on your victory.
So we're here to
fight for all reality.
Okay, Spider-Men,
we don't have much time,
we'd better get going.
What about him?
He doesn't have any powers.
Hey guys,
don't cut me out of this!
This is the adventure
of a lifetime!
No way.
I'm sorry, but he's right,
we can't endanger you.
And I'm sorry
I was angry with you.
Rest assured,
I won't let you down!
All right boys, lets do it!
[Kingpin] Smythe, what is
keeping Spider-Carnage
and those Goblins?
They were due back hours ago.
I warned you not
to trust any of them.
We got delayed. We ran
into another Spider-Man!
What is this all about,
Spider-Carnage?
It's that clone
I told you about!
All that matters is
the few more hours
I need to assemble
my ultimate weapon!
Think of it, we'll use it to
take control of people's minds!
Then, we'll rule
the entire world!
You have secured the final
part that you required?
Of course! My device
will be ready soon.
And then, we'll really get
what we deserve, all of us!
[laughs maniacally]
This device he is building,
is it what he says it is?
I need time to analyze it fully.
Keep an eye on him,
he is a powerful ally,
but he is more evil than
anyone I have ever encountered.
[Armored Spider] I don't get it,
we can swing
through the air, why
are we sneaking
in the front door?
Because, Spider-Carnage
won't expect it,
and that makes him
vulnerable, trust me!
We need to disable the alarm
and observation systems.
No problem, one of my companies
designed security
systems like this.
You own your own companies?
Who do you think built
this armored suit?
In my world I'm
a multi-billionaire, aren't you?
Uh, let's keep moving, okay?
[camera whirrs]
Kingpin! It's Spider-Man!
Five of him!
Five? But I thought
here was only one clone!
It appears our visitors have
disabled the security systems!
Green Goblin, Hobgoblin,
we are under attack from inside!
A laser built right
into your armor?
It's my own design,
I only wish I was able to
bring my giant Spider-Robot
on this mission with us.
Did he say his
"Giant Spider-Robot"?
[screams]
[Hobgoblin laughs]
Nice, what do you
call that stuff?
Impact webbing.
Why didn't I think of that?
Gotcha!
[Hobgoblin] Maybe,
but can you keep me?
Ha!
A gas missile will
take care of him!
No, wait!
Why did you do that?
What were you thinking?
Hey relax, this'll all
work out, things always do!
[Peter] What a foolhardy nit!
It's as if he doesn't even
consider failure!
You have to be careful,
Beyonder!
I must help them even
if it means the end of me!
Hurry! Thanks to the Hobgoblin's
bungling, we don't
have much time!
If we're cautious enough,
we can bypass them, and--
Sorry, I never shy
away from a fight,
maybe 'cause I never lose!
Hey, wait!
Come on!
Impetuous, isn't he?
Try obnoxious.
These look like sonic grenades,
they'll come in handy!
[screams]
This is too easy!
A paralyzer ray! I can't move!
Ha!
[Goblin yells]
Hey! Stop! No!
Gentlemen, stop right there!
You were right, the clones
do seem to be multiplying!
Stop them!
[groans]
Three more sonic grenades
should do the trick!
[groans]
No!
My mutation disease!
It's flaring up! Not now!
Lets use this distraction
to get out of here!
What's happened to him?
He's mutated into a Man-Spider!
I've been through this.
We're in trouble!
[roars]
[theme music playing]
♪ Spider-Man, Spider-Man ♪
♪ Radioactive Spider-Man ♪
♪ Spider blood, spider blood ♪
♪ Radioactive spider blood ♪
♪ Spider-Man ♪