[upbeat rock music]
♪ Spider-Man ♪
♪ Radioactive Spider-Man ♪
♪ Spider blood
Spider blood ♪
♪ Radioactive spider blood ♪
♪ Spider blood
Spider blood ♪
♪ Radioactive spider blood ♪
[explosions booming]
[growling]
♪ Spider-Man ♪
[heroic music]
[car horns honking]
[tires screeching]
[squealing]
[ominous music]
[tires screeching]
[jet engines roaring]
Commander, the colonel
is waiting for you.
Fury, this is
the most sophisticated
organization ever created.
Can't you run it
without an old war dog
like me nipping at your heels?
Sorry to yank you
out of retirement, Commander,
but I've got a problem
only you can solve.
This person is
on the verge of unleashing
a force
that could destroy us all.
No.
[Nick]
You must stop May Parker!
[ominous music]
[man] He's turned down
the street, to the right!
Get him!
[man panting]
[jets whooshing]
[woman] Dr. Groitzig.
Oh!
Silver Sable here.
Mission accomplished.
Robbie, get a load
of this item on the news wire.
German WWII enemy scientist
Dr. Wolfgang Groitzig,
long-presumed dead,
has been kidnapped.
He was living in Moscow
under a new name.
His daughter revealed
his secret identity
in order to report
the kidnapping.
I remember when he was big news
back in the '40s.
Imagine him hiding
all those years.
Excuse me for a second, Jonah.
I have to make a call.
[ringing]
This is Robbie Robertson.
I just got
some very bad news.
[Peter] But, Aunt May,
why do you wanna sell this house
and move in with Mrs. Watson?
Peter, with you
and Mary Jane living
in your own apartment,
it seemed best
for Anna and myself.
After all, you don't want us
to be lonely, now, do you?
Of course not.
It's just that this
is where I--
I grew up with you and Uncle Ben
after my parents died.
Hmm! Just like him,
always thinking about himself.
Aunt Anna,
I am Peter's wife now.
That doesn't mean
I have to like him.
-[glass shattering]
-[gasp]
May, are you all right?
I'm fine, really.
[thinking]
No, she isn't.
I've seen Aunt May upset,
but never agitated like this.
Something in today's Bugle
seems to have set her off.
I wonder what.
Kingpin, are you sure?
Landon, I am positive.
This scientist holds the key
to one of the greatest powers
known to mankind.
No one knew he was still alive.
But what I know
is only anecdotal.
We need the Chameleon
to give us the specifics.
How unfortunate that the
Chameleon is now incarcerated
in the most impregnable fortress
ever built.
Nothing is impregnable
to the Kingpin.
You must be joking.
I will wage war
on this fortress.
But to do that, I will
need to assemble warriors.
Once again, I must band
together the Insidious Six.
Doctor Octopus.
Rhino.
Shocker.
The Scorpion.
Spider-Man has driven
them all underground.
They have been forgotten
by the world, but not by me.
Like all good warriors,
they need a brilliant general
like myself to lead them
once again to greatness.
But there are four of them,
and the Chameleon
will make five.
Who will be
your sixth forgotten warrior?
Meet Mysterio's replacement,
the Vulture.
Kingpin, I've perused your labs,
and I accept your terms.
I think I'm gonna like it here.
Please be careful, dear.
Your helping me move
wouldn't be worth it
if you sprained your back.
[Peter] Okay, Aunt May,
I think I can handle it.
After all, I do have
the proportional strength
of a spider.
Ohh!
Course, that spider agility
of mine
could use a little practice.
Hey, what's this?
These passports belonged
to my mother and father?
According to these,
they've both been
around the world several times.
-I wonder why--
-[doorbell rings]
-[rings]
-Aunt May?
I need to ask you...
-[gasp]
-[Keene] Hello, May.
Keene?
Keene Marlowe?
It's been a long time,
hasn't it?
It has.
But I suppose I should have
been expecting
a visit like this.
Peter, this is Keene Marlowe.
He-- He was your Uncle Ben's
best friend.
Pleased to meet you,
Mr. Marlowe.
Peter? Oh, my goodness,
you're all grown up.
It seems like
only yesterday when...
[chuckles]
May I come in?
Yes.
Yes, do come in.
I've never heard
of this guy before.
How come Uncle Ben
never mentioned him?
So, that's why I'm in town.
Just another boring convention.
Now, what line of work
did you say you were in?
Oh, uh, this and that.
He's been giving me
the runaround all evening.
He'd make a great politician.
Aunt May, I've been meaning
to ask you about something.
Did these really
belong to my parents?
[gasp] Where on earth did
you find those?
In the attic.
They fell out of an old trunk.
-Put them away!
-Why? What's wrong?
Put them away!
-Oh!
-Aunt May.
-I didn't mean to--
-Son, leave her be.
-But I--
-Let me talk to her.
Now, why don't you go out
and take a walk or something?
I need to do something,
all right.
But I'll take wall-crawling
over walking any day.
Who is this Marlowe guy
and what does he know
about my family that I don't?
[Keene]
He has a right to know, May.
You'll have to tell him someday.
But he's so sensitive.
Who knows
how this will affect him?
Besides, you're not here
for the sake of Peter or me.
You're here to collect
what you can't have.
Maybe I can't,
but if that's the case,
you can't sell this house.
I just can't believe
that this nightmare
is starting all over again.
Oh! [sobbing]
Now what's he up to?
[ominous music]
I'm gonna find out
just who this guy really is.
Huh?!
This looks interesting.
SHIELD Headquarters?
I've been here before.
What's his connection
to this place?
None of this makes any sense!
I'm glad they haven't changed
their ventilation system
since I was here last.
[Keene]
May Parker won't talk,
but I won't leave
until she does.
Frustrating isn't it,
when somebody won't tell you
all that they know?
Nick, I know you
want all the details,
but some things have to be
kept secret even from you.
Fine. My job is to make sure
that no matter what,
Richard and Mary Parker's name
must not be cleared.
The official line
is that they died
as Russian counterspies,
traitors!
What?!
And traitors they must remain.
Russian counterspies?
Traitors?
Is Fury conspiring to smear
my parents' reputation?
I can't hide anymore!
I've go out there
and make him tell me
what on earth
he's talking about.
-[explosion]
-[groans]
Uh-oh. Now what?
-What the heck's going on?!
-Colonel!
We're under attack
by a ship that was cloaked!
It must have found a way
to jam our radar!
Get me surveillance video,
all decks!
Security's been breached
on decks five, 10, and 13!
[Nick] Activate
the auto-sentry lasers!
And lock down
all pressure doors!
Can't!
They've knocked out power
to the security systems, sir!
Keene, get
to the auxiliary power station
and try to get
those systems back online!
Will do!
[jets whirring]
Kingpin, Doctor Octopus here.
Good. Attach my comlink
to any available computer port.
It will access
SHIELD's data banks
and show me the location
of the Chameleon.
[beeping]
Excellent.
It will take me only
30 seconds to decipher this.
Do it in ten.
Spider-Man, here?!
It's so gratifying
to be recognized.
I must compliment my PR firm.
[groaning]
Spider-sense! Danger!
[Spider-Man]
Surprised to see me, big boy?
[chuckles] Delighted.
You don't expect me
to stay put, do you?
-Huh?
-Perhaps he needs
for me to hold you still.
[Spider-Man grunts]
-Hey, Spider-Man!
-[groans]
Nobody said
you were gonna be up here!
Now, this is
what I call a party!
[Vulture] Oh, no, you don't,
wall weasel!
[Doctor Octopus]
Kingpin said we'd all
gain a new lease on life.
We'll start
by depriving you of yours.
[ominous music]
[Kingpin] Octavius,
we have found the location.
Rally your men immediately.
Look out!
Men, follow me!
-Spider-Man, are you okay?
-Yeah.
I'd love to chat
about old times,
but we've gotta stop
those goons!
Rhino, Scorpion, cover us
while we retrieve the Chameleon!
It will only take seconds
to overload the laser matrix.
Then its safety fuses
will activate and shut it down.
At last, I've found
the Six Stooges again.
[lasers firing]
Don't worry, Nick,
I'll go after them.
No. We'll handle this.
You go back to the Parker house.
Too bad this won't count
towards
my frequent flier mileage.
-[radar beeping]
-[Vulture] Perfect.
I like a good dogfight.
We're right on them,
Colonel Fury.
Delta Nine is hit.
Pilot is ejecting now.
Delta One, still in pursuit.
Wait, they've gone off my radar,
and I've also lost visual!
Once again,
your cloaking device
worked flawlessly,
Doctor Octopus.
Naturally.
But our sensors tell us we still
have one last minor problem
to contend with.
Uh-oh! Better
not stick around up here!
Blast!
Great! Just great.
What was that all about?
Well, I'm going to get answers
from somebody tonight,
and I know just where to go.
Yes, Peter, if you're looking
for answers,
I can give them to you.
I have to tell you something
I've been hiding
from you all your life.
My parents?
Why haven't
I ever seen this before?
Because if you had,
you would know
that your parents
were spies for Russia.
This can't be true!
It is!
It's all in here!
[sobbing]
Peter, I knew your parents also.
They were American operatives,
and they were
considered the best.
I know
because I was one as well.
You? A secret agent?
Yes. Your parents were
on a mission to find the truth
about a secret doomsday weapon
that was supposedly built
to destroy America.
It had been
an old World War II project
that the Germans initiated.
Rumor had it it was created
by a Dr. Wolfgang Groitzig.
But for some reason,
it was never used.
This doomsday device
was thought to be a hoax
until the late 1970s.
Your parents stumbled
onto Groitzig living
somewhere in Moscow, or so they
told the U.S. government.
So, they were sent to Russia.
But once there, they announced
that they were double agents,
working for the USSR all along.
Then, suddenly, there in Russia,
your parents died
in a plane crash.
Our government had to conclude
that Groitzig wasn't alive.
That Richard and Mary had lied
to hide their real reason
for being on Soviet soil.
But with Groitzig's discovery
and kidnapping,
well, no one knows
what to believe.
-Are you okay?
-No, I'm angry!
I wanna go to Russia
and find out about Groitzig!
Tonight, I overheard
a man named Nick Fury
hint that my parents
might not be traitors.
Somebody is lying.
If that's true, you have
to get to the bottom of this.
MJ, I love you.
If I don't resolve this mess,
I'll go crazy.
But how am I going
to pay for a trip to Russia?
MJ and I barely scrape by
with my freelance work
for the Daily Bugle.
-Hey, that's it!
-[snaps]
Spider-Man is going where?
To Russia.
He told me so himself.
I don't believe it.
Why would he do
a crazy thing like--
You always said
he was a menace to the world.
What if you were right?
What if he's decided
to take himself global?
Wait a minute,
let's think about this.
Of course.
Their government is in turmoil.
You don't suppose
he's going to try
to get them to elect him
their leader?
What if he became
a world power unto himself?
This is a disaster!
America has to know,
Mr. Jameson.
You have to send me
over there to take pictures.
You don't believe
a word of this, right?
No. In this case, I think
Peter's fears are valid.
[both] You do?!
Absolutely.
And if you send Peter to Russia,
then I wanna go, too.
Robbie agrees with me?
But what's he up to?
All right. You two go.
But, Parker, if you
don't bring back a story,
I'll have you shipped
back to Siberia.
Tiger, please be careful.
Don't worry.
I'll guard this
with my life if I have to.
[Peter]
"Good morning."
[reading translation
in Russian]
"Good evening."
[reading translation
in Russian]
-Do you speak
any Russian, Robbie?
-Enough.
Hey, who was that guy who
saw you off at the airport?
Just a friend.
Excuse me, Peter.
I really need
to get some sleep.
Robbie seems so secretive.
It's not like him.
Well, Mr. Robertson,
I'm ready to get on the story
whenever you are.
Get some sleep
and we'll get on it
first thing in the morning.
Fine with me.
That'll give Spider-Man
some time to look around.
[people shouting]
I don't
speak the language.
I don't know where anything is.
Robbie was right.
I should get some sleep
and make a fresh start
in the morning.
Hey, it's Robbie.
What's he doing sneaking
out at this hour?
Who?
Who are you?
The man who gave me your name
told me to show you this.
[gasps] Quickly, come inside.
Come, come.
I am an old man.
I have nothing to tell you.
Mr. Lentz, I mean you no harm.
I just want information.
Now that Groitzig's been taken,
I know they'll come for me next,
searching
for the doomsday device.
He will be forced
to tell them where I am.
I fear for my life!
There are those
who want to try to find out
who kidnapped the professor
so they can be stopped.
I can only tell you
who I think is behind this.
Wait a minute.
-[tingling]
-My spider-sense.
[groaning]
Take Lentz!
[Robbie]
Leave him alone!
I've gotta help Robbie!
You arehere.
I'll be okay,
just get Lentz back!
-Boom!
-[groaning]
[guns clicking]
[jetpacks roaring]
Keep an eye on him.
-Behind you!
-Huh?
[groans]
[both coughing]
We must leave no evidence
that we were here.
Destroy this place.
[beeping]
[both groaning]
[upbeat rock music]
♪ Spider-Man, Spider-Man ♪
♪ Radioactive Spider-Man ♪
♪ Spider blood, spider blood ♪
♪ Radioactive spider blood ♪
♪ Spider blood ♪
♪ Spider-Man ♪