♪ Spider-Man, Spider-Man ♪
♪ Radioactive Spider-Man ♪
♪ Spider blood, spider blood ♪
♪ Radioactive spider blood ♪
♪ Spider-Man, Spider-Man ♪
[lightening crackles]
[Spider-Man] I've never been
so frightened in my life.
I need to do more
tests to be sure,
but your DNA may have
mutated permanently.
You're changing into
something that won't be human.
Gotta find a cure.
There's one man
who might help me.
People say he's the world's
greatest expert on
genetic mutations.
Danger!
But I don't see any...
Huh?
[grunts]
Okay, Spidey, next time,
use the front door.
-[Wolverine] Well, what do you
know?
Put out flypaper,
catch a Spider.
Make one wrong move, please,
and you're shish-kebab.
Spider-Man!
Cool, tell us,
why are you here?
[Spider-Man] None
of your business!
Who are you guys anyway?
Name's Rogue, sugar.
You seem kind of cute,
in a creepy sort of way.
Maybe y'all will tell me
what you're up to, hmm?
He ain't going to talk.
How about we go digging
for an explanation?
[Spider-Man] What
an interesting plan,
but how about this one!
Nice, I come to the
peaceful countryside,
and I wind up in The Pentagon.
[Cyclops] Stop him!
[alarms blaring]
[Spider-Man] Whoa, close.
Even closer.
[alarms blaring]
Got to pick a door.
Any door.
New rule. Never visit the
pentagon without a road map.
Who were those clowns anyway?
He's in the danger room.
Bad news.
I was in there practicing.
I left it on.
Well, what program was running?
Deadly sentinels.
[Spider-Man] My
Spider-sense is going crazy.
[screams, grunts]
Okay.
So, I'm going to be a
little late getting home.
Heads up, guys.
Power of lightning,
strike again!
Um, power of web
shooters, get real sticky.
[Rogue] How's a gal supposed
to keep a boy interested
if y'all keep scaring him away?
Sorry, mon Frere,
but Gambit see no future
for you in the cards.
Jean, go to the control room
and turn this program off.
[Jean] On my way.
-[keys clacking]
-[alarm blaring]
[Spider-Man] Whoa!
Huh?
-I guess the ride's over.
-Not for you, it ain't.
[Charles] Enough!
What do you want here?
I came to see you,
Professor Charles Xavier.
So that's it.
I'm mutating.
Into what, I don't know.
Can you cure me?
I'm sorry, Spider-Man.
My work is not to cure mutants.
I've built this complex,
this school, to train them.
I help them accept
who and what they are.
[Spider-Man] Accept it?
But I don't want to be a freak!
Watch your mouth, pal.
Being a mutant's a gift.
[Spider-Man] Well,
what if this gift
turns me into some kind
of eight-legged monster?
I wish I had an answer for you.
I am sorry for your pain.
[Spider-Man] Don't
worry about my pain.
Worry about yours.
If I mutate into a
dangerous creature,
and you have to stop me.
It's always the same,
I can save the world 10 times
over, but when I need help,
I'm on my own.
Thanks,
for nothing.
Spider-Man don't go!
He could be a big help to us.
[Wolverine] Forget it,
he's too much of a loner.
I don't know that
I agree, Wolverine.
I found him somewhat
reminiscent of you
when you crossed our doorstep.
[Wolverine] Good riddance.
No man is an island
complete unto himself.
John Donne.
Look, he ain't
even a real mutant.
He said it himself.
It was an accident.
Then perhaps he has a
right to seek a cure.
There's a man at the
Brand Corporation
who has been researching
mutant genetics.
Maybe he can help.
Come on, Beast,
this ain't like you.
And what makes you think
you know me so completely?
What was that about?
[Landon] It's me, Landon.
[man] Hope you followed
instructions.
Wouldn't want to
have to tell Kingpin
-you're double-crossing him.
-Don't do that, please.
I have no choice.
I can't let him
have my technology.
[man] Oh, spare me
the sob story.
All right, here's the money.
Excellent.
Now beat it.
I want to be alone with
all my favorite presidents.
[Hobgoblin laughing]
[Landon] I'm sorry, but
you gave me no choice.
[Hobgoblin] Nice try, bucko.
But the price of my
silence just went up.
[phone ringing]
Hello?
[Kingpin] Landon?
Yes?
My informants tell me
that you have left the
Brand Corporation premises.
Kingpin, are you spying on me?
Of course.
I like to keep a close
eye on my investments.
You should be working
-bringing me faster results.
-The work's going fine.
Come to my press conference
and hear for yourself,
or send one of your informants.
-How rude!
-[dial tone drones]
Genius deserves a
little leeway, Smythe.
If he can deliver an army
of genetically
altered super mutants
willing to do my bidding,
then I can tolerate
a little rudeness.
I don't trust him.
You don't trust anyone.
And I'm usually right.
Everything's ready for the
press conference, Mr. Landon.
-Good work, Genevieve.
-Mr. Landon,
are you sure that now is
the right time to go public
with your
genetic breakthroughs?
I'd like to delay it,
but my chief investor
needs reassurance.
To get him off my back,
I'll share some of my
preliminary findings
with the press for now.
But my real work,
for the good of mankind,
won't be finished until
I perform one final test.
Penny for your
thoughts, Spider-Man.
I mean you no harm.
I just want to talk.
[Spider-Man] I've heard
all I want to hear
from you X-people.
Excuse me.
Please, wait.
Have you heard of the
Brand Corporation?
A man there named
Herbert Landon
has been studying your
particular form of mutation.
Perhaps he can reverse it.
He will be presenting
his findings
at the convention hall
tomorrow.
Lewald, I see one!
Talk about luck!
I knew if we watched Xavier's
property long enough,
we'd find a mutant.
He's the world's
top mutie lover.
-But is Spider-Man a mutant?
-Who cares?
There's Henry McCoy!
Now we're talking mutants.
Sounds most promising,
don't you agree?
[Spider-Man] Yeah.
Why are you going out
of your way for me?
No one can turn his
back on another's pain.
I may be a mutant,
but I'm still human.
[Spider-Man] Well,
that's where we're different.
I'm not sure I still am.
How sad.
We are all alone until we
accept our need for others.
[guns cock]
Don't let him get away!
[groans]
Get the restraints on him.
[growls]
He's stunned.
Now, get the net.
[groans]
Call the boss.
Tell him we've got what he
needs, a real, live mutant.
Mary Jane, why do
I torture myself
with thoughts of
us being together?
Why would you want to be
with a mutated thing like me?
I should just leave here,
spare everyone the pain.
I'm sorry, Aunt May.
Uncle Ben, almost forgot
to say good-bye to you.
[Ben] Did you think things
were going to be easy, boy?
-Huh, did you?
-[Peter strains]
But I, I,
I can't do it, Uncle Ben.
You know my rotten luck.
Boy, good or bad luck
is nothing but the
right or wrong mix
of opportunity, preparation,
and confidence.
Now, I know you're prepared
because I had a hand in that.
Son, what you lack
is confidence.
Peter, you can do anything
as long as you don't
give up on yourself.
[Spider-Man] You always did
believe in me, Uncle Ben,
and you always were right.
I can't quit.
I've got to keep fighting.
Cyclops, the engines
are working fine now.
Can't we, please, go back?
Ah, come on, Jubilee,
one more time.
-[Wolverine] Blackbird,
come in.
-Blackbird here.
Either of you see
Beast this morning?
His bed ain't been slept in.
-You tried the lab?
-Yeah.
He gets working on something
and forgets about little
things like sleep.
Already checked the lab.
Over and out.
You seem overly
worried about Hank.
-Why?
-I don't know.
He's been acting weird lately.
He's usually solid
as a rock, but now--
That's the side he
chooses to show us,
but we've all got
our own private pain.
You, of all people,
should know that, Logan.
[sniffing]
Beast and Spider-Man.
Oh, and a bunch of guys
I never smelled before.
A stinking trap.
That punk's gonna pay,
big time.
Brand Corporation must have
made a huge breakthrough
on this mutie research.
Oh, that's what I've heard.
You don't think they'd
let any of those muties
into this presentation, do you?
I don't want to be within a
thousand miles of those freaks.
I'm surprised at you,
Cecily, really surprised.
[scoffs] Mutie-lover.
[man] I now present
Herbert Landon,
of the Brand Corporation.
Thank you, ladies and
gentlemen, thank you.
I stand before you today
to announce the
dawning of a new age,
a new era in understanding
the genetic factors
which create the mutant strain.
As most of you know,
DNA, the microscopic
strands of chemicals
in every human and animal
cell contains the code
for all of our physical traits,
but, occasionally, the strands
are uniquely imperfect,
and we call the result mutancy.
Because of the complexity
and the minute size
of the strands,
scientists have been unable
to manipulate mutant DNA,
until now.
Thanks to the newest
generation of super-computers,
we at the Brand Corporation
are on the verge of one of
the greatest discoveries.
[Peter] Just when it was
starting to get interesting.
Surprised, Landon?
Don't be.
There's nowhere you
can hide from me.
-[people screaming]
-Hobgoblin.
I guess this
meeting's adjourned.
Oh, please. [chuckling]
You didn't think I'd
fall for that old
exploding warehouse
trick, did you?
What kind of a fool
do you take me for?
[Spider-Man] Personally,
I'd never call you a fool.
That'd be an insult
to fools everywhere.
I'll take care of him.
[Hobgoblin] I didn't
come here for you,
but I'll gladly
take a two-for-one.
[grunts]
[Spider-Man] Air Arachnid,
the only way to fly.
I'll take a rain
check on my two-fer.
[crowd clamoring]
Remember, Landon, we've still
got our arrangement,
but now, I intend to
quintuple your fee!
[cackling]
[crowd clamoring]
[Spider-Man] The ceiling!
I've got to keep it
from falling
long enough for the
crowd to get out.
Hang together.
We must leave.
But, but we have to help him.
He risked his life to save you.
[Landon] There's
nothing we can do.
[Spider-Man] It's collapsing.
I've failed.
Huh?
[crowd screaming]
[Spider-Man] Something held
the ceiling up
long enough for me to get away.
But what?
Well, Landon got away okay.
I wonder why
Hobgoblin's after him.
One thing's for sure,
Hobgoblin won't quit.
He'll chase Landon back
to the Brand Corporation.
[helicopter blades whirring]
Seems quiet enough.
[groaning]
What?
-[electricity crackles]
-[screams]
[Landon] I wouldn't
try that again.
We're now increasing
the voltage.
Landon.
-What is the meaning of this?
-Can't you guess?
Don't you remember
when we worked together
all those years ago,
Dr. Hank McCoy?
Remember how eager you
were to find a cure
for your growing mutancy?
So eager that you
risked destroying yourself
in the process.
That was a lifetime ago.
I've changed a great
deal since then.
Obviously, you're
one of them now.
You've changed, all right,
but I haven't.
I intend to use the
research you began
to destroy all mutants.
Herbert, this is genocide.
You can't be serious.
Oh, no?
This chemical
was designed by me
to reduce the physio-electric
energy of mutant DNA
unraveling it into nothingness.
It will make mutant cells
turn against them and
destroy their very bodies.
The human race will
be purified once more.
And to make sure it works,
I'm going to test it on
you, my true blue friend.
The irony is I couldn't
have done any of this
without your
brilliant research.
The research you started
to prevent yourself from
turning into a hairy animal.
[laughing]
[Spider-Man] At last.
Got to time this just right.
No!
[Spider-Man] Surprise!
You!
How did you know
I'd come here?
[Spider-Man] Lucky guess.
No more tricks.
Now, tell me.
Why do you want
to destroy Landon?
[chuckling] You clown,
I don't want to hurt him.
He's my bankroll.
He's paying me to
keep my mouth shut.
I know his dirty
little secret.
[Spider-Man] What secret?
Landon has a hidden agenda.
He's going to
destroy all mutants,
every last three-eyed,
six-legged, four-nosed
[Spider-Man]
I don't believe you.
Maybe if I looked
into your baby-blues--
[Wolverine] Spider-Man.
What have you done with Beast?
[Spider-Man] I don't know
what you're talking about.
[Wolverine] Yeah. Sure.
Beast told you
about this place.
That's how I knew
to find you here.
Looks like your memory
needs a little help.
-[gleeful chuckle]
-[roaring]
[laughing] How entertaining.
A fight to the bitter end.
Problem is, in this fight,
nobody's gonna win,
except me!
♪ Spider-Man, Spider-Man ♪
♪ Radioactive Spider-Man ♪
♪ Spider blood, spider blood ♪
♪ Radioactive spider blood ♪
♪ Spider-Man ♪