[Peter]
Previously onSpider-Man.
[Beyonder] This is the one.
Put him to the test.
[Peter] Who are you?
The Beyonder.
You have been chosen.
For the test of
good against evil.
[Beyonder] We have
Doctor Octopus.
Doctor Doom.
[Peter] Alistair Smythe!
The Lizard.
The Red Skull.
Banish evil from this
planet, or perish.
[Peter] I need help
to save this planet.
Computer, bring me Storm,
The Fantastic Four,
Iron Man, Captain America, now.
I'm the one who brought you.
Millions of lives are at stake.
[Storm] We'd better stop him!
Giant worms!
[Peter] We have to
get the Lizard back!
We've gotta turn
on the force field.
Power of lightning!
My rational mind trapped
in this Lizard body.
I'm with you.
[Peter] Now, we
show the Beyonder
what Earth people
are really made of.
If you'll agree to work with me.
-We're in.
-He is a leader.
Yes, but soon
Spider-Man must face
his greatest horror
in the universe.
[theme music playing]
♪ Spider-Man, Spider-Man ♪
♪ Radioactive Spider-Man ♪
♪ Spider blood, spider blood ♪
♪ Radioactive spider blood ♪
♪ Spider-Man, Spider-Man ♪
[tense music playing]
[engine revs]
[driving rock music playing]
[Morbius growls]
[woman screams]
[armor clatters]
Vampire!
Surrender to your destiny.
You would destroy
your own mother?
My mother is gone.
Now there is only you!
Miriam, Queen of the Vampires!
Then I am disappointed.
This means I cannot save you.
[Blade and Morbius scream]
[Miriam] Excellent my children.
It was easier than
I thought to trick them.
You and your kind will
never win, mother.
We just have, my son.
Alas, who will be left
to fight the good fight,
when Blade and Morbius are gone?
Ask and you shall
receive, queenie.
Move an inch and I fire
this solar light emitter.
[vampires gasp]
[woman screams]
-No!
-Black Cat!
My love!
[screams]
Felicia.
[tense music playing]
[computer beeps]
[Peter] What's wrong?
I thought you two had
this thing figured out?
This is alien
technology, Spider-Man.
Although we've managed
to power it up,
we don't know how
well it'll operate.
I'm doing my best to
bring your comrade here.
Spider!
Where am I?
What have you done?
I've just transported
you from Earth
to an alien planet.
No, no, not now!
At this moment Morbius
and Blade are surrounded
by Miriam and her vampires!
You've got to send me back, now!
Spider-Man, this is the partner
you said was going to help us?
[Peter] She's been
in better moods.
Whoever you are,
stay out of this.
You have no idea
what's at stake.
I'm afraid I do, miss...
I'm called the Black Cat.
My name is Captain America.
You're Captain America?
But that's impossible!
Cat, you really have
to hear us out.
Talk fast, and then we'll
see how angry I still am.
Storm to base,
I've made contact
with those of this planet
who are rebelling
against the evil ones.
I've explained your plan,
but their leader wants
to speak with you.
This is General Korg.
My people are growing
restless and angry.
We are willing to
hold off our attack,
but not for long.
My team and I only need a day
to mount a rear stealth attack
on The Red Skull's stronghold.
Can you give us that?
No, I can only
give you ten hours.
If you're not there in time,
I must attack without you.
Spider-Man,
that won't give us enough--
We'll be ready.
You have my promise.
Then it is agreed.
We will await your signal.
I realize that you
are supposed to be in
charge, Spider-Man,
but I disagree with your plan.
We're already shorthanded
with The Fantastic Four
off launching a separate
attack on Doctor Doom.
You know we have to cross
miles of treacherous,
deadly wasteland
to launch our assault
on the Skull's rear flank.
We can't do it in ten hours.
We have to do it.
Let me get this
straight, Spider.
You brought me to this
planet without my permission,
and now you want me to
go on a suicide run?
I just wish somebody would have
the courtesy to ask me first.
[tense music playing]
It's a good thing
this lab has what I need
to make more webbing.
I think I'm gonna need it.
Cat's been avoiding me.
I guess I'll have to be the
first one to say something.
Cat, I hope you're
still not angry with me.
I certainly am.
I'm sorry!
Look, I didn't bring
you here so we could fight.
Why did you bring me here?
I needed your support, Cat.
You know how I think.
You know how I like to operate.
You and I work like a team.
I just thought--
That I'd make you feel better?
Why do you always think you're
the only one who's important?
I left two young
heroes back on Earth
who need me too.
Do you think it was fair to them
to snatch me away just
to hold your hand?
Spider, won't you ever grow up?
Well that's gotten things
off to a wonderful start.
[tense music playing]
Iron Man, what's happening?
[Tony] It's a sandstorm!
I estimate another five minutes,
and the atmosphere will
render the vehicle useless.
Woops, guess I was wrong.
Hang on, we just lost our power!
The engine is clogged with sand.
We'll have to walk.
My suit may fail like
the hovercraft if I fly.
Uh, I think I'll walk too.
[lava gurgles]
[Spider-sense squeals]
Another quake!
[explosions echo]
If it gets any worse,
it might be wise
for us to turn back.
That's not an option!
We keep moving.
[Peter voiceover]
Boy, you almost sound like
you know what you're doing.
The fact is,
Moe probably does a better job
of leading the Three Stooges.
[tense music playing]
Smythe, I can only
spare one moment
from planning my
attack on the rebels.
Why did you send for me?
I thought you'd want
to see this right away.
Behold, my latest creation.
The Cyber Skull.
Brilliant.
Brilliant!
I have a little surprise
of my own, Smythe.
[Alistair] Doctor Otto Octavius?
The doctor here
has kindly offered
to share his technology with us.
Yes, I ran into a little
trouble with Doctor Doom.
He coveted my kingdom, Octavia,
and he annexed it to become
part of his new Latveria.
Now I find I must
make new friends
who will help me
regain what I've lost.
And so we shall.
As soon as you
enhance my new robot.
Yes, I will begin immediately.
Are you really going
to help Octavius
regain his kingdom?
Of course not.
Keep a close eye on him, Smythe.
As soon as he has
given us what we want,
let me know, I will
dispose of him.
Doctor, I find it
difficult to believe
that you work as a
servant to The Red Skull.
Ha, Otto Octavius serves no one!
As soon as I have
my kingdom back,
you might want to consider
me as your new employer.
Hmm, I see.
[lava gurgling]
Spider-sense, danger!
Look out!
[Felicia grunts]
You all right?
No, I think my power generator
just got damaged.
[Peter] This whole area
is full of seismic activity!
I should take the lead.
My Spider-sense will
at least give us
some warning of danger.
That's an excellent idea,
Spider-Man.
Black Cat and I will
take up the rear.
I was just wondering
how a beautiful young
woman like you, I mean,
how did you come to
be the Black Cat?
Oddly enough, it's your fault.
What?
It began years ago,
the beginning of World War II.
My father, as a young boy,
was hired by The Red Skull
to steal the Super Soldier
formula that created you.
Captain America!
Were you able to
retrieve the information?
They weren't Nazis,
you're trying to get me
to betray my country!
You're the Nazis!
When he realized how
evil The Red Skull was,
my father escaped
from the Skull
without giving him anything.
My father was the only
person in the world
who possessed that formula.
But one day, a villain known
as the Kingpin captured him
and forced him to
reveal the secret.
Wilson Fisk!
What is the meaning of this?
Felicia Hardy.
Allow me to introduce
you to your father.
As a test of my
father's truthfulness,
the formula was used on me.
That's how I became
the Black Cat.
So you see, anything you can do,
I can do as well.
Hmm, or better.
Amazing!
I can honestly say I've never
met a woman like you before.
[Peter voiceover]
Me and my big mouth.
Why didn't you just set
them up on a date, Spidey?
What am I feeling here?
Watch it Spidey,
if you lose your cool,
we're all done for.
[tense music playing]
[Peter] So that's
The Red Skull's fortress?
[Spider-sense squeals]
Something's wrong,
everybody on the alert!
[rocks rumbling]
[Felicia gasps]
Run!
[tense music playing]
[Tony] No, I'm losing power!
Hang on my friend.
Hang on!
Lizard, you go first!
I'll secure Iron Man,
then you can pull him up!
[screams]
Hang on, Cat, I've got you!
Whoa!
Cat, hold on, I'll pull you up!
Doc, I'll shoot you a line,
give me a hand.
Thanks, Doc.
That was too, too close, Spider.
[Steve] What's wrong
with Iron Man?
My power,
I've got to recharge.
[Peter] Well how
long will that take?
At least ten hours.
But we don't have ten hours!
Can you at least walk for now?
No, you see without power,
I can't even breathe.
In reality, I'm very
much an invalid.
My suit keeps me alive.
I'm sorry,
I never would've guessed.
Perhaps I can
reroute the circuitry
and bypass his flight systems.
That might work.
Good, do it.
How much time do you need?
An hour.
Doc, you only have 30 minutes.
How are you doing?
[Tony] Science is saving
my life once again.
If it wasn't for the
protection this suit gives me,
my heart would have
stopped beating years ago.
And I thought
I had problems of the heart.
Spider-Man, I can't hold
the rebels off any longer.
Are you in position for
your attack on the fortress?
[Peter] We will be, soon.
Soon is not good enough!
You promised
you'd be ready now!
We will attack without you!
All right then,
we'll do our best
to get to the fortress
in time to help you.
Rebel forces, move in!
[explosions echo]
[Peter] While the rebel forces
have them occupied out front,
we go in the back door.
Iron Man, can you
make it up the cliff.
-No.
-Spider-Man,
I've give him enough power
to climb and fight,
but not enough for full flight.
You and I may have to help him,
so stay close, let's go!
[explosions echo]
Magnificent!
The Cyber Skulls withstood
their laser cannons!
-What is that?
-[alarm blares]
Our rear security
has just been breached.
Someone has managed to get
through the Sea of Vapors!
Incredible!
Incredible indeed.
You assured me Smythe,
that no one would ever be
able to get to this fortress
from that direction!
Do something!
I'm activating the
Guardian Slayer now.
[Spider-sense squeals]
[Peter] Uh oh!
-[explosion echoes]
-Whoa!
[Felicia screams]
[Peter] Hang on!
[Red Skull]
What is happening Smythe?
There's a damage light on.
The robot no longer
responds to my commands!
The Guardian's
protective shields
seem to be down, who is that?
[explosion echoes]
Great shooting Iron Man.
We'd better get going.
Do something, Octavius!
Or you'll never regain
your precious land!
[explosion echoes]
[Peter] Gentlemen,
and I use the term loosely,
stop right there!
[explosions echo]
Look, up there!
I won't let him get away!
Cat, we've gotta help
the rebels!
The robots are pounding them!
Sorry Spider,
you don't need me now.
[Peter] Give it up Smythe,
you have no chance
of succeeding.
[Felicia] I have
to avenge my father.
This is gonna surprise you,
web-slinger.
-But I agree.
-You do?
Octavius and Red Skull
would spend an eternity
fighting for this planet.
I simply wish to get
back to my father,
and you are the only
ones who can get me home.
If what you're
telling us is true,
help us save those
rebels out there.
I should be able to
deactivate those battle robots
with a few keystrokes.
The Red Skull must
have had Octavius
install an encrypted code
to deny entry to the
self destruct sequence!
Let me see if
I can crack that code.
[explosions echo]
[Steve] Spider-Man, hurry!
Power of the wind, heed my call!
[Tony] Look!
That can only be Storm's work.
She's bought me some time!
You!
Why do you pursue
me so diligently?
You're not going to
get away this time.
This is for my father,
John Hardesky,
and all the others
that you've deceived.
[screams]
[Peter] I think I've got it!
[explosions echo]
[rebels cheering]
-Good job Spider-Man.
-Thanks.
Now we can go after
The Red Skull.
Right Cat, Cat?
She must have gone while
we were watching the battle.
Oh no, we've gotta find her!
[Otto] Sorry to disappoint
you again, feline.
Follow me,
there is an escape pod
at the end of this passageway.
Tell him to let her go,
Red Skull,
and maybe I'll let you survive.
Ah, but I've grown
quite fond of this Cat.
Move away, Captain America,
if you value the girl's life.
Shoot him, shoot him!
Thanks.
[tense music playing]
[explosions echo]
[Felicia screams]
I can't believe it.
We almost had him.
I'm sorry, I know how much
you both wanted The Red Skull.
Getting our Cat back
was much more important.
To all of us.
[Peter] Cat, I am sorry
that I brought you
here against your will.
-I'm not.
-You're not?
I know I was really angry,
but here I am fighting alongside
one of the greatest
heroes of all time.
Yeah, Cap is quite a--
I wasn't talking about Cap.
You Spider,
you're quite a leader.
I wouldn't want to have missed
sharing this action with you
for all the world.
-Thanks.
-But, I, but--
Any luck Morbius?
No, Blade.
The vampires have all escaped,
and there is no sign
of the Black Cat.
I fear the Black Cat
may be in dire peril.
No, I can't explain this,
but there has always been
a spiritual link
between her and me.
I sense that she
is in good hands,
and those hands will
deliver her back to us,
safe and sound.
No matter what.
[theme music playing]
♪ Spider-Man, Spider-Man ♪
♪ Radioactive Spider-Man ♪
♪ Spider-blood, spider-blood ♪
♪ Radioactive Spider-blood ♪
♪ Spider-Man ♪