[upbeat rock music]
♪ Spider-Man ♪
♪ Radioactive Spider-Man ♪
♪ Spider blood
Spider blood ♪
♪ Radioactive spider blood ♪
♪ Spider blood
Spider blood ♪
♪ Radioactive spider blood ♪
[explosions booming]
[growling]
♪ Spider-Man ♪
[Stark] I'm sorry, Dr. Ohn,
but your interdimensional
portal research
is simply too dangerous
to continue.
Please, Mr. Stark, reconsider!
Interdimensional technology
has been my-- my life's work!
I am truly sorry.
We'll find some new
project for you to work on.
I don't think so,
Mr. Moneybags Stark.
You're not going
to stick me on some--
some bathroom tissue
improvement team.
I have got bigger fish to fry!
[Kingpin]
Dr. Ohn, I presume.
Please, step
inside and avail yourself
of the simple comforts
of my automobile.
Oh, uh, thank you.
But I don't usually--
Doctor, where is
your scientific curiosity?
I have a proposition
I do not think you can refuse.
Good heavens, all this for me?
I-- I don't understand.
I am fascinated
by your time dilation portals.
I believe there's
a lot of money to be made
with this new technology.
Oh, yes, of course.
Money.
Now, tell me, Doctor,
have we a bargain?
[footsteps]
-Doctor?
-[woman] Dr. Ohn.
Hello.
I'm Dr. Sylvia Lopez.
[Kingpin] Dr. Lopez recently
joined my team of scientists.
She, too, was seeking
greater reward for her efforts.
She wants to work with you.
Well, Ohn, what do you say?
Do you accept the position?
Hello.
I will take that as a yes.
You've certainly
given that little man
enough big toys to play with.
That "little man" is going
to make me invincible.
Imagine, with these
interdimensional portals,
the world will be at my mercy.
And, as an added pleasure,
I will be able to eliminate
the biggest threat
to my organization: Spider-Man.
[carnival music]
[riders screaming]
You know, I can hardly believe
you're the real Peter Parker.
For the last month,
you've been so attentive.
Paying attention to you
isn't the hardest thing
in the world to do.
[thinking] Especially
when a certain web-head
doesn't come between us.
It's been so quiet lately.
I've barely had to fire a web.
Take that,
you ugly monster!
[Felicia]
That's not a monster.
It's a goblin.
And I think he's kind of cute.
Really?
Felicia, you never
cease to intrigue me.
-[pop]
-A winner!
Oh, marvelous.
I hoped we might be able
to get through one day
without some kind of spider
coming between us.
Jason, I'm sorry.
I can't help feeling the way
I do about Spider-Man.
Neither can I.
Well, at least,
he hasn't been making
any unscheduled appearances
in your life lately.
No, he hasn't.
Maybe it's time I start
appreciating somebody
a little more reliable.
[Ohn] Ready, Sylvia?
Ready.
[beeping]
It's working.
You're brilliant!
Yes, I am rather, aren't I?
Don't get too close!
[Ohn] Don't worry.
It's perfectly safe.
I'd stake my reputation on it.
-[screams]
-Jonathan!
[electricity crackling]
[portal booms]
[Peter, thinking]
What on Earth?!
Stark promised to end
his interdimensional research.
So if he isn't
behind this, who is?
[riders screaming]
Peter, look!
Peter?
He's run off again.
Whoa! Where am I?
-Help!
-Huh?
Spider-Man! Help!
Who the heck is that?
Got to snag him with my-- No!
Aah! Get these things
off me!
How did I get here?
It'll take me an hour
to web back to the carnival.
Mary Jane will think
I abandoned her again.
A great month as Peter Parker
screwed up in five minutes
as Spider-Man.
And no one can explain
where these mysterious holes
are coming from.
[Sylvia] Jonathan!
I did it.
I made it back.
What happened to you?!
Well, I'm not sure exactly.
When I was trapped
between dimensions,
I somehow became a magnet
for these loose portals.
I was terrified, until I
realized that I could control
the portals with my mind.
Watch this.
[Sylvia] Incredible.
Wait, there's more.
I can be here,
or here,
or here before you can blink.
Jonathan, that's amazing!
I couldn't have done it
without you.
You see, I think,
possibly, that is, well,
I've grown quite fond of you
over the last several weeks,
Sylvia.
Oh, Jonathan, I... I...
I nearly forgot.
[reporter] There are
still no explanations
for this bizarre phenomenon,
but New York has been
thrown into a panic
by these miniature black holes.
What have I done?!
I've got to repair
the damage I've caused
before someone is hurt!
Come on, now!
Let's have no more of that!
Can't leave you alone
for five seconds, can I?
Well, that seems to be the lot.
Dr. Lopez, you are being
surprisingly vague.
I need more information.
That is the bargain you've
made with the Kingpin.
Success!
I've got holes in my pocket
right where they belong!
Jonathan,
Fisk just called from his car.
He's on his way.
We've got to tell him
what's happened.
Do we?
I wonder.
All my life, I've been kowtowing
to money-grubbing fatheads
like Fisk!
Please, Sylvia,
we must keep my secret for now.
So I take it your
experiment was a success.
Uh, yes and no.
It has yet to be perfected.
I want that technology,
and I want it soon.
Do I make myself clear?
Crystal!
Safety first, though.
Wouldn't want to have
an arm lopped off
by an unstable portal, would we?
[laughs nervously]
[Kingpin] Do your work
and do it quickly.
Well, that went well.
Jonathan, you have to tell him.
What else can you do?
Plenty.
First, we must put this
where he can't get
his money-grubbing
little fingers on it.
Then we set up
a laboratory of our own.
All we need is a little capital.
And that's no problem.
Not for, ta-da, The Spot!
[Peter] What did you
find out, Dr. Connors?
Your hunch was correct.
Those spots were actually
time dilation portals
similar to the ones
Stark created.
They share some properties
with black holes.
They absorb radio waves,
for example,
but they lack the super gravity
of their big brothers.
Stark has issued
a public statement
saying he's not to blame.
It's a fascinating puzzle.
[thinking]
Fascinating and deadly.
Maybe what Doc Connors
said about radio waves
being absorbed
could be the answer
I'm looking for.
Hey, MJ, Liz!
Wait up!
Mary Jane, let me explain.
Liz, you may tell Mr. Parker
that I think he should
permanently disappear,
because we don't have
anything left to talk about.
Peter, Mary Jane says--
I heard. MJ, please.
Mary Jane!
Happy to see me, friend?
-Harry?
-Oh, you do remember.
I thought you might have
put me out of your mind
when you stole MJ away from me!
Thanks a lot, pal!
Listen, Harry, I-- Listen!
This is just not my day.
[sighs]
[portal rumbling]
Maybe Spider-Man
will have better luck.
-[alarm bell ringing]
-[spider-sense tingling]
A bank robbery?
On Sunday afternoon?
What kind of nut would break
into a bank in broad daylight?
Oh, that kind of nut.
How the heck did
he get in there?
Shouldn't you be the mascot
at a fire station or something?
Whoa! Ooh!
[The Spot]
Did that hurt?
Sorry, I'm
in something of a hurry.
Bit of a goof,
setting off those alarms, eh?
Uh, yeah.
Say, I hate to interrupt,
but are you planning on stealing
that really big pile
of money there?
Uh, yes, rather.
And how exactly
were you planning
on doing that, Mister, uh...
Call me The Spot.
And I was planning
on doing this!
You're the wacko behind
those time dilation portals.
There's no need for all this.
I'm not a criminal.
I just need a little capital
for my research!
Those portals
are too dangerous!
You've got to stop using them!
Nonsense!
Oh, boy. Not this again.
Forgive me.
I usually abhor violence.
Oh, puh-lease!
Well, that does look
like a sticky situation.
Let me give you a hand,
or, actually, a foot.
Gotcha!
There.
Even though this guy
is trouble,
I'm gonna have a hard time
taking him seriously.
But he is serious.
A scientist, in fact.
It's time I started thinking
like a scientist, too.
If I adapt my tracker to
broadcast at radio frequencies
and zero in on wherever there
are gaps in the wave pattern,
any gaps would
indicate a portal.
And wherever there's a portal,
The Spot won't be far away.
[Felicia] What are
we doing here, Jason?
I have to do a little shopping.
Oh, my.
It's beautiful.
It's for you.
Felicia, will you marry me?
Oh, Jason.
Oh, you're so sweet.
It's just that I--
[The Spot]
What a beautiful store.
Nice setting for a robbery.
Now, let's get down to business.
-[tracker beeping]
-A distortion.
Right here!
Oh, Miss!
I know this seems
frightfully rude,
but, the fact is, your ring
looks very expensive and--
Get away from her, freak!
It appears you need
a lesson in manners.
You're the one
who needs a lesson.
Spider-Man!
[The Spot] What are you,
some kind of masochist?
Maybe I need spot remover.
-Are you hurt?
-Felicia?
No, I'm okay, but I've got
to go after that creep.
-Spider-Man, wait!
-What is it?
I haven't seen you in weeks.
Are you avoiding me?
Avoiding you?
Look, Felicia, I thought
I'd made this clear.
We can't let there
be anything between us.
My life is just too dangerous,
and I care too much for you
to jeopardize yours.
I'm sorry.
So am I.
Sylvia, I'm back!
Sylvia?
[Kingpin] And you say Dr.Ohn
controls this power at will?
[Sylvia]
Yes, he needs no machine.
Fascinating.
We must find a way to duplicate
his powers in others.
Understood, Kingpin.
-[Ohn] No.
-Jonathan?
You've betrayed me to Fisk.
Why?
He's a powerful crime lord
known as the Kingpin.
He owns me, Jonathan.
I care for you too much
to watch you try
to take him on and fail.
But, Sylvia,
don't you understand?
I can take him on!
I won't fail!
Mr. Fisk, I'm here to terminate
our contracts with you.
[guns cocking]
You were saying?
Your stooges are
nothing to me, Fisk!
You have no power!
I am the new Kingpin.
I very much doubt that, Ohn.
The Kingpin always holds
the trump card.
Sylvia!
[Kingpin]
You will do exactly as I say.
I don't think I have to tell you
what happens to her if you fail.
Ohh.
-Another time dilation hole.
-[beeping]
It's got to be Ohn!
Bingo!
Well, that's odd.
He's just standing there.
Ah, he said you would come
if I stayed
in one place long enough.
I'm sorry.
[Spider-Man] Sorry?
-For what?
-For this!
Talk about being
in a tight spot!
Gotcha!
[groaning]
Wait a minute.
Those holes are
a two-way street.
Got to trust my spider-sense.
-[spider-sense tingling]
-Now!
[The Spot groaning]
Well, that hit the spot.
She's doomed!
[Spider-Man] Who's doomed?
Listen,
it's clear you're no killer.
What's going on?
Maybe I can help.
[Kingpin] Ohn!
You have done it!
You defeated Spider-Man.
Now for a little unveiling.
[Spider-Man grunts]
The reports of my demise
were greatly exaggerated.
You will wish they were not!
[Kingpin grunts]
I have waited
for this for some time.
What do you have in mind?
A pie-eating contest?
[growling]
Approximately 2%
of my body mass is fat.
Allow me to show you
what 350 pounds of muscle
is capable of.
[dramatic music]
[Landon]
You blundering fool!
-You've destroyed us all!
-[rumbling]
That buffoon left
one of his portals open!
If it keeps growing,
it could pull
the entire Earth into it,
starting with New York!
Can you close it, Ohn?
No, it's too big, too powerful.
Wait, I know this technology.
It should theoretically
be possible
for you to use your original
equipment to boost your power.
Spider-Man is a scientist?
Even if that does work,
we'll need to get
much closer to the portal.
I can't affect it
from so far away.
Gentlemen, perhaps I can
be of some assistance.
[engines roaring]
Why would you help them?!
There is no profit to be made
in the destruction
of the planet.
It is very bad for business.
We're in position.
[Spider-Man]
Think you're up to this?
I haven't the foggiest,
but it's my mess.
I'd best clean it up.
Let her rip!
[electricity crackling]
It's no use!
I need more power!
What are you doing?!
[Spider-Man] I'm channeling
the ship's power into him.
It might do the trick.
-[electricity crackling]
-[The Spot] It's working!
I'm forcing it closed!
[Sylvia] What's wrong?!
The portal
stopped shrinking!
The ship's power isn't enough!
-Ohn!
-Jonathan!
[The Spot] Leave me be!
My abilities increase
exponentially in the vortex!
I don't understand!
I can close the hole,
from inside!
Sylvia, I'm sorry!
-I must!
-I won't let you go!
I love you!
[portal booms]
[thinking] Poor Ohn.
Poor Sylvia.
They sacrificed everything to
repair the damage they caused.
Well, at least in the end,
those two had each other.
Maybe making
sacrifices isn't so bad,
as long as you're
with the one you love.
Maybe it's time I made
a big sacrifice for Mary Jane
and stopped being Spider-Man.
-Hey, tiger. We need to talk.
-[Peter] Mary Jane.
You know,
it can be a real strain
on your relationship
to have your boyfriend run off
when big trouble starts brewing.
[Peter] I know,
and I think I've just decided
not to do it again, ever.
No way, handsome.
That's your job.
I guess I have to try
to keep little details
like that in mind,
especially since I love you.
[Hobgoblin chuckles]
The Kingpin of crime indeed.
He had that awesome power
in his possession,
and he let it slip
through his fingers?
The fool!
Don't worry.
You shall be handsomely paid.
I like having a spy
in the Kingpin's organization.
I will possess that
dimensional portal technology,
and when I do...
[laughing maniacally]
[upbeat rock music]
♪ Spider-Man, Spider-Man ♪
♪ Radioactive Spider-Man ♪
♪ Spider blood, spider blood ♪
♪ Radioactive spider blood ♪
♪ Spider blood ♪
♪ Spider-Man ♪