[Mary Jane]
Previously onSpider-Man.
[Spider-Man] The Hobgoblin
and the Green Goblin
destroying the city?
You! Finish the job, Hobgoblin!
[Spider-Man] Uh-oh!
Hey!
He looks like Carnage,
but in my costume!
Well, dear clone.
Tell me what's going on!
[Madame Web] They're from
parallel realities.
[Spider-Man] The Carnage
Symbiote bonded with
Scarlet Spider's clone and
drove him completely insane!
[Beyonder] Spider-Carnage will
detonate a disintegrator bomb.
The blast will
destroy every reality.
You must stop Spider-Carnage.
Kingpin! It's Spider-Man!
Five of him!
Stop them!
My mutation disease!
What's happened to him?
Man-Spider! We're in trouble!
[theme music playing]
♪ Spider-Man, Spider-Man ♪
♪ Radioactive Spider-Man ♪
♪ Spider blood, spider blood ♪
♪ Radioactive spider blood ♪
♪ Spider-Man, Spider-Man ♪
[orchestral Spider-Man theme]
Spider-Carnage has not
detonated the device yet.
We are powerless to stop him.
How can I help?
[dogs barking]
[Man-Spider roars]
[Scarlet-Spider] Spider-Man!
[groans]
There. It's complete at last!
Then activate the
mind control device.
Look! We've run out of time!
[Spider-Carnage]
And now, world--
Guess again!
You! How did you get
up here so quickly?
-[grenade screeches]
-[Spider-Carnage screams]
[Spider-Man] A good magician
never reveals his tricks!
You did it! You transported
the powerless one there!
Yes, but if he fails,
I'm now too weak to help him.
Stop! Let me go!
All is lost.
-No!
-I will use the last
of my power
to transport Man-Spider away,
then to stay alive, I must
return to our home dimension.
If Spider-Man prevails,
and we survive,
tell him The Beyonder said,
"Thank you".
[Man-Spider roars]
[Beyonder yells]
There! I've
reprogrammed the device!
And I shall rip this imposter
limb from limb for
causing us a delay!
Kingpin,
I know he's promised to
build you a machine
to take over
people's minds, but he's really
built a bomb that
will destroy us all!
These lies won't save
your pathetic life.
It's the truth!
Spider-Carnage has duped you!
Don't listen to them!
[explosion]
What was that?
The dish stolen from
J3 Communications
is magnifying the
dimensional transporter!
A huge portal has been opened!
[Kingpin] A portal?
Spider-Carnage is going to
detonate a bomb within it,
and that explosion will be
magnified through time
and space
until it destroys all reality!
Shut up!
What? Why would you do this?
Ever since that spider bit me,
the world has misunderstood me,
and tormented me!
Now it's my turn,
I'm gonna obliterate you all!
-[laughs maniacally]
-[Kingpin yells]
[beeping]
Guys, I think he just
started the countdown!
I'll try to reprogram the bomb,
you disable the transporter.
How can I help?
You keep your head down,
and stay out of trouble.
That I can do.
No!
Spider-Man, I found it!
It's over, Spider-Carnage!
No!
Hey!
Stop him!
We still have to
disarm the bomb!
Even without the transporter,
it's powerful enough
to blow up this building!
-Where?
-What?
-[Kingpin groans]
-You did it!
You saved reality!
We all did it,
it was a team effort.
Where's The Beyonder?
He had to go back to
our home dimension.
The strain was too
much on his powers.
Madame Web brought you back
just in the nick of time!
I still have a few
tricks up my sleeve.
Behold, I'm sending
him to a jail.
The authorities will find
him under lock and key.
At least it's all over now.
Alas, it isn't.
Observe the window.
[Spider-Man] It's him again!
[Scarlet Spider] And it looks
like he's up to his old tricks!
But I thought--
He has transported himself
into another alternate reality.
Which one?
I am trying to search
through infinity. Ah!
The Peter Parker
Science Foundation?
Wait a minute! That's my world!
I've gotta go back!
You cannot!
You are still paralyzed
thanks to your rash behavior.
Web, can you send
the rest of us there?
Only one of you.
Let me go!
No. I'm the leader here,
I'll go.
My own powers are waning,
I can't place you there
with pinpoint accuracy,
and you will be on your own.
I understand.
Good luck, something tells
me you're gonna need it.
Amazing!
It looks and feels so much
like the New York
of my reality!
-[crowd cheers]
-Whoa!
The people love me,
no wonder my
armored alter-ego
is so arrogant!
I should be in charge of this
group, 'cause I never lose!
Hey, wait!
A laser built right
into your armor?
It's my own design.
In my world I'm a
multi-billionaire, aren't you?
He probably didn't know the
meaning of the word failure!
If I don't find
Spider-Carnage quickly,
this paradise isn't
gonna be around
for my armored
alter-ego to return to.
There you are! How dare you
keep us waiting so long!
Whoa, wait, stop!
Hey, can't your fiancé
give you a kiss anymore?
[Spider-Man voiceover]
Great, Parker.
Here you're engaged to
somebody you don't even know!
I'm sorry, Mrs, uh--
Funny, Peter,
the name's Gwen Stacy.
Look Mr. Comedian, I'll go
down to let them know you've
finally arrived, then you
can make your grand entrance.
My grand entrance?
It's not every night the city
opens a science
center in your name.
And wearing the old costume
tonight, nice touch.
Very nostalgic.
Wait right here!
Sorry to miss the party,
I've gotta go look
for a maniac!
Where do I start,
I'm running low on time.
Come on, where are you?
Oh, this is almost too obvious!
Okay, I'll bite.
[whirring]
Oh boy, well, my alter-ego did
say he owned his own robot!
Robot!
Destroy that intruder!
Spider Sense! Danger!
[Spider-Man grunts]
I'm done for!
Wait, on the side of its head!
Those look like
sonic receivers!
This robot can hear me,
and if he's Spider-Man's,
he'd respond to verbal
orders from Spider-Man!
Robot! Put me down!
No! I command you
to destroy him!
Spider-Carnage must
be controlling him
from some hidden place,
put me down!
No! Listen only to me!
Put me down!
Me!
Uh-oh.
Probably couldn't
handle get orders
from two Spider-Man voices,
now I know
Spider-Carnage is here!
[woman] Hello?
What? I don't believe it!
Mary Jane! It's me, Peter!
Sorry, but I was wandering
around, I heard some noise,
Oh, I'm so happy to
have found you at last!
Whoa handsome,
I appreciate the attention,
but take it easy,
you're wrinkling the latest
fashion from Paris!
M.J., don't you remember
how much I love you?
How much you what?
Mary Jane!
Oh it's you Mr. Parker,
I had no idea you two were--
Aunt Anna,
it's not what you think,
we hardly know one another!
That's not true! I love you!
I am so happy to
hear you say that!
Come on, Aunt Anna,
there's a party trying
to get started in the ballroom,
and without me there,
it's bound to be a flopperoo!
Chao, tiger!
Catch you on the upswing!
Mr. Parker, do come and
visit us sometime soon!
[Spider-Man voiceover] That's
not the Anna Watson I know,
that's not the Mary Jane
I know either.
Care to explain what
that was all about?
-Gwen!
-Did I hear correctly?
-No!
-You love that Watson woman?
Let me explain!
[man] Hey everybody!
We found him!
Peter! Where the heck
have you been, boy?
You had your old
godfather worried!
[Spider-Man voiceover]
My godfather?
Hey, where's that
cool Spider armor?
You know Peter,
he's always full of surprises.
Why don't we all go down
and greet those people
who paid good money
to see the star here?
[Spider-Man voiceover] If I get
trapped down there all night--
I'm afraid I must take
Mr. Parker away
from you for a moment or two.
Wilson, what are
you talking about?
As Mr. Parker's lawyer,
there are a few important legal
papers that he must sign.
[Spider-Man voiceover]
The Kingpin is my lawyer?
At least it gets
me out of here!
Listen, you guy go out there
and have a good time,
I'll be right along.
Thank you for your time, Peter.
No problem, Mr. Fisk, truth is,
I needed a little
distance from them all.
Huh?
Allow me to grant you
your wish.
Well, if it isn't
my old clone friend.
Spider-Carnage has
explained everything
to me about the
alternate dimensions.
Now I see an excellent
business opportunity.
Using him to replace you,
he and I can take over all
Peter Parker's resources
and rule this empire together!
[Spider-Man voiceover]
I should've guessed
that Wilson Fisk
couldn't be trusted!
Listen, Fisk!
He's not interested in
ruling the world, he wants to--
Ignore the slimy clone, Fisk!
Now, what is our next step?
Let us join the party as
if everything is normal.
We can eliminate
him later tonight.
Hey, are you All right?
Yeah, but how did
you know that--
Something my beau worked
up so we'd never be apart.
It can find his heartbeat
from a million miles away.
How did you know
that Peter Parker
downstairs wasn't me?
He's as nutty as a fruitcake!
A girlfriend notices
little things like that.
You don't know the half of it.
Now, how do I get
you out of here?
And I just want to say,
that I intend
to see that you all
get from me,
what you deserve.
And I'm gonna see that
you get what you deserve!
[crowd exclaims]
[crowd screams]
[man 1] There's two of them!
[man 2] And they're gonna
tear each other apart!
Soon, my dear clone,
you'll be nothing more
than a bad memory.
Gwen, now!
[Spider-Carnage shrieks]
Fisk! What's wrong with you?
[Gwen yells]
I'll show you!
I'll destroy you all!
If anyone follows me,
she'll be the first to go!
Destroy us all?
You were tricked, Fisk,
not for the first time either!
I've gotta stop him!
No! That's what
I'm doing wrong!
I have to remember,
that my enemy here is me!
Maybe I shouldn't be
trying to defeat him,
maybe what I need to
do is understand him.
I'm forgetting everything that
Madame Web taught me
over all these months!
Why isn't he trying
to save my girlfriend?
What's wrong with him?
Be quiet! He is using
his head at long last,
something you may
never learn to do.
That's it! He's confused,
and there's only one
person who can help him
remember right from wrong!
If I've guessed right,
this reality
is the only place where that
person might still be found.
What are you doing?
I'm gonna destroy all reality,
even if I have to do it
one dimension at a time.
This heartbeat tracker
really works!
The lady was right!
I told you not to follow me,
or she'd get it!
What're you planning to do?
I devised a way to amplify
the dimensional transporter
only this hole won't lead
to another dimension,
I've re-calibrated
the interphase inhibitor.
You've deliberately
created an imbalance?
Then whatever get
sucked into that hole--
Right! It will cease to exist!
In minutes, this hole
will grow large enough
to suck this city
into oblivion,
then the entire planet!
You can't do something
this horrible!
It just isn't in you,
because it isn't in me,
and you are me!
I'm more you than
you'd ever imagine!
And maybe you're being
overtaken by the symbiote,
there's only one
way I can find out.
I need to reach the real
Peter Parker inside of you,
the one who cares about
the people around him!
He's gone for good!
Is he?
I know he won't talk to me,
but I brought along somebody
that he might want to talk to.
No, it can't be!
Peter? It's me, Uncle Ben.
Uncle Ben?
I've been told everything.
Is it really you?
Did you think things
were gonna be easy, boy?
Huh? Did you?
[Peter grunts]
But I can't do it, Uncle Ben!
You know my rotten luck!
Nonsense!
Boy, good or bad luck is
nothing but the
right or wrong mix of
opportunity, preparation,
and confidence.
Now I know you're
prepared because
I had a hand in that, we're
looking square at opportunity!
I know you've had
a very bad time,
but in this dimension,
I'm here for you
and no matter what, I love you.
I, I love you too, Uncle Ben!
I love you too!
Do you remember what
I taught you about great power?
Yes!
With great power there must
come great responsibility!
Peter, there's an
evil inside you,
it's your responsibility
to the world,
and to yourself to expel it!
Get rid of it!
Please!
Yes! I must! I see that now!
[Peter screams]
What's wrong with him?
He's trying to get
rid of the symbiote,
but it's not giving
up without a fight!
Fight it, Peter!
Fight it with
all your heart and soul,
your real heart and soul!
-[Peter screams]
-[Symbiote roars]
It won't work! Too painful!
I'm sorry for all
the bad things I did!
Forgive me!
Forgive meeeee!
No!
He's gone! Vaporized!
I should've stopped him!
No, he did what he thought
was best for himself,
and for all of us.
You did fine tonight, Peter,
I'm proud of you. I'll miss ya.
And I'll miss you too,
Uncle Ben.
But I'll always have you,
in my heart.
Way to go, boss!
You did well, Spider-Man!
I am proud of you.
The others can go home,
but there is one more place
that you must visit.
Where to now?
[clears throat] I think
she means my reality.
What am I gonna find there?
More than you can ever imagine.
I don't believe what
you're telling me!
In your reality,
I'm a character in fiction?
Yep, and I'm an actor
who plays you on TV.
But there's someone here
I knew you had to meet.
He's the man who created you,
for fans all over the world!
[man] And I said to Jack,
"What if his skin turns green?"
Uh, [clears throat] excuse me,
I'm looking for some
guy named Stan Lee?
What? Spider-Man?
Uh, Pam, hold my
calls for a while.
I think I've finally
gone crazy!
[Stan] Oh, man! Wow!
You know Spidey,
I've always wanted
to experience
real web-slinging!
And I've always wanted to
appreciated as a real hero!
It seems you've made
me into one! Thanks!
Hey, don't mention it!
After saving all of reality,
where do you go from here?
[Spider-Man]
To find Mary Jane,
my Mary Jane!
I've been told she's still
alive! I can't wait to see her!
You know,
for so long I've thought
that I never got
any breaks, but now,
after all I've been through,
for once,
I like my life, I like myself!
And for the first time ever,
I wouldn't want to change
anything about me!
Gee, you're definitely
not the same
guy I've been writing
about all these years!
Well Stan, we all have to
grow up sometime I suppose,
even us characters of fiction.
Spider-Man, it's time to go.
Who is that exotic lady?
Oh her? She's my ride.
It's been great meeting
you, take care of yourself.
You too, Spider-Man!
Farewell and good luck!
Wow, I wonder how I'm supposed
to get down from here.
I suppose I could wait
for the Fantastic Four
to drop by and give me a lift.
[Spider-Man] That Stan Lee,
he's quite a guy.
I think he's truly special.
Well Madame Web, where to now?
Face front, true believer,
we are going to find
the real Mary Jane Watson!
What?
It has been a long,
hard journey.
And I think you are finally
entitled to some happiness.
Amen to that, dear lady,
amen to that.
[theme music playing]
♪ Spider-Man, Spider-Man ♪
♪ Radioactive Spider-Man ♪
♪ Spider blood, spider blood ♪
♪ Radioactive spider blood ♪
♪ Spider-Man ♪