[narrator]
Previously on Spider-Man.
Cletus Kasady, come out now!
-[Terri screams]
-[Cletus laughs]
Freeze!
When I become Venom once more--
This Venom thing never existed.
-Mordo!
-Yes, Master Dormammu?
[Dormammu] When I ordered
you to retrieve the symbiote,
I did so because it was
about to reproduce, and it has.
There is now another.
-I'll take it!
-It must take you!
Now there is Carnage!
[both groan]
Together again.
-Eddie?
-We are Venom now!
Now, we are poised to obtain
the last piece of the puzzle.
Dormammu sent us to get this.
[Spider-Man]
There's another symbiote?
Eddie, are you going
to fight injustice?
Between the two of us, Dad,
there won't be enough
left of Spider-Man
to fit in a matchbox.
[upbeat rock music]
♪ Spider-Man ♪
♪ Radioactive Spider-Man ♪
♪ Spider blood
Spider blood ♪
♪ Radioactive spider blood ♪
♪ Spider blood
Spider blood ♪
♪ Radioactive spider blood ♪
[explosions booming]
[growling]
♪ Spider-Man ♪
[Carnage cackling]
Guess I could say you
axed for this, web man.
[laughs]
Stop! Spider-Man is ours
and ours alone.
-[growls]
-[groans]
-[Venom growls]
You may be our spawn,
but that won't keep us
from destroying you.
Stop this petty squabble.
The master commands
you to bring back
the interdimensional machine.
The dread Dormammu made
you both what you are,
and you agreed to help him.
Do you dare
go back on your word?
The heck with my word, man.
I'm gonna bring this back.
I can't wait to see the horrors
Dormammu's gonna commit
when he gets here.
[Carnage laughs]
[Venom] We must keep our word.
[Ashley moans]
Then hurry, fools.
You were lucky this time.
Mordo won't always be
around to save your hide.
Eddie, come back!
-Eddie!
-After them!
We've got to get
that probe back!
-Well, well.
-[groans]
This is certainly
more than I expected.
I'm finally gonna see
who you really are.
Hold it! I think
he looks good in a mask.
What are you doing?!
I'm a journalist!
[War Machine]
You're also trespassing.
Trespassing?
That's ridiculous!
Here's my press badge!
I don't see no stinking badge.
What are you, nuts?
You'll hear from my lawyers!
I've got the best!
Thanks.
-[groans]
-Hey, you've been hurt.
Spider-Man, please,
get War Machine
to a doctor immediately.
Tony, I'm sorry
I let you down.
Nonsense, my friend.
You softened them up.
Now, I'm gonna send someone
in to finish the job.
Who's he gonna send?
A guy named Iron Man.
[triumphant music]
We're even, Mordo.
And now, we can get back
to unfinished business.
That suits me.
[groans]
That was good, for an old guy.
Stop!
I cannot leave my world
unless an equal amount
of life force
is sent here to replace me.
We don't have time for this.
Our debt is paid in full.
Ingrate.
I'll drag him back here.
Stop!
I don't need Venom anymore.
You will be sufficient
for this assignment.
[thinking]
Kasady's insane mind has bonded
so completely
with his symbiote
that he refers to himself
as "I" instead of "we."
He has to be stopped.
Where will he strike next?
-[people screaming]
-[laser blasting]
[Carnage laughing]
Units three and four, move in!
[explosion booms]
I hate having
my meals interrupted.
[grunting]
Just like sardine cans.
Snack time!
[cackling]
What is he doing?!
-[Carnage groans]
-I know that loud sounds
and intense heat
can stop a symbiote,
but that's no help
to me right now!
[growls]
[Spider-Man groans]
[groans]
I hope your life force isn't
as useless as your life.
[cackling]
No, why isn't it working?!
Carnage. Your body can hold
no more life force.
Come back so that
you can be drained.
I'll catch you
later for dessert.
[groans]
How do we stop that horror?
He's only half the problem.
Venom's still out there,
too, somewhere.
[Aunt May] Thank you for coming,
Anna, Mary Jane.
Oh, I worry myself into fits
when Peter's out this late.
Now, May, you stop that!
If you don't,
you'll make yourself sick.
I swear, Peter is going to be
the ruination
of that poor woman.
-[doorbell rings]
-Hush.
Maybe that's him now.
I'll get it.
Parker here?
No, no, he's not.
Why, I remember you.
You're Peter's friend
from The Bugle, Mr. Brock.
He's there right now.
Really?
Thank you.
Gotta go now.
Gotta get down to The Bugle.
Mr. Brock, I remember you, too,
and I know Peter
isn't your friend.
What do you want with him?
Inquisitive, aren't you?
And beautiful, too.
No wonder we remember
that he loves you so much.
Peter loves me?
[Jonah] It's all your fault
those freaks got
that device, Stark.
Your security staff
is incompetent!
And rude, too!
They just have low tolerance
for yellow journalism.
Yellow?! How dare you use
that kind of language
in a description of me.
-[Ashley] You used
the word "freaks."
-[click]
These are human beings
who have an illness.
You make it sound like
they have the flu, Dr. Kafka.
These monsters must be stopped!
[snarling]
And you know who's
at the bottom of all this?
Spider-Man.
He's the one who's attracting
this trouble and has-- Huh?!
[snarls]
Why, if it isn't our old boss.
-[Jonah groans]
-Perfect appetizer.
Ah, and here's the main course.
This is what we call service.
No! Eddie!
-You?!
-Eddie, listen to me.
It's the symbiote
that compels you to violence.
You must fight its influence.
Yeah, Brock,
d-d-d-don't hurt me.
I've always thought
the world of you.
[snarls]
-Stay away from him, Kafka.
-Eddie.
Venom's appearance here
caught me off guard.
[grunts]
But Dr. Kafka's
bought me some time.
You see, you are strong enough.
You can reject it.
No, Ashley.
Our other is too strong!
Spider-Man!
[snarls]
Raaaah!
[screaming]
[groans]
Goodbye.
[Ashley] Eddie, no!
If you destroy Spider-Man,
the alien will take
over completely.
[groans]
[screams]
Ohh! Can't afford
to lose him again.
[growls]
You were going to follow us?
What made you think
you'd live long enough?
[groans]
-[lasers zapping]
-[groans]
[Iron Man]
That was for War Machine.
This is for me.
[groans]
My head, it's on fire!
Eddie, no!
Help me!
Fight the symbiote.
-Shut up!
-Aaah!
[growling]
I owe you one, Iron Man.
-Thanks.
-Don't mention it.
Any friend of War Machine's
is a friend of mine.
Come on, let's see
if we can catch him!
This is taking forever!
I got people to torment.
Transfer is almost complete.
And then we can
say hello to hothead?
I mean, Dormammu?
The urn is not yet full.
We need the energy
of a few more lives.
Only a few? Too bad.
[Carnage cackling]
Where are they?
Maybe Madame Web would know,
except that weird old crone's
never around when you-- Hey!
Old crone, am I?
[Spider-Man] Look, I
don't have time to talk.
I've got to help Iron Man
find Venom and Carnage.
Hold your tongue and watch.
You see,
time has already passed.
Wh-- Where am I?
Ravencroft?
We-- No, Ibrought you back.
You were right about my other.
When I spared Spider-Man,
the symbiote,
it nearly tore apart my mind.
Right now,
it sees you as a threat.
No, but I can't!
Keep watching.
I can't imagine how you
must be suffering, Eddie.
I can stand it.
I can stand it for you.
Ashley, I know you could
never love a monster like me.
But I could love the man.
We must separate you
from the symbiote
-before it's too late.
-[groans]
No!
Fight it, Eddie.
You must!
Ahh!
The alien is getting stronger!
Then we mustn't waste time.
I have an associate
who can help us.
[Spider-Man]
Where are they going?
- Maybe I can--
- Be quiet.
You can keep watching.
I conducted tests
on this piece of the symbiote
I got from Spider-Man
a few months ago,
and I've learned
that a combination
of high-range sonics
and infrared heat
might separate you
from the alien organism.
I'll take any chance
to be human again!
[Madame Web] And now,
time passes again.
[Spider-Man] How do you do this?
[Madame Web]
Transcend time and space?
It's simple, I practice.
[computer beeping]
[agonized groans]
Aaah!
We can hold it in
this containment unit.
Sporadic sound pulses
will keep it dormant.
Are we, am I--
Yes, you're Eddie again,
and only Eddie.
[Spider-Man]
That's one less symbiote
I have to worry about,
but what about Carnage?
Silence.
[Spider-Man] It's Kasady.
Where is he?
He's waiting for
a mutual acquaintance of yours,
a strong woman.
-Who?
-Remember this:
You must
keep your friends close
and your enemies even closer.
[Spider-Man] Wait, what's
that supposed to mean?
She said Carnage was waiting
for a mutual acquaintance,
but who does he
know that I know?
Oh, no!
There is one person.
Good evening, Detective Lee.
I told you we'd meet again
to settle old accounts.
-Aah!
-[Carnage snarls]
[laughing]
My, aren't we inhospitable?
[Spider-Man] I'll show you
inhospitable.
[Carnage] Aw, you've
ruined my surprise!
-[Spider-Man groans]
-This is Lieutenant Lee.
I need backup
at my place on-- Aah!
[Carnage] I'm gonna
shred you to pieces.
[phone rings]
Hello?
Where? I'll be right there.
[phone beeps]
Ashley, where are you going?
Kasady's just been spotted
near Columbus Circle.
You're not thinking
of going there, are you?
Kasady's also my patient, Curt.
I took an oath.
At least, let me go with--
Eddie needs your help now.
Take care of him for me, please.
[Spider-Man]
He's jamming the cartridges!
The pressure's too much!
Hothead gets your life force,
-but I get the rest of ya.
-[gun clicks]
[Terri] Hold it right there!
Noooo!
-[Carnage screams]
-Got to make sure
he takes the brunt of it.
[Carnage groans]
[Spider-Man groans]
We needed one more life force.
[screaming]
And you're elected!
[Ashley] Kasady!
If one person deserves this
more than him, it's you!
Yes, this is
the last life energy we need.
I must bring you
back immediately.
[chanting in alien language]
[Carnage laughs]
I've got to find out
where they went, but how?
Remember, a warrior
keeps his friends close
and his enemies closer.
[Spider-Man[
The only friend I can think of
who can help me now
is Iron Man.
But as for keeping
my enemies closer,
who was she talking about?
Brock.
I need Brock's help!
He knows where Mordo's lair is.
He's been there, as Venom.
[Eddie groans]
Ashley?
-Dr. Kafka?
-Easy, Eddie. She's not here.
What?
Where-- Where is she?
I tried to stop her.
-Where?!
-Kasady.
She went to help Kasady.
-No.
-I heard on the news,
she's-- she's vanished
with that lunatic.
[Spider-Man] Brock, if you
really love that woman,
you'll tell us where Mordo is.
You want to go up
against Carnage,
Mordo, and that--
that fiery freak?
You don't stand a chance.
-I've gotta--
-Brock, you're still weak
from the separation.
There's nothing you can do.
You're right,
there's nothing I can do,
but there's plenty Venom can do.
[Spider-Man]
You can't be serious.
[Iron Man] Easy, friend.
The last thing the world needs
is to deal
with that monster again.
Besides, if you re-bond
with the symbiote,
you'll never survive
another separation attempt.
That'll be the end
of Eddie Brock.
And if I don't,
it'll be the end of Ashley!
[Spider-Man]
We're wasting time, Brock.
All I want is for you
to tell me where they are.
Okay, okay. You win.
[Eddie grunts]
[Venom] At last,
we are together again!
[Spider-Man]
Brock, remember, Ashley.
-[groans] Ashley.
-Put Spider-Man down!
[Venom snarls]
All right, all right.
Not that you'll be much help,
but I can't do this alone.
We're partners, for now.
[thinking] Partners?
Am I out of my mind?!
Going up against Carnage,
Mordo, and Dormammu
with this lovesick sociopath
is not my kind of buddy movie.
But now
I see what Madame Web meant
about keeping my enemies closer.
[lightning crackles]
There. [cackling]
Full at last.
As soon
as the portal clarifies,
release the contents
of the urn.
-Hey!
-Sorry to drop in
without an invitation.
This is for meddling
in my affairs.
Careful! They're
some kind of mystic volts!
[Iron Man] Didn't think
they were spit wads.
Nice try, Mordo.
Now, you've earned
a taste of my repulsor rays.
[groans]
Tell me!
Where is she?!
[groaning]
Ashley.
Carnage, release
the contents of the urn.
All right, hothead.
We've been waiting for ya.
Do your stuff!
[loud rumbling]
Master!
At last, a new world
and new souls to consume!
[Spider-Man] Sorry, pal.
Dinner's canceled.
That worked real well,
you wall-crawling worm.
I've got another idea.
You think you and Iron Man
can hold them off without me?
Ha! Who needs you at all?
[Iron Man groans]
Now, if I can reverse
the polarity of this thing...
-[Dormammu] No! No!
-[Spider-Man] Sorry, pal.
You're going back
to the old neighborhood.
[groans]
Now, that's two I owe you.
-Who's counting?
-Noooo!
Turn up the power.
No! Mordo!
[groans]
Ashley.
Ashley, you all right?
-Eddie--
-[laser zaps]
Aaah!
I'm so glad you're safe.
You re-bonded
with the alien to save me!
Oh, Eddie.
I can feel
the symbiote taking over.
I'm a monster again.
Don't leave me, Eddie!
-[Iron Man groans]
-[Carnage growls]
[grunts]
[Mordo]
Carnage, the probe!
Oof!
[groaning]
Brock! Help me!
There is no Eddie Brock!
Now there is only Venom!
[Venom snarls]
[screaming]
[Iron Man] You got him!
Now shut it off!
I've been trying,
but it won't close!
Dormammu's created
some kind of energy link
between himself and Carnage.
It won't break.
We'll have to send
Carnage through, too!
[screaming]
I'm not going in there alone!
Ashley!
Eddie!
I'll always love you!
All is lost, for now.
Hey, that belongs
to Stark Industries.
If Tony Stark has a problem,
he can take it up with me.
He couldn't bear to live
as a monster in a world of men.
Perhaps what's left
of Eddie will find peace
in that other strange world
he's in now.
I hope so, Doctor.
I honestly do.
He may have been
my greatest enemy,
but in the end, he proved
to be my greatest ally.
Oh, please! Not this!
Not now!
I sense you're confused.
I am.
Who'd have expected Eddie Brock
to make a sacrifice like that?
You must learn
to expect the unexpected.
You yourself might soon have
to make such a sacrifice.
What are you preparing me
for anyway?
A horror,
a horror beyond belief!
Great.
I'm real glad I asked.
[upbeat rock music]
♪ Spider-Man, Spider-Man ♪
♪ Radioactive Spider-Man ♪
♪ Spider blood, spider blood ♪
♪ Radioactive spider blood ♪
♪ Spider blood ♪
♪ Spider-Man ♪