[theme music playing]
♪ Spider-Man ♪
♪ Radioactive Spider-Man ♪
♪ Spider blood ♪
♪ Radioactive spider blood ♪
♪ Spider-Man ♪
[suspenseful music playing]
[gasping]
Where am I?
[tense music playing]
Stop it.
[screaming in terror]
Mary Jane.
We were made for each other.
Made for each other!
Oh no, you can't
run away from me.
[cackling eerily]
[Mary Jane screaming]
[gasps]
You can't go home, dear.
[cackling]
[screaming]
[Peter] Mary Jane!
-What is it?
-Huh?
Oh.
Nothing.
Nothing, I must have
fallen asleep, that's all.
You had the dream again,
didn't you?
The one you've been having
every night this week.
It's just a dream, Tiger.
Don't look so worried.
Hey, look, we made it!
Niagara Falls. [chuckling]
I can't believe this old
van actually got us here.
It's about time.
This is probably the longest
delayed honeymoon in history.
Sorry, M.J.
[Mary Jane]
It was well worth the wait.
I assure you, Mr. Parker.
But I still think we
should've used the money
on some other luxury,
like our rent, maybe.
A bonus from Jameson is
so rare, Mrs. Parker.
It demands to be spent
on something special.
M.J.?
Yes, Peter.
I just want you to know that--
[gasping in alarm]
What's wrong?
Our boat, it's leaving!
No, it's the last
one of the day.
Come on!
It's no use, we've missed it!
Grab my arm.
[ship horn blaring]
[crowds cheering]
We were both all-American
in track and field.
[whimsical music playing]
All-American?
Well, what's the point of
being married to Spider-Man
if you don't get
some of the perks.
I have to share
Spider-Man with the world.
Right now I want Peter Parker
all to myself.
Now, what was it you were
about to say back in the van?
This.
Our marriage,
the last few weeks with you,
this honeymoon,
these have been the
best times of my life.
I don't ever want them to end.
They won't, tiger.
Not as long as I'm
around to love you.
[bright violin music playing]
[Hydro-Man] Let go of her, now!
-[grunting]
-[gasping]
Morrie Bench?
It's not possible.
I saw you evaporate
into nothing.
[chuckling]
Everything is
possible for me, Red.
I told you nothing
could keep us apart.
Not even oblivion.
[Mary Jane] Morrie!
Leave my husband alone!
Husband?
You think I'm gonna let
this wimp stand in my way?
Uh-uh, we were meant
to be together.
I'm taking you back
to New York, Red.
We're going my way.
[Mary Jane screaming]
[tense music playing]
Mary Jane!
[dramatic music playing]
[gasps] Mary Jane!
[gasping]
[Peter voiceover]
All that's left is her jacket.
With Bench's ability
to move through water,
they could be miles away!
But Bench did say he was
taking her back to New York.
I've gotta get there
as fast as possible.
Come on, van,
don't let me down now!
Tall buildings
at last.
[resolute music playing]
Now I've got
to look everywhere
that Hydro-Man might go.
Places near water.
Where is she?
I've been searching
for hours now
with no sign of them.
If anyone can help me
Terry Lee can.
[Anna]
Why for heaven's sake
didn't you come
to us right away?
Or to the police.
I don't know.
I thought I could
find her myself.
I didn't wanna waste time.
[gasping] The police
are a waste of time?
Oh, I just knew something
like this would happen.
Anna, please be calm.
No, May, I won't be calm!
You're my best friend,
and I hate to have to
say this in front of you,
but Peter's actions are
directly responsible
for Mary Jane's disappearance.
How dare you!
How dare you accuse
me of harming
the one woman in the world
I would give
anything to protect!
Calm down, Parker,
that's not gonna
get us anywhere!
The best thing you all can
do right now is go home
and let us do our job.
And, please,
let's keep Spider-Man out
of this altogether, okay?
[Peter voiceover]
Terry Lee is right.
Spider-Man is useless.
Useless!
My wife's life is on the line
and I seem powerless
to stop that maniac!
Am I too frightened
for her safety
to think clearly?
Why can't I come up with
a plan or find a clue?
[door knocks]
Come in!
Felicia!
Oh, Parker, I was on
my way to the airport
when I heard over the
news what happened.
What can I do to help?
Do, there's nothing to do.
Bench can be anywhere.
Do anything.
All we can do is sit here and
feel the pain of losing her.
[Felicia] I can't believe
I'm hearing this.
This isn't a time to give up.
What about Spider-Man?
You've kept him in the
public eye for so long.
Isn't it time you asked him
to do something for you?
Please, Felicia,
I need to be alone right now.
I am sorry.
I didn't mean to.
You must be under
a lot of pressure.
But don't give up on
finding Mary Jane, Parker.
If you do,
you'll be giving up on
the best part of yourself.
[Peter voiceover]
She's right.
I've let despair consume me.
I've gotta stop thinking
like Peter Parker husband
and start thinking like
Peter Parker scientist!
Parker, if you're not
going to find Spider-Man,
then, maybe, somebody
ought to find him for you.
Somebody like the Black Cat.
[resolute music playing]
[harp music playing]
Oh, don't you ever
sleep, detective?
Not when there's a missing
person out there somewhere.
And we've got a big,
fat clue right under our noses.
But we've tested it five times.
We need fresh minds.
Maybe, you don't require sleep,
Detective Lee,
but some of us do.
All right!
All right, Betty, we'll get
a fresh start in the morning.
[clank]
-Did you hear something?
-Huh?
Like what?
Oh, never mind,
I guess it is getting late.
[unsettling music playing]
[Peter voiceover]
I've been concentrating
so hard
on my work,
I lost track of time.
Classes are going
to start soon.
I don't want any
overachieving science majors
interrupting my work.
I'm betting Bench
in his liquid form
passed through M.J.'s
jacket during the abduction.
Bingo!
To look
at these tray sediments
I'd say it's mud,
but it's so
consistent, artificial.
I wonder--
[Debra] Hey, who
locked this door?
[Peter voiceover]
Oh great, perfect timing.
[Debra] Who's in there?
Open this door!
Go away, Debra!
Peter Parker, is it you?
I've got experiments running.
So do I.
Just give me five
minutes, Debra.
No way, Peter.
You've gotta play by the
rules like everybody else.
Hey!
Hey, some nut has barracked
himself in the lab.
Open this door!
[knocking on door]
[Peter voiceover]
These hydrocarbons
aren't refined at all.
They're crude oil, that's it!
I know where he's taken her!
Please, let there be
some left.
Yes, my special batch of
coagulating web fluid.
It came in handy
when I tackled Hydro-Man
the last time.
[banging on door]
All right,
you self-centered,
egotistical--
Now, where on earth did he go?
Found you, Spider, at last.
The only place you
might find unrefined oil
is either a tanker or a drill.
Bingo!
It's the only one within
a hundred miles of here.
[resolute music playing]
[jet boat engine roaring]
Spider, Spider!
[Hydro-Man] Mary Jane!
Stay away!
You stay away from me!
Come back here, Red.
It's time we had a little
heart-to-heart talk.
[unsettling music playing]
[laughing]
[Mary Jane screaming]
[grunting and screaming]
[Mary Jane] Oh, Peter.
Mary Jane, are you okay?
[Hydro-Man screaming]
Oh no, you don't, Spider-Man!
This is my party,
you're not invited!
Look out!
Stop this, Bench,
before someone gets hurt.
[chuckling] Someone like you!
I can't be hurt, Wall Crawler!
Or didn't your attempt
to destroy me last time
convince you!
You did that yourself, Morrie.
Or have you forgotten all that?
Here's something else
you might have forgotten.
[Hydro-Man grunting]
Well, that's the
last of my web fluid.
It won't hold
him for long, honey.
We've gotta get you
out of here.
No way, I can't leave you.
Look, M.J., I can't
fight him with you here.
I'll worry about you
and make mistakes.
Please, let me do this alone.
All right.
I understand.
Be careful, Tiger.
I love you.
[menacing music playing]
I don't weaken quite so easily.
I have an entire ocean
beneath me to feed my power.
Mary Jane won't get far.
And with her safely
off the platform
I can really cut loose!
Oh great, he wasn't
trying before?
[Hydro-Man laughing]
[crane crash booming]
[grunting]
[laughing spitefully]
[tense music playing]
[grunting]
Oh no, no, no, no,
don't worry, Wall Crawler.
You won't drown, look.
I see.
As soon as the platform
sinks a few more feet,
you'll be fried!
Meanwhile, I'll be
hunting down Mary Jane.
Oh yes,
it's been real nice, ha!
No use, it won't budge!
[dramatic music playing]
[grunting]
It's no use.
I've lost.
Mary Jane, forgive me.
Come on.
Cat, thanks.
Sorry, I cut it so close.
But I had to find
a boat to get me here.
Unfortunately,
that last step is a doozy.
I've got no way
to web over to it.
We've got to jump.
The water is still electrified.
Even with my legs
I don't think we can--
We've got to!
[dramatic music playing]
[explosions booming]
Perfect.
Just ease her in, ma'am.
Who says there's
never policemen
around when you need one?
Whatever you say, officer.
Am I ever glad to see you.
[Officer] Tell it
to the judge, miss.
[Mary Jane] Hey, wait!
What are you doing?
That was a little too close.
Hey, don't take
this the wrong way.
But just how did
you manage to be here, anyway?
Peter Parker's wife is missing.
I thought since you
sometimes work with Parker
you'd be looking for her, too.
But why are you
back in New York?
What about Morbius?
Is he here too?
No, he's still overseas.
Why aren't you with him?
The short answer is
I wanted to get away.
Morbius never lets
up on his mission.
He and Blade are obsessed
with ridding the
world of vampires.
I couldn't handle that
obsession anymore.
I needed a break.
I needed to be with somebody
a little more lighthearted.
Somebody like you, Spider.
I'm sorry, Cat,
it's too late for that.
Much too late.
Well, I certainly
feel a bit foolish.
Cat, I'm not the footloose,
fun-loving guy you knew.
I understand.
Your friend's wife is
in terrible danger.
I just hope Mary Jane
is smart enough
to stay ahead of that creep
until we catch up them.
[Spider-Man] So do I, cat.
Grand theft is no
laughing matter.
Oh, the boat. Well, I just--
Just get in the car.
[Mary Jane]
No, you don't understand.
[unsettling music playing]
No sign of them.
They can't have gotten far.
We search.
We search until we find them.
[Mary Jane] Then I lowered
myself into the boat
and ran into you guys.
How many times do
I have to tell you?
Just until we hear
the truth, miss.
The clerk is checking in to--
Don't you get it?
Bench is still out there.
He won't stop
until he finds me!
Well, then, it's lucky
you're safe in a building
full of policemen.
Yeah, lucky me.
[Officer] The truth.
His name is Morrie Bench.
Yeah, she's here.
But she's being questioned.
Visitors aren't allowed.
I think you can make a
little exception in my case.
[officer screaming]
[laughing]
What on earth was that?
I think I've got
a pretty good idea.
Come on!
[dramatic music playing]
Hey, let's go!
Run all you want, Red!
You won't get far.
[Black Cat]
Still no sign of them.
This is hopeless.
Nothing is hopeless.
Mary Jane knows
I'm looking for her.
She'll find a way to signal me.
What I really need is a weapon.
Hey, wait.
Potassium perchlorate.
Why does that
sound so familiar?
Oh, they're so beautiful.
How do they get those
wonderful colors.
Oh, it's very simple.
If you burn strontium nitrate,
you get a brilliant red light.
And for blue light,
you use potassium perchlorate.
That's it!
Mrs. Parker,
you're getting to be
as much of a science
wiz as your husband.
Strontium nitrate,
where are you?
[gasps]
[suspenseful music playing]
Come on out, Red!
You're only delaying
the inevitable.
[tense music playing]
Oh, nice try, yeah, yeah.
Yeah, but that won't
work this time, Red.
Besides, I've got plenty
of water to feed me.
And I'm not about
to fall to pieces.
[Mary Jane voiceover]
That's why I've got
something else in mind.
That's odd.
What is?
[Black Cat] I've never seen
pollution like that before.
Brilliant!
Mary Jane,
you've done it again!
Spider!
It's only a matter of
time before I find you!
[grunting]
Sorry, Red, but now
I'm really steamed!
I don't mean to
sound like Dr. Ruth,
but, Morrie, is it
possible the lady is trying
to tell you something
by evaporating you,
boiling you,
and fleeing in terror from you?
I am sick of your interference!
Mary Jane, get out!
I can hold him here.
[dramatic music playing]
[Hydro-Man cackling]
Whoops, I guess I'm
just all thumbs.
Cat, this isn't your fight!
Don't be greedy.
It's our fight!
I realize I'm not attracted
to adventurous men,
despite their
dedication to causes.
But because of it,
maybe, it's time for me
to become a bit more
dedicated like them.
Would you two just shut up
and stand still!
[explosion booming]
[Black Cat grunting]
Cat!
Just you and me, pal.
Are you all right?
Hard to believe I came here
to rescue you, isn't it?
[explosions booming]
[urgent music playing]
This time I'm not leaving
anything to chance.
I'm finishing you off myself.
Bye-bye, Spider-Man.
It's time to flush
the bug down the drain!
Oh no!
No! [screaming]
Oh no, is not possible?
[dramatic music playing]
You can't do this to me!
Peter, what's happening to me?
Mary Jane.
Mary Jane?
How could you?
I mean, how on earth did you--
I don't know.
I really don't know.
[theme music playing]
♪ Spider-Man ♪
♪ Radioactive Spider-Man ♪
♪ Spider blood ♪
♪ Radioactive spider blood ♪
♪ Spider blood, spider blood ♪
♪ Spider-Man ♪