["Spider-Man Theme Song"
by Joe Perry playing]
♪ Spider-Man ♪
♪ Radioactive Spider-Man ♪
[guitar break]
♪ Spider blood ♪
♪ Radioactive spider blood ♪
[guitar break]
♪ Spider-Man ♪
[Norman] Toomes,
you're leading your company
into financial ruin,
funding research
to reverse aging.
A fantasy developing technology
to defy gravity?
A pipe dream!
And what about this
science grant
you're giving away tonight?
More dollars
uselessly squandered.
Gentlemen of the board,
let me buy Toomes aerodynamic.
Fold it into Oscorp
and make a greater profit.
Don't be led by someone
who so old and feeble,
he can't even attend
meetings in person.
[Toomes, over telephone]
How dare you?
You are nothing
but a corporate vulture.
You think anti-gravity
is a pipe dream?
Huh, mark my words, Osborn,
there's only room for one
bird of prey in this company,
and I am it.
[Norman] Toomes, are you
threatening me?
Toomes?
Toomes, are you there?
[Spider-Man thinking]
Look at that kid.
Not a care in the world.
Me, I can't survive
without a daily dose
from the neogenic
recombinator.
What was that? the Hobgoblin?
[kid] Ahhhhh!
It works.
[Spider-Man] Get away.
Kid, are you OK?
From rollerblades to geriatrics
in seconds, but how?
This none of your business.
[Spider-Man] Fine, but don't
blame me if you get a splinter
in your way.
Who is this flying flamingo?
Uh oh.
[grunting]
[Vulture] OK, Spider-Man.
Let's see how you like my
cutting-edge technology.
No. No. Not long enough!
He got out of range.
Whoever he is, he's fast.
[kid groaning]
What... What happened to me?
I don't know, but I want
the name of the vitamins
you took this morning.
What kind of technology
did that flying freak
use on this kid?
I need to absorb the energy
of a fully grown adult
to give myself more time.
Then I'm coming for you,
Osborn, I am coming!
Got to get moving
if I'm going to make it
to the awards ceremony in time.
[screaming]
[groaning]
[Norman] I'll win the board
vote tomorrow.
Toomes?
He's too feeble to launch
any kind of a fight.
-He's doomed.
-[wind gushing]
What the devil?
Who... Who are you?
wha-- what would you want?
[Vulture]
Your head, Osbourn. [laughs]
[man] And now to award
the Toomes grants
for scientific achievement,
the winner is Dr. Curt Connors
and Empire State University.
[Peter thinking] Yes,
neogenics technology lives,
and so can I.
Thank you, thank you.
To help me further
neogenic research,
I have chosen
as my lab assistant,
Debra Whitman.
[gasps]
Sorry, Peter, next time show up
for class once in a while.
[Peter thinking]
Once again, my academic life
takes a dive
because of my web slinging.
[Vulture]
I know you're in there.
Come out.
Time is wandering
I cannot waste.
[laughing]
When we started this,
I was sure Michael Morbius
or Peter Parker would win.
-No way. You're the best.
-[camera clicks]
Parker,
are you trying to blind me?
Congratulations, Debra,
I'm so glad it was you.
Flash, this evenings
reminded me so much of Michael,
I'm drained.
Would you take me home, please?
Sure thing, Felicia.
Great work, Deb. See you later.
Uh... Right... later.
Poor Felicia, I guess
she's still not over the loss
of Morbius,
but, hey, congrats, Whitman.
It looks like
you've got it all now.
I don't have everything
I want, Peter.
[Peter thinking]
Well, how do you like that?
I think Deb is actually
interested in Flash.
The big goof
doesn't realize it either.
Ah, poor Deb.
Ah, well,
I know how she feels.
I still can't believe
I practically flung Mary Jane
into the arms of Harry Osborn.
MJ, uh, I can't go out tonight.
[Mary Jane, over telephone]
Parker, what's with you?
You've been avoiding me
for days.
-[sobbing]
-[Peter] Felicia...
I miss Michael so much.
I'll do whatever I can
to bring Michael back,
I promise.
Mary Jane, are you OK?
Harry, how would you like
to take a gal to dinner?
I'd love to.
[Peter thinking]
I need some air.
Uh-oh, trouble.
[Norman] Please.
[Spider-Man]
That bird guy?
With Harry's dad?
Bad combination.
Who are you?
Much like yourself,
I'm a vulture,
but more dangerous.
Your stock is about
to take a plunge, Osborn.
Ahhhhhh!
[Spider-Man]
Don't go anywhere.
You again?
Stop meddling in my affairs.
[Spider-Man]
Not till you explain
that aging trick.
I hate mysteries.
[groaning]
No, I need more time.
More time.
[Norman] Please don't leave,
get me down.
[Osborne]
I must have more time.
[Spider-Man]
No, I can't catch him
in the flesh,
but maybe I can
catch him on film.
[Peter thinking]
The Vulture, huh? I wonder
who he is when he's at home.
Oh, computer
enhancement might help.
Now, let's see ifThe Bugle 's
image databank can ID him?
It's got a 30%
probability of error,
but it's the best I can do.
Adrian Toomes,
is that possible?
[Debra] Isn't it exciting?
We finally got a lab
sophisticated enough to house
all of our neogenic research.
Flash, that's not a video game.
Sorry.
Look, when can I set up another
tutoring session with you?
I'm afraid Miss Whitman
will be too busy
for that sort of thing.
I'm Arthur Avis.
Mr. Toomes' new
second-in-command.
Mr. Toomes told me you were
intelligent, Miss Whitman.
He forgot to tell me
you were beautiful as well.
Why, thank you, Mr. Avis.
[Arthur]
Please, call me Arthur.
I hope I'll be seeing
a lot more of you,
and no offense,
a lot less of you.
What an arrogant,
egotistical...
[Peter]
You know what they say, Flash?
It takes one to know one.
Peter, what a surprise.
Are you here to see
what you're missing
by not being
Dr. Connor's assistant?
Hey, play your cards right
and maybe you can
wash Deb's test tubes.
Deb, I don't think
this place is safe.
Have you noticed anything
peculiar going on?
Anything weird?
Peter, you are weird
and you're obviously
a sore loser.
Now get out. Both of you.
-I've got work to do.
-No, but I am not with--
[Peter] Deborah, wait, I--
Now look what you've done,
flea brain.
Flash, I'm worried about her.
I think somebody here
has a hidden agenda.
Oh, it's that Avis geek.
Did you see the way
that he looked at her?
Wait, why didn't Deb tell him
to take a hike?
Uh, probably because she wanted
to make you feel as jealous
as you made her feel
at the award ceremony.
What?
You should have seen how she
looked at you and Felicia.
She did, really?
Ah, but well, if somebody
as brain pumped
as Debra Whitman
ever see in a jock like me?
Hey, she definitely
likes you, pal,
so she can't be that smart.
[Toomes] Are you enjoying
my life, Dr. Connors?
Oh, yes.
Well, I'm sorry...
I didn't see you there.
Thank you for meeting with me.
I've been anxious
to discuss our plans
for neogenic research.
Neogenics is my hope
for the future.
And of course, your legacy.
Don't rush me
to the grave so soon.
Norman Osborn
is making that mistake.
He dares to take my company
from me, but he will fail.
[coughing]
Mr. Toomes, are you OK?
I'm sorry, Doctor,
but my time is short,
and you were available
to me now.
A man of your soon-to-be
advanced years
must avoid shocks.
So this neural neutralizer
will keep you safely paralyzed.
Surely as a man of science,
you can appreciate my plan.
Look, see my
beautiful talons.
They are the end result
of a lost technology
deciphered from
the tablet of time.
Got yourself a real
bargain there. A real bargain.
[laughs]
These and my anti-gravity wings
are the best weapons.
I have to crush Osborn quickly.
The very advances he scoffed at
will destroy him.
But I agree that
your life energy
will only give me
30 minutes of youth.
Osborn will expected me
to attack him again,
but I have a better plan.
Thanks to my corporate spies,
I'm going to find
his son, Harry.
[Spider-Man thinking]
Well, there's Harry.
We all know why he's here.
The question is...
why was Mary Jane so eager
to have me show up?
As if I didn't have
enough to worry about
with his human buzzard
circling over my head.
Maybe she's in some
kind of trouble.
Nah, with my luck,
she's going to tell me that
she and Harry have
a big announcement to make.
Peter, look at this.
It's a letter from my dad.
Your dad?
But, Mary Jane, I thought
he abandoned your family
when you were just a...
A kid.
Yeah, can you believe it?
I don't see him for years,
and now out of the clear blue,
he wants me to meet him
this Wednesday night at 8:00.
Why are you telling me this?
I need somebody
to be with me
when I meet him
for the first time.
I want it to be you.
You've lost both your parents.
If anyone can understand
what I've been through,
it's you.
But what about Harry?
Harry and I...
[man] Five minutes everyone.
Five minutes.
We'll talk after the play.
It's Goethe's Faust.
Not a lot of laughs,
but you'll love the tunes.
[thinking]
How do you like that?
Maybe there is a chance
for us after all.
[Mary Jane] In all my life,
there's nothing has given
my heart so keen
a pang of loathing
as his repulsive face has done.
Nay, fear him not,
my sweetest one.
[crowd gasps]
[Peter thinking]
Not again.
This isn't how we rehearsed it.
Osborn!
[crowd screaming]
You are mine!
Ahhhh!
No, please!
[Spider-Man]
What is it,
you and the Osborns?
Are you trying to
start a collection?
Sorry, guy, you just pretend
you're the lead in Peter Pan.
-Whoa...
-Aah.
Oh, Harry!
[beeping]
No time to finish.
I guess he had a cake
in the oven.
Mary Jane!
Oh...
And I thought Foust
might be boring.
Harry...
I was so worried about you.
The story of my life.
Save the world, lose the girl.
-[ringing]
-[Peter] Peter Parker here,
please leave a message.
-[beeps]
-Parker, I just saw
some creepy giant bird
land on Toomes' penthouse.
Was this what you were
trying to ask me about?
Well, anyway, I thought
I'd give you the story
before I call the cops.
Get over here
and bring your camera.
[screams]
Get over here
and bring you camera.
[screams]
Debra.
I should have stayed here
and kept an eye on her.
If anything's happened...
Huh?
Thompson,
what are you doing here?
Spider-Man. I was only looking
for someone. See?
For me? You shouldn't have.
No! For a girl
named Debra Whitman
who works in this place.
She didn't show up
for our tutoring session,
and now I find you here.
Something's gotta be wrong.
We have to find her.
-We?
-Yeah. You and me.
We make a heck of a team.
Remember when we faced
the spider-slayers together
and--
Flash, I remember, go home.
All right, you can count on me.
Good.
You can count on me
to be like you
and save the people
that I care about.
[Spider-Man] Debra?
Stop!
Great! I'm trapped
in a gigantic video game.
At least I don't need
any quarters.
A light sensitive grid.
Hooked into the gun,
it's tracking my every move.
Toomes isn't messing around
when it comes to security.
Let's see, if I use a little
geometry to my advantage.
Have to get the angles
just right.
There, this is the spot.
Good thing I'm a math whiz.
Spider-Man? Still alive?
The boyfriend.
He might come in handy.
[Spider-Man]
That disc, I remember
reading theoretical papers
published by Toomes medical.
I think they called it
a neural neutralizer.
-Huh, it pays to stay informed.
-Oh! Aah.
Spider-Man? Where's Toomes?
What did he do to me?
There's no time to explain.
Just get out of here.
[Debra crying]
Anybody there?
Debra?
Flash. [gasps]
No, don't look at me.
Debra, what's wrong?
What happened?
He made me old.
Please do something.
Help me!
Calm down. Don't worry,
I'll get you to a [stammers]
hospital or something.
He stole my life, it's over.
Don't say that,
I care for you too much
to lose you.
Wha...
What do you mean?
I guess I...
Debra, you're changing.
[Vulture] Out of my way, girl.
I need your boyfriend's youth.
His strength.
Uh-uh, you didn't say "may I?".
[Toomes] Leave me be.
I'm fighting for my survival.
You don't understand.
Nobody does.
You're all out to get me!
You got that right.
[beeps]
What did you just do?
I've activated
the self-destruct bomb.
Sixty seconds and this place
blows sky-high.
Release me and we'll both have
a better chance of escape.
[Spider-Man thinking]
He's not bluffing.
My spider sense
is going crazy.
-Well?
-No dice.
See, this works
on a superhero's brain, too.
[laughs]
Sorry, I came back to see
how you were doing, you OK?
Whoa.
Get out of here. Run!
Rescued by Flash Thompson.
How embarrassing.
No sign of Toomes.
Danger!
[screaming]
Thank you, my friend.
Your super-strength
makes me feel stronger
than ever before.
The night is young,
and so am I.
[laughing]
Now, let's see
what you look like
under this mask.
["Spider-Man Theme Song"
playing]
♪ Spider-Man ♪
♪ Radioactive Spider-Man ♪
[guitar solo]
♪ Spider blood ♪
♪ Radioactive spider blood ♪
♪ Spider-Man ♪