[upbeat rock music]
♪ Spider-Man ♪
♪ Radioactive Spider-Man ♪
♪ Spider blood
Spider blood ♪
♪ Radioactive spider blood ♪
♪ Spider blood
Spider blood ♪
♪ Radioactive spider blood ♪
[explosions booming]
[growling]
♪ Spider-Man ♪
[dramatic music]
[lasers whooshing]
-[children laughing]
-[upbeat music]
[portal whooshes]
Well, what do we have here?
You look like you can fetch
old Lenny some pocket change.
Tiger, I do worry.
I love you, and now that we're
together, I'm really happy.
But then when
I think back on Dormammu--
Come to me, trust me.
-Obey me.
-[flames crackling]
[Mary Jane]
And that cult.
This institution's purpose
is to make you
content and fulfilled.
[Mary Jane]
And Eddie Brock and Venom.
[sighs]
Now we're one,
and now you're gonna pay.
From now on, we call
ourselves Venom. [hisses]
[Mary Jane]
And before that, Hydro-Man.
-[water whooshing]
-Get away from her!
She belongs to me!
Do you understand?
I love you.
Tiger, I don't think
it's safe to be near me.
Mary Jane, these things happen.
It's New York.
Sometimes I feel
like you and I attract trouble.
Listen,
this is all that matters.
[romantic music]
I guess you're right.
Good, now stop worrying.
[Peter, thinking]
She's right about one thing.
As long as I'm Spider-Man,
our happiness will
be compromised.
Maybe it's time for me
to give up web-slinging.
Aw, who am I kidding?
It's not something I can
part with that easily.
[Lenny] How much can
you give me for it?
[pawn shop owner]
What is it?
Why, it's a digital
restitutional analyzer.
A servo-controlled
incendiary optometer.
Eh, it makes coffee.
Coffee? No kidding?
How's it work?
It's a simple matter.
Uh, you gotta hit
the slibber-flibber-gibbet
over here, then maybe, uh--
[beam whooshing]
Holy Toledo, what's that?
[wind roaring]
[pawn shop owner]
Turn it off!
[Lenny] I can't!
[people shouting]
Hey, what's the deal?!
Isn't that one of those things
we saw at the fair?
Whatever it is,
it's big news and--
I know, I know,
you've got to cover it,
but be careful.
Help!
Hold on there, old timer!
You two stay put here.
Now, if my guess is correct,
yes, it isthe time dilation
accelerator!
I just hope there's
enough power
left in this thing
to seal up that portal.
-Back off, wall-crawler!
-[spider-sense tingling]
-[laughs]
-The Hobgoblin!
That machine is mine!
What's the matter, Spider-Man?
Losing your grip
on reality? [laughs]
[dramatic music]
Have a nice trip! [laughs]
-[dramatic music]
-[wind roaring]
Now, that was too close.
Can't I ever be rid of you?!
Sorry I can't stick around,
but I've got things to steal.
No buildings around,
experiment time.
Hey [chuckles], it worked!
[Hobgoblin laughing]
[wind roaring]
Ooh!
Blasted machine.
This could have been
my-- my arm or, or-- or leg.
You must be running
out of power.
But I know
where there's more. [laughs]
[ominous music]
[stammering]
Are you nuts?
The Kingpin will find
out I'm spying for you.
Get me a power pack for
the time dilation accelerator,
and we won't need fear
the Kingpin ever again.
This is the last one.
The Kingpin ordered
us to stop making 'em
when he lost the accelerator.
The last one?
I don't think so. [laughs]
[reporter]
The city is still baffled
by the strange holes
which have caused valuables
to literally vanish
into thin air.
Thin air, my eye.
But Ohn and his machine
were lost in the vortex.
Guess who?
I see you've redecorated
since my last visit.
I can assure you
this will be your last visit.
I've got a proposition for you.
The time dilation accelerator?
Ooh, good eye!
Now, as you know,
this little baby
can revolutionize the theft
and smuggling business.
Why do you need us?
What I need is
a power pack for it.
It all becomes clear now.
You need my technology.
Exactly.
I was thinking of hitting
the Federal Reserve
gold repository.
Most appealing.
Just meet me here at midnight.
Be there or be square.
In your case, it would be
easier to just be there.
My time dilation accelerator
in the hands
of that indolent lowlife!
If only we knew who he was,
we'd be one step closer
to destroying him.
Perhaps that information is
accessible from an old friend.
[Jason] Felicia and I want to
thank you all
for coming to celebrate
our engagement.
This lovely woman has made me
the happiest man on Earth.
[Peter, thinking]
I'm trying to just be content
as Peter Parker,
but the Spider-Man in me
is still worried
about the Hobgoblin.
With that time dilation
accelerator,
who knows
when he'll pop up again?
Doesn't Felicia look radiant?
Well, maybe to you,
but I'm holding
the most beautiful girl
in the room.
I couldn't agree more.
Uh, Harry.
So you do remember my name.
That's silly, Harry.
You're my friend.
If you look up "friend"
in the dictionary,
it says nothing about stealing
away girlfriends.
[Peter]
Listen, I didn't steal--
But you did, and for that,
I can never forgive you, ever.
Thanks a lot, friend.
He's got to accept the fact
that I'm not
his girlfriend anymore.
I'm going to go talk to him.
Parker, what are you
doing here?
Why aren't you
developing those pictures
of that hole in the sky?
It's all taken care of,
Mr. Jameson.
-Peter!
-I--
Excuse me, Mr. Jameson.
I have to borrow Parker
to say hello to my fiancé.
Sorry, social obligations.
Jason, you remember
Peter Parker.
But of course. Wonderful
to see you again, Parker.
Whoa! My spider-sense
is going berserk, but why?
Peter Parker, it is so good
to see you looking so healthy.
Uh, hello, Mr. Fisk.
The Kingpin. He must have set
my spider-sense off.
I really must apologize
again for that little mishap
that put you in jail, my boy.
You have no idea
how deeply I regret it.
If you will excuse me.
Oh, Osborn.
Personally,
I find these soirees
to be ever so tedious,
but Felicia absolutely
revels in them.
Did she tell you she's
redecorating the east wing?
-[Jason droning on]
-[thinking] My spider-sense
was right about the danger.
I'm in danger
of being bored to death.
But I'll bet Fisk
and Osborn's conversation
just might be a bit more
enlightening than this drivel.
Uh, could you excuse me
a second, Jason?
Of course, old bean.
[Norman]
Let me get this straight.
The mighty Kingpin
asks my help?
Demands.
I need to know
the true identity
of a new associate of mine,
one with whom I am going to rob
the Federal Reserve
gold repository.
How would I know?
Because you created him.
He's the Hobgoblin.
Hobgoblin?
No, I don't want
to talk about him.
I don't want to talk
about any goblins.
-I need to go.
-Go you shall,
once you have
told me who the Hobgoblin is.
Leave me alone!
As you wish, but I cannot
make the same promise
about your son.
Meet me at Oscorp at 2:00 A.M.
I'll tell you everything.
[thinking] I'm gonna have
to abandon M.J. again
if I'm gonna stop
that repository heist.
Will Spider-Man always
keep coming between us?
So are you here
to wish me good luck?
Felicia! Uh, yes, good luck.
Do you really love
this Jason Phillips guy?
And why should
you care about that?
Unless you've got
a better offer.
This is crazy.
I can't love one woman
as Peter Parker
and another as Spider-Man.
No, I don't.
I just want you to be happy.
So do I.
-[tires squealing]
-[dramatic music]
[Green Goblin]
Norman, don't you understand?
I'm your friend! [laughs]
-[machine whirring]
-[explosion booming]
There was only one
true goblin,
the Green Goblin!
I'm the Green Goblin,
not that you'll live
long enough
for it to matter,
for justice is blind no longer!
[laughing]
No, not again.
I'm your friend, Norman.
You're not my friend!
You're some monster!
No, the others,
they're the monsters.
Kingpin, the Hobgoblin,
Spider-Man.
They're all trying
to hurt you,
squeeze you, crush you.
Yes, that's exactly
what they're doing to me.
And that's why you
should let me stop them.
It would be wrong.
Wrong is what
they're doing to you
and what they want
to do to Harry!
I-- I can't!
You can! You must!
Let me out, Norman.
Let me out now! [laughs]
[Norman] No, no, noooo!
[Green Goblin cackling]
Hobgoblin,
do not disappoint me.
I'll handle my end.
You just make sure
your goons do their part.
[beam whooshing]
[explosions]
-[dramatic action music]
-[men shouting]
What is keeping them?!
Sorry, your boys are
a little tied up.
Well, make that
webbed up, right now.
But I'm sure the police will
find them a nice new home.
No, not this time.
[engine roaring]
Careful, Hobby, if I go kaboom,
your toy goes up, too!
The only one who will
go kaboom is you.
I am going to break you in two.
[Spider-man grunts]
He's crushing me!
[grunts]
[explosion booming]
Stand back for the real goblin.
-What?!
-The Green Goblin!
I thought you were
just a rumor!
You're going to wish I was!
Should we not do something?
No, with any luck, they'll
both destroy each other.
How did you lift that?
Because I'm the real deal,
you cheap imitation!
I must have gotten hit hard.
I'm seeing double.
You rank amateur!
Sorry, but there's
no profit to be made
in my own annihilation.
You don't deserve
to wear that mask!
Blast! Once again,
that time dilation accelerator
has slipped through my fingers!
-[lasers zapping]
-[cackling]
Who areyou?
And where did you get
all of those weapons?
I thought Osborn gave me
his best stuff.
Osborn's got
a new best friend-- me!
[Green Goblin]
Ya ha ha ha ha ha!
You're mine now, imposter!
Au contraire, mon frere.
No!
Get off me,
you meddling insect!
[Spider-Man]
Listen up, Osborn,
I know it's you
under that mask,
so let's touch down and talk
this over, spider to goblin.
Norman Osborn's gone, you fool!
You're dealing
with the Green Goblin now!
I play for keeps!
-[explosion booming]
-[Green Goblin laughing]
Now I must rid
Norman Osborn's world
of that other goblin imposter.
Ah, so many enemies
and so little time.
[gasping]
[thinking]
Ugh. Well, Jason,
your study
is positively cramped.
Maybe if we got rid
of this wall--
[knock echoes]
Funny, that sounded hollow.
[dramatic music]
[screams]
[ominous music]
Now you've done it.
Hobgoblin!
For once in my life,
I had everything, everything!
And then you had
to find this room.
Why are you here?!
[laughs] Can't you guess?
Jason! [gasps]
Jason Philip Macendale,
to be precise.
Former petty crook,
ex-hired thug,
and now your husband-to-be.
[laughs]
You're a criminal?
No! No, I can't believe that!
Oh, I'm afraid
it's true, my dear.
This house, my money,
everything that drew you to me,
it all came from crime.
What have I done?
I can't marry you!
Oh, but now that you
know who I am, you must,
or else I can't let you live.
[gasps] What are you saying?
-[Jason laughs]
-[Felicia screams]
[explosion booms]
[Green Goblin cackles]
You! Here?!
How did you know who I am?
I know all your secrets.
I even know that it was
Norman Osborn who created you,
and now I will
undo his mistake.
I'm reclaiming
everything that ever fell
into your misbegotten hands!
Fortunately, I've had access
to the Kingpin's plans
of Ohn's technology.
I've studied up on
how to use this thing.
Now get in, both of you.
No, it's too low on power!
We could be trapped in limbo.
Think of it as your big chance
to get away
from it all! [laughs]
The Goblin's trail
has gone cold,
but maybe I'll pick it up again
in Norman's old hangout
at Oscorp.
[Jason] Look, whatever
Osborn's paying you,
I'll double it, triple it!
You think
I'm in this for money?
[Jason] Well, what then?
To make life easier
for my creator, Norman Osborn.
Once I've eliminated
all his enemies,
then he won't have
to suffer anymore.
[Spider-Man] Jason Phillips
was the Hobgoblin?
Poor Felicia,
she sure knows
how to pick 'em.
[Green Goblin cackling]
Umph!
You know, that laugh is
getting on my nerves.
You, still alive?
Alive and sticking.
[acid hisses]
[laughs] Who needs a glider
when I can simply leap
through other dimensions?
[Felicia] Spider-Man, help us!
-Whoa!
-I must savor this moment.
Since I hate you most of all,
it's hard for me
to believe this,
but at last I will be
rid of you! [laughs]
Two can play at this game!
Yaah!
[Felicia]
Spider-Man, hurry!
Now to do this!
What have you done?!
-Forget it, Gobby.
-No!
Now that accelerator's
useless to everybody!
I've destroyed it for good!
[energy whooshes]
Don't go in!
It's too low on power!
You'll be trapped!
I'd rather take
my chances in limbo
than be defeated by you!
[portal whooshes]
Why, Jason? Why be a criminal?
Because I had nothing
to begin with.
Everything I have I owe
to crime, including you.
So you see,
my precious darling,
I had no choice.
I have to know,
did you ever love me, really?
Well, I-- I don't know.
I love things about you--
your wealth,
your beauty,
your-- your refinement.
[Felicia]
That's not love!
I've experienced true love,
and it's nothing like that.
-[somber music]
-[police radio chatter]
Every time I lose my heart
to someone, disaster strikes.
I'm like a black cat
bringing bad luck
into everyone's path,
including my own. [sobbing]
I am sorry, Felicia,
truly and deeply sorry.
[ominous music]
[portal whooshes]
Ooh, well, there was
just enough residual charge
to get me back here,
and that's bad news, indeed,
for all of Osborn's enemies--
the Kingpin, the Hobgoblin,
and especially Spider-Man,
because once I complete
my own modifications
on this time dilation
accelerator,
they'll see what
a real goblin can do!
[laughs]
[upbeat rock music]
♪ Spider-Man, Spider-Man ♪
♪ Radioactive Spider-Man ♪
♪ Spider blood, spider blood ♪
♪ Radioactive spider blood ♪
♪ Spider blood ♪
♪ Spider-Man ♪