[upbeat rock music]
♪ Spider-Man ♪
♪ Radioactive Spider-Man ♪
♪ Spider blood
Spider blood ♪
♪ Radioactive spider blood ♪
♪ Spider blood
Spider blood ♪
♪ Radioactive spider blood ♪
[explosions booming]
[growling]
♪ Spider-Man ♪
[mysterious music]
[tough] Hey, what's Spider-Man
doing in this part of town?
-Get lost!
-Shove off!
Get outta here!
[thinking]
My new neighborhood.
There's no place like home.
Come on, Parker,
you only just moved here.
Give the place a chance.
It might not be
so bad after all.
-[spider-sense tingling]
-Uh-oh.
-[alarm ringing]
-Who am I kidding?
Spider-Man, please,
let me-- Mmph!
He's about my age.
Why is he ruining
his life for a few bucks?
Have I battled
so many super-villains
that I've completely lost touch
with real life in the streets?
Peter Parker can protect
himself in this neighborhood,
but do I have any right to move
MJ here after we're married?
And since
this is all I can afford,
maybe I don't have any right
to marry her, either.
Some love nest.
-[spider-sense tingles]
What the--
Took you long enough
to get back home.
-What do you want?
-You have something I need,
and you are going
to give it to me, understand?
Because I know
all about you, Parker,
you and Spider-Man.
I know you and Spider-Man
are partners.
He sets you up
to take your pictures
and you split the cash.
Real cozy.
Uh, right, right.
What are you looking for, a cut?
Ha!
That's chump change to me.
Just who exactly
are you behind that mask?
Know your enemy, huh, Parker?
You know me all right.
I've never seen you
before in my life.
[laughing]
So you don't even remember me?
I'll refresh your memory.
And when I'm done,
I'll make sure
you never forget Hobie Brown.
Yeah, that's my name.
My life began
in this neighborhood.
-Not long ago,
it almost ended here, too.
-[siren]
Times for me were always tough.
I decided that if I wanted
to get anywhere,
I either had to have power
or work for someone who did.
I made the choice
I thought was right.
[heavy thud]
It's time we stopped
risking our pants
for that blue-skinned freak.
We're the ones
taking the chances.
We oughta take
our fair share, too,
-and maybe more.
-[whirring]
[Hobie] I been workin'
for a crime boss named Iceberg.
Rumor was his genes
had been tinkered with
so he could be tougher,
more dangerous.
They say
he wasn't human anymore.
-Over here.
-[Hobie] Rumor was
probably right on.
Good work, boys. You pulled
that heist off smooth as ice.
Thanks, Iceberg.
You know you can count on us.
I used to think I could,
but that was before
I found out you were
a stone-cold liar!
What? But-- But I--
We oughta take our fair share,
too, and maybe more.
[laughing]
It ain't nice
to double-cross the Ice.
Toss this cube in the drink,
and if he melts too soon,
freeze him all over.
Ice, you can't do this to me!
Course I can.
Whoever has the power
makes the rules.
Ice, Ice, you know
that ain't right!
Ice!
[Hobie]
I was done for.
These guys were setting me up
for the big chill.
I had to act fast.
-Angela.
-Hobie?
Baby, I'm in trouble!
-So what else is new?
-Baby, listen to me--
How many times do I have
to tell you, Hobie, I love you!
I wanna be with you,
but I don't want your trouble!
[crying]
Give up this life, Hobie,
and come back to me,
ready to do honest work!
If I did that,
I'd just be a chump
workin' for somebody else.
I want to be somebody
with power!
Right now
you ain't nobody, Hobie.
You ain't nobody,
and you got nothin'!
Thanks for more of nothin'.
If you can't see things my way,
then I'm gonna have to make
some changes in my life,
you understand?!
Hobie? Hobie?
[Hobie]
My life was on the line.
I had to split town,
but that was gonna take cash.
I was desperate.
That's when I saw
you and your lady.
You had it all.
Nice clothes, full wallet,
and the love of a good woman.
I'd had it all
that night for sure,
all the problems
I could handle.
-[landlady] It's now or never!
-[Peter] I--
Got an art student wants
that apartment if you don't.
I think we better
keep looking for--
-We'll take it!
-I'll get the lease.
Why would you want
to live in this dump?
It's too small,
it's too high up, it's too--
It's too bad you don't get
how much I love you, Mr. Parker.
But, I--
I hope this is how you plan
to end all our arguments.
We need someplace to live
after we're married,
and this is
all we can afford, right-- Ohh!
Don't!
Peter, it's not worth it!
[Peter] Anybody messes
with my fiancée, it's worth it!
[squeaking]
12 bucks?! This ain't
gonna get me anywhere!
[Spider-Man]
Oh, I don't know.
It should get you all the way
to the state penitentiary.
Maybe not, wall-crawler.
[ice clattering]
Ha! Now who's
the hotshot, hero?
Gotta think fast!
That's it, give me
an even better target.
Hobie Brown has
a superhero on the run!
And I was gonna leave town!
Okay, Spider-Man, freeze.
No!
Okay, pal, listen up.
That was Peter Parker's lady
you mugged.
Parker and I are partners, see.
I do all the work,
he sells the pics.
Spread the word, anyone crosses
him or his girl crosses me.
Those are my rules, get it?
O-O-Okay!
-Good.
-[siren wailing]
[Hobie] You think about a lot
of things hanging upside down,
waiting for the cops
to take you away
for violating your parole.
Ice had his rules,
Spider-Man had his.
When was I gonna lay down mine?
All that kept runnin'
through my head
was what Ice had said to me.
"Whoever has the power
makes the rules."
I was gonna have plenty
of time to think things over,
or so I thought.
[clattering]
Friend of yours?
Just the competition.
My father has many enemies.
Who's your father?
Someone who'll be interested
in knowing what you did for me.
Yeah, that and a token'll
get me a ride on the subway.
Knowing my father gets you
more than that, my friend.
You'll see,
he has a lot of power.
[Hobie]
I didn't believe him at all.
But then odd things
started to happen.
Somebody hired
a slick uptown lawyer for me.
He told the judge
that there was no proof
I'd broken parole,
and since Spider-Man
wasn't aroundto testify,
the law had to let me go.
He won!
Somebody was
on my side that day,
and I wanted to see
what else they could do for me.
So, you're the man I owe
for my son's well-being.
I-- I had no idea he was
the son of the Kingpin.
I always make good
on my debts, Mr. Brown.
Name your price.
Gold, jewels?
-Power.
-Ah, that.
There's this guy in
my neighborhood named Iceberg.
I want to stick it
to him once and for all.
I see.
That is
an intriguing proposition.
Let me show you my latest toy.
I call it
the stealth battle suit.
Cool Halloween costume.
Does it do anything?
This suit is bulletproof.
It is capable of
pneumatically controlled flight.
It has titanium steel appendages
that facilitate climbing
and offensive maneuvers.
It has rocket-powered blasters
that fire
powerful projectiles at will.
In short, the wearer of this
Halloween costume would gain--
Instant power.
It is yours for the asking.
Mine?
What's the catch?
You saved my son.
This is a small price to pay.
Go on, you did ask for power.
Yes, power.
[dramatic music]
[whirring, beeping, and buzzing]
[powering down]
This suit is incredible!
We're even now, right?
Your son's life for the suit,
no strings attached.
No strings.
[laughing maniacally]
Funny how you always hear that
from the guys pulling them.
I decided to test out
the Kingpin's present
in an old abandoned building
where no one would get hurt.
The force was astounding.
[clang]
The strength was incredible.
I could go anywhere,
do anything.
I wasn't weak like Hobie Brown.
I was somebody new.
I needed a new name.
I felt like a wild animal
on the prowl,
so I decided to call myself
the Prowler.
The balance of power
in New York City
had finally shifted,
to me.
Now it's my turn!
Your fancy suit
doesn't impress me!
I'm gonna rip it to shreds
with you in it!
-[Prowler] I don't think so!
-[groaning]
-[gasps]
-[crunch]
That's impossible.
I'm stronger than you!
Your freak genes
don't cut it anymore,
not when the Prowler's
on your tail.
-The Prowler, huh?
-You!
Catchy name, but just who are
you when you're at home?
-[grunting]
-Nice claws.
You ever hang out
with my friend Wolverine?
You won't take me again!
Again?
I've met you before?
No answer, huh?
No matter.
I've gotta take him
where he can't hurt anyone else.
[tingle]
[coughing]
See how you like my web!
[Hobie] I had done it.
I'd beaten Iceberg and
Spider-Man both in one night.
I was the Prowler.
[Hobie]
Spider-Man was destroyed,
or so I thought.
Maybe I'll never know
what happened to him next.
I know what happened
next all too well,
though I can't tell him.
[straining] Need air!
Got to summon all my strength!
[gasping]
I got out of that one
just by the skin of my teeth.
[Hobie]
Parker, I thought I was it.
All I had to do was officially
take the reins of power.
-[alarm blaring]
-[monitors zapping]
No! No!
Iceberg,
time to cash that check
your mouth's been writing.
Men, hold your fire.
Allow me.
[laughing]
Forgot to tell you,
this suit has
its own nuclear heating unit.
Now where were we?
[confused chatter]
[Hobie]
I wanted Iceberg's operation.
-Now I had it.
-Who is this guy, anyway?
-Where's Iceberg?
-[claps] Iceberg.
Yes?
See if our guests would
like anything cold to drink.
[shocked murmuring]
Gentlemen, ladies, a toast--
to the new order.
-[zapping]
-Ohh! Ahh!
[zapping]
Stay away!
What's wrong with it?
-[zapping]
-[groans]
-Prowler.
-What's wrong?
My goodness,
is something the matter?
The suit, it's hurting me!
You have to fix it!
First, Kingpin doesn't
have to do anything.
Second, I forgot to give
you one little warning
about my toy--
batteries are not included.
What?!
You have to come to me
to get it recharged,
and I'm having the suit
give you sporadic jolts
of electricity to hasten
your return, like so.
You see, Prowler,
I now control you.
You are mine.
You said no strings!
The best puppeteers
never use strings.
I wouldn't take that
off if I were you.
The suit includes
a self-destruct device.
It might turn your neighborhood
into an ash heap.
Why would you do this to me?
I saved your son!
And I gave you what you wanted.
You wanted to defeat Iceberg
and have power over him.
Now you do.
For years,
he has worked for me,
but, lately, he was getting
a little hard to control.
When you came to me
wanting to topple him,
it fit in perfectly
with my plans.
[laughing]
But why do you
want to control me?
Controlling power
is what I do best.
You know where to find me.
Don't wait too long.
If your enemies don't do you in
in your weakened condition,
then the electric shocks will.
How could I have been so stupid?
I was lost all over again.
-[gasps] Aah!
-Shh, please, it's me.
Hobie, oh, no--
You're the Prowler man
I saw on the news?
-No! No!
-Angela.
Henry, stay back.
Why is he here?
[groaning]
He and I are dating!
What was I supposed to do,
Hobie, wait for you?
-He's nobody!
-Why you--
He wants to be my husband.
He works a normal job,
and I know he'll be here
for me when I need him.
Things could have
been so different
if only you'd helped me
that night.
No. You still think power
is the only solution.
If power isn't important,
Angela, then what is?
Life, Hobie.
Maybe I found mine
here with Henry.
I hope you find yours.
You have to go now.
I lost Angela.
I've lost everything that
really meant anything to me.
So why'd you come
looking for me?
-Because I need Spider-Man.
-What?
I saw on the news
that he was alive.
He must've survived
my attack after all.
Now he's the only guy
I know who's strong enough
to help me face off
against the Kingpin,
and I'm gonna make you tell me
where Spider-Man is,
or force him to come here
to save your life.
-[zapping]
-[groans]
Haven't you learned
that strong-arm tactics
aren't the only way
to get what you want?
I need him. Oh, the pain!
You could start
by saying please.
Bad news is there's no way
to get you out of it
without setting off
the self-destruct bomb.
-The good news?
-Who said there was
any good news?
There's a slight chance
that I can reroute
the energy charges that Kingpin
is sending to hurt you.
That can be used to power
some of the suit's functions.
-Not for long, though.
-What good would that do me?
Well, if the Kingpin
is expecting you to be weak,
then you'll have a trick
up your sleeve, won't you?
One that maybe
you and Spider-Man can use
to your advantage.
You'd call Spider-Man for me?
I think this is a fight
he wouldn't want to miss.
[man] Prowler, sir.
I am glad to see
you've reconsidered my offer.
[Prowler] From where I stand,
I only saw one way to go.
Of course. My way.
Sorry, but I'm no longer
in the business
of letting anybody
tell me what to do.
-[beeps]
-[groaning]
I don't know
how you managed that shot,
but I'm pulling the plug now.
[power surging]
Did you really think you could
defeat Kingpin so easily?
Peek-a-boo, big guy!
[guns clicking]
[Kingpin]
Fools! Get them!
Get the high-intensity
laser weapons.
[Prowler] This is it.
Can you figure it out?
[beeping]
[Spider-Man]
It looks fairly simple.
After all, the Kingpin's
not a science wiz,
and he's the one
who operated it, right?
Now go! Hurry!
[beeping]
Got it!
Look out for that stun...
blaster!
[groaning]
[guns clicking]
Well, Mr. Brown,
you are persistent,
I'll give you that much.
I admire that.
I'm tempted
to offer you one last chance.
-Oh, yeah?
-No.
[laughing]
Destroy him.
[clicking]
I wouldn't,
or I'll trip the gizmos
you put in this suit
to keep it on me.
Then we all go boom.
Hold your fire, men!
He's right. That suit
is still quite explosive.
Come on, man,
I used up all the suit's energy
that Parker gave us.
Now you gotta get us outta here.
[Spider-man groans]
Hang on.
Thanks to you and Parker
for helping me
see another sunrise.
For helping me see
a lot of things.
Your head okay?
It's getting there.
What now?
I'm not sure.
I know what
I'm not gonna do, though.
I'm never getting myself
into this kinda trap again.
The only power that means
anything to me now
is my own power
over myself, my life,
and the choices I make.
Only other thing I know is
there's a girl named Angela
who's looking for a man to love.
Maybe I can
still make her understand that
that man oughta be me.
It might not be too late.
I should've listened to her
in the first place.
I've sure got a lot
of apologizing to do.
[light music]
[sighs]
Huh? Peter.
They're beautiful.
But way too extravagant.
I've been worried
about too many things lately.
I've been letting my fears
have too much power over me.
It's time I stopped worrying
and started enjoying
what's right with my life.
I have everything I need,
and nothing else
on Earth matters.
All that's important is
I love you, and you love me.
Tiger.
You're finally
starting to make sense.
Maybe this marriage thing
is gonna work out after all.
I'd bet my webbing on it, lady.
And, man,
have I got webbing to bet.
[upbeat rock music]
♪ Spider-Man, Spider-Man ♪
♪ Radioactive Spider-Man ♪
♪ Spider blood, spider blood ♪
♪ Radioactive spider blood ♪
♪ Spider blood ♪
♪ Spider-Man ♪