[upbeat rock music]
♪ Spider-Man, Spider-Man ♪
♪ Radioactive Spider-Man ♪
♪ Spider blood, spider blood ♪
♪ Radioactive spider blood ♪
♪ Spider-Man, Spider-Man ♪
Ah, nice to just get
away up here sometimes.
Clears out the cobwebs.
Oh. Spidey sense
is going crazy!
A guy can't even sling a
few webs in peace any more!
Flying toys, now why would they
alert my Spider sense?
Oh! Well, ask a
bone-head question.
[male voice] Amazing!
His speed, his agility.
They're a regular
mini air force!
[explosion blasts]
Flying smart bombs!
Hold that pose.
All right,
don't hold that pose.
If you're gonna
be temperamental,
I'll fix it so you never
work in this town again.
Gotta lose them
or they'll blow me to bits!
[explosion]
They split up,
trying to box me in.
Maybe I can use
that against them.
I have to time this
just right.
Here comes the other one.
Last one and I'm home free.
And who is on my tail
this time?
You blew it, you failed,
Smythe!
My father is the
world's foremost expert
in the field of
robotics, Mr. Osborn.
He is not a failure.
Relax, Alistair,
no need to defend me.
No need?
You let that web-slinging
weasel make fools of us.
Not for long, this
was a only a trial run.
The spider seekers
have proven that
my targeting computers
can find Spider-Man.
They're my targeting computers!
I put up the money,
you only invented them.
Good only if they can
catch him.
That's not their job.
Then whose job is it?
That's whose job it is.
Gentlemen, I give you my
Spider Slayer, The Black Widow.
[woman] Then there's
the theater room
the parking attendants,
the musicians,
the cleaning crew, it's
all been taken care of,
right, Mr. Jameson?
Of course,
this isn't the first
charity ball I've
hosted, Miss Hardy.
Yes, but this is the first one
with the Hardy name
attached to it.
Now, what about
the photographer?
Mother says we
absolutely must have one.
Yeah, well, tell
mother that if I spend
any more money on this thing,
I'm going to need charity.
Jonah, remember that
Felicia's mother
is an important
philanthropist and advertiser.
Besides, we know
of a photographer.
You don't mean?
[Peter] Just great, this
is all I need in my life,
flying robots.
Wonder who's controlling--
Peter, Mr. Jameson
wants to see you.
Be right there.
I assure you Miss Hardy,
this charity ball
is just as important
to me as it is to you.
That's why I'm sending my
very best photographer.
Hmm, who might that be?
[Peter] Felicia Hardy!
Peter Parker?
You know him?
We go to college together.
Parker, you're just as
unpredictable as ever.
Mr. Jameson says you're
his best photographer.
He does?
My very best.
You point, you
shoot, no big deal.
Well this charity thing
is a big deal, Parker.
Miss Hardy's mother
is sponsoring it,
and I'm hosting it, think
you can take pictures of
something other than
Spider-Man for a change?
Call me Mr. Versatile.
I'm sure you won't
disappoint me.
No way.
See you there then.
Robbie, see if you
can find Eddie Brock.
He's supposed to have some
big scoop for me, and I--
Parker, your mouth's open.
[sizzles]
[man] Not too close, Osborn.
That acid's the only thing
that can penetrate the
Black Widow's armor.
We're almost ready.
Yeah, almost,
Eddie Brock's biggest
scoop. [chuckles]
The capture of Spider-Man!
You will not regret bringing
me in on this, Mr. Smythe.
Your insurance, Brock,
is immediate here.
Everything will be done
on the up and up.
Wouldn't want things getting
out of hand, would we?
I don't intend to play
judge and jury, Spencer.
I just want
Spider-Man captured.
He's a criminal!
Yeah, and he's big news, too.
I gotta go line up
my crew, see you.
I have to leave also, but
I want to reassure you,
everything will be done
strictly by the book.
You have to trust me.
I get a bad feeling
whenever somebody says
I have to trust him.
That's not entirely
inappropriate, Alistair.
But there is another
consideration.
It'll be just your size
when it's finished.
Is that why you're
working for Osborn?
To serve up Spider-Man on a
platter, in exchange for this?
Alistair, that explosion back
at the old lab was my fault.
I'd do anything to help you.
Even working with Osborn?
Even that, Osborn's
not that bad.
Black Widow's ready.
[Kingpin] Does anyone
suspect that I'm involved?
No, not at all.
[Kingpin]Good, that is as it
should be.
Crime, my livelihood, my life,
all of it jeopardized
by the sudden appearance
of Spider-Man.
How can I run a
world-wide criminal empire
if I can't even control
my home base, New York?
The Black Widow can neutralize
all of Spider-man's powers.
That loose cannon
must be removed.
You don't have a
thing to worry about.
But you do, Osborn.
If it fails, I get
your company, remember?
Interesting way to pay
back a loan, isn't it?
The debt will be paid
in full as of tomorrow.
Something that occurs to me.
Either Spider-Man is
destroyed, or you get Oscorp.
Whatever happens, you win.
That's why I'm the
Kingpin [chuckles].
-Ready?
-I'm not sure.
The seekers found
Spider-Man once, Alistair.
They can do it again.
If we find him, we've
got to destroy him.
Because with Spider-Man, you
don't get a second chance.
[man] Doesn't your dad usually
come to these things, Osborn?
I borrowed his ticket.
There's some big deal
at his factory tonight.
He wouldn't tell me
what, never does.
Do we have to talk about work?
It's so boring.
Flash, everything's working
out so well tonight.
Jameson was--
Felicia?
Peter Parker!
Wonder who his hot date is.
Isn't it incredible?
Just like I told you.
It's nice, Peter.
But I'd be just as happy
watching my cable TV.
Aunt May, you need to
get out once in a while.
That's his date?
I think it's sweet.
I wonder who she is.
You should have brought Mary
Jane, Anna Watson's niece.
A blind date?
-Come on, Aunt May, I--
-Parker!
You look incredible.
Um... Aunt May,
this is Felicia Hardy.
Very nice to meet you.
Mind if I borrow your
nephew for a dance?
Well, I--
Felicia, I should
be taking pictures.
And I should be dancing
with Flash Thompson.
Could've had some boring
blind date instead of this?
Yeah, right.
I had a feeling this
might happen, come on.
[man] Parker's not gonna dance
Felicia away from me.
[chuckles] You look just
like your big hero.
I'd better, I paid enough to
rent this thing
for the frat party.
Well, what do you
think Peter will do
when he sees you in it?
Don't know what he'll do.
Just don't be standing too
close to him when he does it.
[Spencer] Got him,
he's at 39th and 2nd.
Hey, that's
Jonah Jameson's place.
Ho ho, the boss's gonna
have a front row seat.
Good for him.
Now let's get this over with.
[loud engine swoosh]
[claps]
You're a good dancer,
I'm surprised.
Well, a lot of things about
me would surprise you.
I love surprises.
See what you think of this one.
[Peter] Something's
wrong, why now?
Peter?
Why, what does he want?
Felicia, it's just
some imposter.
But how would you know that?
Uh, yeah, yeah, maybe
it really is him.
Spider-Man is here, in my home?
Parker, it's time
we had a talk.
About what, Spider-Man?
About those pictures
you're always taking of me.
I don't like'em.
Well, I'm sorry.
That's a little better,
but it's still not good enough.
Well, what would
you like me to say?
-[screaming]
-Okay, aah!
What is making my
Spider sense go off?
[people scream]
Aunt May!
Peter!
Stay in here, Aunt May.
-But Peter, I--
-I'll be okay, I hope.
You, you're ruining
everything [screams].
Leave her alone!
You wanna dance with
somebody? Dance with me.
The fight of the century
and no photographer!
Parker, where are you?
Hey, Toro, Toro!
When you crash a party,
you really crash it!
Oh, oh.
-[loud rumbles]
-[Spider-Man screams]
Where did he go?
There, Spencer,
go back, get him!
Get him!
[ominous music]
[groans]
A million bucks, that's
what this is gonna cost me.
[TV Announcer] Spider-Man
appears to be dazed!
Huh, what was that?
[Eddie] With
Spider-Man unconscious,
we have a rare opportunity.
And here it is, the moment all
America has been waiting for,
the unmasking of Spider-Man.
So that's what this was
about, Brock's big scoop!
Looks like it was
worth all the damage.
And now, live, and
exclusively--
Cut to the chase, Brock!
[groans]
[Aunt May] Flash Thompson!
You know him?
He goes to school with
my nephew, Peter Parker.
Wait a minute,
are you telling me
Spider-Man's just
some goofy kid?
That's unbelievable.
How can anything
be unbelievable
to a guy who
publishes a tabloid?
[gasps] Spider-Man!
And there you have it, America.
Minutes from now,
the police, huh?
Ladies and gentlemen
this is amazing,
some men just broke into
the lab here at Oscorp.
Ah... Sir, excuse me, but,
what do you want?
Him.
I thought we were going to hand
Spider-Man over to the police.
What's going on, Osborn?
I had nothing to do
with this, nothing.
I trusted you.
Hey, hey, I got first
amendment rights.
We just amended them.
How about that, I'm
in two places at once!
This one's the real deal, lady.
After all this time, I
can practically smell him,
which means Eddie
Brock just made
my whole company
look like jerks.
Not hard to do.
Why you web-slinging
clown, how--
Excuse me, that poor Thompson
boy is in big trouble.
Shouldn't somebody
try to save him?
[Peter] Yeah, somebody's
gotta save the guy
who hates Peter Parker,
guess who?
Talk about dramatic irony.
[loud crash]
[Spider-Man] Knock, knock.
Spider-Man!
Can't be, he's back in there!
All smoke and mirrors,
read my book!
[screams and grunts]
What's going on out there?
Don't know, better
finish him off
and get out of here.
Otherwise the Kingpin
will finish us off.
The Kingpin?
Spencer, I swear--
[Flash] No, you don't
understand, please!
Nothing, you web--
-He said, please.
-[all gasp]
Two of them!
Congratulations, you can count.
And they say the
school system's failed.
[grunts]
Show me how to
start up the Black Widow.
Spencer, there's no choice.
That button.
[engine starting]
So that's her name, huh?
Black Widow!
I already know you're stronger
than me,
but maybe this'll
give me an edge.
Hey guys, chill,
the Widow and I
are trying to share
some quality time.
Thanks, I appreciate
your cooperation.
Where are you going?
To even the odds.
This thing is indestructible.
Foul ball coming.
Do the Mets need me, or what?
Hey, remember our deal?
No Spider splat,
no hover chair.
All right, but take
Alistair out of here.
No, you can't stay!
I'll be fine, I'll be fine.
Uh-oh, the Widow's much more
active than I ever imagined.
Think fast, Spidey!
[groans]
Not fast enough.
Webbing's gone!
I have to change cartridges,
I can't do it now.
[Flash] Spider-Man, keep
that thing away from me!
I'll do what I can.
Maybe if I get up higher.
Some kind of oil, canceling
out my Spider stickiness!
[screams and grunts]
What on earth?
Should have thought
of this sooner.
Only one place.
Now if only I can hang on.
Yippee kay-ay!
Must have jumped off!
[Flash] Hey, no, I'm not him.
Oh that's it, Flash,
a true profile in courage.
Well, maybe I'll
help you out anyway.
[Flash] I don't
stick to walls, see?
I can't swing on webs either!
I get air sick!
Well, let's see how
these web cartridges
gum up your propulsion system.
[Flash] Spider-Man, hurry!
It's getting closer,
please, help me!
Keep your mask on, Thompson,
I'm controlling the
Black Widow now.
What?
Take a dive, Widow.
Didn't look too good
back there, did I?
I always hoped that when
the chips were down,
I'd be like you.
If anyone finds out,
Felicia, Parker,
you won't say
anything, will you?
No, but now you know
what kind of trouble
this costume attracts.
My father, did he get out?
[loud explosion]
The other networks are
laughing at me,
Brock, even Fox!
Can you imagine
the humiliation?
That's all because of you!
Me... Don't blame me,
blame Spider-Man.
I do, but him, I can't fire.
Boss, come on, you know me.
Yeah, I do, through,
finito, out the door!
And get off my Ming vase.
No, no, no, just wait a
minute, wait, you can't!
Get this bonehead out
of here, will you?
But you don't understand!
You want understanding?
See a shrink.
Would you wait,
I am telling you,
it's all the fault of
that wall crawling freak!
I can't believe you'd try a
stunt like that, you dolt!
But Felicia--
That's Miss Hardy
to you, buster.
Ah, forget it.
Watch it, clown.
First the dolt,
now the coward.
Coward, I was only trying to--
You abandoned me!
Spider-Man had to save me.
If you were half the man he is.
Peter, I was so
worried about you.
And I was worried about
you too, Aunt May.
I'm just sorry you
had to see all this.
Well actually,
it was kind of exciting.
Now dear, about that nice
girl I want you to meet.
[ominous music]
[Kingpin] Still no sign of your
father, Alistair?
You know me?
I was an associate
of your father's.
Now I want to be an
associate of yours.
I don't need associates.
I have an offer that
might change your mind.
Suppose I provide the money
to make new
Spider Slayer robots.
Why should you do that?
So you can destroy the
man who's responsible
for your father's
disappearance, Spider-Man.
[upbeat rock music]
♪ Spider-Man ♪
♪ Radioactive Spider-Man ♪
♪ Spider blood, spider blood ♪
♪ Radioactive spider blood ♪
♪ Spider-Man ♪