[upbeat rock music]
♪ Spider-man ♪
♪ Radioactive Spider-man ♪
♪ Spider blood ♪
♪ Radioactive spider blood ♪
[explosions booming]
♪ Spider-man ♪
[birds tweeting]
There it is, Metcalfe.
The ancient pyramid
of the Toltecs.
Lost for 10 centuries.
[suspenseful music]
What?
My light.
Look, look.
Just up ahead.
At last, we found it.
The Tablet of Time.
According to ancient legend,
the Tablet of Time
once held the secret
of eternal life.
Today it is a priceless relic
of a lost civilization.
It will be on display
throughout the world
but first it will be studied
at New York's
Empire State University
under the hospices of
Doctor Curt Connors.
[Reporter] Doctor,
do you seriously believe
that this tablet can
grant eternal life?
I'm just the kind of scientist
who believes that
anything's possible.
Clear the front page Robbie.
This is news.
As to estimate the
value of the tablet,
Connors would only
say it's priceless.
Collectors offer of
50 million dollars
has already been rejected.
50 million.
[grunting]
[News Anchor]
This seems to have started
an avalanche of attention.
[Wilson] This workout is over.
This phenomenal
interest hasn't slowed
since the tablet's discovery.
Bigger offers have
been flooding in
from collectors
all over the world.
I must make plans to add
the tablet to my collection.
Tablet's value on
the open market
is escalating astronomically.
So is its value to thieves.
[News Anchor] Dealers
have never seen
anything like this before.
I might get to use
this new batch of webbing
sooner than I thought.
[News Anchor] A press
release was issued
stating that the Tablet of Time
is not for sale.
I must have that tablet.
[dramatic music]
[helicopter whirring]
Metcalfe, look out.
Get out of here!
[men coughing]
You boys know what to do.
[Peter] I knew
that chunk of rock
was going to attract trouble.
But I didn't expect a
crook like Hammerhead.
Now why's a smart crook like you
pulling a crazy stunt like this?
You've always seemed
so levelheaded.
I'm warning you
web-head, butt out!
[Hammerhead yells]
[metal clanging]
[Peter] Ole!
Ouch, doesn't that hurt?
This is pure adamantium.
No damage, no foul.
[Hammerhead yells]
[Peter] Hey, watch it!
The tablet's no good
to anyone broken.
Use your head.
Uh, forget I said that.
-[fist thudding]
-[Peter yelling]
Ew!
Yuck!
Uh-oh, Spidey.
This time you're up to
your gills in trouble.
It's too slippery.
I can't get any traction.
[gears whirring]
Good thing I made this new
batch of webbing extra sticky.
You're not getting it
that easily, Hammer.
Freeze, creep!
[cocking guns]
No, let him go.
He saved the Tablet of Time.
Something here
doesn't smell right.
Aren't you listening?
Spider-man's a hero.
No, no, I mean phew!
Something really smells bad.
Uh, sorry.
Sorry?
Is that all you can say?
How could you fail so miserably?
It was Spider-man's fault.
It was your fault!
Look at you.
You're a joke.
Everything about
you says washed up.
I'm bringing in someone
else to do this job.
A real pro.
You can't do this to me.
Stop complaining.
At least I'm letting
you live for the moment.
Now get out of my sight!
My dear, I'm growing
old and weak.
Soon I'll lose everything
unless I get that tablet.
Please, don't think
me a foolish old man.
I've spent years
researching this.
The ancient Toltecs revered
strength and bravery.
Every decade they held a race
up the side of
their sacred pyramid
for the warriors who had
distinguished themselves
in years of battle.
Priests did not
make the race easy.
But for the winner
they had a big reward.
Renewed youth!
His life to live over again.
And to do that they
created the Tablet of Time.
[dramatic music]
[light zapping]
With that tablet, I could
make myself young again
and strong enough
to grind my enemies
into the dust beneath my feet.
You will soon retire.
Help!
Please, help me.
Enemies like the Kingpin.
Vanessa, my dear wife,
you seem so distant tonight.
Is something wrong?
I'm not happy Wilson.
What is it you do not have?
Tell me and I will get
it for you immediately.
I want a husband
who is not involved
in this vile business anymore.
I see.
This again.
Furthermore, my dear,
this vile business
as you call it
is how I have been able
to attain our wealth.
We have so much more
than we need now.
Crime has taken over
your entire life.
Nonsense.
When have I not
had time for you?
[phone ringing]
Yes?
My dear, this is business.
You see what I mean?
I'll handle him myself.
Hammerhead.
What an audacious entrance.
I am beside myself
with surprise.
I could destroy you right now.
Could you now?
Yeah.
But to show my good
faith, I ain't gonna.
Yes, but my faith
is not so good.
[chandelier crashing]
Did you really think
you could get this close to me
unless I allowed it?
Now why did Silvermane send you?
He didn't.
I came here on my own.
I wanna work for you.
What do you have to offer me?
I can tell you what
Silvermane's doin'.
Like how he's trying to
get the Tablet of Time.
So?
Everyone wants that.
Silvermane says
the Tablet of Time
ain't just some old rock.
He said it really works.
That is intriguing.
Let me get that tablet for ya.
No, I do not trust you yet.
But I will consider
you for other work.
And if you fail me,
then I will send you
back to Silvermane.
What is left of you anyway.
That new project
of yours, Smythe,
is it ready to obtain the
Tablet of Time for me?
Ready and able.
Debra, what's on
the agenda tonight?
Mm, the usual, Alisa.
Sterilize the Petri dishes
and tidy up the lab.
[horn honking]
Coming, Flash.
Oh, and don't disturb
Doc Connors either.
What's he always doing
around this time that's
such a big secret?
Probably some experiment
that'll help us get that
tomb's research grant.
I gotta run.
Bye.
Spider-man?
And Doctor Connors.
[Peter] So that's
the tablet, huh?
Yes.
We've had to encase it
in protective metal.
Watch what happens
when it reacts to
ultraviolet light.
[buzzing]
[Peter] Incredible.
But isn't it supposed
to make things young?
I'm convinced it can
once we translate
the instructions carved on it
and learn to use it properly.
I believe the
Toltecs stumbled upon
a genetic technology
miles beyond what we know.
That knowledge might
be instrumental
in curing your mutation.
[Peter] So I wouldn't need
these neogenic treatments
every 24 hours?
[laser buzzing]
[Peter groaning]
What happened?
[explosion booming]
[dramatic music]
Not another robot.
Why aren't women
this attracted to me?
I can't stick.
He's coated with some kind
of super slick compound.
[Peter grunting]
[explosion booming]
[Curtis] No!
[Peter] Huh?
No, stay back!
[Peter] Am I seeing things?
Is Doc Connor mutating?
I have to get this over
and fly the toy outta here.
Sorry, I have to take one tablet
every night before bed.
Doc's orders.
[Alisa] Doctor Connors,
are you alright?
I'm okay Alisa.
[Peter] This thing's
really slowing me down
but I've gotta keep it safe.
My life might depend on it.
[explosion booming]
Well, the mighty Spider-man.
How do you like my
new mega-slayer?
[Peter] Smythe.
I knew it.
Why can't you take
up some other hobby?
Joke all you want,
but this time I've built
the ultimate battle robot.
It's got missiles,
lasers, and pulse shock.
And it's humanoid design
makes it extremely versatile.
See?
[Peter] This landing
can barely support me.
I wonder what'll happen if.
Come on Smythe!
Is that the best you can do?
Insolent till the end, eh?
[Peter] It worked.
I'm outta here.
[explosion booming]
Robots.
I hate robots.
Now I've got you.
Joke all you want
but this time I've built
the ultimate battle robot.
Adios wall weasel.
Smythe!
What's taking so long?
Report.
Blast you.
[Wilson] What did you say?
I have the tablet.
I haven't gotten
Connors yet but--
Do we need him?
No, I suppose not.
I'm certainly capable
of translating it myself.
Then stop wasting time
and bring the tablet
to me at once.
[Peter] Wonder why he's leaving.
Hope it wasn't something I said.
[Curtis] I'm fine, just shaken.
Good, he's okay
and still human.
I'll talk to him
later at his place.
Now I've gotta worry
about the Lizard again.
As if I didn't
have enough on my--
Peter Parker.
Alisa.
[Alisa] Did you
hear what happened?
The Tablet of Time was stolen.
Yes, I heard.
It's terrible.
I never thought
something like that
could happen here.
[sirens wailing]
Peter, I'm scared.
Will you walk me
to my apartment?
Well, I'm really
not headed that way.
But I could make a detour.
Sure, the lab
work's kinda boring
but I've met some nice people.
Especially you.
Why don't we have
dinner sometime?
Well, I've been so busy lately.
What am I saying?
Come on, Parker.
Put Mary Jane out of your mind.
Mary Jane and Harry.
Look at them.
They seem so happy together.
I lost her because
of all the time
I spent as Spider-man.
I'm not going to let
that happen again.
Alisa, how about dinner tonight?
[dramatic music]
What do you have in
the way of robots?
Robots are very
popular in the toy biz.
We have an excellent
selection, sir,
right behind that door.
Have you translated
it yet, Alistair?
After the money I've spent
on this new mega-slayer
construction site,
I hope the answer is yes.
No.
What?
How difficult can it be?
It's just a harmless
piece of stone.
If it's so harmless, then
why don't you touch it?
[tablet buzzing]
[Wilson] Why is it doing that?
It seems to react to light.
Just a few minutes ago
I bombarded it
with infrared rays.
Now it's giving off radiation
in increasing amounts.
This might be the beginning
of a chain reaction.
It could become dangerous.
Then it is imperative
we find someone
to control it immediately.
Get Connors.
And this time do not fail.
As you wish.
Margaret, if I change
into that creature
you'll be in terrible dangerous.
Go stay with Billy at
your sisters, please.
But Curt, you may need me.
Please!
[Peter] You sure are
full of surprises, Doc.
When did the Lizard begin
to rear his ugly head again?
For months I've been
feeling it coming on.
It happens when I'm
under extreme stress.
We've got to get the
Tablet of Time back.
It might cure both you and me.
[wood crashing]
Margaret!
You again?
[Peter] Connors, run!
[explosions booming]
I'm getting sick of you.
[Peter grunting]
[Peter] The Lizard is getting
bigger and meaner than before.
Margaret.
I can't see Connors.
Then get his wife.
Get somebody!
[Peter] Mrs. Connors, run!
No!
Let go!
[Peter] She won't do
you any good, Smythe.
You don't understand!
Bring Connors to the top
of the Empire State
Building in six hours.
[Peter] Smythe, I can't.
[Alistair] You have six hours.
[Peter] No, wait!
Getting the tablet
from the Kingpin
ain't gonna be easy, Silvermane.
You know what I'm sayin'?
It's gonna cost you.
Tombstone, I've
got plenty of money
and you'll get more if
you bring me Connors too.
Just tell me where to find him.
I know where.
I work for Doctor Connors.
We'll lay a trap for him
at the neogenics lab at ESU.
Oh yeah, not bad
lookin' for a snitch.
Silence, fool.
That's no way to
talk to my daughter.
[Peter] Hmm, no rust on it yet.
It's fresh.
Wonder where it goes.
Ah, the subway.
At least I won't need a token.
I can't stop the chain reaction.
I think we should destroy it.
There's too much
power to control.
Controlling power is
what I do best, Smythe.
Just get Connors.
Now everything hinges
on his expertise.
Driver, you passed
the restaurant.
We're being followed, ma'am.
What?
Quickly, lose them.
[horn honking]
I believe this is your
stop, Miss Kingpin.
I'm warning you.
My husband will
not tolerate this.
Yeah, I know.
That's why he'll give me
just what I want
to get you back.
[Peter] Huh, tracks end here.
So now what?
[Lizard growling]
[Peter grunting]
[electricity buzzing]
Now where the heck did he--
[rocks crashing]
[electricity buzzing]
Sorry you took the
worst of that, Doc.
At least now you'll
be nice and peaceful
while I can get you
back to the lab.
[Peter grunting]
Let's hope this works as well
on your mutation
as it does on mine.
Doctor Connors, I presume.
[Peter] Who the heck are you?
My enemies call me Tombstone.
[laser zapping]
[Peter] Come on, Doc.
We've got to get out of here.
Now I get the name.
I feel like I was just hit
by a slab of granite.
[coughing]
Let go or we'll both suffocate.
Speak for yourself, bug boy.
I don't breathe.
[Tombstone laughing]
[upbeat rock music]
♪ Spider-man ♪
♪ Radioactive Spider-man ♪
♪ Spider blood ♪
♪ Radioactive spider blood ♪
♪ Spider-man ♪