[Robbie]
Previously onSpider-Man.
That belonged to
Captain America.
A scientist named
Reinstein created a serum
to turn humans into
a super soldier.
When the experiment
was sabotaged,
Reinstein and the
formula were lost.
Scientists tried to
recreate the formula.
One became incredibly fast.
The other could fly.
The Five discovered that their
powers weren't permanent.
They created ring
devices to turn them on
when needed.
The Five became The Destroyer,
Miss America,
Thunderer, Black Marvel
and the Whizzer.
With Cap, they were
the Six American Warriors.
One night, they stumbled onto
the most devious plot ever.
Project Doomsday.
Dispose of Groitzing.
Leave him alone.
[Peter] Captain America
sacrificed himself
so the Doomsday device
would never be used.
Someone is after the keys.
Insidious Six, find those keys.
Whizzer, you got
something I want.
That freak stole something.
[theme music playing]
♪ Spider-Man, Spider-Man ♪
♪ Radioactive Spider-Man ♪
[energetic music playing]
♪ Spider blood, spider blood ♪
♪ Radioactive spider blood ♪
♪ Spider-Man, Spider-Man ♪
[dramatic music playing]
[upbeat music playing]
The reasons for these
mysterious attacks
were unknown,
but in at least
two of the cases,
the only things taken
were small statuettes
of ancient warriors.
[knocking at door]
Who is it?
[Robbie] Omar, it's me, Rob.
Open up.
We've gotta go.
Spider-Man contacted me.
He wants you to get him
the last two keys
for safe keeping.
Are you sure he can be trusted?
You know I can be trusted.
That's all that matters.
All right, I'll get my coat.
I think I'll keep
my eye on this.
There's no telling who
might try to break in here.
[dramatic music playing]
This is it.
[tense music playing]
And here they are.
[laughing]
Thank you.
[triumphant music playing]
You're welcome.
Spider-Man.
And the Destroyer?
Hey! Come back here.
[tense music playing]
[footsteps pounding]
Spider sense.
Ugh!
[groaning]
[tense music playing]
I am sorry, gentlemen,
but I do intend that
the world be my new kingdom.
And you two,
shall be the first to bow
to your new sovereign.
Attack them, my knights.
Say hello to the next
Duke of New Jersey.
The Kingpin gets the world
and he gives you Jersey?
You need a better agent.
[thudding]
[tense music playing]
My powers! No, not again!
[groaning]
Spider-Man, you have been
a pain in my back side
for too long.
I herby decree that at long last
you're life must be terminated.
[shouting]
Destroyer, can you fight?
No, my powers are fading.
[laughing]
[thudding]
Leave him alone.
[grunting]
Black Marvel,
but he can't be alive.
[zapping]
[exciting music playing]
Enough!
It is a good thing
that I never rely
upon fisticuffs alone
in my negotiations.
I will let Mr. Robertson go
when you give me those keys.
Robbie!
[muffled moaning]
We have no choice.
We have to give him the keys.
Hang on!
[moaning]
[footsteps pounding]
[tense music playing]
Excellent.
[dramatic music playing]
You said you'd release Robbie.
And indeed I shall.
No!
[shouting]
No! My web shooters are empty.
Nice catch.
You ever think of trying
out for the Yankees?
Who are you?
The real Black Marvel
passed away years go.
My name is Omar Mosely
and I've been the real
Black Marvel all along.
What?
But how could that be?
It started back in 1942.
Dan Lyons originally volunteered
to become one of the six,
but his millionaire father
was an influential senator
with security clearance.
He found out about
it and forbade it.
To him, it was a dangerous risk,
unfit for his offspring.
But to me, it was a once
in a lifetime opportunity.
I volunteered to replace him.
Well, Dan was disappointed
but he backed me 100%.
We let everyone in
the Secret Service
continue to think Dan
was the Black Marvel.
It gave me a great cover.
Times were different then.
Didn't you ever wonder
why I called myself
The Black Marvel?
I'm glad to finally meet
the real Black Marvel.
My name is Keene Marlow.
I hate to break up
this little reunion,
but we still have
to stop Kingpin
from getting the last key.
The final statue is
held by The Thunderer
but he disappeared years go.
Then we have to assemble
those of us who are left
and go protect the site
of the Doomsday Complex.
[Spider-Man] I feel like
I'm witnessing
a part of this
country's history.
[Keene] This building was
our headquarters during the war.
After seeing the beacon,
we always assembled here.
I had to crack open a map
to remember where
this building was.
How have you been, Madeline?
I've missed you, Keene.
[puttering]
Sorry I'm late.
I guess I'm not as
fast as I used to be.
Whizzer, I was
hoping you'd show up.
It's good to see you.
I have just one
question for you.
Why did you call
yourself The Whizzer?
Hey, that's the sound I make.
Sure, these days
it sounds a little corny
but back then,
it was a swell name.
The only regret I have
is that I didn't continue
being a superhero.
Well, now we all
have one last chance
to prove ourselves again.
That's right.
This man who stole
your keys, The Kingpin,
he must be stopped.
This Doomsday machine has
been hanging over our lives
like the Sword of Damocles.
It's time we put an end to it.
Let's be realistic.
This is a young person's sport.
We'll all get ourselves hurt.
Maybe you're right,
Miss America.
What good can we do now?
Hey, wait.
Now, you may not
be in your prime
but I'd take you all anytime
over the crime
fighters of today.
I don't care what
the rest of you do.
I'm going to help
Spider-Man fight.
I'm ready for action.
Count me in.
Come on, Miss America.
For old times sake?
I'm with ya, as always.
Oh, all right.
You'll need somebody to
watch your achin' backs.
-Great!
-Thank you.
I brought something that
will help inspire us
through the coming battle.
All my searchers have failed.
I can't locate the final key.
Who has it?
He was called The Thunderer.
But his real name
Jerry Carstairs.
He has simply vanished
over the years.
Do you have any good news?
Yes, based on the
old coordinates
that the Parkers connected,
I've pinpointed the location
of the Doomsday Complex.
It's under some condemned
buildings in the Bronx.
I've created this device
that will guide you to
the exact point of entry.
Excellent, and then we
shall secure the location
while you continue to
work to find the last key.
[tense music playing]
Over that way.
No wonder it remained hidden.
Only the lowest form of vagrant
would inhabit these dwellings.
Here's a good example.
What are you doing
around here, old man?
I was just trying to be quiet.
Shocker, Vulture, eliminate him.
[triumphant music playing]
[groaning]
Agents, it's time
to clean up America.
Okay, bird brain,
I'll teach you to pick on
a defenseless old lady.
[thudding]
[punching]
[exciting music playing]
[dramatic music playing]
My flying ability.
I can't sustain it.
Madeline!
I'm getting weak also.
We're too old.
[gasping]
[shouting]
[beeping]
What's that sound?
My ears.
Amazing.
Disguised as a homeless man,
The Thunderer's been keeping
watch over this place
the whole time.
The Thunderer.
Correct, I vowed to
protect this site
and after all these years,
I won't stop now.
[zapping]
No!
My powers are fading.
[crunching]
[moaning]
Quickly, protect him!
[zapping]
[moaning]
You all should have realized
you were no match for
my Insidious Warriors.
Bring me The Thunderer.
He must have the final statue.
Search him and his
discarded clothes.
Excellent.
Who would have
thought the final key
would be so close.
Add this to the other five.
[dramatic music playing]
Yes, oh yes,
it's the same evil place,
Just as we left it 50 years go.
It even smells the same.
This, my warriors,
is a moment to savor.
Each of you will share
in this triumphant event.
[clicking]
Let our rule of
this planet begin.
[zapping]
What? What is the
meaning of this?
[blasting]
No, not again,
it's sleeping gas.
[coughing]
Kragov, the Red Skull's son.
Oh!
[tense music playing]
Why did the Chameleon
turn on the Kingpin?
And what's his
connection to Kragov?
Thank you for
everything, my brother.
So you are the traitor?
You don't understand
any of this do you?
The Red Skull, my father,
created the
Chameleon's technology
and trained him how to use
it when he was just a boy.
He was like an adopted
son in our family.
And now, we shall
free our father.
It looks like our
leader has gotten us
into another fine mess, huh?
Ah, my guests have arrived.
Dr. Groitzing who
designed this complex
and Mr. Lenz was a German
spy in this country
during the war.
He led me here.
All we had to do was wait
for you to acquire the keys
and then take them from you.
Now, good doctor,
activate the portal controls,
and bring my father out of
the matter/anti-matter vortex.
That's how they
power this place,
a perpetual energy field
that keeps matter
locked in stasis.
It's been so many years.
Don't be coy with me, professor.
You know what to do.
Yes, yes, it's working!
Unbelievable!
The German War criminal?
The Red Skull.
Father, don't you recognize us?
It's me, your son, Rheinholdt.
You've been held for
50 years in a vortex.
We are in this Doomsday
Complex you built.
We've come to free you.
Rheinholdt?
You've aged.
And you have not, father,
because of the vortex.
Chameleon, my stepson?
This truly is a joyous occasion.
What? Can this be?
Five of the six
American Warriors.
[laughs] Amazing.
You are withered by time
while I remain
young and vigorous.
We may be old,
but there's enough
fight left in us
to take you on.
[laughing]
During the war,
this entire complex
was built by German agents
to challenge the American Six
and destroy the United States.
To protect the
security of the project
the technology was constructed
by different scientific teams.
We had to smuggle the
equipment in by U-boat.
Then the meddling
American Six interfered.
You were the thorn in
my side all through the war.
But you won't get in
the way this time.
I will conquer the
United states of America
after all.
My doomsday plan
comes to fruition
after half a century.
That's it then.
We were crazy to try to make
any difference at our age.
We are destined to rule
and now we shall!
[dramatic music playing]
Robots, I hate robots.
And now, it is time for
these computerized machines
to meet their commander,
the one who will
lead them to victory.
-[gasps]
-Good heavens!
The living legend himself.
Now it is time to reveal
the piece de resistance.
Then, and only then, will I--
Oh!
You again.
[tense music playing]
[stomping]
[blasting]
[tense music playing]
No time to explain.
Free the others.
Wide-back, attack.
[exciting music playing]
Uh-oh.
[zapping]
[tense music playing]
Move in, move in!
[zapping]
It's us, The American Six.
Here my friend,
you'll need this.
[zapping]
[exciting music playing]
Okay team, let's make the
world safe for democracy.
[exiting music playing]
We must stop The Red Skull
and that traitor, the Chameleon.
[tense, rising music playing]
[groaning]
[crashing]
[tense music playing]
This way, Rheinholdt.
Oh, great.
[tense music playing]
Now what?
We've got them on the run.
Just follow me and stay alert.
[tense music playing]
What's happening to them?
They are losing power.
Lack of foresight isn't
usually a German failing.
That's the last of them.
I'm disappointed.
That hardly seemed
worthy of the Red Skull.
Yes, because of us,
he wasn't able to fully charge
his Doomsday robots.
What do you want me to
do with this creep, boss?
This traitorous reptile
will answer to me.
I don't get it.
I thought you were a mercenary.
I am.
Yes, my day job's for money,
but my father founded the group
to hunt German war criminals.
I was continuing his work
when I stumbled onto
the Doomsday plot.
Now, I know.
You are a friend,
one who can help me
finish my father's work.
[Spider-Man voiceover]
Amazing,
she's really
a Defender of Freedom too.
Heroes really do come
in all sizes and shapes.
I'm gonna help you, all right.
Between the two of us,
The Red Skull is finally
going to be history.
[theme music playing]
♪ Spider-Man, Spider-Man ♪
♪ Radioactive Spider-Man ♪
♪ Spider blood, spider blood ♪
♪ Radioactive Spider blood. ♪
♪ Spider-Man ♪