[Peter] Previously on
Spider-Man...
Hey! I'm losing my grip!
I'm losing my spider powers.
Ughh!
I gotta hide, It'd be too easy
from some villain
to grab me and
take my mask off.
I hope rest is all I need.
Wow! I feel fantastic.
My spider powers are back.
You slept all day
and all night.
What? I'm late for
Dr. Connors' class.
Nice of you to show up, Parker.
Great...
-Peter?
-Mary Jane!
Don't tell me you
were worried too.
Of course I was worried...
about your aunt.
It's incredible,
your DNA's structure
is changing.
I need to conduct
some more tests.
The mutogenic factor
in your blood has undergone
another transformation.
Did you say "mutogenic"?
You're still changing,
and it's accelerating.
So, while I can't tell you
exactly
what your DNA is transforming
you into,
one things already clear,
it won't be human.
[upbeat techno rock music]
♪ Spider-Man, Spider-Man ♪
♪ Radioactive Spider-Man ♪
[rock guitar solo]
♪ Spider blood, Spider blood ♪
♪ Radioactive spider blood ♪
♪ Spider blood, spider blood ♪
[guitar solo]
♪ Spider-Man, Spider-Man ♪
"Mystery thief
strikes eighth target.
Spider-Man suspected.
The police say only someone
with superhuman abilities
could have pulled
off these heists."
But I'm not a thief.
Why can't they ever get it
straight that
I'm one of the good guys?
[woman screaming]
Not even catching the Coney
Island pursue snatcher
can cheer me up tonight.
I'm more worried about
the mysterious disease
that changes me and my powers.
Dr. Connors said
I might be mutating
into some sort of freak.
I can't even think about that.
Maybe I oughta come
out here in the day
and bring somebody who's fun
to be with, like Mary Jane.
No, that would be too much
like a real date for her taste.
I wish I knew why she always
seems so afraid to get close.
Man, can you believe this heat?
What's eating you?
Two million bucks in
rare pearl sitting there
like seeds
in a glass of lemonade.
It's too tempting
if you ask me.
Especially, come on,
with all these robberies.
Relax, man.
Nobody's crazy enough
to try for these babies.
The glass is four inches thick
and everything in
there is under water,
pressurized at 500 fathoms.
Hit the alarm!
[alarm blaring]
[suspenseful music]
Huh?
Don't tell me the beluga whales
are having
a midnight flan bake?
Whoa!
No sign of the guards.
Now who would go and do
an unfriendly thing like?
Ah!
Hold on, kemosabe.
Man, this guy is fast.
Look at this.
It's the tops of all the tanks.
This must be where
they feed the fish.
Spider breeze.
Danger.
[grunting]
Oh, chow time and
I'm the main course.
I may not live long enough
to worry about that
disease after all.
[suspenseful music]
Useless.
Wait a minute.
The spare web cartridges.
[gasping]
Look!
Spider-Man really is the thief.
Oh, great.
Jameson will
probably be selling
"Spider-Man really is
the thief" T-shirts
by noon tomorrow.
Look out for his--
[guards groaning]
He's gone.
Who the heck was that guy?
[Morrie] It's all
for you, Mary Jane.
-MJ?
-Hey, tiger.
Sorry that I'm late.
By the way, I saw your photos
in the Bugle this morning.
Another front page.
Very impressive.
[water drips]
Well, who am I to disagree?
Oh, that reminds me.
Here, your first
professional gig
preserved for
posterity as requested.
You're a total doll.
What do I owe you?
How about if you
pay for both of us
at Coney Island tomorrow?
I don't think that's
such a good idea.
What's up, MJ?
You've been turning me
down right and left lately.
I'm sorry, Peter.
But with my career taking off
I just don't have the time.
Hey, this isn't
about your career.
This is about you not
wanting to get close.
All I'm asking--
MJ, phone for you and
make it AS-PA AB-bae.
or my boss will ill-K me.
Thanks, Liz.
Back in a sec.
Mary Jane Watson,
fabulous supermodel.
[Morrie]
Still the joker, ay, Red?
[gasp] Morrie?
So you do recognize my voice?
[Mary Jane] What do you want?
Meet me in the lobby
of the Hotel Seville
in 20 minutes.
Alone.
No, I can't meet you.
I won't.
You can and you will, Red.
It's as inevitable as
the tides.
[tense music]
Mary Jane.
Hey, wait up!
Where are you going?
Look, Peter.
I'm sorry, but there's some
place I've got to go, okay?
I could tag along
and keep you company.
[Mary Jane whistling]
I'm a big girl now.
I can take care of myself.
So stop following me.
This isn't about me.
That phone call got
her really jumpy.
Well, she told Peter
Parker not to follow her
but she didn't say
anything about Spider-Man.
[tense music]
-Boo! Guess who?
-[Mary Jane gasping]
It's good to finally
see you again, Red.
It's been too long.
What is this?
I always said I'd
give you the world.
This is just the down payment.
Look, Morrie,
our relationship is over.
You were jealous, overbearing
and made my life miserable,
so leave me alone.
At least I never ran out on
you like your father did.
You shut up about him.
We were wrong for each
other two years ago
and we're wrong now.
That's all I came to tell you.
Mary Jane.
No, wait!
Hey, where did that guy go?
Morrie?
Hey, hey, I know why you
broke up with me, Mary Jane.
I had no car,
no cash, no class.
I was a nobody.
How did he beat me here?
You just don't understand.
Oh, but I do.
Things are different now.
I can give you everything
you've ever dreamed of.
You must come with me.
There's something
I have to show you.
I don't have to do anything.
Leave me alone.
Fine.
Have it your way.
I'll show you what I'm talking
about right here.
Kumbaya!
[people yelling]
Not too shabby, huh, Red?
How did you do that?
As long as
I'm close enough to it,
I can control all
the water around me.
What do you think?
I think you're
crazier than ever.
Hold it.
What are you doing here?
A 500-foot geyser
in Washington Square
and you're wondering
why I'm here?
I said hold it.
Is the bigshot hero stuck?
Let me give you a hand.
[grunting] Am I losing my mind?
Did he just turn into liquid?
Now do you understand?
I've been transformed.
I can do anything.
I can give you
whatever you want.
I don't want anything from you.
Red, wait.
[Mary Jane screaming]
Somebody call the cops.
No, call the lifeguard.
...eat your heart out.
This has nothing to do with
you, Spider-Man so butt out.
I can't. They'd take away
my superhero license.
Anyway, there's a strict no
surfing rule in the park, dude.
Pathetic.
You don't really
think you can match
the power of Hydro-Man, do you?
[Spider-Man coughing]
Did you say Hydrant-Man?
The dogs must love you.
It's Hydro-Man and
it's the last name
you'll ever hear.
For somebody new to
this super-villain gig
you've sure got
the cliches down.
The itsy bitsy spider
went up the water spout.
Down came the rain to
wash the spider out.
[tense music]
Forget your water wings, dude?
I'm running out of air.
Bench is waiting
for me up top.
Maybe I can go the other way.
That's water under the bridge
but I'll bet that
barely slowed him down.
I'd better find MJ before
Don Juan in a bottle does.
[Mary Jane screaming]
Relax, it's just me.
Would you please
just put me down?
Sorry.
I just didn't want to make it
too easy for him
to find you, Miss...
Watson.
Mary Jane Watson.
-I'm--
-I know who you are.
I have a TV.
I appreciate the rescue
but I'm just a little
tired of weird men
making unscheduled
appearances in my life.
Speaking of weird,
who is that guy?
He's name is Morrie Bench.
I'm embarrassed to say I used
to date him in high school.
He seemed nice enough at first,
but he turned out
to be a big mistake.
I sure can pick 'em.
And what about the--
The turning into water thing?
That's new.
I don't recall him
doing that at the prom.
I don't think this
guy is gonna give up.
You'd better take this.
What is it?
It's a way for me to be
around if you need me.
Do you want me to
web-swing you home?
Thanks, but I'd rather
just take a cab.
Man, now I know why she's
been so afraid to commit.
This lady hasn't had much
luck with relationships.
Let's hope Bench's liquid form
is as good a catalyst
as regular old H2O.
If so, this little solution
might just do the trick.
I hope.
Hey, Liz.
-Do you know where I can find--
-Mary Jane?
Yeah, she's hiding out at
my place pretty shaken up.
Here's the address.
You should look in on her.
[Peter] Thanks, Liz.
[Liz] Stay cool, Parker.
Guess we are not so
different, huh, Dad?
When things got tough,
I turned tail and ran, too
but not for long.
The difference between us
is I'm not gonna run anymore
no matter what.
[Mary Jane gasping]
Morrie!
MJ needs me as a friend
now more than ever.
[Mary Jane screaming]
Oh no, too late.
[tense music]
Mary Jane?
No!
[Mary Jane screaming]
A spider tracer.
-Horrible.
-She's gone.
No.
That's what
he wants us to think.
She's got to be alive
but where?
Sorry about the bumpy trip,
but I needed to show you this.
It's you.
You're behind
all the robberies.
Right.
I'm not a small-timer anymore.
How did you get this way?
Remember when I was
expelled from school?
After that my parents made
me enlist in the navy.
And they said it was to
keep me out of trouble.
Oh, but you were right
to dump, Mary Jane,
'cause I had nothing.
I was a nobody.
Even after I was transferred
to special research,
I was still a loser.
Then last month,
a miracle happened.
Something deep inside
the Earth changed me.
Turned me from a nothing
into a something.
Now I had power.
[Morrie laughing evilly]
Now I could have anything
in the world I wanted.
And I want you.
Well, guess what.
I'm not a thing, I'm a person.
Don't you get it?
I don't want to own you.
I want to love you.
I want you to remember
that you love me.
Morrie, listen to me.
I don't love you.
I never loved you.
[Morrie] I'll flood the city,
force everyone to run
keeping it for
just the two of us.
-Forever.
-[Mary Jane gasping]
[Spider-Man]
Three minutes under water.
Do I get my merit badge?
You!
Haven't you figured out yet
that your web is
useless against me?
Yes, so I made this
new batch just for you.
[grunting]
What did you do to him?
Is he okay?
No, he's stuck.
I mixed a powerful
coagulant into my web fluid,
one that would react
with the H2O in his body
and become a hardening agent.
What?
Basically, I stirred
powdered gelatin into him.
Let's just say he's getting
his just desserts.
[Mary Jane]
How did you find us?
When I spotted this
pumping station, it hit me.
I realized he could pour
himself into these pipes
and get anywhere in the city,
bank vaults, sprinklers,
kitchen sinks, water picks.
Get away from here.
She belongs to me.
[suspenseful music]
Oh! [groans]
Mary Jane!
There's no way to hide from me.
I am everywhere!
[suspenseful music]
[car horns beeping]
[man yelling]
[Spider-Man groaning]
Mary Jane.
She got away.
But which pipe?
It's like a needle
in a haystack.
Think, MJ, think.
Mary Jane.
[Mary Jane] Morrie!
[Mary Jane groaning]
That wasn't nice.
[suspenseful music]
Hey, you don't belong here.
Get lost.
Oh.
[suspenseful music]
Looks like the end of the line.
That's right.
Nowhere left to run.
So, why don't we all
just take a break.
You again?
Haven't you figured out
yet that you can't beat me?
I don't have to, sleek.
She already has.
Huh?
Don't you get it, Bench?
She's led you away from
the water that feeds you.
You're barely holding
yourself together, pal.
You're almost out of you.
Why, Mary Jane?
Why?
I loved you.
You don't kidnap people
you love, Morrie.
And you don't force
yourself on people you love.
Morrie, it's over.
We've got to get you some help.
[Morrie screaming]
I'll destroy you
with my bare hands.
Morrie, no.
[Spider-Man] Bench, don't.
He's evaporating.
Does this mean he's...
-He's...
-Not necessarily.
H2O is infamous among solvents
for its self-cohesiveness.
Brother, now you sound like
my friend Peter Parker.
Hey, don't insult me.
[thunder]
[cheerful circus music]
Oh, shoot.
I think this is rigged.
You wanna try?
So, let me get this straight.
This woman faces the most
powerful super-villain ever
without falling to pieces
and I, Mr. Superhero, come
whining about getting sick?
Maybe I could learn a
thing or two from her.
A winner!
Stick with me, tiger,
and I'll teach you
how to beat the odds.
Sorry about the rain.
It seems like
you're having nothing
but water problems lately.
You know, right now,
it really doesn't
seem like a problem.
[upbeat rock music]
♪ Spider-Man ♪
♪ Radioactive Spider-Man ♪
[upbeat rock music]
♪ Spider blood, spider blood ♪
♪ Radioactive spider blood ♪
♪ Spider-Man ♪