[upbeat rock music]
♪ Spider-Man ♪
♪ Radioactive Spider-Man ♪
♪ Spider blood
Spider blood ♪
♪ Radioactive spider blood ♪
♪ Spider blood
Spider blood ♪
♪ Radioactive spider blood ♪
[explosions booming]
[growling]
♪ Spider-Man ♪
[thinking]
No man tells me what to do.
Spider-Man doesn't
want me around? Fine.
If he can be a loner,
so can the Black Cat.
Hey, that's odd.
The Hardy Foundation
doesn't have trucks
that look like that.
Bingo! Crime in Progress.
What's Black Cat
doing down there?
Maybe I should keep
an eye on her, spider-style.
[brakes squeal]
'Bout time you got here!
-[gas hisses]
-[groaning]
-Time for your cat nap.
-[gun cocks]
What do you think
you're doing here, lady?
This ain't no sewing circle.
Aww, too bad.
'Cause when I'm through,
you're gonna need stitches!
Believe me, that's
the last thing you wanna do!
[gun firing]
Aaah!
[men grunting]
Uhh!
-Aah!
-Unh!
[groans]
You. How long have
you been there?
Since the overture.
Cat, you shouldn't be
handling this solo!
It's too dangerous!
-Wait here while I--
-Like heck I will!
I can't just let her fight
all these guys by herself!
Huh!
Aah! Unh!
Then again...
Huh!
Aaah! Oof!
Maybe I should reevaluate
some of my male chauvinist
preconceptions.
See, spider?
This superhero thing isn't
as hard as it looks.
-[spider-sense tingling]
-Oh, boy!
Gas! I-- [groans]
Ohh!
Surprise.
Alistair Smythe?
Wait, stop!
When we last met,
I thought you quit
working for the Kingpin!
I did, but my current employer
is also your enemy.
And once again,
that makes you mine.
But before I destroy you,
there's something I need.
Her!
[laughing sinisterly]
Smythe, let her go!
[Spider-Man coughing]
I blew it! I should've
been ready for trouble.
Why'd I let
the Cat have her way?
[baby crying]
Shh, quiet, Father!
The men are back.
They'd better have news
that'll cheer you up.
Smythe, did you get
everything you needed
at Toomes Aerodynamics?
Almost everything,
plus a little bonus.
Silvermane should
see for himself.
We're on our way.
He's up to something!
[Alisa] If he's ruined
your plans, Father,
then we'll eliminate him.
Do you want your bottle now?
No, but this useless body
of mine needs it.
Give it to me!
Oh, how I rue the day
I ever toyed
with that Tablet of Time!
Power of the Toltecs,
give me the invulnerability
that will carry me
into the next millennium!
[lasers shooting]
[groans]
Father! Are you all right?
Better than all right.
I feel wonderful--
[agonized screams]
Dr. Connors, where are you?!
[boy's voice]
I don't wanna be like this!
Make it stop.
Please, somebody help me!
[baby crying]
Bah! My mind is trapped!
I am powerless!
On the contrary.
With Smythe working for you,
you now have
the same scientific knowledge
that Kingpin once enjoyed.
Smythe, I gave you
this lab to develop a way
to make me an adult again,
not collect specimens!
With the equipment we've taken
from Toomes' burnt-out lab
and the data
from the Tablet of Time,
I have almost
all the pieces I need
in order to reverse-engineer
the science of Neogenics.
And I know
of only two such subjects.
Scorpion and the Vulture?
Then get one of them at once!
The problem is,
they've gone underground.
Vanished!
However, that's where
this lovely creature
may help us.
By holding her hostage,
we may be able
to force Spider-Man
to do our legwork,
make him find Scorpion
and Vulture for us.
Ah, clever idea!
Spider-Man's weakness
is that he cares too much!
Good work, Smythe.
Quickly, change my diaper.
Father, I promise
that soon you will be free
to walk the earth
in a new bio-engineered body.
I swear I'll make
Silvermane keep his word.
Though once again, I find
I am working for promises.
[web shooting]
This is hopeless.
I've looked everywhere!
[spider-sense tingling]
Spider seekers!
It looks
like Smythe's found me!
[groaning]
Spider-Man, listen to me.
As you know,
I have the Black Cat.
Do as I say,
and she will be safe.
-Otherwise...
-What do you want, Smythe?
I want one of these two.
Either one.
When you bring
one of them to me,
I will release your friend.
You have 24 hours,
starting now.
Use this device to signal me
when you are successful.
Smythe, wait! Great.
How am I gonna
find those two worms
in an apple this big?
[woman on TV]
And I promise that once you
start using the buff bike.
you'll have the body
you've always wanted!
[Toomes]
Turn it back on!
I said, turn it back on!
Toomes, shut ya trap.
What's the matter, Gargan?
Don't you wanna hear about
getting the body
you always wanted?
-[groans]
-[Gargan] I said, shut up!
You laugh,
but your stupid experiments
have made you a freak,
just like me!
Doc, what are you doin' to me?
Easy, it's the radiation.
Radiation?
Ain't that stuff dangerous?
Gargan, this is
what you said you wanted.
-[Gargan] Stop! Stop!
-Steeler, what's wrong with him?
He'll be okay.
I chose to use a scorpion,
because it's a natural predator
of the spider.
[Jonah] Spider-Man will
at last meet his match.
There's only one reason
I bothered to save
your miserable life
after your lab went kablooey!
It's because I need
a science guy like you
to turn me back
to plain old Mac Gargan.
Fine, then let me go,
so I can cure us both!
[groaning]
You're gonna stay
right where you are
until I can get
the money to build us a lab.
Why don't you steal it,
bug boy?
Petty crime is your forte.
No! I told you,
I'm going straight!
[laughs] You're going
nowhere, Gargan.
You're hiding.
Maybe you should call
yourself "The Cockroach."
Nah, but maybe you
do have a point.
I gotta do something.
You're doing
the right thing, Gargan!
[Gargan] Sarah!
-Mac, what are you doing?!
You can't go out in public!
If they caught you,
they'd put you in jail.
I'd never see you again.
But, Sarah, honey,
don't you want me to be normal?
We'll get the money,
it'll be okay.
I've already saved $500.
Wow, 500 whole dollars!
By the time we have enough,
my young self
will look like I do now!
Don't you ever insult her again!
I'll do it your way.
Thank you, Mac.
We'll make it, I promise.
Then we can get married.
[Peter, thinking]
This is getting me nowhere.
There are no records
of either the Scorpion
or the Vulture being seen
since the lab explosion.
Only eight hours left.
Maybe I should keep
trying to find Smythe.
At least I know he's out there.
I never realized how much
the Black Cat meant to me,
until now.
[knock on door]
Pete, can I come in?
I don't mean
to bother you, but...
Well, I'm feeling
really down tonight.
I thought maybe we could talk?
Not now, Harry, I can't.
Look, Pete, this won't
take long, I just--
That's weird.
I'm sorry, Harry.
Sorry that Spider-Man always
gets in the way of my life.
And my friendships.
[Connors]
You want me to declare
that I've made
a new breakthrough
in the science of Neogenics?
Look, I know your new research
isn't that far along yet,
but I really need your help!
Well, I'm crazy for doing this,
but I do owe you.
[beeping]
J-3 Communications.
This is Dr. Curt Connors
of Empire State University.
I have a story for you.
Neogenics,
the technology to change
the genetic structure
of any living creature,
will be reborn again.
I have rediscovered
the secrets
that Farley Stillwell took
with him when he disappeared.
Hey, that's the stuff
I need to transform me!
I'm appealing to
any institution or individual
to help me
fund Neogenic research,
rebuild
the Neogenic recombinator,
and once again offer
the possibility
of a better life for everyone.
You're right, Toomes,
I gotta act now.
Well, you're finally using
more than your tail, bug boy!
Mac, darling, what's wrong?
Where are you going?
Mac, what are you doing?
I gotta get that money
the only way I know how.
I'm doing it for us!
-[Sarah] Mac! Mac!
-[doorknob rattling]
Don't hurt anyone!
All of you, keep away from me,
and nobody'll get hurt!
[Spider-Man] Took long enough
to smoke you out.
Looks like retirement
didn't mellow you any.
Beat it, you stinkin' yo-yo!
I don't have time
to joke around! [straining]
[groaning]
Scorpion,
you're gonna listen to me
if I have to tie you up
with your own tail!
All right, you want my tail,
Spider-Man?
Here, it's all yours!
Ooh! Aah!
I warned you to leave me alone.
Now it's too late for you.
[Spider-Man gasping]
Scorpion,
you've got to listen!
Hey, my money!
[grunts]
Get away from that money,
you hear me?
Get away from it!
Mac, what are you doing?!
Stupid wall-crawler!
You ruined everything!
-I'm running out of time!
-I'm running out of time, too!
Aaah!
-[crash]
-Ooh!
Smythe, I've got Scorpion.
Excellent, I shall send
a spider seeker to guide you in.
Tell Silvermane
that phase one is successful.
The Spider has caught his prey.
I can't wait to see the Cat.
-You could've been--
-We've got something special.
Can't you feel it?
I care about her
more than I even knew.
You understand, before I
consider our bargain complete,
I must make sure he's genuine.
His DNA patterns are excellent.
He's a Neogenic roadmap.
The perfect Rosetta Stone
for my little experiment.
Mac, no!
I kept my word, Smythe.
And I shall keep mine.
There she is.
Okay, release her.
I'm saving
that privilege for you.
I don't suspect
there's any kind of trap here?
Don't be too upset
about this, Cat.
Sometimes in the superhero biz,
you make a few mistakes.
-Indeed.
-[spider-sense tingling]
No! Spider-Man!
[groaning]
[sighs] Maybe I should take
superhero lessons
from the Hulk instead.
[Silvermane]
Good work, Smythe.
This is one bonus
of which I approve.
Thank you, Silvermane.
Did he say Silvermane?
Silvermane is alive?
Spider-Man, I shall make a trade
to swap your age for mine,
and with your powers,
I will be unbeatable!
-[giggling]
-Excellent idea, Father.
Silvermane is that baby?
So, here's another
fine mess we've gotten
ourselves into, Ollie.
Any bright ideas, partner?
Did I hear you say partner?
Please, you've got to save Mac!
Why should I?
They're going to Neogenic
him or something!
Neogenic? Are you certain?
Positive!
Just the sound of that word
makes me feel young again.
I guess I willcrash
your boyfriend's party!
[laughing]
I'll show you where to go.
[Smythe] Thanks to the DNA
from the Scorpion,
everything is ready.
Then do it now.
I want to be a man again!
Full of youth and superpower
of Spider-Man!
[Black Cat] What are
they doing to Spider-Man?
They're messing up his life,
just like they did to me.
Firing commences
in five seconds.
Great, now I'm
gonna have to learn
to web-sling in a stroller!
[Smythe, laughs]
Four, three, two, one.
[laser blast]
No! He'll ruin the experiment!
[groaning]
Toomes, where's Sarah?
[Toomes]
Never mind her.
Look, they've recreated
my energy-swapping technology!
Shut off the machine!
It's a controlled process!
It can't be turned off!
Then stop him!
Oh!
What's happening?
Sorry, old man,
but your technology is mine now.
[groans]
Stay away
from beautiful machines!
But I created the technology,
and I will use it!
I can't wait
to stop changing like this!
I can't swap energy with him!
Stop him!
Get back into the machine!
Unh!
Thanks, partner.
Don't mention it, partner.
Shut off the machine!
He's too old!
-[groaning]
-[Gargan] Okay, Science Boy,
who's gonna do
the dissecting now?
[growling]
I have to shut off
the main power!
You fool!
You ain't doing no more work
with your machines!
Father, no!
Too old!
I'm young again!
This time,
it better stay that way.
Toomes, with
no one in the machine,
the recombinator will overload!
Who cares?
I have what I always wanted!
Thanks for the new lease
on life, old man!
[laughing]
[Gargan grunting]
Alisa! Get her out of here!
The recombinator
is gonna explode!
Oooh!
[man] Aah!
Hello?
Aggh!
Somebody, help him!
[Spider-Man]
She's right, come on!
But isn't he
one of the bad guys?
Yes, but I got him
into this mess.
[groans]
You are a freak of nature
whom I shall eliminate!
[groans]
Great line
coming from a cyborg!
I gotta get to Smythe!
He knows how to change me back!
[growling]
Smythe, hurry!
[grunting]
We have only minutes!
I'll make sure
they don't follow us.
[Black Cat]
They've sealed the lab!
I'm sorry it turned
out this way, Father,
but at least you won't have
to deal with diapers anym--
I wouldn't be so sure.
I'm sorry, Father,
but once again,
Spider-Man
has thwarted my efforts.
Our long-tailed friend
melted the main panel.
[Gargan]
Don't blame me for this.
You're the one
that brought me here,
and now you've
trapped us like rats!
We don't have much time.
Try and maneuver him
over to the doorway.
Easier said than done.
Please, don't hurt him!
Don't worry, I never hurt
mutated homicidal insects.
[growling]
Hey, bug brain, over here.
You won't be so funny
when I give you an acid shampoo!
[Spider-Man] I love it
when a plan comes together.
Thanks for waiting
till the last second.
Timing is everything.
Here, let me do it.
This takes muscle.
[grunts]
You're right, it did.
Out of my way!
[explosion]
[Gargan]
Will I ever be normal, Sarah?
You have to have faith
and know that our love
will get
us through anything.
[laughing]
[Spider-Man] I couldn't
find any sign of them!
Did you mean what you said
about us being partners?
Well, now that the Neogenic
genie is out of the bottle,
I'll probably need
all the help I can get!
Are you sure I'm not
just a temporary convenience?
You were terrific back there,
and I'd be proud to have
you fight by my side.
Not only that,
but I really care about you.
Partners?
That, and maybe more.
Catch you later, Spider.
You know, I think my life
just got
a lot more interesting.
[upbeat rock music]
♪ Spider-Man, Spider-Man ♪
♪ Radioactive Spider-Man ♪
♪ Spider blood, spider blood ♪
♪ Radioactive spider blood ♪
♪ Spider blood ♪
♪ Spider-Man ♪