[Fury] Previously on
Spider-Man...
You will never win, Mother.
We just have.
Move an inch and I fire
this solar light emitter.
What's happening?
[screams]
Spider, where am I?
-Million planet.
-Send me back.
We can't.
Spider-Man, I must
attack without you.
We'll be ready.
You want me to go
on a suicide run?
It might be wise to turn back.
That's not an option.
Super soldier formula
was used on me.
You are like me.
[Morbius] Red Skull,
behold Cyber Skull.
Otto Octavius?
The doctor has offered
his technology.
Rebels move in.
[Spider-Man] That's the
Red Skull's fortress.
The rebel forces have
them occupied out front.
Security has been breached.
[exploding]
The robots are
pounding the rebels.
[exploding]
-[cheering]
-This way, follow me.
[Black Cat] Not this time.
[screams]
Almost had him.
I am sorry that
I brought you here.
I'm not.
I'm fighting alongside
one of the greatest heroes
of all time.
[theme music playing]
♪ Spider-Man, Spider-Man ♪
♪ Radioactive Spider-Man ♪
♪ Spider blood, spider blood ♪
♪ Radioactive spider blood ♪
♪ Spider-Man, Spider-Man ♪
♪ Spider-Man ♪
[suspenseful music playing]
[Spider-Man] Secret war
log entry number 19.
This part of the alien
planet once belonged
to Doctor Otto Octavius,
until Doctor Doom
laid waste to his country.
Now, The Fantastic Four
are ready to move in
on Doom's stronghold,
a place he calls New Latveria.
But first, we must rendezvous
with The Fantastic Four.
End of log.
These are the
coordinates they gave us,
but I don't see
any sign of them.
-Uh oh.
-What?
Whoa!
Hey!
[growling]
Uh-oh.
[crashing]
[Spider-Man]
Lizard's gone berserk.
He's acting like
his old self again.
[groans]
Are you okay?
Hey Doc, it's me!
I'm sorry, Spider-Man.
I couldn't control my anger.
Maybe when you use
your lizard strength,
you unlock the reptilian
side of your brain.
It might be trying to
take over your mind again.
I fear that you're right.
Reed Richards has helped me
contain my lizard half before.
We have to find him quickly,
so he can help me now.
I'm picking up the homing beacon
from The Fantastic Four's ship.
It's just over that rise.
[suspenseful music playing]
Sue, darling, are you all right?
-Reed.
-Yes, my love.
I'll be fine.
What happened?
We were ambushed.
We were flying in low
to avoid detection
when we were suddenly attacked
by Doom's hidden robots.
[crashing]
[exploding]
They had the element of
surprise on their side.
We never got a chance to
put up a decent fight.
Flame on!
[lasers blasting]
Even though they
had the upper hand,
they didn't finish us off.
Instead they retreated.
Ben.
By taking Ben, it was as if
they had what they wanted.
Why would Doctor Doom
only want Ben Grimm?
I don't know, but we
might fight our way into
New Latveria and rescue him.
If we don't, we may never
see Ben again alive.
[engines roaring]
Ah, Mr. Grimm.
[roars]
Doctor Doom.
Let me go or I'll--
You'll do something
for me, all right.
I brought you here
for one reason.
You will tell me why you were
all brought to this planet,
and by whom.
I ain't telling
you nothing, tin face.
Oh no?
Perhaps this might
convince you to talk.
I call it my Elemental Splitter.
Isn't it beautiful?
[Ben screams]
Without reinforcements,
odds are we'll never make
it to New Latveria.
No, Ben is in jeopardy.
We can't stop for
anything, understand?
Hey, I'm on your side, remember?
Look, bug boy, you have
to understand Reed.
He's never forgiven himself
for causing the tragedy
that turned Ben into The Thing.
We were transformed
into The Fantastic Four
when Reed convinced Ben
to pilot our ship
into outer space.
We were unexpectedly bombarded
with strange radiation
that changed us forever.
[crashing]
But while Reed,
my sister, and I
gained fantastic new powers,
Ben was forever turned
into an ugly monster.
Reed feels responsible for
Ben becoming The Thing.
But he has forgotten that
you're the one leading us now.
What do you want us to do?
Well, I guess we'll
keep moving forward.
Doom might not expect
us to keep advancing.
Personal log entry 52.
I never would have believed it,
but we've encountered no more
robots since the last attack.
We're now at the very
walls of New Latveria.
I fear that this is
some sort of trap.
I sense Doom hiding
around every corner.
Pun intended.
I don't suppose
we just ring the bell.
I have a bad feeling about this.
This looks interesting.
[woman over PA] The citywide
bingo game will be held
in the town hall at 5:30 sharp.
Don't miss the fun.
Unbelievable.
There's a war being waged
all around this place,
yet here it's--
Yes, Doom has created
and idyllic society.
Idyllic, maybe,
but isn't that the promise
of every fascist?
[woman over PA]
Your attention, please.
Spider-Man, The Lizard,
and The Fantastic Three
are cordially invited to tea
at Victor VanDoom's residence
promptly at three o'clock.
[Reed] Well,
we have our invitation.
I don't think
we need directions.
[chains clanking]
[Ben] Come on in, guys.
I'm making tea and crumpets.
Ben, is that really you?
Ben!
-You're--
-Normal again?
Thanks for noticing.
Old Doc D. changed me back
just like I always wanted.
How did he do that?
Doc's some sort of
power separator.
Watch this, I can transform
whenever I want to.
Pretty neat, huh?
Maybe. What does he want
from you in return?
Nothing, other than
for him to be happy.
That's what I want
for all my citizenry.
Then why don't you free
them from your tyranny?
Why don't you leave
them as they were
before you arrived from Earth?
Because it wouldn't be
long before they'd be
swallowed up by someone like
Octavius, or The Red Skull.
I am not a tyrant,
I am their savior.
Look around you,
everyone here is free.
I've been able to
establish an ideal society.
There is no back-breaking labor,
no struggle for food and
shelter, only pleasure.
And I owe it all to
my miraculous robots.
This technology does
nothing but good.
Look what it has done for
Ben Grimm, or even for myself.
The horrible acid burns
that ruined your face,
-they're gone.
-Yes.
A lab accident once turned me
into monster, like Ben here.
But now, I am as
pleasing to look at
as my benevolence is to behold.
I desire nothing but to keep
my citizens content and happy.
You desire nothing but
their praise and servitude.
You're a charlatan.
Hey, now that ain't fair, Reed.
I think I can guess why
you're attacking me, Richards.
I've cured Ben,
something you could never do.
Why, you--
[robots squeaking]
Flame on!
[grunts]
[growls]
The pain!
Doc!
You guys don't understand.
I owe Doc Doom too much!
Since you won't
accept my sincerity,
or my hospitality, you will
all be bound over for trial.
The charge is treason
against New Latveria,
and if found guilty,
you will all be destroyed!
[laughing]
See what I told
you about Richards?
Oh, Reed will calm down.
Then you can release them all.
Can I?
I will not let them
destroy the New Latveria
I've built here.
Do you want all
this to be ruined?
No, Doc, but, trust me,
you can let 'em go.
Why should I trust you when
you don't trust me enough
to tell me how and why
we were brought here?
Okay, but you've gotta
promise to free my friends.
Of course I will.
You have my word.
That's good enough for me.
Spider-Man told us that
some guy called The Beyonder
used some high-tech
transporter machine
to bring us all here.
He wants to play
a game with the good guys
and the bad guys
to see who's gonna win.
A-ha.
I knew there was a higher
power involved in this.
When I was being brought
here across the galaxy,
I used the instruments
in my suit to get a fix
on the source of the
dimensional disturbance.
I traced the coordinates
to an asteroid
that was in orbit
around this planet,
but I had no means
of getting there.
Now, Ben, you tell me of
a space-time transporter.
You must take me to
see it, you must!
Well, well,
I would have never guessed
a lab would be here in
this worm-filled wasteland.
[laser blasting]
My robot will occupy them
with some obedience training.
[Ben] Spidey says
this is the machine
that brought us here.
[Dr. Doom] It is beautiful.
You mean, you can maybe
get us outta here?
That, and maybe more.
[controls beeping]
There, it is done.
And now, to put my
plan into action.
Wait, Doc!
Where you going?
[dramatic music playing]
[laser gun blasting]
What'd you do?
How'd we get back here?
I have willed us here, Ben.
Don't you see?
My elemental splitter not
only separates elements,
it can also be
used to fuse them.
I used it to combine the
Beyonder's powers with my own.
Imagine the possibilities.
With these new powers, my
very thoughts become reality.
The first thing I will do
is end this destructive
and unnecessary
war on my planet.
[Captain America] At last,
I have you where
I've always wanted.
Huh?
[Black Cat] What's
happening to them?
Now, let's deal with
the rest of my guests.
Okay, that was a pretty
neat trick, Doom.
Explain how you did it.
I have taken over the
powers of The Beyonder.
I have sent the
evil-doers back to Earth.
You are all now my guests
here on New Latveria.
My desire is that you should
live amongst my subjects.
Tell them what a great and
benevolent leader I am.
Hold on, Doom,
we're not your pawns.
Under that metal suit,
you're just a very disturbed
human being.
You can't possibly control
the god-like abilities
you've stolen.
You might place us
all in grave danger
if you don't give that power up.
Do you take me for a fool?
Who amongst you has ever wanted
to give up their super powers?
I have, because I've learned
time and time again,
that with great power,
there must also come
great responsibility.
And that's a responsibility
even you can't avoid.
I do not wish to avoid it.
This power,
this responsibility,
is my destiny.
Ah, I grow weary of this
exercise in futility.
Enough, a lizard will
not be dominated.
[growls]
[Spider-Man] Doc, no!
I promised Ben here
I would not harm you.
I have kept my word.
[dramatic music playing]
We're over 50 miles away.
So how do we fight him?
There's no way we can overcome
the powers he has now.
We have to find a way.
Don't you see?
The Beyonder still
exists inside of Doom,
And I think he still wants
to see who backs down first.
Good, or evil.
I agree with Spider-Man.
I say we vote on whether
to oppose Doom or not.
I vote we fight.
An excellent idea.
Yes, fight!
You realize Doom is
probably reading our minds.
If we vote to oppose him,
he may immediately
decide to retaliate.
What's he gonna do, drop a
mountain on us or something?
[rocks crumbling]
[Black Cat] Look!
Run!
Hmm. Farewell heroes.
Doc!
My friends, please.
Tell me what you did with them.
Who knows?
Perhaps they are
hiding under a rock.
Leave me now.
I am tired from
employing my new power.
I must rest.
[Reed] We can't
keep this mountain
from collapsing on us forever.
We have to make
one great effort.
All at once, quickly,
everyone, push!
[crashing]
[Spider-Man] Doc?
We should make camp.
We won't be able to take
on Doom without rest.
Doc, can you make it?
Yes, Spider-Man.
Rested or not,
how can we fight a titan?
Look what I got them into.
I started this fight.
Now I have to finish it.
The Beyonder is the key.
He may still be there,
inside Doom somewhere.
I have to draw him out.
[suspenseful music playing]
Hey!
[growling]
[suspenseful music playing]
Those creatures!
They're coming from the castle!
What the devil?
[grunting]
Spider-Man!
Where are these creepy-crawlies
all coming from?
How dare you!
Look at what you've been doing!
Don't you see?
Your sleeping subconscious
mind used your
Beyonder powers to
create monsters that are
tearing your kingdom apart!
You lie!
Whatever they are,
I can vanquish them
with a mere thought.
No!
Why can't I make them go away?
They are a more
troubled, unhappy mind.
They're your
nightmares made real!
Spidey's right, Doc.
Those powers are gonna
tear you up inside!
You gotta let go of
them for all our sakes!
You simpleton.
This is what
I wanted all my life.
Absolute control and power.
I will not relinquish it.
You're just a human being, Doom.
You were never meant to
have this kind of power.
Enough of your
trifling in my affairs.
I can't breathe.
Doc, stop!
[groans]
[exploding]
Have you come to
bow down before me?
I don't think so.
Flame on!
Then sample my fury!
I gave you the
chance to serve me,
but you foolishly refused.
[groans]
This oughta help me fix things.
This planet is not big
enough for all of us.
My sentiments exactly.
[gun fires]
No!
[gasps]
It is over.
[Storm] What happened?
How did we get here?
You have won.
Good has triumphed over evil.
You will all be returned to
your rightful places on Earth,
and you will retain no
memory of this event.
And I'm gonna lose the ability
to turn into Ben Grimm?
Yes.
All must be exactly as it was.
Well, easy come, easy go.
So that's it, huh?
All that for nothing?
No, Spider-Man.
I can't begin to
fathom who, or what
The Beyonder is,
but I do know who we are.
We're heroes to the core.
And in this war we
acted magnificently.
That is what matters most.
Goodbye.
This was all a setup, wasn't it?
I don't believe that Doom
really controlled your powers.
He could've easily
destroyed is if he had
really joined with you.
You only allowed
him to think he did.
Quite correct.
What I want to know is,
why are we playing this game?
Because, I needed to be
sure that as a leader,
you could handle the
real task at hand.
The real task?
Come.
Your greatest challenge awaits.
[theme music playing]
♪ Spider-Man, Spider-Man ♪
♪ Radioactive Spider-Man ♪
♪ Spider blood, spider blood ♪
♪ Radioactive spider blood ♪
♪ Spider-Man ♪