[narrator] Previously
onSpider-Man...
[Spider-Man] Doc
Connors said I might be
mutating into
some sort of freak.
There's one man
who might help me.
[Spider-Man grunts]
I've gotta find a cure!
[Charles] Enough!
My work is not to cure mutants.
It's always the same.
When I need help,
I'm on my own.
[Beast] Wait! A man
named Herbert Landon
has been studying your
particular form of mutation.
Most promising,
don't you agree?
Why are you going out
of your way for me?
I'm still human.
I'm not sure I still am.
-How sad.
-[gun cocks]
He's stunned.
We've got a real live mutant.
Landon!
What is the meaning of this?
I intend to destroy
all mutants.
Spider-Man! What have
you done with Beast?
[Wolverine yells]
How entertaining!
A fight to the bitter end!
♪ Spider-Man, Spider-Man ♪
♪ Radioactive Spider-Man ♪
♪ Spider blood, spider blood ♪
♪ Radioactive spider blood ♪
♪ Spider-Man, Spider-Man ♪
I'm tired of being diplomatic!
What have you done with Beast?
I don't know what
you're talking about!
[Wolverine yells]
[Spider-Man]
Aren't you at all interested
in that clown who just
threw a bomb at us?
I don't have time
for games, Wolverine.
Good, 'cause I
ain't playin' any!
You boys are having
so much fun,
I'd hate to bust up the
party, but I will anyway!
[Hobglobin laughs]
[Spider-Man] We'll
finish our conversation
after I take care
of laughing boy.
No!
[Hobgoblin] Ah,
the very thing I need!
[alarm sounds]
Talk to me, Lewald!
Intruders, sir! Area three!
There they are!
Mutants! Activate
the missile launchers,
and turn off those alarms!
[Minion] Missiles
locked on target!
Blast that mutant
scum into oblivion!
[Spider-Man] Get out
of my way!
Spider sense! Danger!
Come on! We'll finish our
tap dance somewhere else!
Let me see where you got hit.
Don't bother,
I heal real quick.
Mutant, heal thyself!
I'm impressed!
I'm not here to impress
you, where's Beast?
I told you, I don't
know, I haven't seen him
since last night when
he told me about this place.
[Hobgoblin laughs] Perfect.
You two keep
Landon distracted,
so I can collect
what's owed me!
So, what's with that clown
in the Halloween costume?
He claims Landon
has a secret agenda
to destroy all mutants.
I'm gonna find out for myself,
and you're coming with me.
If you're lyin',
you're filet-of-spider, pal.
I get the picture,
Wolvey, but have you
ever thought
of seeing a manicurist
about those things?
Where are they?
They got away, sir.
Then find them!
They can't be allowed
to disrupt my experiment!
Why are you helping
this madman?
Mr. Landon's not mad,
he wants to eliminate
the mutant condition,
the suffering they must endure.
No, he wants to
eliminate mutants.
If they don't exist,
then they can't suffer.
Maybe it's the only way, you
must've thought so too once,
everything he's done is
based on your early work.
My early work.
Yes, once I was filled
with much self loathing.
I wanted to eliminate my
mutancy more than anything.
Remembering that I
once felt that way
has for years been
my darkest secret.
I was wrong.
Being a mutant
has brought great joy
into my life!
No! There's nothing
good about
being a mutant,
mutants are freaks!
[Beast Voiceover] Me thinks the
lady doth protest too much.
[thudding]
Subtlety is not your
strong point, is it?
Hey, can't even spell the word.
You're the one with the
nose, where to next?
[Wolverine sniffs]
What I smell, is trouble!
Good nose!
[beeping]
Wonderful! Now I'll go
play Trick or Treat!
Mutant genetic research?
Computer, open wide!
Tell me all your secrets!
All data on
mutant genetic code
has been transferred
to CD-ROM.
Nice treat,
now for the trick!
Greetings, your computer data
has just been deleted
by a Hobgoblin computer virus!
Oh, I'm such a bad hacker!
[speaking gibberish]
[guard yells]
[guard screams]
Nice moves, kid!
You're not too bad
yourself, for an old guy.
-Let us down!
-Hey! Hey!
Don't hang around
waitin' for us.
[sniffs] That way.
[liquid bubbling]
Chemicals are at just
the right temperature,
it's time to begin, Genevieve.
Are you sure we're
doing the right thing?
This is no time for
second thoughts!
Mutants are the curse
of the human race!
To be a mutant
is to be cursed.
Sir! Spider-Man and Wolverine
are headed for your lab!
No! You must stop them,
do you hear me? Stop them!
Well, that outta keep
them out of our--
Nice tracking, Wolvey, only
problem is, there's no exit!
Then I'll just have
to make one!
[grunting]
Cool.
We must move quickly!
I'm sorry. It's not my fault.
We each bear responsibility
for the fate of our
brothers and sisters.
This is not the way
I would have chosen
to leave my mark on
the world of science.
[metal tearing]
Yep, claws are definitely
more fun than doors.
[laser gun charging]
There he is! Waste him!
You can kiss your webs
goodnight, wall-crawler!
[guards groan]
Next time, don't barge in
without knocking.
Stop him before he
ruins everything!
[Wolverine yells]
What is this,
a mutant cook off?
I am only a bird
in a gilded cage.
Then it's time to fly the coop!
[Beast] No, don't!
-[electricity arcs]
-[Wolverine screams]
[liquid bubbling]
[grunting]
Perfect! Two mutants
with one stone!
Uh, uh, uh, back
off, Frankenstein!
Hey Beast, you need a hand?
I would not be averse
to some assistance!
[loud explosion]
[Spider-Man groans]
Why does my business with you
keep getting
interrupted, Landon?
Ever heard of karma?
[laser gun fires]
[wires creaking]
[Spider-Man grunts]
Spider-Man! Keep us still
or Wolverine is lost to us!
[grunts] No problem,
but whatever you do,
just don't make me laugh!
Logan! Snap out of it, Logan!
Can't move, need time to--
[camera motor whirs]
Situation critical, sir!
Landon's chasing Hobgoblin,
Spider-Man and the Mutants
are wrecking the lab!
And what about the mutant army
that Landon was
to create for me?
I don't think that was even
Landon's intention, sir.
How disappointing.
Evacuate immediately.
I no longer have need for
a spy on those premises.
My men and I are bailing
out, operation terminated.
I told you not to trust Landon!
Mind yourself, Smythe,
or I may take out
my frustration on you,
do you understand?
Quite.
Landon! I've wiped
out all the data
in your little computer,
and now I have this!
The last and only
copy of your work!
What's it worth to ya?
My life's work!
All those years!
[Landon] Come back
with that disk!
[Hobgoblin] Sorry, finders
keepers, losers weepers!
[Hobgoblin laughs maniacally]
[metallic crash]
[metal creaking]
[Spider-Man] Can't
keep it still!
[fabric tearing]
[Wolverine groans]
Any calls while I was out?
[metal clangs]
Wolverine, quickly! Grab
the bottom of the cage!
Now what were you saying
about losers being weepers?
Do it, and lose everything!
Go on! I dare you!
Ta ta, Landon!
It's been real!
No!
[Landon screams]
[Genevieve screams]
[Hobgoblin] You
scientists always get
too immersed in your work.
My my, right where
I've always wanted you.
Care to play a
little game of catch?
You animal!
The chance of profit
is gone, therefor...
So am I! So long,
suckers! Be seeing you!
[Spider-Man grunts]
How about some action down
there? I'm getting tired!
[Wolverine] No problem.
[metal creaking]
[Beast] Excellent
work, Spider-Man!
Quite a ride, eh Hank?
Not one I would care
to duplicate, Logan.
What is that stuff?
The end result of
a plan to destroy
mutant life as we know it.
Dr. Landon's in there!
We've got to get him out!
[Landon screams]
No!
What is happenin' to him?
[Beast] Landon was
so anxious to create
something toxic to
mutants, that he failed
to determine its effect
on normal human cells!
Do something! You're
mutants, use your powers!
There is nothing we can do.
How ironic, he is becoming
what he hated most: mutant.
[Landon growls]
Look! He's absorbing energy
form that control panel!
Mr. Landon!
He can help you,
it was his work that created
all this, remember?
What?
Forgive me, Logan. I will
explain when this is over.
Remind me not to ask.
[Landon roars]
That's no way to
treat a lady, pal.
You sure showed him.
Shut up, ya puny little geek.
[Landon growls]
Find relief for the pain!
[roars]
It's my worst fear,
turning into some mutated
thing like that.
And now,
I've got to stop it!
[Landon roars]
He's heading for midtown, Hank!
Apparently only the infusion
of electrical energy
can ease its pain.
If we don't do something,
it's gonna drain the
entire city's power!
And if it does,
it will become immense.
-[crowd screaming]
-And unstoppable.
[Landon roars]
[Reporter] This
is John V in with
a J3 News Network live report.
A monstrous creature
apparently drawing energy
from the city's
electric power grid
has escaped
from the Brand Corporation,
where Herbert Landon
has been carrying on
mutant genetic research.
The creature is
now terrorizing the city,
and heading
for Times Square!
And the police are
unable to stop it!
[Professor X] Are you getting
this news feed, Rogue?
[Rogue] I'm gettin'
it loud and clear!
That is one ugly critter!
Beast and Wolverine
are down there,
they'll need your help!
We're on our way, Professor.
[news crew screams]
[Rogue] Why don't you pick on
somebody your own size,
big fella?
[Rogue grunts]
Gotcha!
I'll bet you say
that to all the gals.
We came as soon as we heard
the news, what can we do?
Landon was using
physio-electrical energy
to stimulate the mutant
cells to self destruct.
Now he needs it to hold
his own cells together!
Yes, that would explain
Landon's craving
for electricity!
He is a walking
storage battery.
But what if we
shut off his power?
It would slow his
growth, but not stop it.
However, if we
short-circuited the
physio-electrical
energy field...
Right,
I'll just climb up there,
hand him a wire and
say "Hold this!"
[Spider-Man] Wait! We
can do it remotely!
If we had a microwave
antenna adjusted
to the right frequency,
and a transmitter
big enough to hold
all that energy...
Yes, that would
work! We have both
in the Blackbird!
Come with me!
So there appears to
be a keen scientific mind
behind that garish
mask, eh my friend?
Takes one to know one,
blue boy.
[Spider-Man] Set the
frequency at 28 microfarads.
Done, begin sequence to
align the two antennae.
[Landon roars]
Antennae aligned.
Now it's their
turn on the ground.
[Landon roars]
[thunder claps]
Oh, let the lightning
illuminate the night!
[Landon roars]
This oughta make him
see sparks!
[Genevieve screams]
Gambit gonna deal
you a real fine hand!
[Genevieve screams]
I got her!
Perfect! Now we must make sure
that Landon isn't grounded.
Rogue! Your turn!
Be careful!
Don't worry about me, sugar.
Once bitten, twice shy!
[Landon roars]
Haul away!
[Spider-Man] Full power, now!
[electricity crackling]
It's working!
[metal creaking]
[Wolverine] What's wrong?
The creature's too heavy!
We're going down!
I can't keep her aloft!
Brace yourself for a crash!
No. No more suffering!
Something has taken
control of the ship!
We're leveling off.
You mean they won't be
picking us up with blotters?
I like it!
Thank you for saving us, and
for accepting what you are.
You know?
Know what?
She is a mutant, a telekinetic.
I've suspected as
much for a long time.
A mutant? Of course,
it all makes sense now!
You were the one
who rescued me
in the auditorium when
the ceiling caved in.
It's true, I am a mutant.
That's why I first went
to work for Landon.
I had hoped he really
did have a cure.
I can relate to that.
[sirens blaring]
His problem has been solved,
but what about the
monster within me?
You are possessed
by no monster,
only your own fear
and confusion.
We will introduce you
to Professor Xavier,
Maybe somewhere there's
someone who can help me too.
I'm sorry we got off
to such a rocky start,
you're a heck of a team player.
You got that right,
a regular ace.
Nice workin' with ya, kid.
Real nice.
Thanks, I don't
know what to say.
Just remember, no matter
what problems ya got,
or mistakes you've made,
you don't have to carry
the load by yourself.
Ya got friends if you
need 'em, right Hank?
You are correct,
Logan, and thank you.
Dr. Mariah Crawford?
Well, here goes nothing.
[Mariah gasps]
Spider-Man!
I'm glad you came!
But our time is
short, I must leave
for Africa in three days.
What took you so long to
call me for help?
I had to be reminded
that when I'm in trouble,
I'm not alone.
I need to turn to my friends.
♪ Spider-Man, Spider-Man ♪
♪ Radioactive Spider-Man ♪
♪ Spider blood, spider blood ♪
♪ Radioactive spider blood ♪
♪ Spider-Man ♪