[upbeat rock music]
♪ Spider-Man ♪
♪ Radioactive Spider-Man ♪
♪ Spider blood
Spider blood ♪
♪ Radioactive spider blood ♪
♪ Spider blood
Spider blood ♪
♪ Radioactive spider blood ♪
[explosions booming]
[growling]
♪ Spider-Man ♪
I can't deal with
all these mixed-up emotions.
Sadness,
loneliness,
guilt over
the loss of Mary Jane.
[explosion]
It's my fault she's gone.
But now
I have even more guilt
over my feelings
for the Black Cat.
I think I'm falling
in love with her.
Am I being a traitor
to Mary Jane's memory?
And what kind of new curse
would my love bring
to the Black Cat?
Tag Spider, you're it.
Hey, why didn't
my spider-sense go off?
Cat, come back here!
Is this the best you can do?
Boring!
I should be catching crooks.
For once,
I'm actually having fun.
End of the line, lady!
-[grunting]
-No!
-You could have been--
-Not with you around.
I want to be as good as you.
Instead, I pull
a damsel in distress.
You must think I'm a fool.
I think you are incredible.
I only wish I really knew
the woman under this mask.
Then maybe it's time you did.
Why don't I take off my mask,
then you take off yours?
Wait, we can't
take off our masks.
Why? We got something special,
can't you feel it?
All the way to my toes,
but we can't risk what might
happen to our loved ones
if our secret identities
were discovered.
Ah, Peter Parker's here!
Now the party can really begin.
It's almost as if he knows
I'm Spider-Man.
You know, I saw another one
of your Spider-Man photos
in the Bugle.
How do you get
those fantastic angles?
He does know I'm Spider-Man!
-[evil laughter]
-Osborn!
Mary Jane!
Believe me, the results
can be devastating.
I thought
you were different, Spider,
but you're just like
every other man in my life.
A big disappointment.
I-- I am sorry.
Yeah? Me too.
Look, I didn't mean
to get my claws out.
I better go.
She's definitely stirred up
long lost feelings in me.
I can't take risks!
Mary Jane!
If Green Goblin hadn't
learned my secret identity,
MJ would still be here.
How can I ever get close
to anyone again
without putting
their life in danger?
[waves crashing]
According
to this infra-red scanner,
there's a significant heat
source right inside that cave.
Looks like your calculations
were right on the money, Debra.
Yes, thanks to
the Herbert Foundation
satellite imaging technology.
This could be
the discovery of a lifetime!
Don't get your hopes
too high Clay.
Let's see what we find.
What's inside may be dangerous.
It's my project.
I'll go ahead
and check it out first.
No way! I can't let you
go in there alone!
[Clay]
Won't that light wake him up?
Uh-uh, the harmful rays
have been filtered out.
It's like moonlight.
-[both gasp]
-Morbius the vampire!
He's even more horrible
than I imagined!
I'm sorry,
I didn't mean to say that.
I know you two were friends
before this happened.
Michael Morbius was
more than a friend, Clay,
a lot more.
I just can't keep
my feelings for you
bottled up
any longer, Michael.
I-- I love you.
[Eastern European accent] You
are a wonderful woman, Debra,
but my heart
belongs to Felicia.
[reporter]
Dr. Carter, sir,
is it true that Michael Morbius
is the vampire creature
terrorizing the city?
[Carter]
I'm afraid it's true.
How exactly is Empire State
University involved?
Morbius tampered
with ESU's Neogenics equipment.
He accidentally turned himself
into a creature
-that needs human plasma
to survive.
-[shocked gasps]
[reporter]
Where is Morbius now?
No one knows.
The poor young man
simply vanished into the night.
[Clay] So they never found
Morbius' body?
Since he merged
genetically with a bat,
he may now be
hibernating like one.
The satellite photos
have located this cave.
It's the kind bats
use for hibernation.
-So it's true?
-Flash!
Don't you remember
how he almost killed me?
Is Michael Morbius
more important to you than me?
I'm sorry, Flash,
I can't answer that.
[man] Find anything?
We sure did!
Bring the solar resistant box!
Just sleep, Michael.
Hopefully, I'll
find a way to awaken you,
and the monster inside
will be gone.
-[kids laughing]
-Felicia! Can you
cover my class?
Doc Connors just called
a press conference,
and I want
to go get some photos.
Parker, I'll hardly have time
to pack for my flight tonight.
-Where are you going?
-To the West Coast.
The Hardy Foundation is going
to open a youth science
center out there.
I'll be gone a few weeks.
Cool! Do this favor for me,
and I'll pay you back
when you return, I promise!
Parker! Parker!
[exasperated sigh]
[Connors]
Ladies and gentleman,
I am here to announce
that a team
led my brilliant assistant,
Debra Whitman,
and financed by a grant
from the Herbert Foundation,
has at long last recovered
the sleeping body
-of Michael Morbius.
-[reporter] What is that?!
-A vampire!
-What?!
[Connors] Please!
Please, don't be alarmed!
Morbius is in a state
of hibernation.
We're going to try and
re-engineer the lost science
of Neogenics to restore
Morbius to his human self.
But, Doc, aren't you
jeopardizing all our lives
by bringing him
back to the city?
No! We're reviving a victim
of a horrible tragedy!
Wait till I write this up!
"ESU resurrects
bloodthirsty vampire!"
The city's gonna go ballistic!
It was my blood sample
that caused what happened
to Michael.
What are you up to,
Peter Parker?
I will expose the last
of this mutated plasma sample
to the Neogenic process.
No, no!
Get out of there!
-[screeching]
-Aah! Noo!
[Morbius] Like the vampire bat
whose genes I have inherited,
I hunger for plasma!
I let him down,
just as I let Mary Jane down!
But if anyone
can help Morbius,
it's Debra and Doc Connors.
They know more about Neogenics
than anyone else.
Still, it's risky.
I'm glad Felicia's
going out of town.
Being here for this would
be too painful for her.
-Ms. Hardy, your limo is ready.
-Come in, please.
-I'm just packing
a few last things.
-[TV reporter] Today at ESU,
Dr. Curtis Connors made
a shocking announcement.
He has discovered the body
of former ESU student
-Michael Morbius!
-[gasps]
Connors hopes to restore
this mutated creature
to his human form.
It's getting late, Ms. Hardy.
I can't go.
I'll call if I need you.
[crying]
[Morbius] It feels like
an eternity since we kissed
in the band hall.
Oh, Michael!
I missed you so much!
Where have you--
[gasping]
-Aah!
-I am immortal!
And you, my love,
will be just like me.
I can't live a life
that preys on innocent people.
I must get help to be changed
back to the man you love.
-[screaming]
-Nooo!
I will love you always!
-Michael!
-[screaming]
I'm going to need some help
on this one, Budgems,
serious help.
[Connors] Well, we've done
all that we can.
It's time to test it.
[Clay] Doc, are you sure
that he won't wake up
and chow down on us?
That shouldn't happen, Clay.
The restraints are secured.
We're as ready as we'll ever be.
[electricity crackling]
[alarm blaring]
Look, look!
[Debra]
Something's wrong!
I'm terminating the power!
The tray's coil blew!
It'll take time to fix.
Better take a break, Debra.
Exhaustion brings stupidity.
[sighs] For a moment,
I thought we did it.
[Kingpin]
For a moment, so did I.
I am beginning to lose patience
with our Empire State
compatriots.
It was a brilliant stroke
of yours
to create the Herbert Foundation
solely for the purpose
of funding their research,
but they're close enough now.
I'll be able to handle
the final stages.
Good.
I will finally have
a chance to cure myself
and possibly
make us both immortal!
Where's the Black Cat?
She's usually found me by now.
Do you think
maybe she's still angry?
Eh, you're right Bruce.
I should quit whining
and just do my job.
It's time I visited Doc Connors
to see how things
are going with Morbius.
Still, I wonder
what Black Cat's up to.
[gun cocks]
[Whistler]
That's far enough.
You can put that thing
down, Whistler.
You know my name?
I'm a friend.
I'm here about Michael Morbius.
[Whistler] Unfortunately,
Blade's in Europe,
hunting a particularly
elusive vampire.
It's just as well.
I want to handle
Morbius myself,
but I need your help.
Why should I help you?
Because someone has
to be ready in case Morbius
awakens still a vampire.
Just know that I want
no harm to come to anyone.
Please help me.
I usually wouldn't
help a stranger.
Not even a beautiful one.
But if Morbius the vampire
arises again,
someone must be prepared
to save the city.
[gasp] Who's there?!
It's just me.
I wanted to apologize
for the way I reacted
to this Michael Morbius thing.
Look, I just want you to know,
if this is
that important to you,
then I guess
I'm behind you 100 percent.
Why, that's
the nicest thing you ever--
-[loud whooshing]
-What-- What the--
-[Debra screams]
-[Flash] What the heck?!
[helicopter whirring]
Shocker, get Morbius!
Piece of cake.
-No, they can't!
-They won't.
[grunting]
[screaming]
Flash! Look out!
-[roaring]
-[Shocker screaming]
[groaning]
He's coming this way!
I am weak.
I must feed!
Look at this,
you're experiment worked.
-[screaming]
-Sort of.
[spider-sense tingling]
Shocker? Landon?
Why are you two here?
Who do you think
the Herbert Foundation
was named after?
I, Herbert Landon,
paid for all of this!
Morbius belongs to me!
[laughing]
[groaning]
Ohh!
[growling]
Must feed!
[Landon] Get him!
He holds the secret
to Neogenics.
Are you all right?
[groaning] I'll tell you
when my head stops ringing.
[growling]
Morbius!
You! Why do you torment me?!
I never wanted it to be
this way, Michael!
Never! Come back to the lab
where they can help you!
Please.
[Landon] There he is!
Get rid of Spider-Man! Now!
[grunting]
Starving.
[Spider-Man groaning]
Must have plasma!
[snarling]
[Spider-Man]
Can't let him drain me.
Aaah!
No, Michael!
Aaaaah!
[roars]
Michael, wait!
He's too fast!
He's getting away!
[groaning]
Are you okay?
Yes, thanks to you.
What is that thing?
Sorry, you've got your secrets,
I've got mine.
I wish I had time to
chat, but--
Black Cat, wait!
She's gone, but where?
I just don't get it.
Black Cat saves my bacon,
then she ditches me?
Isn't that true
to form for Peter Parker?
Just when I start having
feelings for someone,
they get weird on me.
[roaring]
-Aaah!
-I must feed!
I am so hungry!
No, Michael!
I can't let you do this!
Who are you to try and stop me?
[roars]
Michael, it's me, Felicia.
How dare you use her name!
Look at me!
-No!
-You used to love me,
and I have never stopped
loving you.
Felicia,
what has happened to you?
A lot, but I'm all right.
I have missed you
desperately, Michael.
Get away.
I am a monster!
No! You are
still the man I love!
How can you love me?
I am doomed!
Felicia, will you
help me find peace?
Yes, meet me in the Clock Tower.
It's been rebuilt.
I can't let Cat throw me off.
I'll deal with Morbius first,
and then figure out what's
wrong between her and me.
Now, if I were Michael Morbius,
the first thing I'd do
would be to go see the person
who loved me the most.
-Good thing Felicia's
out of town.
-[cat meows]
Hey, I don't remember
her having a cat.
Although, you do look
kind of familiar, puss.
You didn't happen to see
a plasma-sucking monster
here tonight, did you?
-[yowls]
-My spider-sense!
Long time no see,
Web for Brains.
Yes, we also thought
Morbius might come looking
for his long lost love.
Great minds do think alike.
Finish him.
[Shocker groans]
[Landon groaning
Let's get out of here!
Fine, but let's do it my way!
[explosion]
Thanks.
Why am I getting
a mixed message from you?
I'm sorry.
It's a difficult time for me.
Try to understand
I'm going through something.
Something I have to face alone.
[Spider-Man] Cat!
Cat!
What is wrong with you?
[Whistler] What you're
telling me is most disturbing.
I had no idea you had
feelings for this creature.
You've got to help me,
Whistler.
I need one last thing from you.
Something that will end
his agony.
This is what you need.
No! The hunger,
it's too strong!
[roaring]
[frightened shouts]
I must not! I can't!
Michael? [gasping]
Can you help me, Felicia?
Yes, I've been given a device
that will end your misery.
You will never walk
as a vampire again,
but you will never walk
as a human, either.
It will return you
to the limbo of sleep,
between mortal
and immortal forever.
[Morbius]
It is the only way.
Do it.
-[crash]
-Stop!
Perfect.
Didn't you think we'd remember
Morbius once used
this Clock Tower as his refuge.
I guess I had other things
on my mind, Landon.
I think about you
as little as possible.
Ah, well,
my troublesome Ms. Hardy,
we shall soon
carry out an execution
we originally wanted
your father to witness.
The Clock Tower!
Morbius!
Are you all right?
Yes, now that you're here.
A guy could get the wrong idea
and think a certain someone
likes him.
No matter what
I'm going through,
I do care for you.
[sirens approaching]
I'm just doubting myself
these days.
For what it's worth,
I think you're doing great.
Yeah, so great that I let
them get away with Morbius.
Well, they won't get far.
I just tossed a spider-tracer
on their copter.
Very smart, Spider.
Come on,
we've got to follow them.
It wouldn't be a party
without the big guy, would it?
How much longer?
Only a few more minutes,
and then all the Neogenic
knowledge will be ours!
-[power surging]
-[agonized groans]
[Spider-Man]
Sorry, school's out!
What?! [groans]
Cat!
Can't breathe!
No! Felicia!
-[roaring]
-[pounding]
Stop! Stop!
Rraaaah!
[roaring]
[heavy thuds]
We shall meet again.
[roaring]
Stay back! Stay back!
Aaaah!
Landon, what in the name
just happened?
That ought to keep you quiet!
[roaring]
Morbius, keep away!
What's that?
Something
that will stop him forever.
No! There's
got to be a better way!
Michael! Come back!
[roaring]
Morbius!
[Black Cat]
I blew it, didn't I?
No, you did the right thing.
If part of him
is still human,
there's hope he can be saved.
He'll seek out
shelter from the sun.
We'll have to wait
until he stalks at night again.
I just hope we get to Morbius
before anybody else gets hurt.
I thought that once I decided
to become a crime fighter,
I would instinctively know
the right thing to do.
I never expected
my emotions to get in the way.
How do you deal
with life behind the mask?
I wish I had answers
for you. I don't.
But maybe I can help
you get through this,
if you'll let me.
Thanks.
But I may need to get
through this struggle alone.
Why is love so complicated?
I'm sure glad that Felicia
is out of town.
Seeing Morbius is something
she could never have handled.
[upbeat rock music]
♪ Spider-Man, Spider-Man ♪
♪ Radioactive Spider-Man ♪
♪ Spider blood, spider blood ♪
♪ Radioactive spider blood ♪
♪ Spider blood ♪
♪ Spider-Man ♪