[theme music playing]
[zapping]
[funky guitar music playing]
♪ Spider-Man, Spider-Man ♪
♪ Radioactive Spider-Man ♪
♪ Spider blood, spider blood ♪
♪ Radioactive spider blood ♪
♪ Spider-Man, Spider-Man ♪
[dramatic music playing]
[Madame Web] Are you afraid?
No.
You will be Spider-Man.
You will be.
Soon you will face your
greatest challenge in life.
Look into my eyes.
No.
My limbs are going rigid.
I'm paralyzed.
Madame Web has lured
me into a trap!
[dramatic music playing]
This is the one?
This fragile being?
I have grave reservations
that he can succeed.
Never-the-less, he is the one.
He alone can
make the difference
between existence
and destruction.
I wager that
he may surprise you.
Put him to the test.
I shall.
Let us begin.
[gasping]
Web, what have you--
Greetings, Spider-Man,
Peter Parker.
Who, and what are you?
No doubt I startle you.
Let me assume
a more familiar form.
Think of me as one from beyond.
Call me The Beyonder.
My servant, known to
you as Madame Web and I
are beings who take many forms.
We have traveled a long way
and have seen many curiosities,
but none as perplexing as
a planet we stumbled upon
called Earth.
Our scrutiny has revealed
much about humans
that we don't understand.
The most intriguing
are your concepts
of good and evil.
I thought they warranted
further study and observation.
You are obviously
an agent for good.
Therefore,
you have been chosen.
Chosen? For what?
For the ultimate test
of good against evil.
Yes, I want to know
which one is stronger.
You're crazy.
There's no way you can do that.
Ah, but you are wrong.
I intend to devise
an experiment.
Behold, a planet
somewhere in the galaxy.
This planet has found
peace for centuries.
Their technology has eliminated
hunger, pain and unhappiness.
These humanoids have
no concept of evil.
This place is what
you Earth people
would call paradise.
For my test,
I shall introduce evil
to this unsuspecting planet.
No! Why would you interfere
with these innocent lives?
I won't let you do it.
[zapping]
Whoa!
You cannot change this.
It is already decided.
Just as we found you,
we have scoured the
Earth to find those
who best represent
the evil we require.
Here we have one Otto Octavius,
known to you as Dr. Octopus,
who uses science
to justify evil deeds.
He is a good first choice.
In this place we shall
find another doctor,
a tyrant who equates
evil with power.
He is so despised by his people
that they have hired
assassins to eliminate him.
[dramatic music playing]
Yes, I have use
for this Dr. Doom.
Now here's one who
deludes himself
into thinking that
his evil can be dismissed
because he has a just cause.
He wants to save his father.
Alistair Smythe.
[Beyonder] Next, I have
chosen one for whom evil
is a disease.
His brain poisoned
by radio activity.
Clark Connors.
No, leave him out of this.
He's go a wife and a child.
It is his alter ego,
the Lizard, that I am after.
[Spider-Man]
You gotta stop this.
I desire only one more,
one whose evil is so strong
that it has transcended
the boundaries of time,
The Red Skull.
Now I will introduce
these examples of villainy
to our paradise planet.
But, they'll destroy it.
You mustn't.
Web, you can't let him do this!
It's not for me to
choose in this matter.
[Beyonder] Look.
[zapping]
[dramatic music playing]
[screaming]
[tense music playing]
[Beyonder] There,
phase one is complete.
Now for phase two,
I shall accelerate time.
Time will pass equal to
one of your human years.
You can do that?
The Beyonder
can do many things.
What am I up against here?
Who is this guy?
[Beyonder]
Look at what has happened.
The evil ones have used this
planet's advanced technology
for their own gain
and used their powers
to seize control.
The result is that those beings
who originally
inhabited this planet
have been trampled under foot.
You had to wreck
an entire civilization
to prove that evil is bad?
For such a powerful being,
you're a few stars
shy of a galaxy, pal.
[Madame Web]
Then you shall have
the pleasure
of making all that
is wrong right again.
-What?
-The Beyonder has chosen you
as this planet's savior.
Yes, I issue you
this challenge.
Restore this planet
to its rightful owners
and banish evil
from their presence
or perish trying.
[zapping]
[dramatic music playing]
[Beyonder] An intriguing game,
wouldn't you say?
But one side has
all of the pieces
which hardly seems fair.
Therefore, I have now infused
this device with power.
It has just enough
energy to transport
a fixed number of people
through time and space.
You may use this to bring
a small contingent
of the forces of
good to this planet,
a group which you must
then lead into battle.
This computer contains
a database of heroes,
as you call them,
whom I have observed on Earth.
Now, use it and choose
your game pieces wisely.
For your only chance
to save this planet
and return home
is to lead the fight
against evil, and win.
Come back.
Beyonder!
This is insanity.
Great, now I'm
some kind of pawn
in a galactic game of chess.
My only way out of
this is to bring help,
not only to save this planet
but to fight
The Beyonder as well.
I need to assemble
a team of people
that I know can be
useful to me.
Okay, now...
who's fought that Dr. Doom
guy before and won?
Of course.
Computer, can I transport
to this planet
the Fantastic Four?
Affirmative.
And, there's another
who was a big help to me
against Carnage and Venom.
My friend, Iron Man.
Affirmative.
And there's only one man
that can fight the Red Skull:
Captain America.
Affirmative.
There will only
be enough energy
for one last teleportation.
There's another
team of Superheroes
that I've worked with before.
Computer, bring me one of
the X-Men.
Which one?
Good question.
Let's see,
there was one so powerful
that she could control
the very weather.
She might be a suitable match
for the Beyonder's powers.
Computer, bring me
the one called Storm.
Affirmative.
All right, bring everyone
that I've called for now.
[blasting]
Wh-what happened?
That's my fault, I guess.
Spider-Man?
I'm the one who brought you.
Tell us what's going on
or I'm gonna squash you flat.
Stop, you know Spider-Man,
you can trust him.
Hey, don't wrinkle the rocks,
ya rust bucket.
[thudding]
[zapping]
Bad move, pal.
That's my friend
you just messed with.
Flame on!
No, Johnny, stop.
Hey, hold on, hot head.
Gotcha!
Reed, let me out!
Everybody, calm down.
We've got to figure
out what's going on.
My spider sense.
[banging]
You tried to trap me
and keep me in a cage.
But I got free, didn't I?
Now I will destroy you.
He really means it.
It feels like he's trying
to break me in two.
Ugh.
[roaring]
Just my luck.
Everybody form a perimeter
around that monster
and we'll attack
from all sides.
You can try to surround me
but I will tear you apart.
Move in!
Try to restrain him now,
while he's down.
But try not to hurt him.
Whoa!
Great, I'm supposed to be
the leader of this group
but so far, all I've got
on my hands is chaos.
Can't restrain him.
Hold on, big guy.
No, don't hurt him.
It's not his fault.
Hey, will somebody please
get me out of here?
I don't know, kid.
This is one way of keeping
you out of trouble.
Now you go some
explaining to do, bug boy.
And we're all ears.
No problem, I'm not sure
I understand it all myself,
but here's what I know:
there's this intergalactic
entity named The Beyonder
and he wants to
see who would win
in a battle of
good against evil.
[dramatic music playing]
[Spider-Man] And that's it.
I'm supposed to lead you
against the forces of evil
on this planet.
Millions of lives are at stake.
You have to help me.
I say we forget this place
and figure out how to get home.
The only way The Beyonder
will send us home
is if we free
the people of this planet.
Exactly what planet are we on?
I don't know.
And where is this
Beyonder you speak of?
I don't know that either.
This so-called evil ones
who've taken over,
why aren't they here?
It is odd that this
place is abandoned.
For what little I can tell,
this is some
impressive equipment
and whoever was here
even managed to capture
our lizard friend.
If it's true that
the villains have take over
everything of value,
why is this place vacant?
Stretch is right.
Something smells.
Whose side is the
web-head really on?
Well, I'm not
waiting to find out.
Flame on!
I say we make you talk.
Maybe I oughta put
you in the hot seat.
Good idea.
And this time,
if he tries to web ya,
I'll clobber him.
Ben, Johnny--
If you don't back off,
rock brain,
I'll smash you into
a pile of pebbles.
Boys, boys, can't we
settle this quietly?
Look if you don't simmer down,
I'm gonna lose my cool and--
[banging]
No, we can't let him get away.
He could hurt innocent people.
Come on, we better stop him.
[dramatic music playing]
My spider sense
if going bonkers.
Where did he go?
It's him!
Where the heck did he--?
[roaring]
Oh, boy.
Giant worms,
they're all over the place.
Unbelievable.
We have to get back to the lab.
[roaring]
[tense music playing]
This thing's got is own armor.
It doesn't even feel my fists.
[zapping]
[thudding]
[roaring]
[exciting music playing]
It's clobbering time!
[banging]
[zapping]
Thank you.
[roaring]
It's no use,
there are too many of them.
We gotta fall back
towards the lab.
I'm with ya web-head!
[zapping]
[tense music playing]
Spider-Man, get out of here.
No, we have to get
the Lizard back.
Believe or not, he's my friend.
You can't be serious.
Don't worry,
my invisible force field
will get him back,
just protect yourselves.
[tense music playing]
It's no use,
those worms are on their way
and they're gonna
tear this place apart.
Not if I can help it.
My shield will keep them out.
[pounding]
Sue can't keep that up forever.
What are we gonna do?
You know, Spider-Man
was telling the truth.
The scientists of this
planet must have made this
their last fortress
against the forces of evil.
Those worms would have provided
a natural defensive barrier.
Yeah, not even Doc Doom
would want to rule a land
full of these guys.
If that's the case,
then this lab complex had to
have its own security system.
I can't be certain,
but I think that this dish
might have created a kind
of energy force field,
a protective barrier.
Why did they shut it down?
Maybe this is the answer.
I think it's an energy gauge.
This whole complex
simply ran out of power.
My guess is that the Lizard
smashed their power source.
How awful.
You mean the shield
dissipated and they--
I can't keep this
up much longer.
We've gotta find
some way to harness
enough power to turn
on the force field.
We can't just get
power out of thin air.
Yes, we can.
Storm! I remember that you
can harness the elements,
like electricity.
Yes, Spider-Man.
Good! We have to locate
the Sheila generator
and feed a line into it.
Are you ready?
Go for it!
Power of lightning,
come to my aid.
It's working,
we're almost there.
They must hurry.
Now!
[gasping]
You did it, darling.
You saved us.
[roaring]
[dramatic music playing]
He took a bad hit.
Is he gonna be okay?
I think I can revive him.
There seems to be two different
components to his brain.
One part, the savage lizard
part is now unconscious,
but the other
has been lying dormant
in some kind of stasis.
That's got to be where my
friend's consciousness resides.
Then I'm going to try to
reawaken that dormant part.
[buzzing]
[tense music playing]
Where am I?
Spider-Man, what's going on?
It's okay, doc.
You're here amongst friends.
This story you're telling
me is unbelievable.
And yet, here I am
with my rational mind
trapped in this lizard body.
Well, I'm with you.
I'll help you in
whatever way I can.
Thanks, doc.
Listen, all of you.
We've always acted heroically
because it was
the right thing to do.
Now, we can show this
alien monstrosity,
The Beyonder, what Earth
people are really made of,
that is if you'll all
agree to work with me.
I, for one, accept your
leadership, Spider-Man.
I too am with you.
As always, it's a pleasure
to fight by your side.
Thank you.
And you?
I agree with you all.
Ben?
The Fantastic Four
ain't gonna fink out
when there's a
battle to be fought.
Besides, I owe you one for
saving my hide out there.
And Ben Grimm always
pays his debts.
We're in.
[Madame Web]
So you see, he is a leader.
Already he has rallied
them behind him.
Yes, a most promising start.
But there is still
much to be done
if Spider-Man is to
survive destruction.
Soon Spider-Man must
face his greatest horror
in the universe.
[Connors] A penny
for your thoughts.
Huh?
Oh, Doc Connors, it's you.
I was just thinking
and planning.
I sense that you're worried.
I've never led
a scout troop before,
let alone a group
of Superheros.
I'm worried all right.
Don't despair, my friend.
I think you have what it
takes to get through this.
Thanks.
What's that in your hand?
It's some kind of
recording device I found.
This is going to be the
biggest battle of all time.
And I'm going to use this
to keep a diary of it.
I'll record whatever happens
so that the greatest war ever
fought isn't a secret war.
[theme music playing]
♪ Spider-Man, Spider-Man ♪
♪ Radioactive Spider-Man ♪
♪ Spider blood, spider blood ♪
♪ Radioactive spider blood ♪
♪ Spider-Man ♪