[upbeat rock music]
♪ Spider-Man ♪
♪ Radioactive Spider-Man ♪
♪ Spider blood
Spider blood ♪
♪ Radioactive spider blood ♪
♪ Spider blood
Spider blood ♪
♪ Radioactive spider blood ♪
[explosions booming]
[growling]
♪ Spider-Man ♪
Ooh, a fine down payment,
but when do I get the rest,
Miss Silver?
Or can I finally call
you Miss Silvermane?
Yes, you may.
You'll get paid again
as soon as you kill that exposé
the Daily Bugle is preparing
on me and my organization.
And, Tombstone, don't forget
the incriminating photos
they have of me.
I must have them.
They're yours.
I've already
got my plan in motion
to collect a favor from
an old friend at the Bugle.
-[laughs]
-[door closes]
And to think,
I once wanted to date her.
You're lucky it didn't
work out, Peter.
Who'd have thought
Alisha Silvermane
would take over
her father's criminal empire?
We're finally gonna blow
this Silvermane story
wide open.
But it seems no sooner
does one problem get licked
when something worse turns up.
See? Take this Bandana Gang,
for instance.
They're terrorizing everyone.
I get to thinking, this city's
no place to raise a son.
I often try to convince Jonah
that Spider-Man is making
this city safer to live in,
but I guess Spider-Man
can't do everything.
[thinking]
No, but he might
give it a try.
[fence rattling]
-[car alarms blaring]
-Hey, get out of here!
[gang member] We're just doing
a little car shopping.
Got something against that?
Uh! Let go of me,
you miserable punks!
Take care of him.
He can't do anything to us.
You want in the posse or not?
-Do it now.
-[swoosh]
Isn't it a little late
for a test drive?
It's Spider-Man, let's jam!
I wasn't gonna do
anything to him.
That's not what it looked
like from my angle.
You? Randy Robertson?
What's he doing
with these punks?
Is crime going to infect
and poison everyone I know?
-Where's the Parker kid?
-[gasp]
We have some business
to discuss.
[dramatic music]
Who are you?!
What do you want?!
The name's Tombstone,
and I want Parker's negatives.
I'm calling the police!
-[laughs] Be my guest.
-[gasp]
Was it right for me to
just let Randy go like that?
Oh. Poor Robbie,
he can't possibly
have any idea
what his son's been up to.
But do I want to be
the one to tell him?
[dramatic music]
Stop! Stop!
[Aunt May]
Hello, police?
This is an emergency.
There's a monster
in my house and he...
Now you've made me mad!
Pay dirt.
-[tingling]
-Spider-sense, here?
Tombstone.
No! Aunt May!
If he's hurt her...
No, officer,
I'm all right. He's gone.
But I'm so afraid.
Who knows what this monster
might do to my nephew, Peter?
Oh, good, she's all right.
Better not let
her see Spider-Man.
That might upset her even more.
-[loud thud]
-Pull over!
You?!
[revving]
I said pull over!
[grunting]
Oh, dear! I forgot
you and Parker are buddies!
Where do you get off attacking
defenseless old ladies?
Is that
how you get your jollies?
No, that was work.
This is how I get my jollies.
[crash]
I didn't say I was finished
with you, rock head.
And I'm not through with you!
[Spider-man groans]
But I'm late
for a funeral-- yours!
Unh!
Way to go, Spidey.
You get angry,
you get careless.
And you lose your man.
[dramatic music]
The Amazing Randy slipped
right out of the spider's web.
Spider-Man,
he's nothing but a wimp
-in red and blue spandex.
-[slap]
So did I make it? Am I in?
Chill, Ran-day.
That was just the first stage
of your initiation.
Now you're ready
to meet the big boss.
You're gonna have to pack
some heat for the next stage.
Huh? But-- But, um...
You got a strap, don't you?
Yeah. Yeah, sure,
I got one at home.
[Aunt May]
And I tried to call the police,
and then he ripped
the phone out, and the...
Aunt May, the important thing
is you're okay.
You should get some rest now.
Yes, I suppose I should.
Who knows who else
will show up here?
Some giant lizard,
a human octopus.
Peter, you really must find
some other line of work.
[door closes]
[thinking] Everything's
here but the negatives
for the Alisha Silvermane
exposé.
Tombstone must have taken them.
That means Robbie's in trouble.
He's got the only other copies.
I've gotta warn him
about Tombstone!
Should I tell him
about Randy, too?
Where's Dear Abby
when you need her?
Martha, I'm home.
Oh, thank goodness,
we have to talk.
-What's wrong?
-The school called.
Randy's been cutting
classes for over a week.
What? I can't imagine
him behaving that way.
Robbie, you're just so busy
these days.
You don't know your own son.
Honey, I'm sorry,
I didn't mean that.
I'm just so worried.
[Robbie]
Where is he now?
[Martha] He's out,
and don't ask me where.
He doesn't tell me anymore.
[rattling]
-Randy! What are you doing?!
-Uh-- Nothing.
Nothing? You call this nothing?
What did you want with
my old service revolver?
Don't you know how
dangerous these things are?
What is this?
You're not
in that gang, are you?
Are you?!
What if I am?!
At least they care about me!
And you think we don't?
The posse's always there
for me.
They're like a family, and I'm
gonna prove myself to them!
-Randy, you don't have to--
-You just don't understand.
[Spider-man]
Well, looks like Robbie's
got the bad news already.
-[phone ringing]
-Hello.
-[Tombstone]
Hey, homey, what's up?
-Who is this?
Don't tell me you've forgotten
my voice, Mr. Straight Arrow.
Lonnie? But it can't be.
I thought you were...
Don't be so sure I'm not.
I wanna meet
and talk about old times.
I... I can't right now.
Oh, yes, you can.
See, I especially wanna rap
about a good friend of mine,
a foxy lady by the name
of Alisha Silvermane.
What's wrong with Robbie?
He looks like
he's seen a ghost.
Meet me at Veteran's
Memorial Park, midnight.
Something urgent's
come up at the Bugle.
I have to go.
Yeah, something urgent's
always coming up.
You go straight to your room!
We'll continue this
when I get back.
[crickets chirping]
[Spider-Man]
This is a cheery little spot.
I'm glad I came along
for the ride.
[footsteps echoing]
[scraping]
Lonnie, you here?
[Tombstone] I'm here.
I still can't
believe you're alive.
-Am I?
-Oh, what happened to you?
Oh, this?
Just a little mishap.
You haven't changed
much, though.
Still a straight arrow.
Robbie and Tombstone? Buddies?
I want the Silvermane story
buried, Robbie.
What makes you
think I'd do that?
Raah!
You owe me, remember?
You're an old friend, Robbie,
but if you don't kill
that story on your own,
-I'll make you do it.
-No way!
Always the straight arrow.
Ohh!
-You again!
-Revoltin', isn't it?
[groans]
I was sloppy last time,
crypt keeper.
This time,
I'm at the top of my game.
[grunting]
Now I'm gonna prepare
a coffin for you.
A real flat one, brother.
[grunts]
He ain't my brother,
he's heavy.
Ooh!
Oh!
No!
[dramatic music]
It seems like you're
always saving my tail.
[gasp] Look!
Rest in pieces.
Looks like Tombstone got away.
How do you even
know somebody like that?
You know,
I've been asking myself
the same question
for the last hour.
I knew Tombstone way
before he was Tombstone.
His real name
is Lonnie Lincoln.
Closed? Dang!
You know, it's your fault
we're too late, Straight Arrow.
And I'm dying for
an ice cream sandwich, Lonnie!
If you weren't so busy
getting your homework done...
[glass shattering]
Hey! Well, what a shame.
Some dishonest thieves
could just reach in
and grab some ice cream
if you give me a boost.
What?! No way!
This is me who's asking you.
We're like family, remember?
-[police siren]
-[grunts]
I managed to get away.
But Lonnie went right
to juvenile court.
[siren]
I eventually
graduated with honors.
But Lonnie,
he got a different degree.
I've always felt guilty that
I got away and Lonnie didn't.
And I felt even guiltier
knowing that Lonnie
never gave my name
to the police.
Back then, even one strike
could ruin your life.
I often wonder
what would have happened
if I'd gotten caught
instead of Lonnie.
Later, I got a job
as a cub reporter
at a local paper.
One night,
I got a tip on a break-in
at the Spalding chemical plant.
I thought the story
would be my big chance.
-Whaddaya say, Straight Arrow?
-Lonnie?
So, after all
your fancy schools
and your cushy little job,
you can still remember my name?
I'm touched.
In fact, I'm so touched,
I even got
a little gift for you.
I'm gonna give you
a chance to experience life
on the other side
of the tracks.
What are you talking about?
I told you on the phone
there'd be a break-in.
I can even name
the one who broke in.
Joseph "Robbie" Robertson.
I mean, look around,
your prints are everywhere.
You really
should've come prepared.
Why are you doing this?
Why'd you let me get caught
robbing that grocery store?
Is that what this is about?
I took the fall for you, man!
-[glass shatters]
-[fire alarm ringing]
Now it's your turn
to take the rap.
And when you get out of jail,
we'll be family again.
'Cause no one else
will hire you.
Lonnie, this is crazy!
Aah! Aah!
Aaah!
There was nothing
I could do for him.
[sirens]
I waited
for the police to arrive
and hoped they'd
believe my story.
Luckily the guys at the paper
backed me up on the phone tip.
I didn't think
Lonnie survived.
-They told me he was...
-Maybe they really thought so.
He sure looks it.
Anyway, he came back.
I had no idea he'd
become this underworld hit man,
this walking tombstone.
Right now, I just wanna get
back to my wife and son.
[thinking] It's so strange
to see Robbie this way.
To Peter Parker, he always
seems so strong, so proud.
How ironic that in
his moment of despair,
he seems stronger
to me now more than ever.
Randy, honey,
I wanna talk to you.
Randy... [gasps]
Randy, my man, come over here
and meet the big boss.
[gasps]
Hey, kid, you and me
are gonna be good friends.
I'm going to look
for Tombstone.
You should get back
to your family.
Robbie, he's gone!
He snuck out!
[keys jingling]
-Still there.
-[phone ringing]
Hello?
[Tombstone] We've still got
lots of catching up to do.
I tell you what, let's meet
at the Spalding Chemical Plant,
for old times' sake.
Spalding Chemical, what for?
How 'bout this:
there's a new patsy
about to take a fall, your son!
Was that about Randy?
Everything's gonna be
all right.
I'm going to pick him up now.
Robbie, I know that look.
Something is really wrong,
and you have got
to tell me what it is.
Haven't I always stood by you?
You have,
and if anything happens to me,
you've got to stand
by Randy as well.
Robbie, what are you doing?!
Something I should've done
a long time ago.
Get rid of this.
I don't ever want to see
another weapon in this house.
Everybody grab something
and get started.
Um, I don't get it,
what are we doing here?
-Move!
-Unh!
You're so close
to being in the family.
Don't mess it up.
-[thump]
-Mrs. Robertson?
Spider-Man, what do you want?
Easy, easy.
I'm looking for someone,
but I haven't had any luck.
I was hoping
your husband could help.
He's not here.
He-- He got a call.
Something about
the Spalding Chemical Plant.
Oh, gotta run.
That's where Tombstone
tried to frame Robbie.
Robbie's more than
just a friend to me.
He's the only one who likes me
as Peter Parker
and as Spider-Man.
I've gotta help him
out of this mess.
And the only way to do it is
to write Tombstone's epitaph.
[Madame Web] Spider-Man,
a rash and foolish plan!
Huh?
You've fought this
man-mountain twice before,
trying to defeat him
with brawn,
and twice you failed.
Madame Web!
Are you going to go for three?
What are you, a scorekeeper?
[whooshing]
[Madame Web]
Someone's got to keep score,
and I'm not sure you can count.
Do I really need this
right now?
You must not use
your superhuman strength
to confront Tombstone again.
But the guy's strong as an ox!
It will not help you
in the mission that lies ahead.
Some evil can only be
fought with the human heart.
Think about it
with your brain,
if you still remember
how to use it.
[Spider-Man] I don't know
why this strange mystic
decided to be my advisor,
but I really wish she'd
just leave me alone
and get her own talk show.
[Robbie]
Where's my son?
Straight Arrow,
glad you could make it.
Your son's developing into
quite the little criminal. See?
Randy, no!
Aw, and isn't that cute?
He forgot to bring his gloves,
just like his dad.
I know you must be proud.
That's why I'm recording
a permanent record
of this special moment.
Of course,
you can save your son
from heading down
the wrong path.
All you have to do is
kill the Silvermane story.
I won't do it.
There you go with that
integrity stuff again,
but deep down,
you're just like me.
-I'm not!
-Think what we
could do together.
You with your connections,
me with my strength.
We could
own this city, but first,
you've got to kill that story.
You're too late, Lonnie.
I've already rushed
it into print.
In a few hours, it'll be seen
by a million readers.
Then it's out of my hands.
At least I'll have the pleasure
of seeing the Robertson name
go down in flames.
[maniacal laughter]
This stuff's worth a fortune,
and Tombstone says we're
gonna get a big cut.
So, the Posse's
working for Tombstone.
He must be using Randy
to get to Robbie.
Hey, let go of me!
-Shh!
-[muffled complaints]
They're setting
you up, Randy.
Your fingerprints
must be all over this place.
You don't even know
what you're talking about.
They care about me
more than my real family.
That's where you're wrong.
Your dad's right here
to save your hide
and risk his own
against Tombstone.
-No way.
-[swooshing]
You think you got
such a great son,
it shouldn't take much
to get him into the game.
Nobody talks
about Randy that way!
Ohh!
I'm gonna take you down
once and for all!
Even if I have to go with you!
And how do you plan
to pull that off?
Simple, I'm not
afraid of the police.
-[alarm sounding]
-No!
-Look!
-I'm outta here!
What about Randy?
To heck with Randy,
it's every man for himself!
So what do you think
of your family now?
[grunts]
Dad! Leave my dad alone!
Get out of my way,
you little...
[dramatic music]
You always were too caught up
in your greed to think
straight, Lonnie.
Unh!
No!
[Spider-Man] Well, now
that I've used my brains,
I guess a little brawn
wouldn't hurt.
Huh?
[groans]
Come down here
and fight like a man!
I don't suppose
I could convince you
to come up here
and fight like a spider?
Haah!
Now, what'd I tell you
about playing ball
in the house, young man?
-[clang]
-Ooh!
Aaaah!
[Spider-Man[
You better stay still.
Another swim
in that chemical soup,
and your hair might turn green.
Dad, dad, come on,
we gotta get out of here
before the police come!
We're not going to run, son.
We're gonna stay here and face
the consequences, together.
-But your reputation!
-Don't you see?
You're more important
than anything else to me.
I'm sorry, Dad.
I'm here for you, Randy.
I'll always be here.
[dramatic music]
Oh, thank goodness.
[Spider-Man]
It looks like Madame Web
did add one more weapon
to my arsenal:
belief in the human spirit.
I suppose
I really should thank her,
but she's got
a big enough head already.
[upbeat rock music]
♪ Spider-Man, Spider-Man ♪
♪ Radioactive Spider-Man ♪
♪ Spider blood, spider blood ♪
♪ Radioactive spider blood ♪
♪ Spider blood ♪
♪ Spider-Man ♪