[Felicia] Previously
onSpider-man.
[Spider-man] Morbius,
stop this blood lust.
I don't like this
from a mere mortal!
[Spider-man] That sword-swinging
biker wants to destroy Morbius.
-Why are you protecting him?
-You are you after him?
He's got fangs too.
Who are you?
Blade and I want to destroy you.
[Spider-man] Blade no,
I turned him into a vampire.
Now you want to save him.
[Spider-man] The vampire
we've been chasing
is the result of an
experiment with a machine,
the Neogenic Recombinator.
That machine,
I have to destroy it.
I'm not finished with you.
Then book me or let me go.
Fine but remember,
I'm watching you.
You've underestimated
my powers and thanks to
the Recombinator, the whole
world will become vampires.
You've got a lot to learn
about catching vampires.
[engine revving]
It's gonna be a long night.
[mid tempo rock music]
♪ Spider-man, Spider-man ♪
♪ Radioactive Spider-man ♪
[mid tempo rock music]
♪ Spider blood, spider blood ♪
♪ Radioactive spider blood ♪
♪ Spider-man, Spider-man ♪
[Spider-man] I'm gonna
spend all night searching
for Morbius but thanks
to the vampire compass on
Blade's chopper,
we found him in record time.
Blade says we would've found
him even sooner but the compass
is ancient and it works
slowly in the modern city.
The question is now that
we've found Morbius,
can we stop him?
If I don't get the
Neogenic Recombinator
back from Morbius,
I'll start mutating
again into that mad
spider monster and Morbius
will use it to create a
whole race of vampires.
[dramatic trumpet music]
[electric warbling]
I think I know where
he's headed, follow me.
How would you know
where he's going?
[Spider-man] All right,
then don't follow me.
[engine revving]
[truck horn blares]
I got a positive
ID on Spider-man.
Location, the George
Washington Bridge.
He's being followed
by a person unknown on
some kind of souped up
chopper, run the plates for me.
[police sirens blaring]
[Spider-man] Shut
that thing off.
He may already be inside.
What would Morbius
be doing here?
[Spider-man] I didn't
think Doc Connors'
security precautions
would keep Morbius away,
so I took a special CPU chip
out of the Recombinator.
He can't work without
it, this is the only
place in the city that
makes these chips.
[anxious ensemble music]
No.
[snarl]
Fool, I should have known
better than to team up with you.
[electric warbling]
[steam hissing]
[Spider-man] Morbius, stop.
Freeze, police, nobody's going
anywhere until I get
some questions answered.
Now we're going to do it my way.
[gasp]
[Spider-man] Stop.
[Michael] I will try anything.
[scream]
She's mine.
[Spider-man] I can't let
him get away with that chip.
I'll meet you back
at your place.
Hey, hey, hold it right there.
You have an interesting
way of saying thank you.
Somebody's got to come
down to the station
to explain this and you
are the only one left.
[snarl]
You don't want to go for it.
Hey, hey, great, now
I've lost 'em all.
[dramatic trumpet music]
Gimme that chip.
[Spider-man] Please, let
me help lift your curse.
Ha ha ha,
I am not cursed, I am blessed.
Nothing can stop
me, I am immortal.
[Spider-man] Out of
webbing, way to go Spidey.
I'm sure gonna hate
explaining this to Blade.
You know, it's getting
so you can't tell
the cops from the peeping
toms in this town.
Right, Detective Lee?
Hold it, are you
trying to tell me
there really is such
a thing as a vampire?
[Spider-man] Yes and there'll
be more of them unless
we stop this one.
And just how are we supposed
to do that, with this stuff?
No, these are just
historic relics.
This new device of mine is the
kind of thing we use today.
-[electric warbling]
-What the?
Relax Spider-man, it's only
a force field of
photosynthetic particles.
It can't possibly harm you
but if you were a vampire,
-you'd be trapped.
-Hey smiley,
I'd like to see you
fit that on your bike.
Well perhaps I do need to
make it a little more compact.
[Spider-man] I think
I'll stick to my webbing,
-if you'll pardon the pun.
-We've got work to do.
What are we waiting
for, Whistler?
We need to regroup,
we need to make a new plan.
[Spider-man] And I need to
get more webbing cartridges.
I'll meet you back
here in an hour.
[Blade growls]
What's wrong?
He'll be all right, Blade
it's time for your serum.
Get some rest, you're
going to need it.
Why does he need a serum
and where did he
get those teeth?
All vampires have fangs.
He's a vampire too, but how?
It's a long story, Miss?
Lee, Terri Lee.
Just take it slowly from
the top, I'm all ears.
[Spider-man] I gotta be quiet
so I don't wake up Aunt May.
In my own home, Aunt May,
thank goodness she's all right.
Why is my Spider-Sense
going crazy?
Morbius, what's he doing here?
Of course, he's looking
for another sample
of blood for the Neogenic
transformation process.
I can't fight him
here, something could
That was much too
close, he'll keep
coming back until he gets
what he's looking for.
Oh Mr. Robertson,
I didn't hear you come in.
Haven't heard anything from
Peter Parker, Jonah, nothing.
That punk kid told
everyone he was working
on an assignment but we
didn't send him on any--
[gasps]
-Where is Parker?
-Who the heck are you?
-Where is he?
-I have no idea.
What the heck was that?
[ambulance siren blaring]
I'm fed up with you
and your secrets, kid.
Now I want the whole story.
Why was that refugee from an
Anne Rice novel looking for you?
-I can't say, Mr. Jameson.
-Can't or won't?
Look Peter, first you disappear
for days and then this.
We're more than a
little confused.
No kidding, you have no
new photos of the top
story of the hour, Spider-man
or even a man-spider.
Why am I keeping
you on our payroll?
Why don't I just fire you?
Think fast, Parker.
Because I'm about to get you
the picture of the century.
Picture of what, smart-mouth?
Of the living vampire that's
really behind all
the trouble at ESU.
That is if you keep me on.
What do you say, Jonah?
Peter's never let
us down before.
I say you have 24 hours to
make good on that promise, boy.
Or you might as well
hock your camera
because you'll never snap
another picture in this town.
I'll make good, don't worry.
But I'm gonna need something
from you, Mr. Jameson.
What?
It better not be money because--
No no, not money, something
that'll help me even more.
How humiliating, at least
Jameson came through for me.
[Terri] Whistler, is
this Blade's mother?
[Whistler] Yes, he's
still searching for her.
He was devastated when
she abandoned him.
And the serum?
Blade requires
regular injections.
It prevents him from
needing blood himself.
It keeps him from
being a total vampire.
Shh, someone's coming.
-Well, can anybody--
-Who are you?
What are you doing here?
I'm Peter Parker,
Spider-man's sent me.
He does know
Spider-man, he's cool.
Knowing Spider-man
does not make him cool.
Just hear me out,
Spider-man has a plan.
[anxious violin music]
My Spider-Sense is
going ballistic.
-I'll bet Morbius is back.
-Peter.
Mary Jane.
I've had a hard time
catching up with you.
Now I see why.
Look, I can't explain right now,
can we talk a little later?
Peter, with you it's
always a little later.
I won't deal with that anymore.
I came here tonight to try
to save our relationship.
[Peter] Morbius
is getting closer.
What's the matter,
cat got your tongue?
Let me make it easy for you.
Just tell me you want
Felicia Hardy, and I'm gone.
What I want is to get
you out of danger.
Okay, it is Felicia.
I thought for a minute
we had a good thing going.
Shows what I know,
goodbye tiger, see ya around.
[Peter] MJ, I'll make this
up to you someday, I promise.
Parker, you may
never have Felicia.
[Peter] I have to play dumb.
-Nobody will have her but me.
-Who are you?
You do not recognize me?
I am Michael Morbius.
Morbius, you can't be serious.
-Dead serious.
-What do you want with me?
I need a sample of that
Neogenically-treated
blood you created.
I don't know what
you're talking about.
[Michael] Do not play
the fool with me, Parker.
-It's working.
-Give it to me at once.
Okay, okay, I've
got one in the van.
Get ready, Blade.
[anxious violin tones]
[Blade] You're mine.
[electric crackling]
You're in league with
that vampire hunter?
-Peter.
-Aunt May.
-What's going on?
-Stay back.
[Aunt May] Peter.
Aunt May,
no!
Don't do it, Morbius
please, let her go.
Give me my blood sample.
It's in my locker at ESU.
Now just ease her
over to me gently.
No, she is insurance until I
determine you have given
me the right information.
[Peter] No!
If only the generator
hadn't blown.
I feel terrible
about Parker's aunt.
Don't, this is war, sometimes
the innocent are sacrificed.
What's running in
your veins, ice water?
Have you forgotten how you
felt when you lost your mother?
Whistler talks too much.
Blade, I'm sorry.
I didn't mean to
hurt your feelings.
The ability to feel seeped out
of my soul years ago, Terri Lee.
Learning to feel again may
not be as hard as you think.
[Spider-man] I'm glad
somebody has time
to enjoy themselves when
there's so much at stake.
How dare you, if
you'd been there,
we might have saved
the Parker woman.
[Spider-man] We don't
have time to argue.
We need to make another plan.
I'm tired of this
teamwork garbage.
I'll finish this mission myself.
[Spider-man] I'm sick of
hearing of you and your mission.
It's not like any
of your brilliant
weapons and schemes have worked.
Why don't you all go
back into the cave
you flew out of,
I'm working alone again.
Aunt May is with that madman,
I've gotta find
him but how, where?
Of course.
Lucky for you, I have
already fed tonight.
That sedative I've given you
should keep you out of my way.
Soon my darling Felicia,
we will be together again,
forever.
[Spider-man] Morbius will
come here to Felicia.
She'll be the first
human he'll want to
turn into a vampire and
I'll be ready for him.
Hey, what's this?
Tell me Mary Jane, I mean I've
been asking you out for
months with no luck.
What made you finally say yes?
Harry, I'll never
forget how you bravely
tried to protect me from
that man-spider creature.
Thank you for making me feel
like the most special
woman in the world.
You are special
to me, Mary Jane.
[Spider-man] Mary
Jane, I brushed her off
and right into the
arms of my best friend.
Now May is in the
arms of a vampire.
What else could go wrong?
[Michael] Felicia,
my love.
Who,
who's there?
It feels like an eternity since
we've kissed in the band tower.
Michael?
Oh Michael, I
missed you so much.
Where have you [gasp, scream]--
[Spider-man] Felicia!
I'm too late, he's got her.
Gotta stay on his tail,
if I lose him now,
I lose everything.
[anxious rock music]
What are we doing here?
Michael, it was you.
You're the one responsible
for the plasma disease.
Yes but it is also
true that I am immortal
and you my love, you
will be just like me.
We will be together forever.
[scream]
Thanks, that was close.
And no accident, it was a
trap, he's expecting us.
How about a blast of solar
radiation, instant fry you.
No, don't hurt him.
Let me take him into custody.
He's a vampire,
you destroy them.
Blade, human beings don't
destroy lives, they save them.
Think of what your
mother wanted for you.
She gave you up to keep you
from a life as a vampire.
Let Spider-man try to help him.
Perhaps you are right.
-I won't let you hurt him.
-I wasn't going to,
and now you let him get away.
[Spider-man] Great, why don't
I ever look before I leap?
Look.
There's not much time.
You must become a vampire
and help me defeat them.
[Spider-man] He's
activated the Recombinator.
I don't want to be with you.
You're not the same person
I fell in love with.
But I am.
No, listen to me, the
man I loved wanted to
stop a plague and the pain
and suffering it caused.
You are a plague.
I can't live a life that
preys on innocent people.
Please Michael,
don't make me do it.
[scream]
You are right.
I do love you, Felicia.
I must get help to be changed
back to my human self,
back to the man you love.
[metallic creaking]
-[electric warbling]
-[screaming]
I always loved you.
-Always!
-I know.
[Morbius screams]
[Spider-man] Aunt May, no.
[anxious violin music]
I can't lose Aunt May the
same way I lost Uncle Ben.
If ever my spider strength meant
anything at all,
this is that time.
Your time is finished
vampire, accept that fate.
Michael.
What happened to him?
[Spider-man] This power setting
completely merged his
genetic code with bat DNA.
He'll never be human again.
I'm so sorry, Miss Hardy, more
than you could ever imagine.
So I guess this is goodbye,
will I see you around?
Maybe we could catch
a movie or something.
No, it's not a good idea.
Forget what you saw tonight,
forget everything
except this, Terri Lee.
Great, of all the
men in the world,
I had to fall in
love with a vampire.
Love, who needs it?
[relaxed violin music]
Peter?
-Peter dear, is that you?
-You called me, Aunt May?
Oh my, I had the
most horrible dream.
It all seemed so real.
[Spider-man] The best thing
to do is try to forget.
Sleep tight, Aunt May.
Morbius and Felicia
were so much in love.
Who ever said true
love conquers all?
I wonder what
happened to Morbius?
[Michael] So tired,
I finally can sleep.
Yes.
Sleep.
My
Felicia.
[dramatic trumpet tones]
[mid tempo rock music]
♪ Spider-man ♪
♪ Radioactive Spider-man ♪
[energetic rock music]
♪ Spider blood ♪
♪ Radioactive spider blood ♪
♪ Spider-man ♪