[upbeat rock music]
♪ Spider-Man ♪
♪ Radioactive Spider-Man ♪
♪ Spider blood
Spider blood ♪
♪ Radioactive spider blood ♪
♪ Spider blood
Spider blood ♪
♪ Radioactive spider blood ♪
[explosions booming]
[growling]
♪ Spider-Man ♪
[lively music]
Peter, don't forget
to water all the plants.
Aunt May, relax.
You're just going to be
staying around the block.
I know, dear.
But I wanna give Anna Watson
all my attention.
She's been devastated
since Mary Jane's been gone.
[thinking]
She's not the only one.
Shall I ring the bell?
No. Anna gave me the key.
Take care while I'm gone.
Dear Aunt May.
She's never given up her faith
in the value of helping others.
I wish I could feel the same.
But after
what happened to Mary Jane,
I'm angry at the world.
Question is,
can I be this angry
and still live up to my
responsibilities as Spider-Man?
I got your message.
What'd you wanna see me
about Felicia?
Mother and I are preparing
our budget for next year's
youth science program.
We need your input.
[warning beeping]
[alarm sounding]
There's a break-in
in the east lab
near the warehouse storing area.
[Peter, thinking]
I don't believe it.
It's Sergei Kravinoff.
What's he doing here?
[guards grunting]
[groaning]
Who is that wild man?
Stay here while I see
if I can help!
Parker, come back!
[Russian accent] This
does not concern any of you!
I don't know about that.
I'm a caring kinda guy.
Spider-Man.
You are the last person
I wanted to see.
[dramatic music]
[groaning]
I forgot. This bolas wire
is stronger than my webbing!
-Run!
-Look out!
Aah! Oh!
[Felicia] Mother!
Are you all right?
Yes, thanks to you.
That maniac nearly killed you.
I'm going to get help.
[Spider-Man]
The last time I saw Kravinoff,
he helped me as a friend.
Now he's acting more like
his insane alter-ego,
Kraven the Hunter.
What's changed him?
[dramatic music]
Aaaah!
[coughing]
Hang on tight.
You okay, Spider?
Yeah, must have been
some chemical in that powder.
It's making my head
pound like a jungle drum.
[Black Cat]
I'll give you a hand up.
Forget it.
I'll be okay in a sec.
Spider, you really do
have to take
better care of yourself.
[thinking]
This is humiliating.
I'm saved then chided
by the Black Cat.
Who does she think she is?
The superhero version
of Aunt May?
[Anastasia]
This lab is ruined.
What did that maniac want?
Good question.
What was in this cabinet?
Why, it contained serum
that a doctor named
Mariah Crawford
had been working on.
It was one originally developed
by a friend of hers.
A Dr. Reeves.
[Spider-Man]
Dr. Reeves?
[Anastasia] Reeves
gave me the last vile
of his wonder drug.
[thinking]
Could this have been the serum
that turned Kravinoff
into Kraven in the first place?
Is Dr. Crawford here in town?
Last I heard,
she was still in Africa
fighting an outbreak
of the plague.
The serum is gone.
That jungle man
must have taken it.
Did Kraven use the serum again
and turn himself back
into that monster?
I will not hurt lion!
So you're
gonna hurt me instead?
And if he did, why?
You don't seem
to understand, Spider.
I've been given
this great power.
I owe it to the world
to give something back.
Like you, I want to do
good things with it.
Do yourself a big favor.
Forget it.
My great powers have given me
nothing but grief.
Quit while you still can.
If it's so bad,
why don't youquit?
Lady, I've been asking myself
the same question
every night since--
-[growling]
-What was that?
Sounded like
some kind of wild animal.
[man] Aah! No!
Someone's being attacked.
[men yelling]
Rraarr!
He's as strong as me!
Heis Kraven now.
-Kraven the Hunter!
-[groans]
Last time,
we met as friends.
But make no mistake.
I would sooner destroy you
than suffer your interference.
Not this time, pal.
You've taken the serum!
I want to know why!
Yaaah!
[groaning]
Is this private
or can any party animal
join the hunt?
Stay back!
Kraven's too dangerous!
[Kraven] Yaaah!
[groans]
Thanks.
You gave me time
to untangle his little toy
and use it on him.
See? We really ought to
work together, Spider.
Look, I've told you before,
I'm not interested.
I can't take the risk
of anyone else getting hurt.
That's why I work alone.
[both groaning]
[gears grinding]
Watch it!
Cat, stay out of his way!
[yowling]
Stop!
Oh! What?!
Cat, look out!
[Spider-Man grunting]
If you ever try
to stop me again,
-I promise I will destroy you!
-[coughing]
[groaning]
Spider!
[grunting]
Thank goodness.
You're only stunned.
Blast!
-He got away because of you!
-[meows]
What were you thinking?
You risked both
our lives for this?
I couldn't let an innocent
creature be destroyed.
Don't you care
about anybody anymore?
That's just the problem.
I don't think I do.
Wait.
I don't know why you wanna
be a crime fighter.
Take my advice. In the end,
you'll regret it big time.
I wish I could tell him
why I wanna be a crime fighter.
It's not just for me,
but for my father as well.
I wanted something
better for you.
Better than the life I had.
Daddy, this isn't your fault.
There was no way
you could've stopped
the Kingpin
from giving me that serum.
Maybe.
But what about all the times
you needed me
when you were growing up,
and I wasn't there?
Will you ever
forgive me for that?
That's all in the past.
I wanna make up
for all the mistakes
he made in his life.
That's what he'd want me to do.
But Spider's become
so hard-hearted lately.
How can I make him understand
what a great companion
a cat can be?
I should feel
badly about this.
After all, Kraven did
save my life once.
Now I'm trying to bring him in.
Why am I always hurting people?
Especially
once this mask is on?
And I wonder how Aunt May's
doing with Anna Watson.
Maybe I ought to peek in
to make sure everything's okay.
Hey, who's that guy
watching the house?
It's Harry Osborn.
Looks like he's taking
Mary Jane's disappearance
as hard as I am.
I should talk to him.
But I have nothing to offer.
The Black Cat was right.
I feel nothing in my heart
right now for others.
And that makes me
a worse monster than Kraven.
[dramatic music]
-[roaring]
-[grunting]
Help!
[snarling]
[growling]
-[animal snarling]
-No! No!
Aaah!
That's interesting.
Uh-uh! Whoa!
Oh! Flash!
This would be much easier
if you would hold still.
Debra, I never
did anything like this
for any of my other dates.
Not even Felicia Hardy.
Hmm. I'll consider myself
a member of an elite society
from here on in.
Yes! Claw marks.
And a hair sample.
This supports my theory
that the night stalker
is some strange animal.
Phase one of my investigation
is complete.
Now phase two.
Phase two?
All right, Spidey.
You've faced this puzzle before.
How do you hunt for the hunter
in an asphalt jungle
as big as New York?
The last time,
I tracked him down
to the special jungle exhibit
at the Central Park Zoo.
He's at home
in that kind of environment.
-It's where
he has an advantage.
-[growling]
I'll start there.
I just wish I knew
what he's after.
Okay, the coast is clear.
Debra, what are we doing here?
Listen, Flash, this was where
that creature was spotted last.
If I can prove its existence,
maybe I can get funding
for another project
I've been wanting to do.
-Project? What project?
-[growling]
Shh!
I thought I heard something.
Wait a minute.
I just figured it out.
Figured what out?
You've been
into this weirdo stuff
ever since Michael Morbius
disappeared.
You think that this might lead
to Morbius, don't you?
That's your project, isn't it?
You don't know
what you're talking about.
[Flash] Well, you wanna
find that vampire?
-Debra, are you crazy?
-Look, Flash--
[growling]
-What on earth?!
-[Debra screaming]
Sounds like I
came to the right place.
It's gotta be Kraven!
-[roaring]
-Help!
Raaarrr!
Come out of hiding, jungle man!
I know you're here!
So it is you!
Kraven.
I have already warned you
to leave me alone Spider-Man!
Oh, no.
Not more jungle dust.
[gasps]
Can't see straight.
Can barely move.
[grunting] I cannot risk
further interference!
[roaring]
I will keep my promise
and end this charade now!
-[Debra screaming]
-[Flash] No, don't!
[roar]
-Back off!
-[Kraven groans]
Oh! Aaaah!
[groans]
Are you all right?
There's nothing
that beast can dish out
that this beauty can't handle.
Look!
-Stay back!
-[birds squawking]
Why do you stalk this city?
This hunt is not my passion!
It is my tragedy!
Great! Just great!
Don't worry, Spider.
I'll help you find him.
I don't need your help.
I need you to stay
out of my way.
Out of my life!
[Debra] What's with him?
I don't know.
He seems to be going through
some personal struggle
right now.
Unfortunately,
it's giving him tunnel vision.
I mean,
there's more involved here
than what Spider thinks.
For instance, why did Kraven
call his hunt a tragedy?
And you two.
What are you doing here?
We're not doing anything
that I wouldn't drop
in a hot New York minute
if you needed me.
In fact, if Spider-Man
doesn't wanna be your partner,
I'm willing to--
[Flash grunts]
Ahem! I have a scientific
interest in the stalker.
So I tracked him down
to his lair
here in the park.
Really?
Perhaps we need to talk.
Is Kraven
and this ferocious stalker
one in the same?
But if so, how does
he transform himself and why?
Was it a nasty aftereffect
of his taking the serum?
I've gotta figure out
where he'll strike next.
Now that Central Park
isn't his lair any longer,
does East River Park seem
like the next best location?
I couldn't see it clearly.
It was some kind
of horrible monster.
It headed east out of the park.
Well, I had the right park,
but I'm too late.
Kraven's on the move again.
The Williamsburg Bridge
leads to Brooklyn.
Now, why would Kraven
be headed there?
Of course.
Prospect Park.
It has a botanical garden
and zoo.
Kraven's probably picked
up the animal's scent.
[sniffing]
[ringing]
-Yes?
-[indistinct voice on phone]
Debra? What's wrong?
You need what?
Okay.
Okay, I'll be right there.
-[spider-sense tingling]
-Kraven!
-Aaaah!
-[groaning]
You won't dare interfere again!
Now I'm really mad!
You got my suit wet again!
-You're not getting away.
-Ohh!
Not until you tell me what your
connection is to that stalker.
Are you that creature?
Me?! [laughing] No.
I am not creature!
But I did create it.
-What?
-Yes!
I created it willingly,
and then it destroyed
my love, Mariah.
My little Calypso
exists no more.
No! I can't
have lost her, too!
Why did you let that happen?
-Why?!
-Spider, wait! [grunts]
-Leave me alone!
-You've got to calm down.
There is something here
you don't understand.
Something you must know
about that creature.
All I need to know
is that it destroyed
a good friend of mine.
And after I finish
with this scum,
-I'm going to destroy it.
-No!
Debra Whitman analyzed
the hair samples in the lab.
She discovered
the creature's DNA.
It's female.
-What?
-Don't you get it?
When Kraven spoke
of his tragedy,
he said it
with passion in his voice.
With love.
That creature is probably
someone that Kraven loves.
A woman.
No, it can't be.
-That's the truth, isn't it?
-[Kraven straining]
No use trying to break free.
I mixed up a stronger batch
of webbing just for you.
Better for you to talk, Tarzan.
Tragedy is like strong acid.
It dissolves away all
but the very gold of truth.
My beloved Mariah Crawford
went to Africa to help
the victims of a lethal virus.
[Mariah moaning]
I was devastated when she
contracted the disease herself.
The doctors said
she could not be saved.
There was only one hope.
The serum that Mariah used
to save my life
when I was the Hunter.
She was still trying
to perfect it,
to make it safe.
That was why we had it with us.
I did not know if I had
done the right thing.
[moaning]
Her recovery was miraculous.
She seemed completely healed.
[thunder crashing]
I brought her back
to New York to recuperate.
All was well at first.
But then the serum
had an effect even stranger
-than the one it had on me!
-[screams]
She became
a worse feral creature
than I had once become.
-[Mariah screaming]
-Mariah?
-[growling]
-She was too strong.
I couldn't hold her!
[growling]
I only knew one thing
that could make me powerful
enough to catch her.
The remaining sample of serum
that transformed me
into Kraven the Hunter!
I didn't want to take it,
-but I knew it was
my only hope.
-[screams]
As Kraven, I could hunt her
with abilities far beyond those
of an ordinary human.
I only wanted to capture her
before someone else did
and cure her.
[Spider-Man]
So Dr. Mariah Crawford
is the hideous creature?
Yes.
You must know I would never
harm my beloved Calypso.
-Calypso?
-His nickname for her.
Calypso was a Greek goddess
who offered Odysseus
the gift of life.
I believe you.
And I want to help you,
but I don't know how.
Wait, I do.
Debra Whitman figured
enough of this out
to go ask
Dr. Curt Connors for help.
Connors was familiar
with Crawford's work.
He used that knowledge
to make this.
It's a possible antidote
based on the sample
of Dr. Crawford's plasma,
which was on file
at the Hardy Foundation.
It probably won't
be a complete cure,
but it might reverse
some of her transformation.
-Can we use it on him?
-No! No.
It's tailored
only to her blood cells.
[Kraven sniffing]
I have the creature's scent.
I know she is nearby.
You must set me free!
-Well?
-All right, let him loose.
After all, I wouldn't
wanna be accused
of being heartless.
[dramatic music]
[growling]
[shrieks]
[Kraven] Help me!
[Kraven grunting]
[roaring]
Calypso?
Kraven, my darling.
Dr. Crawford?
Spider-Man.
Is there a cure for her?
Can she be transformed
all the way back
to her normal human self?
The only one
who could come up
with that antidote is
Dr. Mariah Crawford herself.
No!
I do not want to change.
Don't you understand?
You and I, we are truly
kindred spirits now.
I do understand.
We must go.
[Spider-Man] Go?
But where?
We will go where we can be free.
Perhaps it is better this way.
I vow to stay by her side
and protect her always.
[zoo animals growling
and calling]
I feel like
we lost this one.
At least Kraven and Mariah
still have their love
for each other.
And what kind of life
are they going to have?
I forgot you don't believe
in happily ever after
these days.
But don't you still
believe in love
and opening
your heart to others?
Seems to me it's a prerequisite
for you line of work.
I don't know.
Maybe I will again, someday.
[knocking]
Peter.
What are you doing here?
You still need a roommate?
Well, it is a big place.
I got to figuring,
maybe we need each other
right now, old pal.
[upbeat rock music]
♪ Spider-Man, Spider-Man ♪
♪ Radioactive Spider-Man ♪
♪ Spider blood, spider blood ♪
♪ Radioactive spider blood ♪
♪ Spider blood ♪
♪ Spider-Man ♪