[upbeat rock music]
♪ Spider-Man ♪
♪ Radioactive Spider-Man ♪
♪ Spider blood
Spider blood ♪
♪ Radioactive spider blood ♪
♪ Spider blood
Spider blood ♪
♪ Radioactive spider blood ♪
[explosions booming]
[growling]
♪ Spider-Man ♪
[Spider-Man]
The city looks gigantic
when you've lost
someone you love in it.
Mary Jane has disappeared?
D-Disappeared where?
I don't know.
She was supposed to meet
a man she said was her father.
That's impossible!
He abandoned her family
when she was a little girl.
Why wasn't I told about this?!
I'm sorry.
She wanted to keep it a secret.
Why would she tell you
instead of me?
I'm her boyfriend!
You had no right
to keep this from us!
Anna, please,
remember your blood pressure!
Oh, I know something is wrong.
She's never gone for this long
without calling me.
Oh, my poor niece!
She's out there somewhere!
She could be in danger,
or worse!
Why weren't you there
to look after her?!
[sobbing]
Anna Watson has every right
to be angry with me.
I should've been there.
I've finally gotten rid
of my mutation disease,
but what good is it if
I've lost the woman I love?
-[whooshing]
-Huh?
What on earth?
[clink]
What in the name
of the Vishanti?
-[groans]
-[crash]
Hey. These guys have
got super strength.
[groans]
And this one's got
a bear hug like a bear!
Huh? [groans]
Mary Jane?
-[laser blast]
-[groaning]
[whirring]
We have found
the Wand of Watoomb!
Stop Spider-Man
and then we can get it!
[grunting]
Unh! Mary Jane!
Noo!
[Spider-Man groaning]
By the power
of omnipotent ?????,
I command you to cease!
[grunts]
I don't know who you are or
how you did that, but thanks!
I summon forth the shielding
powers of the Vishanti!
Impressive!
He sure puts Mysterio's
hocus-pocus to shame.
[blast]
[Mary Jane] He is too powerful!
We must flee!
Wait. They possess powers
you cannot possibly fathom.
Thanks for the warning,
but I've got
a personal stake in this.
She's starting to fly
faster than I can swing!
If I can just get
close enough.
Whoa!
[beeping]
-[beeping]
-Huh.
The Center
for Reunification,
I hope they
don't mind if I have
a little reunion of my own.
-[blast]
-Uhh!
[power humming]
Ooh!
What is this?!
The Crimson Bands of Cyttorak.
I urge you to turn
away from this place!
Not a chance!
Who are you anyway?
I am Doctor Strange,
master of the mystic arts.
[blast]
He should take
that act to Vegas.
All he needs is
a couple of tigers.
Well, now I know
where Mary Jane is,
but how do I get
inside to see her?
And how did she get
mixed up in all of this?
[speaking incantation
in foreign language]
[men] Ahh!
-Prophetic words.
-Oh, yeah.
Oh, Brother Mordo,
I-I had such a wonderful visit.
Good, child.
This institution's purpose
is to make you content
and fulfilled.
Oh, I am,
and for the first time
in my life,
I'm-- I'm really happy!
Now, my children, go back
to your chambers and rest.
We will have another
visit very soon.
-[blast]
-[groans]
[explosion]
-You have failed me!
Master!
Master Dormammu!
You did not retrieve the wand!
I am doomed! Doomed!
I need the Wand of Watoomb!
Bring it to me
no matter what the cost!
[whirring]
Mordo. It can only be Mordo.
But, Doctor, how can you be
so sure that it's him?
It fits in
with his dark purpose.
it is time you knew
the whole story, Wong.
Ours is a deadly rivalry
that began years ago,
when a car accident
ended my career
as a prominent
New York doctor.
I lost the delicate touch
that a surgeon requires.
It left me a bitter,
broken man.
Finally, in desperation,
I trekked through
the far corners of Asia
to seek a maven known
only as the Ancient One.
I wanted
an instant miracle cure,
but the Ancient One
told me to study with him,
to learn his mystic ways and
find the cure within myself.
Alas, I was
too bitter to listen.
On my way out, I came across
the Ancient One's student.
His name was Mordo.
He was attempting
to destroy the Ancient One
and take his place.
I had to warn the old man!
Mordo tried to stop me!
But, luckily, the Ancient One
had known of Mordo's plot,
and was prepared.
[zapping]
The Ancient One told me
I had been tested,
and that there
was goodness in my soul.
I agreed to become
the Ancient One's pupil,
so I could fight Mordo and
the evil magic he stood for.
I have studied
the mystic magics.
My life has taken
on deeper meaning
as I have prepared
for the inevitable
confrontation with Baron Mordo.
[Peter] Brother Mordo.
So he's the head of
the Center for Reunification?
Yes, it's some kind
of secret cult.
They say
this Mordo fellow recruits
-his disciples with promises...
[phone ringing]
...of reuniting them
with lost loved ones.
Mr. Robinson,
call on line four!
First I lose
Mary Jane to Harry,
now to this dangerous cult!
I have to find
a way to save her,
but what hold does
this Mordo have over her?
[man]
I'm sure that Brother Mordo
can help you
in your quest, Mr. Parker.
That's why I came here.
He's the last hope I have
-of becoming--
-Reunited, yes!
It brings us inner peace
and true fulfillment.
You may rest here
in your chamber,
while I see to your first
session with Brother Mordo.
Peace and reunion to you.
Uh-oh, someone's coming!
Oh, good, they didn't see me.
Well, at least I'm in.
Peter!
What are you doing here?
I've come to take you home,
Mary Jane.
Peter you don't understand!
My father is here!
Brother Mordo has reunited us.
I see Daddy every day.
Peter, it's just
what I've always dreamed of,
having a wonderful
relationship with my father.
We've become so close, nothing
can come between us again.
I can't go.
Mary Jane, what about
the things you were doing
earlier this evening?
The break-in
at Greenwich Village?
I-- I don't know
what you're talking about.
I was here this evening
with Daddy.
No, you weren't.
Look, I've gotta
get you out of here.
You're not taking me!
I won't let you!
[alarm sounds]
[grunting]
Can't risk
using my spider powers
with all
these people watching.
Take him to Brother Mordo.
Mary Jane arrived here seeking
the truth about her father.
She has found it and found him.
Why would you deny her
such fulfillment?
Isn't that what
we're all longing for?
After all, isn't there someone
with whom
you want to be reunited?
Ah, yes.
Of course there is.
Mom?
Dad!
You're alive!
But-- But I was told--
It's all right, Peter,
everything...
...is all right.
I'm here with you now, son.
You're with us again,
and we'll never let you go.
Never.
Where am I?
What happened?
Did I really see my parents?
I've gotta get Mary Jane
and get out of here
before Mordo
brainwashes me, too!
My children,
our time is at hand!
We must dispel our enemies.
Listen to my words.
You are the army of Dormammu.
You must recover
the Wand of Watoomb.
Let nothing,
not even your own destruction,
stand in the way.
[Spider-Man]
Nothing must stand in the way.
[glass shatters]
Stand fast!
I am ready, Doctor.
[lasers blasting]
[explosion]
[whooshing]
Spider-Man?!
What are you doing?!
Doctor, I can't
fight them all! I--
[grunts] Nothing will stand
in the way of Mordo's will,
not even you, Doctor Strange!
Spider-Man, listen to me!
Spider-Man!
O great
all-seeing Eye of Agamotto,
you must come to my aid!
As I suspected.
Omnipotent Vishanti,
empower my amulet,
remove this spell
that clouds his mind.
Doctor Strange,
how did I get here?
The all-seeing Eye of Agamotto
revealed to me
that you had been placed
under a hypnotic spell
by Mordo,
and now Mordo has
the Wand of Watoomb.
-The Wand of Watoomb!
I am overjoyed
with your success, my child.
Thank you, father.
Oh, Daddy, I love you.
And I love you, too, my child.
Our world is in grave peril
now that Mordo has the wand.
No doubt he will use it to try
to free the dread Dormammu.
Who?
Dormammu is
a powerful evil entity,
who travels
from dimension to dimension,
draining the light energy
out of all universes.
Now he wants to come
to feed on ours.
He must draw the life force
out of our reality or starve.
Dormammu has ultimate power.
If I face him, it will be
the struggle of my life.
But I'll be there to help you.
I must warn you,
the odds against us
returning alive
are astronomical.
Big deal, I've been
through the Bronx. I'm ready.
All is now prepared, Master.
The wand is ours.
I hunger
for new life energy to devour.
Release me
into your dimension!
With pleasure.
The time has come.
[thunderclap]
Thanks for the free trip, Doc,
This is saving me
a fortune in webbing.
[power whirring]
Looks like they're
closed for the night.
I invoke the Hosts of Hockoth!
[Spider-Man]
Remind me to call you
if I ever lose my house key.
Here we are again, Wong,
about to leap into the unknown
to fight the deadliest battle
of our lives.
-Exciting, is it not, Doctor?
-It is.
No offense, but you guys
are really weird.
[Doctor Strange]
Let us go.
[whooshing]
Oh, look,
the welcoming committee.
[man groans]
Steal is mightier than wood!
And let's not forget,
good is mightier than evil!
[whooshing]
My multiplicities dictum!
[groans]
[Mordo]
By the power of the wand,
I release my master Dormammu
into this dimension!
[web shoots]
You borrowed this
without asking permission,
so I'll take this little
doohickey out of your hands!
Wong! We have to help him!
We cannot!
This is a mystical battle
that only Doctor Strange
can win.
My years of devotion
to the dark arts
have made me strong--
stronger than you!
No, you betrayed
the ancient one.
I will show you
the folly of your decision.
Omnipotent Ashtoor,
power my amulet.
Observe, servant of evil,
as the mighty light of Ashtoor
blots out your darkness!
Help me!
Mordo, you are a fool!
I will help you
attack him through you!
[Dormammu] Now you will know
what true power is, Strange!
I call down
the Rain of Ragadore.
Okay, I've had enough
sitting on the sidelines!
Spider-Man, no!
Oh, boy!
You dare to challenge me
in my own dimension?
So be it.
Uh-oh! Maybe this wasn't
such a smart move after all.
[grunting]
Can't breathe!
[groans]
I summon
the Seven Rings of Ragadore.
Come to my aid.
[grunts]
Wong, stand guard
while I go help our friend.
By the Light of Agamotto,
disperse Dormammu's magic!
Spider-Man, we must
get back through the portal
and close it!
[Spider-Man]
I can go along with that!
I control this side
of the portal,
and you will not escape!
[Doctor Strange] Vapors
of Voltor, hold him fast!
I call upon the energy
of the 12 moons of Munipul!
The wand!
Give it to me!
Go fetch!
No!
You'd do well
at the obedience trials,
but you're not very fast.
No!
Daddy!
Are you in here, Daddy?!
No! Your father
isn't really here!
Listen to me!
Mordo tricked you!
I don't believe you!
I have to find him!
Let me handle this.
Mary Jane, you must learn
to face the truth
about your father.
And this house,
it's never clean!
Lousy kids!
Look on your father as he was.
We all have emotional ties
that have been severed
in our lives, and Mordo
knows how to use his magic
to seemingly reconnect them.
[Mordo]
See me as your father.
I suspect that's what
he did to gain power over you.
-You must embrace them.
-[crying]
And let go
of your bitter memories.
You understand?
Excellent.
Is she okay?
She is very well.
[whoosh]
[screaming]
We cannot help her now.
Dormammu must be accepted
into our world
by someone who embraces
him, like Mordo.
He will try to trick her
into inviting him.
You have come to me, my child.
Stay here,
and we can be together.
You're...
You're not my father!
Why, yes!
Yes, I am, my child!
Come to me.
Trust me. Obey me.
No! No!
This is all wrong!
This is another trick!
You're not my father!
Stay away from me!
Do not reject me!
That is the one thing
you cannot do!
Nooo!
[explosion]
[screams] Oh!
Mary Jane,
thank heavens you're back!
[Doctor Strange]
She did it!
She had the strength of mind
to see through Dormammu's ruse,
and now I chant
the words to close
this portal of evil
once and for all!
Tonn konn champon kraa!
-[burst of electricity]
-No!
[Wong]
We must go, Doctor!
The fluctuation of
the diminishing portal's energy
is threatening
this entire area!
Yes, Wong. By the power
of the the Vishanti.
[crash]
[explosion]
Mary Jane, are you okay?
Yes, I'm all right.
I just wanna go home.
To the people who love me.
Thank you, Doctor Strange.
Wong, thank you for everything.
It has been a pleasure fighting
by your side, Spider-Man.
You are a worthy ally
in the battle against darkness.
May the Vishanti
watch over thee.
And may your amulet...
never... tickle.
The Vishanti have
smiled on us,
and I hope they will do
the same for Spider-Man
and Mary Jane.
Our work here is now--
[Wong] What is it, Doctor?
What's wrong?
[Doctor Strange] I sense
that we are being watched
by someone
whose powers dwarf my own.
[upbeat rock music]
♪ Spider-Man, Spider-Man ♪
♪ Radioactive Spider-Man ♪
♪ Spider blood, spider blood ♪
♪ Radioactive spider blood ♪
♪ Spider blood ♪
♪ Spider-Man ♪