[Kingpin] Previously
onSpider-Man...
- The rock's bleeding!
- Get back up here now.
Help me!
[Kingpin] Rhino, did you get
the Promethium X?
[groans]
Yeah!
[Kingpin]
Bring it to me, immediately!
Anyone else in there?
[Spider-Man thinking]
Hudson River pollution,
rich and creamy.
Spider-Man robbed the shuttle.
Spider-Man did it,
I'm offering a million dollars.
[Peter thinking]
For once in my life,
I'm worth something
and I can't collect.
No!
[Spider-Man thinking]
I don't know how I got here,
and I'm in a costume
I've never seen before.
-[man 1] There he is.
-[man 2] Grab him.
[police siren wails]
[Spider-Man thinking]
Look how strong I am now.
I used to have trouble
lifting a Volkswagon.
It would be nice if you were
a little less conspicuous.
Nothing on earth
could do what this does.
I like your style.
Look who suddenly
developed a backbone.
I've developed a lot
more than a backbone.
Parker, you scare me.
[groans]
No, you can't!
[Spider-Man thinking]
I am different.
No!
[Spider-Man thinking]
What's happening to me?
[theme song playing]
♪ Spider-Man, Spider-Man ♪
♪ Radioactive Spider-Man ♪
♪ Spider-Man ♪
♪ Spider-Man, Spider-Man ♪
♪ Radioactive Spider-Man ♪
♪ Spider blood, spider blood ♪
♪ Radioactive spider blood ♪
♪ Spider-Man, Spider-Man ♪
[man on radio]
I have a Spider sighting
at 3:00, do you copy?
[man on radio 2]
Copy, Red Leader,
let's move in on our
$1,000,000 target.
[Spider-Man thinking]
You punk heads can't catch me,
not when this suit makes me
stronger and faster than you.
Blast Jameson
and his stupid reward.
He's got the whole
world after me
for something I didn't do.
I can hardly move
without somebody
wanting a piece of me.
Don't you yahoos get it?
The Black Spider-Man
is unbeatable!
Nice try little man, my turn.
Should I try the sonic blaster?
We've tried everything else.
[Spider-Man thinking]
Ah! The suit!
[groans]
What's happening?
I'm getting weak.
Everything's going dark.
Easiest million we ever made.
This is weird, maybe
this ain't Spider-Man.
How many other wall crawlers
hangin' around here?
Hey, look, how did he do that?
[Mercenary] What's going on?
-[Spider-Man yawns]
-Get him up there.
[Spider-Man] Must have
passed out. Hey!
[groans]
Whoa, my suit has
cruise control.
But your suits, ah!
[man] He just passed out.
[Spider-Man thinking]
Your suits have battery packs
that blow up if they get wet.
Bye bye!
Now to go right to
the source of all my troubles.
[police siren wails]
[Jameson] Thanks to
your photos we've got
the webslinger dead to rights.
[Brock] I told you I
could do the job, JJ.
[Spider-Man] You did
the job all right, on me.
[Brock] Spider-Man?
Think you can hide in some
cockamamie new costume?
I've got nothing to hide,
especially from a couple of
second-rate hacks like you.
Yeah, well, pictures don't lie.
Like you do.
[stammers]
I know what I saw.
You didn't see me
take the Promethium X.
[Brock] Well, who else
could've taken it?
What about the clown in
the rhino costume, punk?
A rhino?
I think that new suit's cutting
off the oxygen to your brain.
If you don't call off
that reward, I'm gonna--
[police officer]
Don't even think about it.
Who needs to think?
[Police Officer]
Hey! Watch it!
Look out!
[Spider-Man thinking] Almost
lost it again back there.
As bad as he was before,
in that suit he's even worse.
[Spider-Man thinking]
What is happening with me?
I gotta get some
questions answered.
[scientist] Well,
here it is, gentlemen.
How do we know
it's the real thing?
We've set up this
special test site,
just to give you
a demonstration.
Promethium X
is the most powerful
fissionable element
ever discovered.
Less than a micro-gram should
give us proof of its power.
Shouldn't we be wearing
protective gear?
A Promethium X doesn't
radiate until it's heated,
that's the beauty of it.
The most powerful fissionable
material in the universe
and you could carry it
around in your pocket.
Now all we need to do is
increase the temperature,
and ignite it.
That choke you have...
It could destroy
this whole planet.
I only handle the best.
Dr. Connors, I need your help.
You're a wanted man,
tell me why I shouldn't call
campus security?
I helped you once when
you were desperate,
I could've turned
you in but I didn't.
What do you want?
It's this suit,
I need it analyzed.
Cut off a piece of
the material, if you can.
What do you mean, if I can?
Go ahead and try.
How did it?
Cut here, quick!
Where did this thing come from?
The Hudson.
It's got cell structure!
The nuclei are even dividing.
That's what I was afraid of.
It's alive isn't it?
As alive as you and me.
Well, doc, what do
all the tests show?
This is truly astounding.
Look, take a single
host organism,
like this one from
a nitrogen based environment.
Now, I'll add a molecule
chain from that suit of yours.
They're bonding.
It's replicating and mutating
the molecular structure
of its own DNA.
It's actually improving
on the host organism.
Host organism?
That's what I am to this thing?
Apparently.
It's a symbian,
an organism that thrives
by bonding with another.
In this case, me.
But not only does
the suit bond,
in time it replaces.
I'd almost be willing
to see if this piece
of material
is a sentient creature.
You mean it thinks?
Where do you think
you're going?
You've got to get
that suit off!
I can't, not yet.
I have some things I have
to take care of first.
[Dr. Connors] Get rid of it!
I need it!
[groans]
It's gone... the man
in a rhino costume.
[groans]
There was a guy
in a rhino suit.
You lied to me!
OK, OK,
it was just some fool
in a bad Halloween costume.
What's the big deal?
I can't have someone
who works for me
coloring the truth
and leaving out facts.
It's against
everything I stand for.
You're history, Brock!
Outta here! Fired!
What? No, no, wait!
I have more pictures.
Out!
Come on, you hate Spider-Man,
both of us do.
I thought you'd be
glad to hear he took
the Promethium X.
JJ, I did it for you.
You did this
for yourself, Brock.
Get me security, I've got
some trash they can throw out.
Because Eddie Brock,
an ex-Bugle reporter withheld
important evidence
in this case,
I must regretfully withdraw
my reward for the capture of
Spider-Man until this matter
has been thoroughly
investigated.
Who is this Eddie Brock?
We have to make sure
that none of this
can be traced back to me.
I've got the perfect device,
and the perfect man to use it.
Spider-Man, everywhere
I turn he's in my way.
He cost me my job,
my reputation,
[sneezes] my health!
My apartment?
[Spider-Man thinking]
Now for a little game
of hide and seek.
I figure Brock's hidden
that film of the rhino
in here somewhere,
and I'm gonna find it.
Come on, Brock, where is it?
Not too hygienic,
you know, but clever.
And now Mr. Brock
will learn a serious lesson
about the dangers of lying.
[man]
You Eddie Brock?
[Brock] Who wants to know?
My boss wants to know.
[Spider-Man thinking]
What's this about?
This is why they
call me The Shocker.
So, very painful, or sort of
painful, it's up to you.
Where are the photos
of the crash site?
What's this, a fight,
and nobody invited me?
You stay out of this?
Reasonable advice.
But I haven't had much
use for reason lately.
Getting rid of you
is gonna be a blast!
[evil laugh]
Rest in pieces, wall crawler.
How about I follow you instead?
All right, Shocker,
which door did you use?
You can confuse my eyes,
but not my spider sense.
Did you take care of Mr. Brock?
No, he got away.
[Spider-Man thinking] Now maybe
I can crawl through
an air vent.
Air vent?
That's the old Spidey talking.
I did smash Spider-Man though.
Oh, well, if it isn't my
old friend Allister Smithe.
How did you get in here?
[Spider-Man]
Since I got my new suit,
I get invited to all
the best parties.
Don't go.
This party's just
getting rolling!
The Promethium!
No kidding.
Shocker, he's got
the Promethium X!
I can see you're all tied up
so I'll be on my way.
Let's see why everybody's
so hot for this little rock.
[electronic beep]
Hmm, basic structure.
Density, molecular weight.
Ah, it looks like it's
heat activated.
Well... what do you know?
What's the matter with you two?
What happened?
Spider-Man took
the Promethium X.
Then you will have
to get it back,
even if you must take
the whole city hostage.
Excellent idea.
[announcement over PA]
[groans]
Who are you?
What do you want?
We got important
business you and I.
What have you done to my son?
Listen and listen well.
This just in,
Astronaut John Jameson
has been kidnapped
from his hospital room.
We go now to
the colonel's father,
J. Jonah Jameson,
with a statement from his
Manhattan home.
Spider-Man, wherever you are,
if you're within
the sound of my voice,
you must contact me.
It's a matter of
life and death.
So now I'm supposed to
come running when you call?
[sighs] This is for John,
old man, not for you.
I'm getting real
tired of cleaning up
your messes, Jameson.
I knew if I tailed you
long enough
somethin' would turn up.
Bet you're plotting
against me with Spider-Man.
John?
First, hand over
the Promethium X.
Not until we see
Colonel Jameson.
Son!
All right, Smithe, you win.
Here it is.
Dad, I knew I
could count on you.
Always, son, always.
Jameson,
untie the colonel and get him
as far away from here
as you can.
I'll guard you
both from the rear.
That's it then, deal's done.
Not quite.
A double cross?
Big surprise.
If you think that's a surprise,
you're in for a real shock.
And I'm gonna tear
you limb from limb.
Oh, I'm all shook up.
Oh, Spider-Man's in trouble,
perfect.
Pathetic.
Can't pull the wool over me!
[grunting]
Come on! Let's get
this over with.
I said come on!
It's payback time, web slinger.
[groans]
I still got business with you.
Forget him,
you're not done yet with me.
Surprised, Shocker?
Let me tell it to you straight.
I am invincible!
Get back here, Shocker!
Shocker!
You can't escape me,
I'll chase you
to the ends of the earth!
Hey, what--
What good are those
blasters to you now?
[mumbles indistinctly]
[groans]
You?
I'm gonna save you for dessert.
[groans]
And you,
you're the main course.
You'll pay for this.
The check's in the mail, baby.
Oh! What are you trying...
No. I give up.
Come on.
You're supposed to be the
good guy, you can't do this!
Why not?
I have the power.
Ah, my Uncle Ben,
he always used to tell me,
with great power comes
great responsibility.
[groans]
I knew you wouldn't.
[screams]
[Spider-Man thinking]
What have I done?
[screams]
What's this costume doing?
Doc Connors was right,
the symbian's taking control.
I gotta get it off.[groans]
Oh, it's too late,
it won't let me.
[church bell rings loudly]
This suit is in pain,
I can feel it, why?
[groans] Sonic vibrations!
Noise makes you crazy,
I should've
guessed that before.
Why didn't I know
your weakness?
Did you block it from my mind
to protect yourself?
Was Connors right?
Stay away from me.
I thought I wanted
what you had to offer,
but I'm not like you, and I
won't let you do this to me.
No!
[church bell continues]
[Peter thinking]
At last, it's over.
I gotta get out of here.
[groans]
I have it!
Now, gentlemen, what am I bid?
Wait a minute, first you
need to prove to us again
that this is the real stuff.
As you wish.
Eh! What are you
trying to pull now?
This Promethium X is almost
completely transmuted
into lead.
How could that have happened?
It appears to be
the nature of Promethium X,
it's radioactive half-life
must be only days.
Why didn't you tell
me this before?
Because you never gave me
an opportunity to study it.
Then it's useless!
He knew it, Spider-Man knew it.
[groans]
Ah!
[growls]
[Venom] Spider-Man!
Enjoy the fame while it lasts!
♪ Spider-Man, Spider-Man ♪
♪ Radioactive Spider-Man ♪
♪ Spider blood, spider blood ♪
♪ Radioactive spider blood ♪
♪ Spider blood ♪
♪ Spider-Man ♪