[theme music playing]
♪ Spider-Man ♪
♪ Radioactive Spider-Man ♪
♪ Spider blood, spider blood ♪
♪ Radioactive spider blood ♪
♪ Spider-Man, Spider-Man ♪
[laughs maniacally]
I don't understand why
you do these things.
It's important that
I convince the press
that I'm public spirited.
They must never suspect
my real occupation.
I don't believe it! Why me?
I know this is a
little sudden, Parker,
but it's a beautiful,
huge apartment,
overlooking Central Park.
But why do you want
me as your roommate?
We hardly know
each other Osborn.
Besides, you're Flash's friend.
Why aren't you rooming with him?
Okay, look.
I just have to get
out of my dad's place,
but he won't pay the
rent unless I get a
roommate who's responsible.
You know, top of the class...
I mean Flash is a fun guy,
but Einstein he's not.
[Peter] Then you
really are serious?
Me? Hardly ever.
But my old man is.
So, for my sake, please say yes.
But how I'm gonna afford it?
All taken care of!
Dear old dad will
pay for everything!
Some deal!
Yeah, he's been
spoiling me ever since
he and my mother got divorced.
He thinks he can buy a good
father-son relationship,
like he can buy everything else
[Peter] Look, I've
gotta think about this.
Yeah, the problem is though,
my dad's here for
the dedication.
And since I'm not privileged
enough to see him every day,
if I don't tell him now,
then the deal's off.
Nothing like giving
a guy plenty of notice.
[camera clicks]
That's Parker.
If he misses a good shot--
We are gathered here today
to begin a great project at ESU.
[microphone feedback]
Our new Criminal
Science building
is about to become a reality.
Thanks to one of New York's
leading philanthropists,
Wilson Fisk!
[clapping]
[Peter thinking]
It would be great
to have my own
place in the city,
closer to campus. I wonder how
Aunt May would take it?
Thank you very much, Mr. Osborn.
It's an honor for me to turn
over this first load of earth,
on the site of what
will soon be the
Fisk School of Criminology.
[high pitched sound]
Dig a hole, Fisk.
Wide enough for your
final resting place!
Huh?
[Kingpin] Together, however,
they make a clear and
unambiguous statement
about the values we as
citizens should support.
-Furthermore--
-[laser blasting]
[crowd screams]
That blasted kid!
[crowd screaming]
[man] Who's that?
[Peter] Just what
the world needs,
another nut in a costume.
Osborn, did you see
what Parker just did?
Hey! Where'd he go?
Get down!
[laser blasting]
[policemen screaming]
Sorry, Charlie!
Spider-Man!
But you're a little
late for Halloween.
Name's Hobgoblin,
and you're right on time,
-for your funeral!
-[laser blasts]
[man] Look out!
[woman] He won't be
a match for Spidey!
[man 2] Man, I hope they
finish each other off!
I want to know who
that madman is!
Why are you after Fisk?
Trust me, it's nothing personal.
Well this is!
You're pathetic! How did you
ever get your reputation?
Must have been the tabloids.
Man, this clown's outmaneuvering
me every step of the way.
How do I nail this
flying lunatic?
[suspenseful music playing]
Whoa! Nosebleed territory!
Why do I get myself into
these things?
Uh-oh.
Enjoying the flight?
Eh, some flight.
No peanuts, no Stallone movie?
I'm outta here!
[Hobgoblin laughs maniacally]
Now to make an easy
spider-landing.
Oh, no! My web
shooters are empty!
Oh! Never done this before.
Only one chance to get it right.
Uh-oh!
Yes!
No!
This might work.
Yeah.
Perfect landing,
just like I planned it.
How do I manage to find
all these nutcases?
Where do they come from?
And how do I get
them to go back?
[Harry] Are you okay, Dad?
Fine, fine.
Yeah, thanks, I'm okay too.
You. Hobgoblin,
you failed me miserably.
[laughs] No, you failed
to tell me
Spider-Man would get involved.
It's just a block in the road,
it does raise my rates though.
You pay up, and I'll take
another shot at Fisk.
No way, Fisk will
be on his guard now.
Why do you wanna
take him out anyway?
What's he got on you.
That's not your business.
None of this is anymore,
you're fired,
and leave me that.
You can't talk to me
like I'm some punk.
Before the wing and the
weapons you were just a punk.
An ambitious hood in a mask.
I made you the Hobgoblin
and now I'm unmaking you.
Don't forget I know
your real identity,
and I've stored it
where it will come out
if anything happens to me.
You owe me, Osborn.
And I'll take the wing
as my down payment.
[Hobgoblin laughs]
[reporter] A Young
Bugle photographer,
Peter Parker of Queens,
pushed Fisk out of harms way.
Oh, good gracious Peter
you could have been hurt.
If I'm to sleep peacefully
at night when you're
living on your own you
must promise to stop
taking all these risks.
Aunt May, I won't move out
if you don't want me too.
No, no, this is something
young people have to do.
As a matter of fact Anna
Watson tells me that Mary Jane
might room with
some of her friends.
Really?
Anna's not too keen on
having that big house
round the corner all to herself.
So, we discussed her
moving in with me.
Well this is perfect,
you'll have someone here to
keep you company and I can go.
Yes, just about perfect.
Ah, I knew you'd understand,
but I want you to
know something,
no matter where I go, I'll
always be here if you need me.
Well, thank you, dear.
Are you ready for dessert?
[Peter] Sure.
[reporter] After his audacious
daylight attack, the person
known only as the Hobgoblin
jetted off into the skies.
[faint music playing]
Parker, I can't
believe your dumb luck.
Come on Flash, back off.
This is the man's
home now, okay?
Hey Pete, you almost missed
our big house warming.
This place, it's incredible.
Well don't just stand there.
So, when do I get
to thank your dad?
Ah, who knows,
he hasn't come by the place yet,
too busy with his
precious work at Oscorp.
Well, got to go take
care of the guests.
Peter, what a beautiful place.
I just hope you two
bachelors don't ruin it
with day glow velvet paintings.
Oh, And I suppose your
place is gonna be
filled with Warhol's.
Please, Hockney's
and Motherwell's.
No offense, but you and
Harry could be busted
any minute by the design police.
Lucky for you I'm here to help.
[Spider-Man theme plays]
Hmm. Big windows.
Perfect for web slinging.
Moving out it could be
the best thing I ever did.
[rocket whooshing]
[lasers fire]
What are your secrets, Fisk?
There's money to be
made from secrets.
[sinister organ music playing]
[dramatic music playing]
Well done.
Not even you can fly high
enough or fast enough
to avoid a trip
to the next world.
[Hobgoblin laughs]
So this is what it's all about.
I didn't think
this place existed.
I thought it was a legend,
like El Dorado or Shangri-La.
A pipe dream followed
by criminal lunatics
to entertain the gullible.
But it's true, isn't it!
There really is one nerve
center that controls
most of the crime
on this planet.
And this is it!
Call off your men, Fisk.
And why should I do that?
Cause you can do just
about anything Fisk,
or should I say Kingpin.
All the more reason
don't you think,
to simply dispose of you.
[laughs]
Aren't you curious
who hired me to wipe you out?
Audacious hey, Smythe?
The man wants to bargain.
The impudence,
he's in no position.
Men, lower your weapons.
What?
Hobgoblin, you amuse me.
Now tell me what
you really want?
Money! [laughs]
A chance to show how
valuable I can be to you,
and most of all, I want this.
[laughs]
Your entertainment value alone
will justify your presence.
But first things first,
the name of your
previous employer.
Osborn.
Norman Osborn.
I must teach him a lesson.
And at the same time,
I'll test your loyalty to me.
If you are to work for me,
you'll need better weaponry,
more in keeping with your
inexplicably bizarre appearance.
Why do you dress that way?
For centuries the
Hobgoblin's been a symbol of
irrational fear and terror.
I want this face to be the
very last thing my enemies see.
[Hobgoblin laughs]
Ugh... the perfect
bachelor mess.
Good thing Aunt May's
not around to see this.
[phone ringing]
Hello,
What!
Harry!
Harry?
Hey, hey,
what's all the racquet?
It's my Aunt May,
she's on her way up.
[doorbell rings]
Worse then that, she's here.
[high pitched sound]
[Peter thinking] That's funny,
Aunt May's never set off
my Spider-Sense before.
Peter! What on earth!
[Hobgoblin laughing]
You! Perfect, I'm getting
two birds with one stone.
[explosion]
[Harry] Peter?
Harry!
Aunt May!
Can you hear me?
[dramatic music playing]
[phone dialing]
I need an ambulance, fast!
[slow dramatic music playing]
Doctor, how is she?
It's a form of seizure,
the mind retreating into
itself under extreme stress.
All we do is give her time.
[Peter thinking] Why do
the people I care about
always get hurt when I'm just
trying to do the right thing.
It happens whether I'm
Spider-Man or Peter,
I just can't seem to win.
First Uncle Ben, now this,
how can I live with myself if
anything happens to Aunt May.
[Keene] He'll be the ruin of us.
He's devious,
a liar,
and entirely too ambitious.
Exactly,
those are the
qualities one needs in
order to advance
in this enterprise.
He reminds me of
myself as a young man.
Perhaps I'll train
him as my protégé.
How touching.
[Hobgoblin] Special
delivery from me.
Welcome to the low
rent district, junior.
[Harry] What do
you want from me?
Your dad's loaded,
if you have to ask.
[grunts]
I am pleased Hobgoblin,
very pleased.
[laughs]
Things went better
then I expected,
I even got a change to
settle an old score,
now about that bonus.
All in good time.
Hey I earned it!
Pay up!
You'll be paid when
I say you will be paid,
you work for me now,
and you must never forget that.
[laughs]
Okay, Kingpin.
If that's the way
you wanna play it.
[computer beeping]
Ah, Norman, glad to see
you so hard at work.
What is it Fisk? I'm a busy man.
Too busy to talk
about your son?
Harry!
What is this, Fisk?
This is what happens
when someone tries
to double cross me.
Hello Osborn,
I found a new job.
[laughs]
Hope you don't mind but I
used your name on my resume.
Isn't life full of surprises.
I was surprised when you
sent the Hobgoblin after me.
I had no idea
you wanted to end my
silent partnership in Oscorp.
But so be it,
All I want now...
are your inventions.
My inventions?
They're my life's work.
You have 24 hours to
sign them over to me.
Do be prompt.
It'll wipe me out!
It is your decision.
Your life's work or your son.
[sad music playing]
[Peter thinking]
Giggling piece of dirt,
I'll rip his.. Mary Jane.
I was worried, I had to come.
Thanks. Has there
been any word from
the police about Harry?
Nothing.
This is all my fault.
There wasn't anything
you could have done.
The Hobgoblin's a lunatic,
attacking people at random.
No, not at random.
He wanted me, or did he?
[Peter thinking] How could
have know I lived there,
and didn't he say something
about two birds with one stone.
Peter?
MJ I've gotta get out of
here for a few minutes.
Can you stay with Aunt May?
Sure, but where--
Osborn, we got to talk.
Talk!
You kidnapped my son!
Kingpin's a
double-crossing snake.
You're a lying opportunist!
[Hobgoblin laughs]
Naturally, but this
time I'm tell the truth,
and I've got a plan.
We can get Fisk together.
What are you suggesting?
You have your
company and your son.
[Osborn] What's in it for you?
I want the Kingpin.
You gotta let me see Mr. Osborn.
I'm his son's roommate.
Wouldn't matter if
you were his mother.
He's not to be disturbed.
If I'm going back there,
I need a better weapon.
I've already given
you what I have.
Come on, Norm, you geniuses
always make one thing
and have a better one
on the drawing boards.
[dramatic music playing]
[buttons beeping]
It goes twice as high
and four times as fast as
your old glider and has a
full complement of missiles,
smart bombs,
and it's even got
a remote control.
[rocket whooshing]
[Hobgoblin] Perfect fit.
[laughs]
I'd know that laugh anywhere.
[action music plays]
[Peter] Different wings,
same jerk.
Well, well, what a perfect
opportunity to test
out my wonderful new toy.
Tell me Spider-Man,
how'd you find me?
I followed the slime trail.
I'm going to enjoy
shooting you down.
Let's see what this
baby can really do.
[rocket whooshing]
[web snapping]
Osborn says these
are smart bombs.
[bombs beeping]
How do I get him now?
That's the mother
of all flying wings.
Time for a little double team.
That wing's got
a mind of it's own.
[sign breaking]
[Hobgoblin laughs]
-[thud]
-Oof!
Hey Spider-Man, how about a
scenic tour of the village.
[action music picks
up pace and tempo]
Just need a little luck,
I might be able to...
Wrong kind of luck!
What a nice surprise,
they are smart bombs.
[explosion]
[Hobgoblin laughs]
[theme music playing]
♪ Spider-Man ♪
♪ Radioactive Spider-Man ♪
♪ Spider blood, spider blood ♪
♪ Radioactive spider blood ♪
♪ Spider-Man ♪