♪ Spider-Man ♪
♪ Radioactive Spider-Man ♪
♪ Spider blood, spider blood ♪
♪ Radioactive spider blood ♪
♪ Spider blood ♪
♪ Spider-Man, Spider-Man ♪
[Spider-Man] New York City.
If only everything down there
was really as peaceful
as it looks from up here.
[honking]
[footsteps]
[electric surging]
[man] Yeah,
hold it right there.
Yeah, like I was saying,
you're gonna love
working down here.
It's cool in the summer
and warm in the winter.
And uh, no office politics.
Well, sounds better
than my last job.
I was in the
television business.
TV really?
Hey my old TV gets
these double images,
you know what I mean.
Hey maybe you could uh...
No. I was a TV executive.
Oh, you're better off
down here.
-[footsteps]
-Holy...
[growling]
[groans]
[dramatic music]
[growling]
Oh! It has got me!
What? Help!
Help!
[tires screeching]
Those eyes, they're after me.
[tires squealing]
[crash]
What's this.
Another satisfied
graduate of New York City
cab driving academy.
Hit the brake.
-Turn, turn.
-[honking]
[tires screeching]
[crashing]
[yelling]
What was that all about?
Red eyes.
Red eyes after me.
Uh huh, and did they belong
to little pink elephants?
No, mister, it was real.
It was real I swear.
Yeah, all right, fine.
Just don't let the cops
blame this one on me, okay.
The red eyes.
Sure, pal.
Whatever you say.
[sirens blaring]
New York City,
never a dull moment.
Well, guess it all
goes with the job.
Peter,
I have a new job for you.
You've always gotten good
shots of Spider-Man right,
let's see what you can
do with The Lizard.
-The who?
-[man] The Lizard, Parker.
If you'd ever get here on time,
maybe you'd know
what was going on.
There've been reports
of a giant lizard
down in the subways.
In this town, who'd notice?
[Brock] I'd notice.
If this weren't serious, Parker,
I wouldn't have
gotten the assignment.
I don't know about that, Brock,
you're just the
reporter I'd send on
a wild goose chase.
It's not a wild goose
chase, smart mouth.
Look, subway repairman missing.
His friend says
The Lizard got him.
Boss, I got those
names of the scientist
who worked with reptiles.
Good, then you can interview
them for background.
Right, closest one's at
Empire State, name's Connors.
Dr. Curt Connors?
[Mr. Robertson] You know him,
Peter?
He's one of my
teachers, Mr. Robertson.
He's an expert in recombinant
DNA and reptile mutagenics.
He's also a genius.
Yeah, yeah, whatever.
You'll be the contact with
Connors from now on, kid.
-But, boss...
-The kid already knows him,
and, besides, do you have any
idea what muto-what its are?
Mr. Jameson, I still think
this whole lizard thing
is just a big hoax.
Parker, the first one
to get a photo
of The Lizard for
my nightly news,
gets a thousand dollar bonus.
Ah, color or black
and white?
[thunder rumbles]
[man] A thousand dollars,
I could put it down
on a new motorcycle,
maybe a car.
Wait till I tell Aunt May.
Hey, pretty lady,
why the frown?
Nothing, Peter, nothing at all.
I Just can't decide what to
make for dinner, that's all.
[Peter] Why does she always
keep things from me?
Look at these bills.
And here I am, thinking of
things to buy for myself.
She's been like a
mother to me for years.
It's time I paid her back.
And if I can't...
A thousand dollar bonus.
Spider-Man will.
[thunder rumbles]
Just once I want an assignment
some place sunny suburb.
Anyway, this lizard thing is
probably just an urban myth.
Wait a minute, looks
like I was myth-taken.
[thunder rumbles]
[Debra] Peter.
Oh no, not Debra Whitman,
the little sister I
never had or wanted.
Since when do you
have night class?
In fact, I've always
thought of you
-as having no class at all.
-Nyuk, nyuk.
It just so happens I've got
something to show Doc Connors.
Oh, really, what?
None of your... hey.
Hmm, that's interesting.
Obviously reptilian
of the Squamata order.
But look at the imprint
left by the heel.
It's an imprint.
So?
Yeah, but look how deep it is.
A lot of weight on it.
Well, maybe it's a
very fat Squamata.
Or maybe, Peter,
it walks on two legs.
I knew that.
You did...
Shh, something's wrong.
You're darn right,
you were suffocating me.
[glass rattles]
[electric buzzing]
Nice time for a brown out, eh?
Hmm, no kidding, the storm
must be causing it.
-[bang]
-Who's there?
Who is it?
No, stay away.
[Debra] Dr. Connors?
-What's wrong?
-No, Debra, wait!
It sounds like he needs help.
[screams]
[growling]
Peter!
Debra, are you all right?
I got the wind
knocked out of me.
[growling]
What's that thing
done to Doc Connors?
Stop! Come back!
[thunder rumbles]
Peter, don't leave
me here alone!
It's all right.
Everything's okay now.
[sighs] You were downright
brave back there.
It was quiet a surprise.
Why, Ms. Whitman, is that
a compliment, from you?
Don't push your luck, Peter.
What was that thing?
And why would it
kidnap Dr. Connors?
[Peter] Dr. Connors,
I'm ready to proceed.
Temperature Alpha,
respiration alpha,
life signs all register
normal, Dr. Connors.
If I'm right, Mickey here
is better than normal.
Look, look, there it is.
A reptiles ability to grow
a new limb in a mammal.
Because of a couple
of micrograms
of reptile DNA and the
Neogenic Recombinator.
Incredible.
No, Peter, this is
just the beginning.
When we do the same
for human beings,
when we can replace
limbs lost in accidents
or during a war,
that will be incredible.
Why would anybody want to
kidnap Doc Connors?
[somber music]
[growling]
Mommy, is Daddy coming home?
I don't know, Billy. I...
[screams]
Stay away, leave us alone.
Easy, Mrs. Connors.
I'm looking for the Professor.
No, I won't let you
hurt my husband.
-Hurt him, I...
-No!
[groans]
No, no, please.
-[growling]
-[groans]
[growling]
You're for real.
Just hold that pose, Smiley.
[growling]
Great, there goes my
thousand dollar photo.
Well, when am I gonna get the
hang of being a superhero
and a photographer
at the same time.
[growling]
Good reflexes,
for a future handbag.
[growling]
Now that you've crawled
out of your sewer,
maybe you'd better
stick around.
Cause I wanna know what
you did with Doc Connors.
[growling]
[gasp]
Now you're
really making me mad.
[groans]
-[crashing]
-[grunts]
[growling]
[boy] Help, Daddy, stop.
Billy.
[thunder rumbling]
[groans]
"Daddy"?
Did I hear right?
Did he say "Daddy"?
Yes, yes, that was Curt.
It all started with a device.
[thunder rumbles]
[woman] Curt called it the
Neogenic Recombinator.
He used it on himself,
as an experiment to
make his arm grow again.
But it turned him into
that, that creature.
Why haven't you told
anybody, the police?
No, they'll think
he's a freak.
They'll hunt him down
and hurt him, or worse.
[sighs] I know how that goes.
But not if I can
reach him first.
I'm so scared.
We'll keep this quiet.
-As long as we can.
-[rustling]
-[footsteps receding]
-Oh-oh.
We're not alone.
When I break this story,
it'll be Pulitzer time.
[yells]
Hang loose, Brock.
That webbing will melt
in a couple of hours.
You can't do this.
I already have, I won't
let you ruin Connors' life.
[distinct yelling]
[woman screams]
[Billy] Mommy. Mommy!
Billy, where's your mom?
Daddy came back and took
her away, down there.
The sewers.
Listen, I'm gonna carry
you to a neighbor's house,
where you'll be safe.
Then I'll go get your mom
and your dad too, okay.
Okay, don't let
anything happen to them.
[woman strains] Let me go!
Let me go!
Ugh, what a slimy mess.
Why can't I be one of those
galaxy hopping superheroes?
Why do I end up in the sewers?
Yuck, ugh.
[gasping and spitting]
You don't find
The Fantastic Four in a sewer,
or the Avengers.
Never have I seen the Avengers
in a sewer.
Or The Defenders.
Well, maybe The Hulk.
Quit grinding, Parker, you know
what's really bothering you.
You're scared.
This lizard creature's
powerful enough
to tear you limb from limb.
But you can't even hurt him.
Because trapped
inside is your friend.
But I have to fight him,
it's the only way to
stop him, to save him.
Well, isn't this
the story of my life.
[Mrs. Connor] Put me down.
Stop, no, don't.
Got to reach her fast.
Whoa, not this fast.
Uh oh. [indistinct]
Time to put on the brakes.
[grunts and groans]
My webbing's losing
its consistency,
I better change
cartridges soon.
Worst part of all this is,
I was the one who helped the
Doc with his experiments.
If it wasn't for me... huh?
Save me.
The missing subway worker.
Was building some
electrical thing,
couldn't do it himself,
needed my help.
But I got weak.
No food, no sleep.
-[sighs]
-[woman yelling]
You'll come back for me, right?
Hey, I'm a hero, remember?
Why did you bring
me here, Curt, why?
So we could be together.
You're still my husband.
I love you.
I want to be with you,
but not like this.
I love you too.
I need you, and I
needed your help.
With this.
I need your hands to
operate it for me.
Mine can't grasp like other
humans with scales.
Wh--What are you going
to do with that?
Don't be afraid, Margaret,
it'll transform you.
You'll be able to heal
any wound,
replace any limb.
First you, then everyone.
Once I connect the
Neogenic Recombinator
to these electrical conduits,
I can reach every
home in the city.
Every man, woman, and child.
I can transform all of them.
No more suffering,
no more pain.
But, Curt, after you
transform everyone,
we'll all be like you.
-Of course.
-I'm the first of a new race.
A better race.
If you're so much better,
why do you need
my hands to help you?
You're not better,
look what you've become.
No, you're twisting things.
I can make people well again.
And I won't stop for anything.
Not even for Billy?
You want him to
be like you too?
My son, I have a son.
Sorry, Doc,
I'm doing this for Billy
as much as for you.
[growls]
[grunts]
His mind's all reptile now.
[growls]
Mrs. Connor,
get away while you can.
He's dangerous.
No, don't touch that thing.
Mrs. Connors, run!
[screams]
Oh, no.
Margaret, I'm sorry.
One chance at this,
or I'm lizard food.
Oh-oh, chow time.
Curt.
[Spider-Man]
Strange, so strange.
A week ago this creature
was a scientist,
my teacher, my friend.
He cared for me and wanted
to help me, just as I do.
And now look at
the both of us,
fighting each other.
Fighting for our lives.
Curt, Spider-Man.
[electric surging]
[gasp]
Curt.
Is he...
He'll be okay.
Oh, thank heavens.
I'll help you carry
him out of here in a second.
But first, I have
to get something.
A thousand dollar
photo, not too shabby.
And what's Eddy Brock
going to end up with,
an exclusive story nobody's
ever going to believe.
I tell you, JJ,
The Lizard is Curt Connors.
I woulda had you
out here earlier
but Spider-Man webbed me.
Dr. Connors is a
respected scientist, Brock.
-[car door closes]
-And Peter Parker already
brought me photos
of The Lizard
earlier this morning.
But I'll show you
The Lizard himself.
You better be right
about this.
Boss, if I'm wrong, I'll eat
today's issue of The Bugle.
J. Jonah Jameson, what
brings you here this morning?
[gasp]
You want it cooked or raw?
Peter,
where did you get this?
I sold an exclusive
photo to the Daily Bugle.
- Oh, dear.
- What's wrong?
Exactly how did you happen
to get this picture?
Well, I um...
- No hemming and hawing.
- Aunt May, I...
You followed Spider-Man
into the sewer, didn't you?
Uh, yeah, right.
It's cold and damp down there.
You probably got germs
incubating even as we speak.
You need some hot soup
and a good long rest.
A nice boy like you taking
pictures in a sewer.
And what if that horrible
Spider-Man had caught you?
[Peter] Aunt May, she'd
never understand.
Spider-Man's already
caught me in his web.
And for better or worse,
he and I are stuck
together, forever.
♪ Spider-Man ♪
♪ Radioactive Spider-Man ♪
♪ Spider blood, spider blood ♪
♪ Radioactive spider blood ♪
♪ Spider-Man ♪