[Narrator] Previously,
onSpider-man,
-[squeaking]
-Oh, no,
-I'm losing my spider powers!
-[whooshing]
You're changing, into
something that won't be human.
-[energy whooshing]
-[explosions booming]
-[whooshing]
-[metallic thudding]
I came to see you,
Professor Charles Xavier.
I'm mutating into
what, I don't know.
-Peter!
-I am Michael Morbius.
-Charmed.
-Is it a date?
You can call it
a date if you want.
Great!
-[machinery clanking]
-Oh no,
-I'm losing it again!
-[web hissing]
I don't know where Peter is.
What do you got in
the purse, honey?
No!
-This does not
-[footsteps tapping]
-belong to you!
-[siren whooping]
-Are you all right?
-You shouldn't be out alone.
How would you like
to keep me company?
Felicia, I'm really sorry
I missed our-
Date?
Maybe we can have
dinner tonight?
Felicia is having
dinner with me tonight.
-Oh.
-Ciao, Parker.
Yeah, ciao.
Please help me.
What took you so long
to call me for help?
I had to be reminded I
need to turn to my friends.
-[sizzling]
-[theme music]
-♪ Spider-man, Spider-man ♪
-[whooshing]
-♪ Radioactive Spider-man ♪
-[thudding]
-♪ Spider-man, Spider-man ♪
-[wooden crashing]
-♪ Radioactive Spider-man ♪
-[shutter clicking]
-[explosions booming]
-♪ Spider-man, Spider-man ♪
-♪ Radioactive ♪
-[explosions booming]
-♪ Spider-man ♪
-[whirring]
[explosion booming]
[gas whooshing]
-[doors crashing]
-♪ Spider blood, spider blood ♪
♪ Radioactive spider blood ♪
-[whooshing]
[weapon booming]
-[clicking]
-[web hissing]
-[missiles whooshing]
-[explosion booming]
-[weapons zapping]
[growling]
-♪ Spider-man, Spider-man ♪
-[slamming]
I've been racing for
my life, racing against time,
but now, there's
someone who can
stop the mutation that's
eating away at me!
She's been working on the cure,
and now she says,
she may have found it!
-[alarm bell ringing]
-Huh?
It's possible that this
is some kind of inner
city midnight ski team.
-Move it!
-[doors slamming]
-But I don't think so!
-[tires screeching]
-[engine revving]
-[whooshing]
[tires squealing]
[engine revving]
[thudding]
Look out!
[wooden crashing]
[metallic ripping]
-Come on, let me go!
-Party's over for you,
crash dummies!
Oh, feels like I'm getting
a massage by Wolverine!
-From the inside!
-[truck horn honking]
[tires screeching]
-[metallic crashing]
-[thudding]
-[groaning]
-[water splashing]
What are you stopping for?
Check it out!
Spider-man don't look too good!
-Hey, if we ice him,
-[guns clicking]
we could be heroes!
What's the matter, you sick?
Maybe you need to
get your shots!
[gasps] I can't believe it,
after all the
super-villains I've fought,
in the end I'm
gonna be ventilated
-by a bunch of street hoods?
-[guns clicking]
Let's nail this
-son of a gun!
-[guns clicking]
-[sirens whooping]
-Freeze!
-[footsteps tapping]
-[grunting]
-Talk about dumb luck!
-[shouting]
-There he is, there he is!
-[thumping]
Who says cops are never
around when you need them?
Hey Spider-man!
He's webbing off!
-He's getting away!
-Stop!
[keyboard clacking]
[clattering]
[gasping]
Oh, do you ever use a door?
Uh-uh, don't believe in 'em!
-[grunting]
-Are you all right?
No, pain in my sides!
Tell me some good news!
-Look at this, my new serum
-[whooshing]
seems to reverse
the mutation process!
The cells in your blood sample
are returning to normal!
-So you found a cure?
-Maybe.
-They're normal now,
-[glassy tapping]
but who knows what
will happen in time.
-We have to wait.
-I can't wait!
Doc Conner said I could mutate
into some monster any day now!
But if my calculations
are wrong,
this serum could remove
your spider powers,
or destroy you,
is that what you want?
What I want is to be
my old self again!
You must give me
that new serum!
I can't, not in good
conscience!
Conscience?
Your conscience didn't keep you
-[liquid splashing]
-from using an untested formula
on your boyfriend,
Sergei Kravinoff!
-And when a toxin in
-[thudding]
the serum turned him into
that madman Kraven the Hunter,
you found a cure,
and made him normal again!
If anyone can help me,
you can!
Now please, hand me that
serum, or I'll find it myself!
Wait, you're not
-being rational!
-[equipment clattering]
-Just give me what I need!
-[glass shattering]
Stop, Spider-man, don't!
Look at yourself,
you're acting like a monster
you don't want to become!
You're right, what am I doing?
-[thudding]
-[door clattering]
No more violence!
Here, take it.
I'm sorry, forgive me.
No apologies, not after all
you did for me and Sergei.
But, as your friend,
I'm warning you.
Taking this serum
could be a big mistake!
-I'll be careful, I promise.
-Spider-man, freeze!
-[weapons whooshing]
-No, don't hurt him!
[whooshing]
-I'm glad Doc Conners is
-[footsteps tapping]
leaving the lab open
in the evenings,
but if you go back in tonight,
you'll be there til dawn!
-Of course.
-[gasps] Michael,
you've already worked on
your neogenics experiment
for 24 hours straight!
[sighs] Don't you ever sleep?
Not when I compete.
While the rest of you snore,
I shall leap ahead.
Well, I'm not gonna [yawns],
pass out into a Petri dish,
I'm going home to bed.
-Thanks for dinner.
-Sleep well, Debra.
Sleep the sleep of
the dearly departed.
I can understand Dr. Crawford
-being cautious about
-[door clicking]
this serum, what if it makes
me lose my powers, or worse?
I think I'll see what it does
-to my blood, outside
-[cork popping]
-my body first.
-[liquid gurgling]
-[glass breaking]
-What was that?
[hinges creaking]
-Better not take any chances.
-[lock clicking]
-[test tube clinking]
-[door clanking]
So that was you, Mickey?
Your table manners
are atrocious.
[cage door thumping]
-Well, back to [grunts]...
-[lockers clattering]
It hurts more than before!
Well that's all
for tonight, folks.
[latch clicking]
[door thumping]
[door creaking]
What are you up
to, Peter Parker?
Amazing!
-[clicking]
-Personal science log
entry 814, according
to computer analysis,
-[computer chittering]
-Parker's sample of engineered
DNA might give a person
tremendous power!
This brilliant work will
win Parker the job as
Conner's research assistant,
unless I figure out
how he did this!
Nothing must stop
me from beating him!
[footsteps echoing]
-Oh!
-[spider chittering]
[footsteps tapping]
[door clattering]
Hello?
[hinges squeaking]
Hello, is anybody here?
Hello?
-[scuffling]
-Hey, mmm!
-Michael!
-You were expecting
maybe, Bela Lugosi?
Very funny!
See if you were expecting this!
But why go to all the
-trouble to set this up?
-It was no trouble!
-I borrowed--
-You mean, pilfered.
Borrowed, the equipment
from Dr. Conner's lab.
I will return it by
the time he's back.
Is this an actual
neogenic device?
One of them.
-[metallic clacking]
-[machinery whirring]
-[electronic beeping]
-And, the school is kind
enough to supply the power,
without their
knowledge, of course.
Doesn't that make you
feel just a little guilty?
Not at all!
This school will benefit
if we get the grant money!
Wouldn't it be easier to
work in the school's lab?
Why all this secrecy, Michael?
Because in America those who
succeed must have an edge!
I-I didn't realize
winning that research job
was so important to you.
You are wealthy, you do
not know the poverty,
the suffering I have seen!
-[bats squeaking]
-My village was a
beautiful place
before the appearance
of a mysterious virus.
Now, it is being destroyed.
It has no one of wealth, no
one of privilege to rescue it!
I promised my countrymen,
that I would learn in America,
and be a success,
then, one day,
I would return with a cure!
I cannot fail them.
Michael.
-I had no idea.
-[bat screeching]
-[screaming]
-A bat!
-Yes, uh,
-[bat chittering]
I'm studying them.
This one must have
gotten loose.
-[bat chittering]
-I suspect that bats
carry and spread
the horrible disease
that threatens my people, but,
-[cloth rustling]
-these are all healthy.
What kind are they?
Vampires.
-Vampires?
-[metallic clattering]
-Don't they feed on--
-Yes [chuckles],
but of small animals
only, not people,
[chuckles] like in the movies.
Relax, my princess, I would
never let anything harm you.
You, I believe, Michael.
-[bats screeching]
-It's them I don't trust.
[crickets chirping]
[Peter] Mary Jane!
I feel like a heel, for not
having called her all week.
But what can I say?
"Hi, let's have a relationship.
By the way, I'm
turning into a mutant!
Next time you see me I might
look like your last nightmare."
Hey, isn't that Peter Parker?
Peter!
Hmm, guess he
didn't hear you, MJ.
Or he didn't want to hear me.
I think he's been
avoiding me, Liz.
If a man avoids a
major babe like you,
it can only mean one thing.
-What?
-He isn't human anymore.
[Mary-Jane] Yeah, right.
-[clicking]
-Personal science log,
entry 827, getting nowhere.
-All my attempts to trace
-[computer chittering]
the origin of this DNA
have proven negative!
I have got to know
how Parker created it!
I will expose the last of
this mutated plasma sample
to the neogenic process,
to disassemble its components.
-It is a dangerous step,
-[wings fluttering]
-but there is so little time.
-[switches beeping]
I am now activating the
neogenic recombinater,
-[recombinater humming]
-and I'm about to attempt
-[zapping]
-to mathematically analyze the
-[bat chittering]
-mutations at the core,
in the genetic
structure of the blood.
-These numbers,
-[computer beeping]
they make no sense!
-What is causing, no, no!
-[screeching]
-[hissing]
-Get out of there!
[bat chittering]
[mumbles] no, let
go, [mumbles]!
My hand, ah!
[bat screeching]
-The pain, oh!
-[clattering]
-[thunder crackling]
-[bat chittering]
[eerie crackling]
-[whooshing]
-My pain's gone
for the moment!
How can I live
without web slinging?
-[whooshing]
-[thudding]
But tonight just exercise,
no crime fighting, the
pain's too unpredictable.
Hey Bruce, what do you think?
It's not wrong for me to
want to keep my powers is it?
Knew you'd agree.
Personal science log.
The bite from the bat somehow
made me feel stronger.
I feel energy,
surging through me!
I can hear every
heartbeat around me!
-And I can defy gravity!
-[whooshing]
-[gasping]
-[chuckles] Incredible!
No!
My face, skin!
Translucent!
Basal structure distorted!
-[footsteps tapping]
-I, have got to reverse this!
There is something else,
-I feel a hunger!
-[whooshing]
Dr Crawford tries to
help me, I run away!
Just like I run away
from Mary-Jane.
-Do we sense a pattern
-[siren howling]
here, Bruce?
I finally figured out
what I'm mutating into.
A real jerk.
[whooshing]
[leaves rustling]
[hissing]
No, no!
[whooshing]
-[thumping]
-[grunting]
[hissing]
Please!
Don't!
Thanks for listening,
I know what I have to do now!
-[patting]
-I'm gonna go back to
Dr. Crawford's so she can
finish her tests,
and I'm gonna spend
-more time with MJ.
-[whooshing]
I need her now more than ever.
Wonder if she's still
-on campus?
-[whooshing]
[screaming]
[groaning]
Somebody call an ambulance!
This guy looks really sick!
Now I know what this hunger is!
Like the vampire bat whose
genes I have inherited,
I hunger for plasma, I
took it through my hands!
-I could feel it coursing,
-[sucker lips smacking]
through his skin,
right into my fingers!
And as repulsive as it
was, I must have more.
[whooshing]
[boots thumping]
-[gasping]
-[snarling]
[footsteps pounding]
-[screaming]
-[thudding]
-[hissing]
-Please, don't, no!
-[screaming]
-[thudding]
-Back off!
-[thumping]
-[grunting]
-What do you think
you're up to, creep?
-Leave me alone, stay away!
-[whooshing]
That weirdo can fly?
Where'd that refugee
from The Rocky Horror
-[whooshing]
-Picture Showgo?
[Spidey senses ringing]
-[thudding]
-Whoa!
-[scuffling]
-[whooshing]
-[thumping]
You're strong!
-[thudding]
-[crunching]
Good thing you don't
have my spider agility!
-The pain!
-[siren howling]
-Not now!
-[grunting]
No!
[hissing]
[grunting]
The pain is excruciating!
-[hissing]
-No, I cannot!
[gasps] He's gone!
He had me totally at his mercy!
But he chose not to harm me.
Who was he?
How would I even
begin to find out?
Huh, what's this doing here?
-[clicking]
-[Morbius] I have got to know
how Parker created it!
-[clicking]
-[tape squealing]
-The bite from the bat,
somehow made me feel stronger.
Now I know what this hunger is!
Like the vampire bat whose
genes I have inherited,
I hunger for plasma!
-[clicking]
-Michael Morbius?
Messing with a stolen
sample of my blood?
-I never should have left
-[fist thudding]
it at ESU, now
Morbius is in the same
neogenic nightmare I'm in!
-[whooshing]
-If I can't save myself,
at least I can try to save him.
Why is it that
everything I touch,
everything that touches me,
-is poisoned?
-[footsteps tapping]
Whatever happened to Morbius,
it didn't happen here.
[footsteps tapping]
-[whooshing]
-[thudding]
His dorm room is normal too.
But he had to make his
transformation somewhere.
[webs hissing]
-[whooshing]
-[crickets chirping]
-Where could he be?
-[thudding]
And what's his next move?
Where would I go if I were him?
In a way I am him,
so how do I feel?
Deep inside, I wish I had
someone close to talk to.
Someone to help
me get through it.
Morbius must want the same.
[footsteps tapping]
-[birds chirping]
-Felicia!
Uh, I'm really
sorry I missed our--
Date?
-It's okay Parker.
-Well, maybe we can
-have dinner tonight?
-Felicia's having dinner
with me tonight.
-Oh.
-Ciao,Parker.
Sure, ciao.
Goodbye, Parker.
[Peter] Felicia, Morbius
will go to Felicia!
[doorbell ringing]
-[door clattering]
-Parker!
-You look terrible!
-[pants] Has Michael
-been here?
-Not tonight.
Do come in.
Something's happened
to Michael,
you've gotta keep
away from him!
What are you talking about?
Felicia, I know it
sounds weird,
but you've absolutely got
to stay away from him!
-He's dangerous!
-I never would have
believed it Parker, I thought
you were bigger than this!
[Peter] What are
you talking about?
You're jealous!
-What?
-You've come here
to try to scare me into
not seeing Michael!
You must be crazy to
think I'd fall for this!
-Now get out!
-But Felicia!
Get out before I
call the police!
[wooden slamming]
Oh, of all the nerve!
[wind howling]
Felicia...
[gasping]
[screaming]
You must help me, please!
-[clattering]
-[gasping]
-[glass shattering]
-Uh!
I hunger...
No, never hurt you...
-[whooshing]
-[thudding]
-[crashing]
-[scuffling]
-[door clattering]
-Michael, you need help!
How do you know?
-[thudding]
-[grunting]
-[thumping]
-Morbius!
-[whooshing]
-Come back!
He's not as strong as before.
Maybe he's getting weak
from lack of plasma!
I hope that'll even the odds!
I need all the help I can get!
[whooshing]
-[groaning]
-Morbius, wait!
[whooshing]
He's headed back to
his feeding ground!
The university!
[whooshing]
Feel so weak!
I need more plasma!
-[whooshing]
-[thudding]
[grunting]
-[elbow thudding]
-[both screaming]
-[thudding]
-[grunting]
-I'll feed on you!
-You wanna feed on me?
You don't know where I've been!
[Michael screaming]
[whooshing]
Michael!
-[webs creaking]
-[thudding]
-[Michael groaning]
-[thumping]
-[eerie shrieking]
-Incredible!
He's completely normal again!
-The sun must have done it!
-Hey!
What have you done to
-[holster clattering]
-that kid?
[whooshing]
Stop!
[grunts] Spider-man,
[grunts], don't,
don't hurt me...
I won't hurt you, Michael.
I won't hurt anyone anymore.
You've helped me
make my decision.
I'm going to take
Dr. Crawford's serum.
[Felicia] Please,
I'm here to see
the patient, Michael Morbius.
[eerie crackling]
[hissing]
[footsteps tapping]
[whooshing]
-[curtains rustling]
-[wind howling]
He's... gone!
[car horns honking]
Felicia...
[whooshing]
-[electronic chirping]
-[dial clicking]
-[gasping]
-Oh, no!
[Nurse] He couldn't
have left on his own,
-he was comatose!
-So somebody took him?
How? Not through the window,
we're on the sixth floor!
Wait, that'd be no
problem for Spider-man!
He put Michael here
in the first place!
What if he's kidnapped him?
[Man] Put out an APB,
Spider-man's gone too far!
-[clattering]
-[keypad beeping]
[telephone ringing]
-Yes?
-Sergei?
At first, the serum seemed
to make the cells normal,
but, just now, they
mutated like crazy!
If Spider-man takes it,
it'll change him
almost immediately!
-[crickets chirping]
-[grunting]
-[glass shattering]
-[thudding]
I thought that the serum
-[moist crackling]
-was going to help me,
but the pain,
it's excruciating!
[screaming]
[cloth ripping]
No, no!
[theme music]
♪ Spider-man, Spider-man ♪
♪ Radioactive Spider-man ♪
♪ Spider blood, spider blood ♪
♪ Radioactive spider blood ♪
♪ Spider-man ♪