[Announcer] Previously
onSpider-Man.
[Spider-Man] Hey! [screams]
[Spider-Man thuds]
I'm losing my spider-powers!
Because of Spider-Man,
you've failed, Kingpin.
[Kingpin grunts]
With my Insidious Six,
Spider-Man is finished!
[man] Greetings from
the Kingpin, Chameleon.
A helicopter will
land in the main yard
it will take you to freedom.
Welcome, my Insidious Six.
We're sure to
defeat Spider-Man.
[Spider-Man] I can't find
a trace of them anywhere,
no bank robberies,
no jewel thefts.
No, not again!
[Spider-Man yelling]
I keep losing my powers.
Can I help you?
Peter collapsed on the street.
Good heavens!
Take me to him.
Aunt May!
If you want to see
your Aunt May again.
Aunt May.
You poor dear.
Ready for the end,
my pretty?
[laughs maniacally]
♪ Spider-Man ♪
♪ Radioactive Spider-Man ♪
[upbeat guitar music]
♪ Spider blood, spider blood ♪
♪ Radioactive spider blood ♪
[upbeat guitar music]
♪ Spider-Man ♪
Are you okay in here,
Mrs. Parker?
I'm fine.
But is there any news
about Peter's condition?
It's serious,
but he's getting good
treatment from Dr. Octavius and
his people.
Time to take your medicine,
you fly-eating fool,
and my shock therapy's just
what the doctor ordered.
[barrel rattles]
[Spider-Man] If I thought
it would bring back
my spider powers,
I'd be tempted,
but since the attending
physician is Doc Ock,
I'd better steer clear.
[arms smashing]
-[holocubes rattling]
-My holocubes!
I told you to store
them somewhere else.
[lasers blasting]
[Spider-Man] Lucky for me
I have a little bit of
my spider agility left.
Mysterio's virtual
reality technology...
Amazing.
What is wrong with you,
Spider-Man?
Why do you hide behind
these silly tricks?
Why do you not fight us?
[Spider-Man] For one simple
reason without my powers,
I'm as phony as this jungle.
I still got to avoid
the wild animals though
and that includes rhinos.
[grunts]
Scorpions.
And especially octopi.
What a disappointment.
I had wanted a much
tougher battle.
[Spider-Man] All I
want are my powers back
so I can rescue Aunt May.
Gentlemen, I must
congratulate you.
You've justified my faith
in your combined abilities.
Kingpin, Silvermane
is on line two.
Kingpin, the crime
lords have been patient,
but your failure to
squash Spider-Man
forces me to act
on their behalf.
Alistair, patch our
friend Silvermane
into the video
from the warehouse.
What's this?
You've actually
caught the vermin?
You see it with your own eyes,
assuming they have not
failed you yet, old man.
It seems that
congratulations are in order.
The crime lords
will be pleased
to learn that you've fulfilled
their request.
I captured Spider-Man,
not at anyone's request,
but because he is my enemy,
and I always
eliminate my enemies.
It is time to proceed.
Unmask him.
Doctor, the honors are yours.
[arm rattling]
[Peter] No!
[dramatic music]
Spider-Man is Peter Parker?
Well, so, Peter Parker
is the face
behind the Spider-Man mask.
Yes, it all makes sense now.
[chair rattles]
[Spider-Man] I've lost.
Even worse, I failed Aunt May.
[Mysterio] I say
we destroy him now!
Your mind is as empty as that
fishbowl you cover it with.
Can you not see the truth?
He is not Spider-Man.
I'm not?
Think of his miserable
performance here tonight.
The last time I fought
Spider-Man he was formidable,
powerful, agile,
almost invincible.
[metal clangs]
This time he was ridiculous.
Wait a minute, I get it.
You couldn't find the real
Spider-Man so you put on
a cheap Halloween costume?
Right.
Sure can't trick you guys.
[Shocker] What do you
take us for, fools?
I'm shocked, and
you're going to be too!
-[beam squeals]
-[Peter thuds]
What'd you ruin my blast for?
I did not want you to
hurt the lad, Shocker.
I only wish all my students
were as resourceful.
Thanks, I guess.
The truth is, Parker,
if you are really concerned
about your aunt's safety,
you can guarantee
it by leading us--
To the real Spider-Man?
You always were a fast learner.
It seems my congratulations
were premature, Kingpin.
We crime lords asked you
to destroy Spider-Man,
and instead you
kidnap an old lady
and strong-arm
her weak nephew.
Pathetic!
To think I used to admire you.
[monitor buzzes]
[Kingpin grunts]
[statue crumples]
Hammerhead, Kingpin has failed.
The time to take
him down is now.
We got the firepower.
Kingpin don't stand a chance.
The crime lords are
going to hit me,
but I will hit them first,
and thanks to my Insidious Six,
I will hit them harder.
Now pay attention, all of you.
[Peter] Wish I knew who
they're listening to
on those headsets.
Who's their leader,
and what does he
have in store for me?
Aunt May.
Oh, Peter,
I've been so worried.
The doctor says I had a virus.
Don't worry, ma'am,
with Dr. Octavius
your nephew's in the
very best of hands.
[Peter] Yeah, all six of them.
I do not want you
to worry anymore.
I will call a cab
to take you home.
Leave him to us and
he will be fine.
And don't worry,
Aunt May, just go home.
I can't, not without
doing this first.
Stay healthy.
I'll do my best.
[Mysterio] I thought
she'd never leave.
Now remember, Parker,
if you don't lead
us to Spider-Man,
we'll go after her again.
This time she'll need
the hospital bed.
[dramatic music]
[tires squealing]
Hey, buddy,
where do you think
you're going?
Anywhere I want, punk.
[Henchman]
Oh, Mr. Hammerhead, sir.
I didn't realize it was you.
Hammerhead,
what are you doing here?
What's going on?
The fat man beat
us to the punch.
We got to get you
out of here fast.
-[helicopter whirs]
-[dramatic music]
Security alert, all floors!
We're under attack!
And now it's time
to pay the piper.
[helicopter whizzes]
-[Rhino grunts]
-[wall crackles]
[men screaming]
[Scorpion] Go, go, go!
[explosion thunders]
Silvermane!
[Shocker] Your
hide belongs to us.
We got an armored
car in the basement.
Thank you for the assistance,
Hammerhead.
[elevator whirs]
Hey, I thought you said we
were going to the basement!
You also thought you
were a match for Kingpin.
On both counts, you were wrong.
This is The Chameleon.
I've got him.
[explosion booms]
-[guards yelling]
-[dramatic music]
[helicopter screeching]
[dramatic music]
Thank goodness
you escaped, sir!
No thanks to your incompetence.
Get the word to the others,
the attack on
Crime Central is off.
Kingpin is too powerful.
Now get out of my sight,
you useless dunderheads.
[Guard] Yes, sir!
[Silvermane chuckles]
[helicopter screeches]
Ah, Silvermane, so
glad you could join us.
[Bellhop] Coats, gentlemen?
No, thanks, I already got one.
And thankfully, it'll keep
this costume hidden.
I'm only going to get one
chance to trick these guys
into letting me escape,
and I've got to make it count.
[dramatic music]
What time do you usually
meet with Spider-Man?
Midnight, on the roof.
Why here?
Why this roof?
Well, it's big.
He can see if I'm alone or not.
He doesn't really trust me.
Why does he meet
with you at all?
I think he likes to see
his picture in the paper.
He needs all the
PR he can get, right?
[helicopter screeches]
[Mysterio] All set.
Since my number-one student
says Spider-Man is
due at midnight,
it's time I gave
myself some elbow room.
You really think
he's going to show up
with the six of you standing
around like lawn furniture?
[Mysterio] Thanks
to my technology
we'll get the drop on him.
[laughs maniacally]
[Peter] Thanks to
your technology,
I'll get the drop on
you, laughing boy.
-[cube hums]
-What the?
What's that?
[missile whooshes]
[explosion thunders]
[Mysterio] Get up,
you Neanderthals!
He must have gotten ahold
of one of my holocubes.
No geek makes a fool
out of the Rhino.
[Peter] Luckily,
I don't have to.
These holocubes can
do the job for me.
-[cubes whooshing]
-[Rhino yelling]
Time to give an
award-winning performance.
Huh?
Look out, Spider-Man,
it's an ambush!
[Shocker] Shut up!
-[Peter grunts]
-[dramatic music]
[Peter] Shocker's blast
should have creamed me,
but it didn't.
That can only mean one thing,
my spider-powers
must be returning.
Oops, but they're not
back 100%.
[Shocker] Hey, fly-eater,
what happened to the kid?
Did he go splat, or what?
I took care of that
snitch, Parker,
and now, I'm going
to take care of you.
Right.
For starters, I might just
drown you in nervous sweat.
The best seats
in the city, as promised.
Once you've witnessed
Spider-Man's demise,
you will inform
your fellow crime lords
that I will be taking
over your territory.
Never!
Perhaps a seat even
closer to the action
will change your mind.
[dramatic music]
[Silvermane] Help!
[Peter] Hey, who's the old man?
Someone else who was
injudicious enough
to have crossed us.
[metal rattles]
[webbing whooshes]
Please help me.
I hadn't realized we were
fishing for spiders,
eh, Smythe?
No!
What are you doing?
Well, you did ask
for help, right?
Silvermane and
Spider-Man, allies?
[webbing whooshes]
[Silvermane grunts]
[Spider-Man] Smooth.
Just the way I planned it.
Chameleon, Mysterio,
Rhino use the fire escape.
The rest of you, down
through the building.
[door creaks]
[dramatic music]
[Spider-Man] So,
why'd you get invited
to this little party?
I'm very wealthy.
They said they were
holding me for ransom.
You've gotta hand
it to those guys,
they've never met
a crime they didn't like.
Stay here 'til I come back.
If I come back.
Got you, web-head.
[Spider-Man] Calm down,
Rhino, it's me, the Chameleon.
I'm only looking this way
so I can get close enough
to grab the old man.
I wish I could think up
brilliant plans like that.
[Spider-Man] You don't have to.
You can catch Spider-Man
and the old man yourself.
Look.
[Rhino roars]
-[metal rattles]
-[boxes thudding]
[Shocker] Rhino, you clown.
Your horn just ripped
my electro-suit!
What's wrong with you?
It wasn't my fault.
Chameleon told me to.
Make a fool out of me,
will you?
Think I'm stupid, do you?
[Spider-Man] Our playmates
are busy, let's go!
My spider-sense, it's back.
Whoops.
-Wait here.
-What?
But!
[webbing whooshing]
[Spider-Man] I just
toss out the garbage.
-[Doc Ock screaming]
-[glass shattering]
Oh no, I'm losing it again.
Come on,
let's get out of here before
the six stooges return.
[dramatic music]
Shocker, get them!
[Spider-Man] Peek-a-boo.
[Shocker grunts]
[Shocker] Blast you, rhino!
The rip in my suit,
water's getting in.
I'm going to blow up!
[tower booms]
[Spider-Man] Whoa, talk
about wearing flashy clothes.
[Shocker] My suit is gone.
My beautiful suit.
Blast you all!
What's going on out there?
Report, report!
[webbing whooshes]
[Spider-Man] You know,
I've never been one
to seek out the spotlight.
Sorry about this,
but if you say
ho-ho-ho real loud,
there's less chance
you'll get stuck.
Tempus fugit and your time
has run out, Spider-Man!
[Spider-Man] No way
I can defeat Doc Ock now.
Wait, maybe I can get
Scorpion to lend me a tail.
[tail thwacks]
[Smythe] It's no good.
We've got to land.
I'm heading back to base.
[Kingpin] No, no, you can't!
I won't let Spider-Man
defeat me again!
Go back!
[helicopter whirring]
[acid splashes]
[Spider-Man] Ouch,
I'd hate to see
the repair bill on that.
Can't you work with anybody
coordinated to work with?
Scorpion, you
malodorous bungler!
People are always doing that.
I hate to be called names!
[arm whacks]
[Spider-Man] Scorpy, you
going to take that abuse
from a six-armed freak?
Never!
[Scorpion grunts]
[Spider-Man]
This is my cue to skidoo.
Scorpion, you have
made the big mistake
of making me angry!
[Spider-Man] Blessed
are the peacemakers.
Oh, sorry, children, I only
bring presents on Christmas.
[Spider-Man]
Good, you're all right.
Thank you, Spider-Man.
Not only did you save me
many dollars in ransom,
but you've enhanced
my reputation as well.
Bye, Santa.
[Spider-Man] Not bad.
Aunt May's safe and I saved
a kindly, sweet old man too.
He must be annihilated.
Kingpin is nothing but a plague
upon the city of New York.
He must be eradicated!
[Spider-Man]
Ah, at last I can go home
like a normal wall-crawler
and get some sleep.
[Scorpion]
So, what do we do now?
The Kingpin's promised
the world,
but he ain't delivered.
He's nothing but
a bag of hot air.
I'm out of here.
I feel that there are
more verdant pastures
to be explored.
No, you can't leave!
I command you to stop!
Command this, windbag.
Now Silvermane will rally
the crime lords against you.
You've dug yourself
an awfully deep grave
this time.
This is only
a temporary setback.
In the end, Silvermane will be
the one to occupy that grave.
-[birds chirping]
-[light music]
Felicia, I'm really
sorry I missed our--
Date?
It's okay, Parker.
Well, maybe we can
have dinner tonight.
I am afraid Felicia's having
dinner with me tonight,
-and for the rest of the week.
-Oh.
Look, we've got to run.
Michael's taking me
to a science exhibit.
He makes everything
seem so interesting.
And, he thinks enough of
me to show up on time.
Ciao,Parker.
Yeah, sure, ciao.
Good-bye, Parker.
[Peter] Unbelievable.
Peter!
Dr. Octavius let me go early.
Bless his heart.
He did such a good job
taking care of you.
He did a job on me all right.
Well, you look
pretty good to me.
Mary Jane!
Don't tell me you
were worried too?
Of course I was worried, Peter,
about your aunt.
Stay loose, tiger.
[upbeat music]
[Spider-Man] Come on, doc,
my powers came back,
and I feel great.
How bad can
the test results be?
This bad.
The mutagenic factor in
your blood has undergone
another transformation.
[Spider-Man] Did you say
mutagenic, as in mutant?
I'm afraid that's right.
As near as I can figure,
whatever turned
you into Spider-Man
was not a one-time process.
It was just the beginning.
The beginning?
Of what?
You're still changing,
and it's accelerating,
so while I can't tell
you exactly what your DNA
is transforming you into,
one thing's already clear,
it won't be human.
[upbeat guitar music]
♪ Spider-Man ♪
♪ Radioactive Spider-Man ♪
[upbeat guitar music]
♪ Spider blood, spider blood ♪
♪ Radioactive spider blood ♪
♪ Spider-Man ♪