[upbeat rock music]
♪ Spider-Man ♪
♪ Radioactive Spider-Man ♪
♪ Spider blood
Spider blood ♪
♪ Radioactive spider blood ♪
♪ Spider blood
Spider blood ♪
♪ Radioactive spider blood ♪
[explosions booming]
[growling]
♪ Spider-Man ♪
[dramatic music]
[Anastasia Hardy]
And this could prove to be
one of the most
dramatic developments
in the history
of medical technology.
The Hardy Foundation
is now pleased to present
Dr. Michael Pingree
and his argon matrix laser.
[crowd applauds]
The argon matrix laser works
on a sub-molecular level,
which allows us to control
the type of atomic nuclei
the laser will affect.
In this case, I have
designated that the laser cut
only inorganic matter,
the metal,
leaving the organic matter,
the pumpkin, untouched.
This laser could save
millions of lives
by targeting certain types
of tumors and tissue.
The laser can be programmed
with pinpoint accuracy.
Fools!
You are applauding
the wrong person.
[frightened screams and shouts]
I have a feeling this isn't
going to be termites.
Doc Ock!
Not him again!
[groaning]
We got to get out of here!
Not you, Parker,
you stay and get pictures!
I'm staying, all right,
but I might be
too busy to take pictures.
[Doctor Octopus]
I can't let you and Mrs. Hardy
take all the credit
for my invention.
We both worked on it, Otto!
Pingree, you were
merely my assistant.
And as for Mrs. Hardy,
she owes me a debt
that I've come to collect.
[Spider-Man] Sorry, Ock,
this time your reach
exceeds your grasp.
[groans]
[grunts]
This laser will heal
one problem I've had
for much too long--
the scourge of Spider-Man.
Noo!
Huh? Well, what do you know!
I forgot that it was set so it
wouldn't cut organic matter.
Too bad Dock Ock's
tentacles are inorganic!
-Aah!
-[grunts]
[groans]
[Doctor Octopus]
Out of my way!
[screams]
Ohh! Spider-Man!
[Spider-Man]
Are you all right?
Yes, but he--
he's out of his mind!
[Spider-Man] Ock,
you've really made me mad.
You're not getting away,
not this time!
[groans]
That's the medical lab!
If they damage any of
the research material in there,
it'll take years to replace!
Why couldn't Spider-Man
just let Octavius escape?
Because Spider-Man's
a glory hog
who never thinks
of the consequences
of what he's doing!
[grunts]
[Doctor Octopus]
No! It's going to explode!
Great, now I have to save
this clown and myself.
[explosion]
[groaning]
[man] Freeze, creep!
Hold it right there,
Spider-Man.
-Sorry, gentlemen.
-[men shouting]
But even
with my present handicap,
I have all the hands I need.
[sirens wail]
[Spider-Man]
What have I done?
How could I have been
so irresponsible?
[thinking] I let my temper
get the best of me.
I didn't consider the risk.
This town is
finally going to see
that wall-crawling slime bucket
for what he really is.
A menace.
He's wrecked everything
from sewers to subways.
And now a medical facility.
But, Jonah, he was
only trying to catch Doc Ock.
And who hired him
to do that, Robbie?
You? Me?
Anyone?
It's the job of the police.
I'm going to use
all my resources
to ruin Spider-Man for this.
How does this always happen?
I mean well,
but in the process,
I mess up everything.
The world needs Spider-Man
about as much I need him.
I'm through. I quit.
-Peter? Peter!
-Huh?
Will you be seeing
Spider-Man soon?
I don't think so,
Mr. Robertson.
If I were Spider-Man,
I wouldn't show my face
in this town again.
Well, if you do see him,
give him this fan letter.
Some little girl's parents
sent it to the paper.
I figure he can
use all the support
he can find about now.
[Peter] "Dear Mr. Robertson,
your newspaper
always prints those wonderful
pictures of Spider-Man.
Could you please ask him
to come and visit
our little daughter?
She's his biggest fan
in all the world
and we would love
for her to meet--"
Yeah, yeah,
I don't need fan mail
at a time like this.
At last, this is it.
My life as Spider-Man is over.
All I need is
a superhero retirement pension
and everything
would be perfect.
-[woman's voice] My dear boy.
-What?!
Whoever said that everything
was supposed to be perfect?
-[Parker] Who said that?
-I did.
Who's there? Who are you?
Isn't the real question,
who are you?
[laughing]
[Peter] What's this?
Some phony fortune-teller?
[Madame Web]
Phony? Moi?
Ha! You are the phony.
[Peter] How did you know
what I was thinking?
I know much more than your
trivial thoughts, Spider-Man.
I'm not Spider-Man.
You are a terrible liar!
-Please, don't waste my time.
-What?!
I am not your enemy,
Peter Parker, you are.
Isn't it strange that
with all the power you have,
you've hurt so many
of those close to you?
Your Uncle Ben, Felicia Hardy,
Mary Jane?
How do you know about them?
Come see me and find out.
[laughing]
[Spider-Man] My costume.
How'd it get on me?
Good going, Spidey.
You walked right into a trap.
[Madame Web] You are wrong,
Mr. Parker.
As usual.
How do you know who I am?
And how do you know
so much about me?
I want some answers!
You will get them.
Now sit down.
I'll stand, thanks.
It is usually a good idea
to have a seat
when your world is about to be
-turned upside down.
-[snaps]
Whoa!
Huh?
You are about to embark
on a period of training
for a mission
I will soon require of you.
The only thing I'm embarking on
is a trip outta here.
Parker, this is one situation
you cannot crawl away from.
[grunts]
[Madame Web] In order
to succeed in this mission,
you must first
overcome the self-pity
that threatens
to end your career.
Oof!
What do you need me for?
You obviously
have powers of your own.
[Madame Web]
Powers are nothing.
More important is your tendency
to question yourself.
That is an interesting quality.
Tedious, but interesting.
Whoa!
[Madame Web]
This is your card.
No, thanks.
I'm not what
you'd call a believer.
[Madame Web]
Not so easy, is it?
It is telling you
that you must believe in me,
and you must have
the faith of a child.
What's that supposed to mean?
-[vortex whooshing]
-No! Wait!
Did I just take a trip through
the Twilight Zone or what?
This kind of weird stuff
is why I'm quitting.
Hey, it's that letter
Robbie gave me.
How did it get here?
Huh.
Madame Web did say something
about the faith of a child.
There, Spider-Man.
This is your best picture ever.
[Spider-Man] Thank you,
Maria Taina Elizando.
Huh? Who's there?
Just your friendly
neighborhood Spider-Man.
Spider-Man!
Is this a dream?
No, I'm really here,
just as your parents
asked for in their letter.
They what?
Wow!
It really is you.
Can you do something for me?
Please?
Sure, Maria, what is it?
Don't call me Maria.
Only my mom calls me Maria.
Everybody else calls me Taina.
Okay, Taina.
So now that I'm here,
what did you want to tell me?
That I'm your
greatest fan ever,
and I wanted to show you this.
My Spider-Man collection.
Look.
I even have the first story
The Bugle ever ran about you.
You didn't believe it, did you?
Nah. They say a lot
of silly things in there.
But the pictures are good.
Like this one
by that Peter Parker guy.
Do you know him?
Sometimes too well.
I cut out this ad
from when you were on TV.
Oh, this takes me back.
That's when I thought
I could use my powers
to make lots of money.
Where did you get your powers?
Timmy says you're
from a dying planet,
and your parents sent you here
in little a spaceship.
I think Timmy has me confused
with someone else.
I'm actually an accident.
An accident?
Yes. It all started
when I was in high school.
-I was actually
kind of a nobody.
-Who were you?
I'm gonna have to keep
my name to myself,
but I can tell you
what my life was like.
Hi, Liz.
I was wondering
if you'd like
to go downtown
to a science demonstration
with me.
Now, let me see, Peter,
should I go to the big party
with Flash Thompson
and have a really great time,
or go to the science
demonstration with you
and be bored to tears?
Oh, I just don't know.
Well, actually, this is
going to be a demonstration
of an exciting new technology
called Neogenics.
[Flash]
No contest, bookworm.
Liz and I have
some partying to do.
Whoa! Ooh!
-[Flash laughing]
-[Liz] See you around, Peter.
-But-- But--
-[Liz laughing]
[Taina] This is pitiful,
Spider-Man.
You really let him
get away with that?
Hey, I wasn't quite as strong
back then as I am now.
[Doctor Octopus]
The long and irritating saga
of Spider-Man is about to end.
He will meet defeat
at the hands
of my new Octobot.
Its arms
are powerful, agile,
and controlled
by my very thoughts.
Two octopi
for the price of one.
So did you go
to the demonstration?
Oh, I went all right.
It was
at Empire State University.
It was being given
by a famous professor.
Wow, Professor Stillwell.
Can you actually
harness radioactivity
for genetic experiments
with this device?
Of course. I'll demonstrate.
[Spider-Man]
But unbeknownst to us,
just as he activated
the device,
a small spider
dropped down right in the path
of the radioactive blast.
[thinking]
Ouch! It bit me!
Why is it glowing that way?
Is it radioactive?
I feel so strange.
Yikes!
Did you go to the hospital?
No, I probably should have,
but I didn't know what to do.
What's the matter, Parker?
Did our little demonstration
upset you?
[laughter]
[Spider-Man]
I ran out as fast as I could.
[thinking]
What's happening to me?!
I've been poisoned
by that spider!
I'm turning
into a spider myself!
Oh, dear! A spider?
Aunt May, it's me! Peter!
Oh! I hate spiders!
[Peter]
Can't you hear me?!
I know how to get rid of you!
Noooo!
[screaming]
Where-- Where am I?
[gasps, screams]
-[frightened shouts]
-Hey!
[gunfire]
No!
You don't understand!
[sighs]
[Spider-Man]
It was just a dream,
a hallucination.
But my head
was still throbbing,
so much so that
I didn't notice
a car coming right at me.
-[horn honking]
-I jumped out of the way.
I'm sticking to the wall!
I can climb straight up!
[Spider-Man]
Somehow, when that
radioactive spider bit me,
it must have transferred
its powers to me.
I gained
a whole new equilibrium,
the agility of a spider.
The strength, too.
And a spider's craving
for dark corners
and new heights.
[Taina] Too cool.
Is that spider still around?
No, and it's just as well.
That spider
also caused me a lot of grief.
[Kingpin] Impressive.
Is that all you have to say?
I shall reserve further
judgment until I see results.
And you shall see them soon.
With a spider-seeker
to ride it,
my Octobot will
find and crush Spider-Man
and anything else in its way.
[Taina]
When that spider bit you,
did it give you power
to make webs, too?
No. I did that myself.
I make web fluid and store it
in small pressurized containers
that load into
these web-shooters I built.
Wow! You must be super smart
to think this stuff up.
I think when I was bitten,
the spider passed
on an instinctive knowledge
of how to combine enzymes
to make this strong,
sticky webbing.
The trigger
is this sensitive electrode
located here, in my palm.
It requires exact pressure
from these two fingers,
so that I don't
accidently activate it
when I make a fist
or grab something.
By adjusting pressure
at the nozzle,
I can fire
a thin, strong web line.
See?
Or a fine wide spread.
This is great.
Think they'll let me keep it?
[Spider-Man] I'm sorry,
but like real spider-webbing,
it's biodegradable.
It dissolves
in about an hour or so.
No wonder I've never
been able to find any.
So you made your web-shooter
and then went out
and started catching
bad guys, right?
Not exactly.
First, I tried show biz.
Show biz?
[Spider-Man] Yeah.
I made this very costume
so I wouldn't be recognized,
and I went
on a television show.
[gasping and cheering]
Even though
I was wearing my costume,
I felt like I was showing off
to all those creeps
in my high school
who thought I was just a nerd.
Then I met an agent
who made me
an offer I couldn't refuse.
[man] Hey! Help!
Grab him!
Don't let him get away!
Hey, sorry, pal.
I'm a wrestler, not a cop.
I figured,
why should I get involved?
All I cared about
back then
was taking care
of number one-- me.
The police were
at Aunt May's.
Aunt May, where's Uncle Ben?
What's happened?!
I have bad news for you, son.
Your uncle tried to stop him,
but he was armed.
No. Not Uncle Ben!
Who did this?!
The punk who did this
has been chased to a warehouse.
We'll get him.
[Peter] Whoever it is,
I want him first.
And nothing's going
to stop Spider-Man.
No. Not you!
[Spider-Man] It was
the crook from the arena,
the one I should have stopped.
I've never forgiven myself
for letting my Uncle Ben down.
I had no idea.
And now I've done
something just as bad.
You heard
about that medical building.
That was an accident.
You'll be more careful
next time.
There won't be
a next time, Taina.
I'm not going
to be Spider-Man anymore.
No! You can't quit!
Just be more careful.
You can do that.
You can do anything.
I wish I could do anything,
like rebuild the medical center
or cure people's diseases.
I wish you could, too.
But you can't quit just
because you did one bad thing.
You never quit.
That's why you're my hero.
It's the hard choices
I'm always having to make.
I just can't handle it anymore.
You're not going now, are you?
No, I just need
to clear my head,
do some web-slinging.
Not without me, you're not.
No, Taina, I couldn't.
Please?
Just once I'd like to see
the world like you see it.
Just once, before...
Oh, all right.
I suppose it won't hurt
for you to come
along on a quick trip.
But you have to dress warmly.
[Taina] All right!
[dramatic music]
Wow!
I'm 100 stories high!
[spider-seeker beeping]
[Spider-Man] Hang on!
[beeping]
Now, my pet, go to your prey.
[Spider-Man] I want
to show you something.
Remember I told you
about my spider agility?
Watch this.
♪ Ta-da! ♪
-[tingling]
-Spider-sense?
Ock's tentacles
moving by themselves?
Taina, hide.
[groaning]
Do you like my newest design,
Spider-Man?
Autonomous
telepathic tentacles.
I call it the Octobot.
What's the matter, Ock?
Afraid to face me alone?
You had to call
in second stringers?
You brought a little friend.
Where is she?
Let's just make this
one-on-one, okay?
Delighted.
Crush him!
[grunts]
Did he say telepathic?
As in controlled
by his thoughts?
[grunts]
It's too much for me, Doc.
Did you steal this
from Pingree, too?
Pingree?
He had nothing to do with this!
-Nothing!
-[thinking] It's working.
He's losing his concentration.
They're loosening.
Nobody gives me my due!
I'll give you your due!
What?!
[screaming]
You never learn, do you?
On the contrary,
I've learned a great deal
from our encounters.
Sleep well, Spider-Man.
It's your reward
for underestimating my power.
This time, you lose.
Spider-Man! On, no!
[upbeat rock music]
♪ Spider-Man, Spider-Man ♪
♪ Radioactive Spider-Man ♪
♪ Spider blood, spider blood ♪
♪ Radioactive spider blood ♪
♪ Spider blood ♪
♪ Spider-Man ♪