[upbeat rock music]
♪ Spider-Man ♪
♪ Radioactive Spider-Man ♪
♪ Spider blood
Spider blood ♪
♪ Radioactive spider blood ♪
♪ Spider blood
Spider blood ♪
♪ Radioactive spider blood ♪
[explosions booming]
[growling]
♪ Spider-Man ♪
[dramatic music]
[elevator bell dings]
Hey, Parker,
don't you know these two?
Who are you talking a--
-Harry and Mary Jane, engaged?
-[phone ringing]
Peter, line 12,
it's some kind of emergency.
[Peter, thinking]
Now what?
Something wrong at home?
Hello, Aunt May?
[man] Parker? This is someone
whose life is in your hands.
You must contact Spider-Man
for me immediately.
[Peter] I don't believe it,
it sounds like--
He's the only one who can
rescue me from my employer,
a crime lord
known as the Kingpin.
The Kingpin?
Now, listen carefully.
My name is Alistair Smythe.
I knew
I recognized that voice.
[Alistair] I realize Spider-Man
doesn't owe anything
to someone who's tried
so hard to destroy him.
But if he can help me,
I will guarantee him
Kingpin's head on a platter.
But tell me something, why
would you betray your boss?
[Alistair] Because I think
he's about to betray me.
Tell Spider-Man
to meet me on the roof
of the old Brandon Building,
8:00 P.M. sharp.
I'll have some
interesting data for him.
-Smythe, wait.
-[click]
[Alistair] Some
interesting data indeed.
As you should know, Smythe,
in spite of my size,
I have the agility of a cat.
Too bad you have
the loyalty of a jackal.
[thinking]
What I really wanna do
is talk to MJ
about her engagement to Harry.
So why am I going off
to meet Smythe right now?
Because I also wanna
bring down the Kingpin.
There he is, right on time.
-Huh?
-[tingling]
Uh-oh!
-Rarr!
-Smythe, is that you?!
It's Smythe all right,
but what has he done
to himself?
[groans]
Kingpin has demanded
you must be located,
and then you
must be terminated.
[beeping]
[thinking]
Smythe's become some kind
of Ultimate Spider Slayer.
And that makes me toast.
Yaah!
[Alistair roars]
[lasers firing]
Aaah!
[computer clicking
and beeping]
[grunts]
[groans]
Ohh.
[clicking]
[static]
Blast, what is wrong?
[air howling]
[groaning]
Where-- Where am I?
[Madame Web]
Please get off the floor.
I just dusted it for cobwebs.
[Spider-Man, thinking]
Madame Web.
Oh, not her again.
I'd almost rather
be facing Smythe!
Alistair nearly had him.
-Do something.
-[keyboard clicking]
There, I've got
the visual back.
But Spider-Man was
able to escape.
It seems the new Alistair
is just as disappointing
as the old.
His synapses haven't fully
adjusted to my treatments yet.
I'll bring him back for more.
Let us hope
that is all he requires,
for his sake,
as well as yours, Dr. Landon.
[Madame Web]
Another pathetic effort
like that, Spider-Man,
and even my telekinetic powers
won't be able to save you.
Pathetic?
What more could I have done?
For one thing, you must
stop being distracted
by your romantic dilemmas.
Well, that's easy
for you to say.
But even if I could,
how am I going to beat Smythe?
He's too strong.
It's not how to defeat
your enemies, it's why.
Why do they
want to destroy you?
That's obvious.
Smythe's working for Fisk and--
Your Aunt May
seems intelligent.
So perhaps ignorance doesn't
permeate your family.
Perhaps it's just you.
Hey, I never asked to
come here in the first place.
Then worry about your
little romance elsewhere.
Go, go, go.
And remember,
my confused young man,
it's not the how you must
master, it's the why.
How am I supposed to know
what that busybody
is talking about?
And why should I care?
She's right about one thing
though, I am distracted.
I've gotta talk to Mary Jane.
[elevator whirring]
Welcome back, Smythe.
My dear fellow, it's time
for another treatment.
No more treatments.
You will do as you are told.
Go ahead, try it.
[beeps]
[Landon]
I'm sorry about that.
It's a minor malfunction.
Easily corrected.
The good news is
the fail-safe programming
which prevents Alistair
from harming either of us
is completely intact.
See that it stays that way.
Come with me.
We can discuss
my plans for Smythe.
-[gas hissing]
-[tense music]
[Fisk] We have come to the end
of our long association.
You have failed to keep your
part of our bargain, Smythe.
Your Spider Slayer robots
have been totally ineffective
in destroying Spider-Man.
Even worse, because
of your incompetence
in that Peter Parker affair,
my son is in jail
and Spider-Man now
knows of my existence,
making him more dangerous
than ever.
It is time for me to cut
my losses and make a change.
No!
[Landon] Metal is the way
of the past, Smythe.
Flesh-- mutated, restructured,
and enhanced--
holds the key to the future.
And even though
I'll be replacing you
as the Kingpin's lieutenant,
there'll still be a place
for you in the organization.
A new and improved version
of you, that is.
Where you once failed,
you'll finally succeed.
[dramatic music]
[whirs]
Ah, everything has turned
out just as I wished.
Dr. Landon,
you are sure he no longer
has any feelings
or will of his own?
None whatsoever.
He's the humanoid
equivalent of a robot.
How ironic.
Spencer Smythe loved robots,
and now his son has become one.
[Spencer] It'll be just your
size when it's finished.
Is that why
you're working for Osborn?
Alistair, I'd do
anything to help you.
Remember our deal?
No spider splat,
no hover chair.
All right.
My father.
[explosion]
[dramatic music]
[alarm blaring]
Hey, freak,
get back in your cage!
Aaah!
Stay back! He's too strong!
[Landon] Stop!
I command you to stop!
The humanoid equivalent
of a robot, eh?
[May] You must be so
happy for Mary Jane, Anna.
Oh, I am.
Harry is such
a nice, responsible boy.
Still, it's sad.
What is?
I had always hoped Mary Jane
would settle on Peter.
Pardon my frankness, May,
but Peter never
was there for her.
He's always running around--
Aunt May, I'm late.
I've gotta get dressed
for that press conference
at Oscorp Towers.
Oh.
Hello, Mrs. Watson.
Oh, hello, Peter.
Did you say you were
going to Oscorp Towers?
Well, Mary Jane's going
to be there with Harry.
Did you know they've
announced their engagement?
Uh, yeah.
I saw the picture in the paper.
[ominous music]
:New target: Norman Osborn.
Objective: Revenge"?
Landon, what is going on?
Alistair is apparently
accessing his memories
in order to reprogram himself.
Fascinating.
That is not
the word I would use.
[computer] Current
location of Norman Osborn,
Oscorp Towers.
Probability, 95.37%
This is a disaster.
Osborn and I have
resolved our differences,
and his resources
are important to me.
Reprogram Smythe immediately!
[static]
I can't!
He's just terminated
our connection!
[Jonah]
You sure know how to keep
the Oscorp stockholders
happy, Norman.
According to your
press release,
this subway car
is just the first
of dozens
of defense conversion projects.
It's a big step, Jonah.
That's why I wanted
a major press event
to announce the contracts.
Take lots of pictures, Parker.
This could be
a multi-billion dollar deal.
[Peter] Yes, Mr. Jameson.
-Hello, tiger.
-Mary Jane.
I guess you heard
the big news already huh?
Uh, yeah.
I was a little surprised.
I wanted to tell you myself,
but Harry let the word out.
Oh, sometimes
he's so impetuous,
like a kid
on Christmas morning.
I'm very happy for you.
Actually, that's a lie.
What I wanna ask is--
Why Harry?
Listen, Peter, all my life,
men have let me down.
Harry's different though.
He gives me a lot of attention.
He seems like he'll
always be there for me.
But do you love him?
Excuse me, Peter, I promised
Mrs. Peabody Oakhurst Smith
that I'd discuss, uh, wedding
gown designers with her.
She'll be crushed if I don't.
[thinking]
No. I didn't think so.
[ominous music]
[Norman]
Ladies and gentlemen,
I have an important
announcement to make.
But first, I'd like
to congratulate my son Harry
and my future daughter-in-law
Mary Jane Watson.
As you saw in today's paper,
they've just announced
their engagement.
[crowd applauds]
[ominous music]
- Now--
- Spider-sense!
Danger!
-[explosion]
-[crowd screams]
[Harry]
Dad, what's going on?!
[woman] Oh, my gosh!
[computer]
Norman Osborn located.
Norman Osborn.
[Harry] What does
that-- that thing want?!
Objective: Revenge.
[people screaming]
No!
-Norman Osborn!
-Put me down!
-[lasers firing]
First me, now Osborn?
[groans]
Isn't there any way
to stop him?
I've already sent
the retrieval unit.
[pilot]
Retrieval Unit to Kingpin,
we have visual contact.
Dad!
Harry, stay back!
Retrieval Unit,
we have some unexpected guests.
Make sure they do not
see where they are going.
[hissing]
Mary Jane, Harry, no!
Bingo!
[dramatic music]
Take Smythe to the lab.
Lock them up.
Please accept
my humble apologies
for the inconvenience, Osborn.
Inconvenience?
There's an understatement.
Fisk, what in the world
did you do to Smythe?
A misstep in the furtherance
of science.
Had I known he held you
responsible
for his father's
disappearance, I--
Me?! It was your men
who caused the explosion
at his father's lab!
Smythe should be going
after your throat, not mine!
It's your fault
he lost his father!
Ah, but Spencer Smythe
is not lost.
What?!
Somehow, he survived
the explosion of your factory.
[explosion]
I found him amid the wreckage.
I knew he would be
unwilling to work for me.
But all the same, a genius
is a terrible thing to waste.
So I put him
into cryogenic suspension.
And when I told Alistair
that Spider-Man
was responsible
for his father's disappearance,
I gained a younger genius
and one willing to share
a valuable robotic
technology for nothing
but the promise of revenge.
That's unbelievable.
-Where is Spencer Smythe now?
-[click]
In the same cryogenic unit
that he has always occupied.
In this building.
Five floors down.
[whispering] Hey,
check out the unauthorized
ceiling ornament.
-[tingling]
-Uh-oh!
Spider-Man!
At last, I have him!
-[grunting]
-Hey!
Landon, reactivate Alistair
and give him the new
hover-chair you created.
But I haven't finished
reprogramming!
Do it now!
[ominous music]
Oh!
Looks like Alistair
got a good deal
on his trade-in.
[grunting]
Now he's even more
agile than I am!
How am I...
Wait a minute.
What was it Madame Web said?
It's not the how you must
master, it's the why.
Well, I know how Alistair
is whipping my hide,
but better still,
now I know why.
Alistair, don't!
I can help you
find your father!
My father?
Alistair, he's lying!
I'll show you who's lying!
Spider-Man!
[Alistair]
My father lives?
Kingpin's holding your father
in cryogenic suspension
five floors down.
Alistair, what I did
was for the best.
[Landon] Don't worry, Kingpin,
Alistair's programming
prevents him from harming you,
regardless of what
you did to his father.
You see?
Aaaah!
Oof!
Take me on, if you dare.
[growling]
[grunting]
[groaning]
Osborn, why don't we let
these two boys talk
this over alone?
[Norman]
Huh? But, but--
[Mary Jane] We've got
to get out of here.
Did you see those guards?
They're serious.
Of course they're serious,
and we have to be, too.
This is the real world,
Harry, not some game
where your dad
makes all the rules.
Well, what do you
want me to do?
I don't know.
But something.
Come with us.
Okay, okay.
It's not okay with me!
[guard] Hey, you, stop!
[grunting]
[Spider-Man]
A winning combination.
Scarlett O'Hara's eyes
and Bruce Lee's moves.
I think you're ready
for the big time.
Gee, thanks, Spider-Man.
You could probably handle
a leading role yourself.
I knew I could count on you.
Of course, son.
I wouldn't let
anything happen to you.
-Not now or ever.
-[explosions]
[gasps]
That's enough for me!
Let's go!
[Kingpin grunts]
Spider-Man!
We've had enough of you.
[Spider-Man]
Hold on, Mary Jane.
In the last few minutes,
things have changed.
They have indeed.
[Spider-Man] Remember, take
the elevator five floors down.
Yes, I will remember.
[explosions]
[Spider-Man] Okay,
now let's get out of here!
[Mary Jane screams]
Kingpin, you're alive!
Not for long if we waste
any more time here.
But what about Smythe?
Forget Smythe!
[dramatic music]
Father?
It's Alistair,
Father, your son.
Dad, will you please
tell me what's going on?
Harry, you don't look well.
Let's call a cab.
[whistles]
Hey, over here!
[Harry]
Oh, do I have a headache.
Harry, I'll call you later.
I-- I need to clear my head.
Wh-- What?!
But-- But, Mary Jane,
you can't--
[Mary Jane] Care to take me
for a spin, Spider-Man?
-I need some air.
-Uh, sure.
Wow!
I would say that pretty much
did the trick.
Well, that's
how it works for me, too.
I don't know
why I'm telling you this,
but back there,
I suddenly realized
that even though
I was really scared
and concerned for Harry,
it was as if I was worried
about a little brother.
Don't get me wrong, I love him,
but it's not the kind of love
I should have
for a future husband.
Besides, I think
there's someone else
I'm really in love with.
And all along, I've been trying
to convince myself I wasn't.
Really?
And who might that be?
Hey, there's a cabstand.
You can put me down there.
We've gotta do this
again sometime.
Good night, Spider-Man.
[Spider-Man]
So long, Mary Jane.
And I hope Peter Parker
is the lucky guy you're after.
[ominous music]
[Alistair] Soon you will wake,
Father, and then,
for all the crimes
committed against us,
you and I shall reek
a terrible revenge.
[upbeat rock music]
♪ Spider-Man, Spider-Man ♪
♪ Radioactive Spider-Man ♪
♪ Spider blood,
spider blood ♪
♪ Radioactive spider blood ♪
♪ Spider blood ♪
♪ Spider-Man ♪