♪ Spider-Man, Spider-Man ♪
♪ Radioactive Spider-Man ♪
♪ Spider-Man ♪
♪ Spider-Man, Spider-Man ♪
♪ Radioactive Spider-Man ♪
♪ Spider blood, spider blood ♪
♪ Radioactive spider blood ♪
♪ Spider blood ♪
♪ Spider-Man ♪
♪ Spider-Man on top ♪
[dramatic music]
[Woman] Please stop it!
Don't touch me!
What are you doing?
Stop it!
This is exactly why I left.
I have come all this
way for one purpose.
To take you home.
Sergei,
let me finish my research.
I can cure you.
Okay, Pete, take a deep breath.
Just nail this interview
and you'll be working
in a real research lab.
-[glass shattering]
-[speaking foreign language]
[Kraven] You have
found someone else?
Dr. Crawford, is
everything all right?
Stay out!
I sure hope he's not
interviewing for the same job.
Mariah, stop!
Mariah, you cannot give
your heart to another man.
Don't touch me.
I love you.
I do not want to harm you.
[Spider-Man]
Dr. Crawford, watch out!
[screaming]
Gotcha!
[Mariah] Spider-Man!
[Spider-Man]
Nice outfit. Don't tell me,
you're a Leo, right?
Whoever you are, this
is none of your concern.
After what you just did to her,
I'm concerned enough to
haul you into the police!
Mariah, for his own sake,
tell him to remain out
of our affairs!
[groaning]
[Spider-Man] Faster than
a speeding web line,
who am I dealing with here?
I will not hurt her.
[Spider-Man] So, you're
going to hurt me instead?
Spiders are revered as
hunters, but you have proven
to be easy prey.
[Spider-Man] Thanks for
showing me the view but,
I'm afraid of heights.
Is this guy a pro wrestler?
That would explain the tights.
Sergei!
Where's Sergei?
[Spider-Man] He disappeared.
He'll be back, you can't stop
him, nothing can stop him!
[Spider-Man] Okay,
okay, calm down.
Let's get out of here
before Mr. Right comes
back for a second date.
Who was that wildcat?
I knew him as Sergei Kravinoff.
He's descended from
Russian nobility.
He was a big game
hunter in Africa.
When hunting was outlawed
he became one of the leading
guides, that's how I met him.
I hired him to help me
look for Dr. James Reaves,
a colleague of mine
who disappeared
while doing research
in the jungle.
-[hissing]
-[gasping]
I was drawn to Sergei,
we fell in love.
[Spider-Man] So
when did he change
from Rhett Butler
to Freddy Krueger?
[Mariah] It was months later,
our search finally ended.
We found my friend,
Dr. Reaves.
He had synthesized
a miracle drug.
This substance could
heal all wounds,
preventing disease
and infection!
But Reaves had tested
the serum upon himself
with frightening results.
It was transforming him
into a feral creature.
[growling]
Reaves gave me the last
vial of his wonder drug.
He warned me not to use
it in its current form
under any circumstances.
I had to get him to
come back with me.
I followed him.
That was a big mistake.
Oh!
[growling]
Mariah!
[growling and snarling]
Stop!
[yelping]
Sergei was seriously injured,
there seemed to be no hope,
nothing I could do
to save my love.
As I watched his condition
deteriorate, I made a decision,
one that still haunts me.
I gave him the drug.
Sergei's recovery was
immediate, it was a miracle.
But my greatest fear
came true,
new instincts
burned in his blood.
Gradually, he became more
primal, more bestial.
[growling]
He started hunting
like a jungle animal.
He changed so much that he
took a new name for himself.
-[sniffing]
-Kraven, The Hunter.
I fled back to America
to work on a cure
for Reaves' formula.
I need more time and your help.
[Spider-Man] Look, doc,
I'm sympathetic,
but I don't usually
handle domestic disputes.
He's dangerous. He's the most
dangerous animal alive!
Until he's cured, he could
hurt anyone around him.
[Spider-Man] The guy that
lives here is out of town.
It ought to be okay for you
to hide out here for a while.
I can't stay here, I must
find a lab and finish my work.
[Spider-Man] With the
king of the jungle
running around out there?
Not a chance.
But Kraven will hunt
the both of us down.
[Spider-Man]
Stop worrying, doc.
We webbed across the city 10
stories high,
it's not humanly
possible to track us.
Kraven isn't human,
not anymore.
[Spider-Man] Look, I have
to be someplace right now,
but I'll be back, and
then we can set you up
in a lab somewhere, okay?
The fear in her eyes
has got even me spooked,
but I don't think this
Kraven guy can find her.
With any luck, the cops
will nab him first,
or maybe animal control.
[sniffing]
[chuckling]
[horns honking]
[gasps] Sergei!
[beeps]
[J.J.] Robbie, sorry about
cutting your vacation short,
but that big Baumgartner
trial is going to the jury.
I need you here right away!
Okay, J.J, I'm coming.
-[growls]
-What?
Where is she?
Where?
Who are you?
What's going on here?
I can still smell her perfume.
You are hiding her,
you must be the other man.
"Other man?" What are
you talking about?
Mariah Crawford.
I don't know her.
[Kraven] You are lying!
I got to get going, Aunt May,
or I'm gonna be
late to the plaza.
I feel like an undertaker
in this outfit.
You look very handsome.
Now, you tell Mary Jane
that I'm so sorry I
couldn't make it tonight.
Do you have the invitation?
Good, it was nice
of her to invite you
to that jungle animal show.
It's the Animal in You
Fashion Show, Aunt May.
I don't think there
are any real animals
or jungles involved.
Bye, Peter.
At least I hope not.
If I missed her, I put on
this monkey suit for nothing.
Peter, I'm so glad you made it,
and you look great.
[Man] One minute warning,
Mary Jane.
Okay.
I'm sorry, Peter, I have to go.
Let's skip the party afterwards
and get a bite to eat,
just you and me, alone.
Really?
Uh, great.
[Announcer] Here
comes our next model.
It's Miss Mary Jane Watson.
[upbeat music]
A theater student at ESU,
Mary Jane looks stunning
in this faux
leopard skin print.
Wow, that outfit brings
out the animal in me.
[Announcer] And now,
here we have Katrina
in a fantastic zebra design.
[Woman] Look, it's
the guy from cats!
[gasping]
[sniffing]
Spider-Man.
Huh, Felicia Hardy?
Parker,
what are you doing here?
My aunt gave me her invitation.
What are you doing here?
This is
a Hardy Foundation event.
Mother's the chairperson,
and I'm helping her.
This is a wonderful surprise.
You can take me to
the party later.
Yeah, but...
We'll talk. I've got to run.
I'm supposed to go out with
Mary Jane after the show.
[gasping]
[Peter] Kraven,
he must have my scent!
Parker? Why is he--
Leaving?
There he goes with that
disappearing act again.
[scoffs]
-Back off!
-[Woman] What are you doing?
Spider-Man, I know you are
here. Stop hiding from me!
What a great show!
These foundation events
are usually stale.
[Spider-Man]
Yo, Jungle Jim, up here.
[crowd gasping]
[audience applauding]
[Kraven] Where is my woman?
[Spider-Man] You're the hunter,
can't you find her?
Whoa!
Mariah!
If I go, so does your comrade.
[Spider-Man] My comrade?
Jungle freak, if
you hurt Robbie!
You have six hours
to save your friend.
Bring me Mariah!
[chuckles] She'll know
how to find me,
and don't
underestimate me again.
[laughing]
[Spider-Man] He's
kidnapped Robbie,
and it's all my fault,
my fault.
[answering machine beeping]
[J.J.] Robbie, where
the heck are you?
The airline says your
plane landed hours ago.
What happened to you?
[Spider-Man] How
does "I was kidnapped
by a crazed big-game
hunter" grab you, J.J?
Robbie's one of the people I
respect the most.
When will I learn to keep
my friends out of my fights?
Now I have to find
him and the doctor,
but where do I start?
[phone dialing]
Hello, Paula?
I need to use your lab.
Great, great.
I'll see you in an hour.
I'll explain when I get there.
[lion moaning]
Would you like some water?
[panting]
Why are you doing this?
I was raised in the traditions
of nobility,
and now I live in
the world of the jungle.
The codes of conduct that
govern both are very similar.
If you take what
belongs to another,
there must be retribution.
I don't know what
you're talking about,
this isn't the jungle!
It's a concrete jungle,
the same rules apply.
[Spider-Man]
I'm running low on time,
and on labs.
Come on, doc, where are you?
[bus door hissing open]
No, I'm doing this all wrong.
I'm letting Kraven
call the shots.
Maybe I should be
looking for him instead.
That's it!
I must hunt the hunter,
but where?
Kraven is who I am.
I belong among the animals.
[Spider-Man] Of course!
[rats screeching]
[monitor beeping]
The African Jungle Exhibit.
Oh, this is almost too obvious.
Robbie's the bait.
Okay, I'll bite.
Whoa!
[dramatic music]
Welcome to my jungle.
[Spider-Man] Misfire!
It must have been
damaged in that fall.
-[growling]
-Oh, boy!
[growling fades out]
Robbie!
[whimpering]
[Kraven] Where's Mariah?
[Spider-Man] I don't know.
Look, can't we talk this
over like civilized men?
Nyet.Your friend is lost.
[Spider-Man] Kraven,
let Robbie go.
Leave him out of
this, he's innocent!
We had a deal, and
your time is up!
[Spider-Man] Oh!
Your smoke screen's
no match for my spider sense.
You're nothing but an animal!
I know evil and good,
fears and delights,
the silver of the Prussian
moons,
the crimson of the
Prussian nights.
[Spider-Man] Quoting
Solzhenitsyn doesn't
make you human.
Sergei, I'm here, let him go!
[Spider-Man] Doc, wait!
Nyet!Mariah, no!
[growling]
Mariah!
[muffled whimpering]
[Spider-Man] You okay?
Spider-Man?
Get me out of here.
-[Spider-Man] Uh-oh.
-[crocodile hissing]
Have to do this the hard way.
Not bad for a guy
with a busted web shooter, huh?
Boy, I'm sure glad
you showed up.
[Spider-Man] I'm sorry I put
you in such danger, my friend.
[snarling]
Kraven, hang on!
[Mariah] Sergei!
[Spider-Man] He's
been badly wounded.
Sergei, I love you.
Don't leave me.
[speaking foreign language]
please.
[yelling]
I feel so strange.
That's the antidote
taking effect, Sergei.
You're becoming once
more the man I love.
[Spider-Man] Penny
for your thoughts.
Will you please just tell
me what's going on here?
How did I get involved?
[Spider-Man] I guess you
have me to thank for that.
[ship's siren blowing]
Mariah, the nightmare
is finally over.
I feel human again.
[Spider-Man] Yeah,
okay, bye-bye.
What a beautiful happy ending.
I feel like I'm trapped in
a Danielle Steele novel.
Correct me if I'm wrong but,
isn't the hero supposed
to get the girl?
I saved the city
from jungle boy,
and I'll be lucky if
Mary Jane or Felicia
ever speak to me again.
Not to mention the fact
that the animal kingdom
walked all over my costume.
Never again do I get in
the middle of a lovers' spat.
Stick a fork in me, I'm done.
[theme song playing]
♪ Spider-Man, Spider-Man ♪
♪ Radioactive Spider-Man ♪
♪ Spider blood, spider blood ♪
♪ Radioactive spider blood ♪
♪ Spider blood ♪
♪ Spider-Man ♪