["Spider-Man Theme Song"
by Joe Perry playing]
♪ Spider-Man ♪
♪ Radioactive Spider-Man ♪
[guitar break]
♪ Spider blood ♪
♪ Radioactive spider blood ♪
[guitar break]
♪ Spider-Man ♪
[plane engine roars]
[woman] Oh, my god!
Freeze! Don't even
crack a smile!
[crowd screams]
[coughing]
After him!
[gasps]
Hey, you look just like...
me.
What took you so l-- [yells]
Colonel, in pursuit of subject
in stolen helicopter, over.
[Colonel] Spread out,
I don't want an accident.
But stay with him.
[Spider-Man] Uh, oh, good thing
no one's moved
into this building yet!
C'mon, pal, let's beat it
before the fireworks start!
[cheering]
Help! Help!
[screams]
[gasps]
Buddy, you OK?
Get out of my way!
[crowd cheers]
Way to go, Spider-Man!
Hey! You! Stop!
What the--
[woman screams]
[siren wailing]
Hi, Ms. Grant!
Peter, you can't go in there!
Nah, I don't want
escargot, I hate escargot.
-I want caviar!
-Mr. Jameson?
Mr. Jameson! Mr. Jameson!
Parker, can't you see I'm busy
organizing the party
of the century?
Mr. Jameson, you're late
for your tuxedo fitting,
and the limo's waiting.
Blasted monkey suits,
I hate em'.
Mr. Jameson, hold on a second!
Mr. Jameson, wait!
I need to talk to you!
[pants]
I just wanted to ask if I could
photograph the peace
treaty signing.
Are you nuts?
This isn't gonna be some
web-filled crime scene
it's an important world event!
[Peter] But--
-I want a seasoned pro there!
-But, Mr.--
-[John] You're strictly
freelance, Parker!
-[Peter] But I--
But let me plead my case!
You got from here
to the tailor's, kid,
make it good!
-Get in.
-All right!
Sir, two world leaders signing
a peace treaty after centuries
of hostile aggression,
this is the kind of photo that
can win a Pulitzer!
All I need is one good shot!
Can't. Each newspaper is only
allowed one photographer.
Well, what about
your party tonight?
It's the only time
the two leaders
will be seen together
before the signing!
After all the great Spider-Man
photos I've taken for you?
[John]
Oh, all right, all right!
I'll see if I can
get you clearance.
Driver, what are you doing?
My tailor isn't anywhere
near this place!
[Peter] Hey!
-[gasps]
-Just be calm, Mr. Jameson.
No harm will come to you.
Maybe you forgot to pay
your last tailors bill.
You don't let me go
immediately,
you'll wish you'd
never eyes on me!
[Peter thinking]
I'd better hang tight
and see what's going down,
unlike Mr. Calm next to me.
[Jameson] Do you know
who you're dealing with?
Whoa! [grunts]
[Peter thinking]
I'm here by accident,
but why do they want Jameson?
Only one way to find out.
[laser guns firing]
What is this place?
This looks like some kind of
training center for assassins!
Maybe this is a way out!
[wind blows loudly]
Whoa!
I'm airborne!
How did I end up here?
What is this place?
[Peter grunts]
Whoever these guys are,
they mean business!
But what have they
done with Jameson?
[John] What have
you done with Parker?
[man] You and I've got to talk.
[John]
Just who the blazes are you?
[Fury] Name's Fury.
Colonel Nick Fury.
I call the shots around here.
It can't be!
[Peter thinking] The war hero?
What's wrong, Jameson?
You look like
you've seen a ghost!
You're not supposed
to be alive!
That's what Uncle Sam
wants the world to believe.
But I printed your obituary!
I wouldn't brag
about it, Mister.
Bugle.
Obits.
Fury.
Nick.
You flipped the negative
of my picture.
My patch is on the wrong eye!
You're a real piece of work,
Jameson, now listen up.
From now on,
zero mistakes, get it?
What is this place?
Welcome to Supreme
Headquarters International
Espionage
Law-Enforcement Division.
We call it S.H.I.E.L.D.
Never heard of it!
Even the FBI and CIA
are kept in the dark about us.
S.H.I.E.L.D.'s job
is to secretly try to
keep the world in one piece,
no matter what it takes.
This is the Chameleon,
a deadly stop-at-nothing
hit man.
He can transform himself
into a carbon-copy
of any person who's image
he can grab with this.
I first heard of him
in Istanbul
when he blew up an embassy.
In Rome, he attacked
a military post,
and then gave us
the slip by taking
on the appearance
of a clergyman.
Last I ran into him
was in Sarajevo,
he got away as nurse.
No way he's gonna beat me
again!
So? What's this
got to do with me?
The Chameleon's been hired
by terrorists to total
the peace treaty.
And that could mean war.
[Peter thinking] So that's it!
[Fury] This morning he arrived
in New York City.
New York? My party!
And that's where we'll
find the Chameleon!
In a disguise
that's undetectable!
But I'm having police,
security, and FBI there!
The place'll be sealed
up tighter than--
[Fury] They won't
even notice him.
[John] Then why don't
we just cancel the party?
No can do, gotta act
like everything's normal.
If we shut down every time
someone threatens us,
the whole world would stop.
Now, I need you to wear this.
Nobody knows your employees
better than you do.
That's why you're
important to me.
If you see anything
suspicious, tap on this pin,
and undercover S.H.I.E.L.D.
agents will respond pronto.
The Bugle building is
crawling with them.
But what do I--
Just keep your eyes open.
I'm sending you back now.
[Peter thinking]
Oops, that's my cue!
[dramatic music]
What was that all about?
National security, Parker,
can't discuss it.
[beep]
[Glory] Mr. Jameson!
You're back early, is your
tuxedo fitting all done?
Yeah, all done.
I need the security
plans for tonight!
I left a copy in your briefcase
a half hour ago.
I need them in my hands
right now!
Do you have a problem
with that?
No, sir, I'll get them. Again.
Oh, hi there, Jonah.
Robby, I must talk to you
in private. Immediately!
[Peter thinking]
Something's not right.
-Here.
-What's this?
[Glory] The security
plans for tonight.
You gave me a copy
before I left.
I know, that's what I told you!
Are you trying to
drive me crazy?
What's wrong with her?
Jonah! I've gotta make
a quick phone call.
I'll be right back.
Uh, Mr. Jameson,
I've gotta run.
Hold it, Parker.
This little event today,
I don't want you to--
Hey! Where'd those
security plans go?
Well, they were right here.
Maybe Robby took them?
Well, why on Earth would he--
[gasps] No!
Robby!
[badges beeping]
[Robby] Hey! Hey!
What are you--
[Spider-Man thinking]
No spider sense, no Chameleon!
You've got it wrong!
Let him go!
Spider-Man?
What's he doing here?
[Fury, on radio]
Agent 1, get him!
[Agent 1] No imaging device!
He's not the one! Fan out!
You! Stop!
I've got him!
Floor seven, west wing!
He's in the form of Ms. Grant!
[Fury]
All agents, floor seven!
Detain Glory Grant!
Cover all exits!
[Spider-Man] Gotcha!
I don't usually pick
up strange women.
Funny, but not too smart.
[Spider-Man coughs]
[groans]
Stupid! Should've had him!
Talk about the dangers
of second-hand smoke!
[footsteps]
[elevator bell dings]
Just the man I was looking for!
Peter, I'm understudying
the lead
-in the Shakespeare Fest
tonight...
-[elevator bell dings]
...and I've saved you a seat.
Will you come?
[Mary Jane moans]
I'll take that as a yes!
Peter, why'd you do that?
I had to.
What made you think
I'd let you?
I took a gamble
that Peter Parker
was the luckiest man on Earth.
[suspenseful music]
[cameras clicking]
All units, red alert!
The VIPs are arriving.
It's showtime!
Aha!
Bruce, looks like
the Chameleon has arrived!
Keep smilin', old buddy.
Intruder alert!
Floor 31, sector five!
There's been a breach!
Floor 31!
[Spider-Man] Chameleon, stop!
Whoa, nice haircut!
[Spider-Man coughing]
This guy's gonna
ruin my lungs faster
than tailgating
a Manhattan taxi!
It's the Chameleon! Get him!
No! Stay back!
This is stupid!
While we fight, the Chameleon
gains the advantage!
Time to lose you boneheads!
Maybe it's time for me
to change faces, too!
[Fury] Agent 1!
[Agent 1] Yes, Colonel?
Situation's code red.
I'm coming there in person.
I'll rendezvous with you
at the penthouse in 10 minutes.
Aye, sir. Over and out.
Penthouse. Code red.
I've got to get the VIPs out.
The Colonel thinks
the Chameleon's
moving upstairs.
[groans]
[speaking in French]
OK, OK, I'll check it out!
Gotta check the gas main.
Wherefore was I to
this keen mockery born?
When at your hands did
I deserve such scorn,
that you must flout
my insufficiency?
[Mary Jane thinking]
Where in blazes are you,
Parker?
Good troth, you do me
wrong, good sooth, you do,
in such disdainful
manner me to woo.
But fare you well.
Perforce I must
confess, I thought
you lord of more
true gentleness.
How the heck did this happen?
[chefs cheer]
[muffled yell]
[elevator bell dings]
[Peter thinking]
Now, if I were a Chameleon,
who's colors would I choose?
Spider sense!
The Chameleon's close!
But where is he?
The Colonel says it's time
to get the VIPs out.
Great, they've been
here long enough.
[Peter thinking]
The VIPs are leaving?
Maybe I'd better keep
an eye on things.
Good job, agent.
Colonel! You're early!
My daddy once told me,
it's the early bird
that catches the Chameleon.
Follow me.
Whaddaya know,
Fury's here in the flesh!
I guess he wanted to
personally get them to a safe--
Wait a minute...
Oh, no!
You! Hold it right there!
[crowd screaming]
Hold your fire!
I knew it'd happen!
Spider-Man's
finally gone berserk!
Wait! You don't understand!
Stop! Look at Fury!
The eye patch!
It's on the wrong eye!
There's your Chameleon!
[Fury, on radio] Agent 1,
I'm on my way up.
Report your location. Report!
Do you copy?
Fury?
Send a crew
to check the wreckage!
We have to make sure
he didn't bail!
But how could the Chameleon
make such a stupid mistake?
That's simple, picklepuss.
He probably based his disguise
on Fury's picture
from the obituary
in your files.
The one that was printed
flipped?
But he didn't know that!
I guess it really does pay
to practice shoddy journalism!
Keep it up, J.J.!
Why you!
Gotta run!
[cameras clicking]
[audience clapping]
For a while there,
I didn't think
we were gonna get to see this.
I heard that.
Parker,
what are you doing here?
How in blazes did you get in?
I have my methods, Mr. Jameson.
Like any good freelancer,
when I wanna get a shot,
nothing gets in my way!
All I need is one
good clean shot.
[crowd creaming]
Now I've got you!
And there's no escape!
No! Get your hands off me!
[John's voice]
Let go, you fool!
[Glory's voice]
Don't stop me now, I'm...
[Robby's voice] So, so...
[Fury's voice] close. So...
[Spider-Man]
Sleep tight, Chameleon!
Maybe when you wake up,
you'll feel more like yourself!
The Chameleon, here?
Right next to me?
[groans]
I need a long vacation.
[cameras clicking]
[Spider-Man] Well, Bruce,
I saved the world again.
And what do I get for it?
As usual, zilch!Nada!
Nothing, that's what.
Heck of a job, Spider-Man!
Thanks!
[Spider-Man]
Did he say "thanks"?
Someone thanking Spider-Man?
Huh, that's a first!
[doorbell rings]
I'll get it, Aunt May!
Oh, Mary Jane!
Thanks, for not coming
to my play as you promised.
As I promised?
And don't you ever
kiss me that way again.
What kiss?
The Chameleon!
Oh, no!
Mary Jane, wait!
I--I can explain!
Well, at least, I think
I can explain!
OK, maybe--maybe
I can't explain,
but wait, just listen!
Listen to me! Hold on a second!
[indistinct]
["Spider-Man Theme Song"
playing]
♪ Spider-Man, Spider-Man ♪
♪ Radioactive Spider-Man ♪
[guitar solo]
♪ Spider blood, spider blood ♪
♪ Radioactive spider blood ♪
♪ Spider-Man ♪