[upbeat rock music]
♪ Spider-Man ♪
♪ Radioactive Spider-Man ♪
♪ Spider blood
Spider blood ♪
♪ Radioactive spider blood ♪
♪ Spider blood
Spider blood ♪
♪ Radioactive spider blood ♪
[explosions booming]
[growling]
♪ Spider-Man ♪
[tense music]
This is crazy, Osborn!
We've already been
at this 18 hours straight!
We'll go another
18 if we have to!
We've got to perfect
this formula!
Oscorp secretly creating
chemical weapons?
A polluted wellspring
of revenue!?
You may be the head
of this company,
but you're still responsible
to the stockholders
and humanity!
This news leak creates grave
problems for us all, Osborn.
But it's all Jameson's fault!
If he hadn't printed that
story in the Daily Bugle--
I have an obligation
to inform the public!
I'm a journalist first
and a stockholder second!
What are you gonna do
about this, Osborn?
I know what I'm going to do!
I'm going to urge this board
to replace you
at our next meeting!
[computer beeps]
[Norman] You!
You're running out
of time, Osborn.
Why did I ever allow myself
to be controlled by you?
Now I could lose everything!
Most unfortunate.
However, discontinuing
the manufacture of the gas
is not an option.
While, as Wilson Fisk,
I must pretend to loathe it.
As the Kingpin,
I require the gas
for my various enterprises.
If you do not
deliver it quickly,
you will be useless to me,
and you know what
that will mean to you,
and your loved one.
You heard him, Mordell.
Our lives are at stake,
and so's Harry's!
We have to finish!
We may never get a working
sample of this gas in time!
And if we do,
we have no idea how long
its effects will last!
I'll get a sample, even
if I have to do it myself!
Norman wait, you haven't
secured the air line!
[explosion echoes]
[Spider-Man] That's Oscorp!
That's gotta be trouble.
[Reporter] We interrupt
our regular programming
to bring you
this news bulletin.
There has been
a giant explosion
-at the Oscorp
Industries complex.
-Dad!
[Reporter] Firefighters
are rushing to the scene.
[fire crackles]
[Spider-Man]
Hang on to me!
Was anyone else in there?
Yes, Norman Osborn.
Osborn!
[explosion echoes]
[tense music]
I barely survived that inferno!
It doesn't look good for Osborn.
Huh, Osborn?
How can that be?
You!
What are you doing here?
My father, he's got
to be here somewhere!
We must find him!
Spider-sense
going off the scale!
[explosion echoes]
No, we can't
leave him behind!
[sirens blaring]
Dad!
Poor Harry,
there's no way his dad
could've survived.
And there's nothing I can do
now that the cavalry's arrived.
[Fisk]
We're welcoming young Harry here
to honor the memory
of his father,
whom we lost two weeks ago
in that horrible accident.
This is truly a sad
moment for all of us,
but we must name a successor.
She's absolutely right.
-[board chatters]
-Hey, wait a second!
They never recovered a body!
There's still a chance
my father survived.
Don't torture yourself
with false hope, my boy.
Don't call me boy!
I am every bit the man
that my father was.
He considered you
all his friends.
And look how you betrayed him!
If he really is gone,
then you are all guilty
of driving him
to his destruction!
Young Mr. Osborn
does have a point.
His father's demise
cannot yet be proven.
Therefore, I suggest we table
the issue of his replacement
for the moment.
I move that this meeting
be adjourned.
[tense music]
Why would young Osborn
blame us for what
happened to his father?
That poor child.
Stromm, the current confusion
has diverted
everyone's attention
away from
the chemical weapons issue.
This offers an excellent
opportunity for you
to continue your experiments.
After all this, you still--
I still want that gas, yes.
And you had better deliver.
[goblin laughing]
Aaah!
-Peter?
-Mary Jane?
Harry won't return my calls.
Will you check up on him?
I'm worried.
Of course.
I'll do what I can.
Thanks, Tiger.
Why do I always find myself
playing matchmaker between
Harry and Mary Jane?
Even though I'm
in love with her, too.
Harry, are you okay?
No, leave me alone.
Look, thanks for asking.
But I don't wanna talk
to you or anyone else!
Harry, wait! Harry!
He doesn't seem like himself.
I know what it's like
to lose both parents,
but at least I've
always had Aunt May.
[explosion echoes]
[goblin laughs]
[grunts] Hey!
Hey, what's that?
That could only
be the Hobgoblin.
Now what's he up to?
He's got Jonah Jameson!
Spider-Man!
I shoulda known you'd
be involved in this!
[Spider-Man] All right Hobgob--
You're not the Hobgoblin!
How observant you are!
No, I'm not the Hobgoblin maker!
I'm the Green Goblin,
not that you'll live long
enough for it to matter!
Aah! This goblin's
got super strength!
[web-shooters click]
He's crushed my web-shooters!
[Green Goblin laughs]
[Spider-Man]
Agility one point, gravity zero!
[explosion echoes]
I still can't believe it!
Now there are two goblins?
What does this one
want with old flat top?
Hope the Green Goblin's trail
didn't get too cold while
I fixed my web-shooters.
The Hobgoblin originally
got his weapons from Oscorp.
This green goon's weapons
looked about the same.
Maybe there's a connection.
Problem is, I'm not even sure
what to look for.
Hey, it's Harry, and he
looks mad about something!
[door slams]
Hey, these are blueprints
for goblin weapons,
and goblin muscle
enhancing armor.
Is this what Harry
was after in here?
[glider engines roaring]
Harry? Is it possible?
[tense music]
[Green Goblin laughs]
My collection is
almost complete!
Soon, the final judgment
can begin!
[camera shutters click]
Guys, that's enough for now.
[Spider-Man]
Paging Lieutenant Terri Lee.
Spider-Man!
What brings you
to the big city tonight?
This. Do you have any idea
what these high profile
kidnappings have in common?
Yeah, but why should I tell you?
Just because you
saved my life once?
Twice, but who's counting?
So far, all we know
is that the victims
are all on Oscorp's
board of directors.
Have you warned
the remaining members?
I was just about to.
You may not be fast enough!
This kidnapper moves
like lightning!
[Terri] Hey, wait!
[Spider-Man] Whenever
Felicia's mother is in town,
she stays here with Felicia.
I've got to get
to Mrs. Hardy before--
[explosion echoes]
[Green Goblin laughs]
[women scream]
Mrs. Hardy, no!
[laughing]
[Green Goblin laughing]
Leave these two alone,
and we'll settle
this just between us!
Are you joking?
The more the merrier! [laughs]
Aah! No!
[Felicia] Let go!
Double jeopardy, Spider-Man?
There's no way you can save
two of them at the same time!
- Is there!?
- No!
Are you all right?
What about my mother?
[Green Goblin laughs]
[Spider-Man] I knew
he wouldn't let her fall.
He wanted to take her hostage.
You've got
to save her, Spider-Man.
I'll do
my best to get her back.
You have my word.
[helicopter blades whirring]
The Hobgoblin?
No, someone new.
Take evasive action now!
Knock him out of the sky!
[explosion echoes]
The weapons aren't
having any effect!
He's too fast!
[grunting]
Aah!
[laughs] Didn't count on
me having super strength
or titanium cables,
did you, big boy?
[Spider-Man] Jameson, Hardy,
Fisk, and the others all gone.
And I'm up against a dead end.
Mary Jane!
Have you heard
anything from Harry?
No.
Oh, I hate myself
for saying this,
but I'm beginning to think
something awful about him.
Awful, like what?
These kidnappings in the news.
I think Harry might
be involved in them,
to avenge the death
of his father.
Mary Jane, that's crazy!
And maybe close to the truth.
You don't understand.
There's a dark side to
Harry that he keeps hidden.
It comes from the anger he felt
about growing up
unloved, lonely.
I've tried to be there for him,
but even I can't
help him sometimes.
What if that anger
has taken over
and driven him insane?
Don't you think it's possible?
[thinking] If I told her,
it would only make her
feel worse about Harry.
But would it make her
feel better about me?
Peter, what's wrong?
Talk to me.
No, I can't do it.
Harry was-- ismy friend.
He's also innocent
until proven guilty.
I don't know what
to think Mary Jane.
But I do know this,
if we love Harry,
we have to trust him
and stand by him now
when he needs us the most.
Where are you going?
I've got to be by myself,
and do some thinking.
Peter, even though
things didn't work out
between you and me,
you really are a good friend.
I care about you too, Mary Jane.
And I'm not gonna let
anything happen to you,
just in case Harry has
gone off the deep end.
[tense music]
Harry?
[screams]
Well well, someone spying on me!
Didn't you know that
curiosity killed the cat?
[laughs]
[Spider-Man] Good thing
I decided to keep
an eye on you, MJ.
[Mary Jane screams]
[click]
[tense music]
As with the others,
justice will be meted
out to you in due time,
my little miss!
But first, I must call
this court to order.
You are all charged
with the crime of hypocrisy!
A crime that destroyed
Norman Osborn.
You claimed to be his friend,
yet you filled
your newspaper with stories
to ruin his reputation!
That's a lie!
You called Osborn
a threat to humanity,
but who was it that
funded Dr. Otto Octavius,
one of the greatest
criminals of all time?!
You're mad!
Let us go!
And you, the worst of them all.
Your sins are exceeded
only by your girth!
Good thing I made your shackles
out of indestructible
titanium too, eh?
Justice will be served,
and all of you will
suffer for your crimes
against Norman Osborn!
[engine roars]
For justice is blind
no longer! [laughs]
[Spider-Man]
All you megalomaniacs
have such a weird
sense of humor!
Aah!
[energy crackles]
[explosion echoes]
[Green Goblin]
Yes! Looks like a mistrial!
This court is adjourned!
[explosion echoes]
Aah!
Somebody, help us!
What's your angle in this?
Saving your ungrateful life!
Why I oughta!
Mr. Jameson, come on!
[screams]
Careful, my dear.
[Spider-Man] Jameson,
you're an old Navy man.
You drive!
Huh, me?
What about you, Spider-Man?
I have a goblin to catch.
[spider-sense tingles]
[grunting]
[explosion echoes]
Look out!
[Jonah] Wilson,
why did you do that?
Jonah, we have to rid the
world of both of those maniacs.
[tense music]
[Spider-Man]
Okay, Harry, now we--
Norman Osborn!
No no, that weakling was
destroyed in the explosion!
The same explosion
that gave birth to me!
The exploding gas gave me
great strength!
And of course
the Hobgoblin's weapons
were right there at Oscorp,
ripe for the picking!
But they no longer
were meant for him.
The gas saw to that!
There was only one true goblin,
the Green Goblin!
Me! Give me my mask!
I must have it!
Aaaah!
You don't need this!
It represents the evil,
ugly side of your life.
-Let it go!
-I can't!
You have to, for yourself,
and for Harry!
[explosion echoes]
[Norman screams]
No, stop staring at me!
I can't lift it!
My strength, going!
We may never get a working
sample of this gas in time,
and if we do, we have no idea
how long its effects will last.
The gas,
[normal voice]
it's wearing off, no!
I need my strength back,
need my strength.
I've gotta get us
out before we both drown.
[grunting]
Not enough time to move it all!
Dad, Spider-Man!
-Is he all right?
-He'll be okay.
Do you know
of a way out of here?
Follow me!
I found the blueprint
for this underground complex
in a hidden room
in my dad's office.
Apparently this was all built
as a secret weapons
testing site.
It seemed to me
like the only place
where my dad could've
escaped from the fire.
The blueprint showed that
there was an access tunnel
under the burned-out
part of Oscorp.
But it took me a while to
find it under all that rubble.
How did you get here?
Uh, I followed a kidnapper
who called himself
the Green Goblin.
The Green Goblin?
- Did you catch him?
- Ugh, where am I?
Son!
Did the Green Goblin
hurt ya, dad?
Green who?
I-- I can't remember anything.
You won't have to
worry about the Goblin anymore.
It looks like he was destroyed
back in that complex.
And from now on,
Oscorp is out of the chemical
warfare business forever.
[audience applauds]
A bold move, Osborn.
I am in full agreement,
for the moment.
This is not
a profitable business.
Too many complications.
[Norman]
I have another announcement.
I'm going to ease up
on the affairs at Oscorp.
I need a rest.
It's time my son Harry
started playing
a more active role
in the running of Oscorp.
I'd like you by my side
if you feel you're ready.
Absolutely!
[crowd applauds]
I was wrong about Harry, but
you stood by him all the way.
You're a heck of a guy, Tiger.
He's lucky to have you
as his friend.
[Peter, thinking] He's
even luckier to have you.
Parker, if you happen to take
another picture of Spider-Man,
please, give him this.
What?
But I--
[Spider-Man]
Parker gave me your note.
It said you wanted to see me.
What for?
To thank you
for rescuing my mother,
and for always
being there for me.
You can't. Hey, wait.
[upbeat rock music]
♪ Spider-Man, Spider-Man ♪
♪ Radioactive Spider-Man ♪
♪ Spider blood, spider blood ♪
♪ Radioactive spider blood ♪
♪ Spider blood ♪
♪ Spider-Man ♪