[upbeat rock music]
♪ Spider-Man ♪
♪ Radioactive Spider-Man ♪
♪ Spider blood
Spider blood ♪
♪ Radioactive spider blood ♪
♪ Spider blood
Spider blood ♪
♪ Radioactive spider blood ♪
[explosions booming]
[growling]
♪ Spider-Man ♪
[dramatic music]
[Peter, thinking]
I wonder what Aunt May
has in mind for a wedding gift
that brings us here.
She can't afford
to give me money.
I'm just going to have
to refuse her gently.
Open it, Peter.
No. Aunt May,
I can't take these.
They're yours
and Uncle Ben's wedding rings.
Giving you these heirlooms
is my way of saying
that I want you and
Mary Jane to be as happy
with each other
as I was with Ben Parker.
-Aunt May, I--
-[spider-sense tingling]
-[booming]
-Oh, no.
Aunt May, stay in here
while I see what's going on.
No! Peter, come back!
Turn over the cash, all of it!
-Freeze!
-Melt!
-[laughs]
-[sizzling]
Whoa!
Ohh!
Sorry, Scorpion,
you've exceeded
your daily withdrawal limit.
You again!
Why do you always show up
no matter where I go?
Hey, I'm a superhero,
remember?
Stay out of there!
No way!
Well...
What are we hiding here?
Keep away from me,
you hideous man!
[gasps]
Put me down! Put me down!
Nice rings.
They'll look real good
on my Sarah's hand
when we get married.
[grunting]
[May]
Please, don't take my rings.
[Scorpion] Finders, keepers.
Not so fast.
You almost got me,
but you wouldn't hurt
-an old lady now, would ya?
-Ohh!
-No!
-Didn't think so, bug head.
-Adios!
-[Aunt May screaming]
Aunt May!
[Scorpion]
Spider-Man's gone.
You've been
pretty good insurance, lady.
You'll need insurance
if you don't give me
back those rings!
[Scorpion] Hey,
I like a lady with spunk.
[Spider-Man]
I don't wanna rile him,
or he may drop Aunt May.
Hey, you gargantuan,
green goofball!
Only a sissy would hide
behind a defenseless woman!
I couldn't agree more.
If she wasn't busy,
you'd probably send
your own mother
to fight your battles!
[Scorpion] That does it!
Good, he's let go
of Aunt May.
Calling me names is one thing,
but nobody talks trash
about my mother!
What's happenin'?!
My suit's gone crazy!
[grunting]
-Scorpion! Come back!
-[Aunt may screams]
Aunt May!
You stay away from me!
Stay away!
She's more afraid of me
than she was of the Scorpion.
[screaming]
-[Aunt may swoons]
-She's fainted,
but she's okay.
At least we got these back.
[moaning]
Oh, Aunt May,
thank goodness you're okay!
I think these
will be safer with you.
I wonder what else
is gonna get thrown in my way.
[gasping] I--
I see my father coming back!
He's gonna make
everything all right again,
but then Spider-Man attacks.
Oh! And no matter
what my father does,
he can't get away from him!
-[roars]
Ah! Spider-Man destroys him!
Spider-Man's after--
after Mary Jane, too.
He wants to take her away
from me, and he does it,
not as himself,
as Peter Parker.
[laughing sinisterly]
Dr. Kafka, these dreams
of mine seemed so real.
I really began to think Peter
was Spider-Man.
In dreams, your subconscious
colors reality,
trying to make sense out of
things that can't be explained,
things like why your father
would be involved
in the development
of the Hobgoblin devices.
Or why the woman you loved
ended up
with your best friend Peter.
-[Harry]
Or what part Spider-Man...
-[Mary Jane screams]
played in both
their disappearances?
[Ashley]
Exactly, Harry.
[gasps]
But your father
isn't the Green Goblin,
and Peter Parker is
definitely not Spider-Man.
All your life, you've struggled
with loneliness and abandonment.
Now those emotions
have twisted themselves
into acute paranoia.
You see betrayal at every turn.
Here at Ravencroft,
we'll try to help you cope
with that paranoia.
But the dreams,
are they ever going to stop?
Yes, when you discover
that you are loved
by somebody,
by your friends.
I don't have any friends.
Of course you do, Harry.
You just don't realize it.
[orderly]
Osborn, you got visitors.
I do?
[Mary Jane] I'm glad
you're with me, Liz.
I'm happy to do it.
I worry about Harry
a lot myself.
Do I detect something more here
than just friendship?
It's just that he seems
so alone, so vulnerable.
I guess I've always had a soft
spot in my heart for strays.
Liz, it's good to see you again.
Hi, Harry.
Um, I've got a special visitor.
Hello, Harry.
What are you doing here?
I have some news.
I wanted you to hear it
from me first.
-What is it?
-Peter and I are
getting married!
Harry, I didn't wanna hurt you,
but I thought
it would be unsettling
if it came from someone else.
I understand,
and I hope
you'll both be very happy.
I'd better go now.
Dr. Kafka says
I should have plenty of rest,
and I need to be alone,
so very alone.
You all right, Harry?
I'm fine, Liz, really.
[Liz] Um... well, I'll see
you again soon, Harry.
[Mary Jane] I shouldn't
have come here.
If he had found out
some other way,
it would have been worse.
At least you're gonna be
around to comfort him, Liz.
Heaven knows he needs
somebody right now.
-Harry!
-You!
Why have you been
shutting me out?
I was once your father.
It wouldn't do to cut
me out of your life.
I didn't want you in my head.
I didn't need you until now.
Now I need you!
[Peter]
I don't get it.
Wilson Fisk, Spider-Man's
enemy, wants to see me?
Ah, Mr. Parker,
how good of you to join me.
[Peter] No spider-sense,
no danger.
I read about your impending
marriage to Miss Watson,
and, frankly,
-I can't let you do it.
-What?!
That is why
I have taken the liberty
of arranging the details myself.
Why would you do that for me?
You forget
that you once saved my life.
People expect
no less from Wilson Fisk,
and, besides, it is good
publicity for a newspaper
that I have just acquired,
the Daily Beacon.
-Smile.
-[click]
I've been scooped
by the competition.
I don't believe it.
Parker, how could
you do this to me?!
I'm sure Peter didn't know Fisk
had bought a rival newspaper.
No, I swear, I--
It's bad enough
Fisk thinks he can beat me
at my own newspaper game,
but to out-scoop me
using my own employees,
I don't think so.
I wanna give Parker
a wedding that'll make
that Princess Di thing
look like a clam bake.
You do?
Yes, nothing personal,
but between Fisk and me,
this wedding business is war!
Oh, fine.
And don't worry
about paying me back.
You can work it off
over the next decade or two.
Huh? But--
Lori, get me that snake
in the grass, Wilson Fisk.
Parker, haven't
you got work to do?
[Kingpin] J. Jonah Jameson,
my new business rival.
What can I do for you?
Fisk, Peter Parker's
like a son to me.
I've been planning
his wedding for weeks.
It was going to be a surprise.
I've already hired
the top florist in Manhattan.
[Kingpin]
I'm having roses imported
from Ecuador on my private jet.
[Peter]
Unbelievable.
[Jonah]
What about the cake?
I know
the top pastry chef in Queens.
[Kingpin] And I know
the Queen's top pastry chef.
[grunting]
[Green Goblin laughing]
You've forgotten, boy,
that you've got
the power of the Green Goblin.
Osborn, what's going on in here?
Oof! [groans]
[Green Goblin laughing]
Well done, my son.
[laughing]
You're free!
[Harry] Thanks to you.
You must teach me again
how to be the Green Goblin.
Oh, I have
big plans for you,
but first you must forge
another important partnership!
This partnership
will be of great benefit
to us all, Mr. Smythe.
My employer, Silvermane,
only makes alliances
to become stronger.
I will retain ownership
of the company,
but Silvermane will control
the daily operations.
Very good, but it does come
as rather a shock
that you are the Green Goblin.
Well, it was
no less shocking for me
to learn of Silvermane's battle
against Wilson Fisk,
the criminal known
as the Kingpin.
How did you find out?
I was told
by the same third party
who brought us together.
He wishes to remain anonymous.
No matter. With Oscorp's
manufacturing capabilities
and my technology, Silvermane
now has the extra muscle
he needs to take on the Kingpin.
And speaking of muscle,
Scorpion,
is your suit
functioning properly?
You fixed it real good,
Mr. Smythe.
Meet my new assistant.
I thought he would prove
useful to you.
He can be the point man
for this army of robots
you are going to build for me!
Can you begin right away?
As promised, but why
in such force so quickly?
Like Silvermane,
I too have a powerful enemy,
and I won't stop until he's
reduced to a whimpering heap!
[welding torch buzzing]
Finished.
I call it
the Goblin Robo Warrior.
I'm not interested
in your dramatic flair
for names, Smythe.
Can it do the job?
Please observe.
What one can't do, many can.
[laughing]
Excellent! Excellent!
[Peter] I really wanna thank you
for being my best man, Robbie.
I always thought
Harry would do this,
but with him ill
and now missing--
I understand, Peter.
You've got the rings, don't you?
I do unless they jumped out
since you asked me
two minutes ago.
Come on, Debra,
I wanna get a seat up front.
-[Felicia] Flash! Flash!
-Huh? What?
-Felicia Hardy?
-[kiss]
How are you, Flash?
You look great.
Where have you been?
-In Europe, overseeing
my mother's business.
-[horse whinnies]
[Flash] Hey, look.
Huh. Now that's
what I call style.
-Indeed.
-Hmph!
Smythe, this army
of robots is excellent.
They're all programmed
to obey your every command.
Then my first command is
let's go attend a wedding!
-A wedding?
-Follow me!
[playing classical music]
We are gathered here
today to unite these two
in the bonds of holy matrimony.
[ominous music]
And if there is anyone
who objects to this union,
let them speak now
or forever hold their peace.
-[spider-sense tingling]
-No. Please, not now!
[screams]
I object to this marriage!
Ah ha ha ha ha ha!
-She's going to marry me!
-Mary Jane!
It'll be a private ceremony!
Attendants!
[guests screaming]
There's nothing
I can do as Peter Parker.
I've got to get into costume!
Come on, Aunt May,
let's get you to safety!
-Let's scram!
-[lasers blasting]
Felicia, where are you?!
This is an outrage!
Better an outrage
than an obituary!
Let's beat it!
[shouting and screaming]
There, this is more like it.
Nice and quiet.
Just right for a wedding.
[Spider-Man] Hey, tinhead.
-Spider.
-Cat!
Looks like I got here
just in time.
I didn't know you were
on the guest list, Spider-Man.
[sizzling]
-[Harry] Let's get on with it.
-[Mary Jane] Please!
Mary Jane, I'll show you
that I'm one you really want.
I know who I want, Harry,
and it's not you!
Marry me now, MJ, or I'll
blast us all to smithereens!
[swooning]
No, not now!
Get up, you buffoon!
Landon, that last Mega-Slayer
that Smythe made
before he left my employ.
Activate it immediately.
Hurry!
[robotic whirring]
Stupid wall-crawler!
You ruin everything!
Stay put, blast you!
[grunts]
[groans]
-Fisk!
-I'll rip his transistors out!
A bad idea, young lady.
You see, I'm here to help you.
These robots are obviously
the work of Alistair Smythe.
If he and Silvermane
are allied with Osborn,
it poses a serious threat
to my business.
I cannot let them succeed.
That's enough
out of you, big boy!
Gargan, your corrosives have
no effect on this robot.
-Well, what about this?!
-You figure it out!
[Scorpion]
Aah-aah-aah-aah!
Aah-aah-aah!
I broke him? A pity.
I was just beginning
to have fun.
[coughs]
Get up!
Now let's get married, blast it!
Begin the ceremony!
[stammering] Uh, dearly...
[Mary Jane screams]
Get on with it!
Do you take Mary Jane Watson
to be your wedded wife?
I do!
And do you take this man
to be your wedded husband?
She does!
I don't have time for this.
I've gotta get inside!
[Black Cat] Hurry, Spider,
the coast is clear
for you to get inside now,
and, Spider,
it was nice working
with you again.
[Harry] Get on with it!
Then I now pronounce you--
-Let them go, Harry.
-Never!
Stay back, or I'll
blow this place sky high!
Harry, if you
really love Mary Jane,
you must let her go.
Oh, really?
Suppose I'd rather destroy her
than see her
in the arms of my archenemy?
Harry, you think
you know who your enemies are,
but aren't you forgetting
who your friends are?
-Liz?
-Deep down, you must know
that you and Mary Jane
aren't meant to be.
She loves Peter,
but that doesn't mean
that she won't
always be your friend.
No! You're confusing me!
The Green Goblin
is my only friend!
You're wrong, Harry!
I'm your friend,
and I was hoping that some day,
we'd be more than friends.
I love you, Harry.
You-- You love me?
Yes, but if we're
to have a future together,
then it has to begin now.
Someone loves me. Ohh...
Take me back to Ravencroft, Liz.
I'm not well, you know,
and I hate weddings anyway.
[chuckling]
What the--
[alarm whooping]
It was so nice to partner
with you, my dear.
If ever you need a job--
Can it, Fisk.
Next time I'm going to do
a job on you.
[Mary Jane] I just can't
believe it ended this way.
Yeah, I guess you'd probably
like to go home and--
No way. I'm late enough
for my wedding as it is.
-Are you all right?
-Um, yes, I am.
Uh, Spider-Man,
could you go get Peter for me
so we can get married finally?
[minister]
The ring, please.
Oh, Peter, it's so beautiful!
[minister] I'll skip
the "for better or worse part,"
since we've been
through that already.
So I now I now pronounce
ya husband and wife.
[cheering]
[applause]
Congratulations, Parker.
Here's a little something
for you.
[Peter]
What's this, car keys?
My boy, it's a wedding gift
Wilson Fisk didn't think of.
Oh, Mr. Jameson,
that's so generous of you.
Yeah, I don't know what to say.
No need to
thank me now, Parker.
Your coach awaits.
Well, you're right
about one thing, Mr. Jameson.
Wilson Fisk would
never have thought
-of giving us a gift like this.
-[rough-running engine]
[Jonah]
Think nothing of it, my boy.
No, it can't end this way!
You can't leave me
alone like this!
Harry, where are you?!
Harry! Harry!
[upbeat rock music]
♪ Spider-Man, Spider-Man ♪
♪ Radioactive Spider-Man ♪
♪ Spider blood, spider blood ♪
♪ Radioactive spider blood ♪
♪ Spider blood ♪
♪ Spider-Man ♪