[Kingpin] Previously
onSpider-Man.
[male voice] Amazing.
His speed, his agility.
[Kingpin] We've
got to destroy him.
because with Spider-Man, you
don't get a second chance.
[Spider-Man] So who's
on my tail this time?
You've failed, Smythe.
My father is not a failure.
It'll be just your size
when it's finished.
Is that why you're working
for Osborn,
in exchange for this?
Spider-Man, that loose
cannon must be removed.
[Felicia] I love surprises.
See what you think of this one.
[Smythe] The Black Widow
can neutralize
all of Spider-Man's powers.
[Newscaster]
The moment all America
has been waiting for.
The unmasking of Spider-Man.
-What was that?
-Flash Thompson.
-Two of 'em?
-[man] Get him!
[Spider-Man]
Think fast, Spidey.
Remember our deal, no
Spider-splat, no hover-chair.
[Spider-Man]
Take a dive, Widow.
-My father, did he get out?
-[explosion booms]
[Kingpin] I was an associate
of your fathers.
Now, I want to be an
associate of yours,
so you can destroy the
man who is responsible
for your father's
disappearance, Spider-Man.
♪ Spider-Man, Spider-Man ♪
♪ Radioactive Spider-Man ♪
♪ Spider blood, spider blood ♪
♪ Radioactive spider blood ♪
♪ Spider-Man, Spider-Man ♪
[Spider-Man] I'm sure
Mrs. Watson's niece
has a very nice personality,
Aunt May,
but I hate blind dates.
Okay, Aunt May, if it makes
you happy you can tell
Mrs. Watson that I'll take her
niece out...
and but just this one time.
Yeah, okay bye.
[electronic beeping]
Blind dates are
like the lottery.
The odds are so
stacked against you,
you're nuts if you expect
to ever hit the jackpot.
Huh?
The Black Widow?
I thought I destroyed
that thing months ago.
Someone's rebuilt it.
Is Spencer Smythe
still alive?
A microwave relay dish.
This oughta sizzle
your circuits.
[electric crackling]
I better check this out, huh?
Another one and it's bigger.
[groans]
Good thing I
reloaded my webbing.
Think fast web-head,
think fast.
Only a few seconds.
Yes! He nails the dismount.
Didn't mean to drop in
without a reservation.
Look out!
[mechanical whirring]
[indistinct chattering]
I don't know where you
came from,
but thanks to my Spider-Tracer,
I'm sure gonna know
where you're headed.
[electronic beeping]
The wall-crawler
is still alive.
Not for long, I've designed
this operation perfectly,
and it's going according
to plan, I won't fail.
Let us hope not, I'm rather
hard on employees who do.
Remember, my employment here
is a temporary arrangement.
And you remember this
lab becomes yours
if and only if you
destroy Spider-Man.
It may be Kingpin's money
and Kingpin's lab,
but revenge for what happened
to my father will be mine.
[electronic whirring]
I barely stopped
The Black Widow,
how am I gonna stop you?
A freeze ray.
Wow, this is enough to
give me arachnophobia.
The Black Widow, it's back.
How can I deal with two
Spider-Slayers at once.
Gotta start somewhere.
And now for you, huh?
Mommy, it's a big bug,
I want one.
-Cooper.
-No, drop her!
[dog barking]
-Spider-Man.
-Get away from here, hurry.
Oh boy, I should've
taken my own advice.
[grunts]
If I get myself out of this,
I'm gonna need to
track you down too.
[mechanical cranking]
[coughing]
Excellent!
He looks rather tiny
for a superhero.
Mr. Jameson, I have something
that might interest you.
What's with all the
secrecy, Smythe?
[Smythe] Good evening,
Mr. Jameson.
-Where's Spider-Man?
-There he is.
Ready for your inspection.
Well, what do ya know?
I've waited a long time
to see you apprehended.
Now let's see who's
under that mask.
[Spider-Man] Hey, hold it,
when was the last time
you washed your hands?
Hey, what gives, Smythe?
[Spider-Man] It's obvious,
he wants a mate and
you're the lucky guy.
You called me here to
witness Spider-Man's capture.
I must admit,
I had an ulterior motive.
[Jonah] What are you doing?
[Spider-Man] No, no, no,
take it back.
It clashes with the
color of my costume.
A perfect fit,
these indestructible manacles
contain a powerful explosive.
It's set to detonate
in one hour.
[Spider-Man]
Hey, don't look at me.
Maybe you didn't deliver
his paper this morning.
-What are you, nuts?
-You had to ask?
You and your
web-slinging friend's
petty rivalries
destroyed my father.
His only dream was
to see me walk again,
-a dream you both shattered.
-Excuse me,
but your father attacked
me with a Spider-Slayer.
Yeah, Smythe, you were
in on that whole deal.
Why don't you attach yourself
to this bomb and
leave me out of it?
[Spider-Man] Have you ever
thought of becoming
a family therapist?
Quiet, you're both responsible
and so are your associates,
Flash Thompson, Eddie Brock,
and Norman Osborn.
[Spider-Man] You hate a
lot of people, Smythe.
Must be rough
around the holidays.
If you let me go, I can fund
your research, set up a lab.
[Spider-Man] Forget it JJ,
he's not playing
with a full deck, you
should understand that.
You should be grateful,
Jameson.
When Spider-Man
meets his demise,
you'll have the privilege
of sharing his fate.
Can't you pry this thing off?
[Spider-Man] You want a
trial separation already.
-I understand but... I'm hurt.
-Enough talk.
My Spider-Slayers
are programmed
to transport you away.
Then they'll eradicate those
who helped you
destroy my father.
[Spider-Man] Gonna get more
sleep tonight than usual.
Oh, my aching head.
Get up Jameson, we don't
have much time to track
those slayers before they get
to Thompson, Brock, and Osborn.
Look at this, you're
severely bruising my wrist.
[Spider-Man] Coyotes
caught in traps
chew through their own
legs, you could try that.
Okay mister smart-mouth,
what if I decide
to just sit here
and not go anywhere.
[Spider-Man] Look bright eyes,
until I can figure
out a way to get this
bomb off us, you're
coming along for the ride.
So fasten your safety belt.
[Jameson screaming]
[Flash] We had a great
time tonight, Felicia.
Naturally, you were with me.
-Hey, Flash. Hi, Felicia.
-Hello, Harry.
So, how's it going buddy?
Great but it'd be a lot better
if you made yourself scarce.
Oh, oh, oh, right.
See ya later.
-Flash.
-Now what?
Is this another one of
your gags, Flash Thompson?
No.
Felicia run,
it's after me again.
Help, help!
Why do these bugs
have a thing for me?
[Spider-Man] Looks like
we got here just in time.
-Lasers? Exactly what I need.
-You're crazy.
-What are you doing?
-Just cutting the ties
that bind.
Just get out of here, run,
I'll keep this thing busy.
Time for me to give
this act the hook.
Come on kid, let the
bugs fight it out.
We gotta make some calls.
[engine starts]
[Spider-Man] I hope nobody
wants to see my union card
or my exterminator's license.
That's got to stop him.
[electronic warbling]
[Jameson] Robbie, get a crew
out to ESU right now
and get me a line
on Eddie Brock.
No, I don't want
to re-hire him.
You gotta call my dad.
[man] Hello, Jameson, what
can I do for you?
Another Spider-Slayer?
Don't worry, I can handle it.
Get me security.
[Editor] Jameson at
The Bugle says he
fired you because
you're bad news, Brock.
It's a lie, I'm telling you.
I was set up by Spider-Man.
Look,all I need is a chance
to prove myself.
Well, lucky for you I
happen to need a reporter.
Just stay out of trouble.
Oh, that's great,
that's great, thank you.
I promise you will not
get any trouble from me.
[rumbling]
[crowd screaming]
[metallic clanking]
Another Spider-Slayer.
Why is it after me?
[car horn honking]
[Spider-Man] Looks like
the Spider-Slayer
found its next target.
My lucky day.
I get to save Eddie Brock,
and still have time
to be blown to bits.
You.
You just won't stop 'til
you ruin me, will you?
Use your head for once, Brock.
I'm trying to save your life.
This thing's stronger than me
but fortunately,
it's not smarter.
[electric crackling]
Shocking!
[sirens blaring at distance]
My office. My newspaper.
Wrecked.
Jameson was right,
you're fired.
Oh, no, no,
he's done it to me again.
I'll get even with you.
I'll get even with you if
it's the last thing I do.
My masterwork is done.
[mechanical humming]
Why'd they call out
those robot tanks?
I think that's the reason.
[electric zapping]
[Spider-Man] Sounds like
something's attacking
Oscorp, but what?
Well that answers my question.
The biggest Spider-Slayer yet
and I have only minutes
to stop it
before this bomb blows.
[electric zapping]
Launch the heli-drones.
[Spider-Man] Remember to
never try and crash
one of Osborn's parties.
Don't worry, it's harmless now.
[mechanical whirring]
[indistinct chatter]
[Spider-Man] I'm out of
web fluid.
Now's a good a time as
any to change cartridges.
[mechanical whirring]
[electric zapping]
Okay Spidey, which
to deal with first,
this bomb or that
mechanical monster?
Oops, that settles that.
So much for Mr. Osborn's
place of business.
-[tires screeching]
-[electric zapping]
[Spider-Man] That was
close but I'm still alive,
for another 15 minutes anyway.
Liquid oxygen, hmm.
This stuff's almost 200
degrees below zero Centigrade.
It'll affect these
manacles the same way
the Slayer's Freeze Ray
worked on that street lamp.
Ah, another example of better
living through chemistry.
Not much time,
I gotta move fast.
I'll take this little
plaything with me.
[tires screeching]
[car horn honking]
[groaning]
Come on Osborn, this is the
worst possible time for a nap.
[electric zapping]
You stay here Norman,
I've got a present to deliver.
Hey rivet head,
let's play tag. You're it.
[mechanical whirring]
Perfect, just the
right position.
I hate to borrow
someone else's line but
it's clobbering time.
Bull's eye!
I've never liked
Osborn that much,
but for Harry's sake,
I'm glad he's okay.
Oh!
Now how did that...
My machines,
my beautiful machines.
A deal's a deal, Smythe.
You promised me you'd
destroy Spider-Man,
and you'll work for
me until you do.
[mechanical humming]
There's nothing left.
What a night.
I'm battered, bruised and to
top it off, my costume's torn.
And what do I get
for all my troubles?
Nothing, life never seems to
have any big reward for me.
[sighs]
The worst thing about
a secret identity
is you can't ask someone
else to do your sewing.
[Aunt May] Peter, I hope
you're getting ready
for your date with
Mary Jane Watson tonight.
My blind date,
I completely forgot.
Oh, why didn't I just
let Smythe's bugs eat me.
[coughs] I'm not feeling
too well, Aunt May.
Well you do feel warm but
she'll be here any minute.
-[doorbell rings]
-That's her.
Go answer the door, Peter.
[sighs]
Don't I get a last meal?
Face it tiger,
you just hit the jackpot.
♪ Spider-Man, Spider-Man ♪
♪ Radioactive Spider-Man ♪
♪ Spider blood, spider blood ♪
♪ Radioactive spider blood ♪
♪ Spider-Man ♪