[woman]
Previously onSpider-Man.
Parker, my father.
I have been looking for a way
of expressing my gratitude.
Just place
your future in my hands.
-Aah! Oh, dear!
-Hold it right there!
We want that computer disc.
It's diagnostic data!
[Choi] We knew somebody was
selling government secrets.
Better get yourself
a good lawyer!
Never met
a blind lawyer before.
Well, I'm your man.
-[Peter] You framed me?
-I engineered your escape
to leave no doubt that you
and Spider-Man are guilty.
-[gasping] Who are you?
-The Daredevil.
Look, I need that
disc to clear myself!
[Daredevil] More likely
you're planting evidence
against Parker!
-[man] The bomb's gonna blow!
-Look out!
[upbeat rock music]
♪ Spider-Man ♪
♪ Radioactive Spider-Man ♪
♪ Spider blood
Spider blood ♪
♪ Radioactive spider blood ♪
♪ Spider blood
Spider blood ♪
♪ Radioactive spider blood ♪
[explosions booming]
[growling]
♪ Spider-Man ♪
[dramatic music]
[explosion]
Nice save!
-Thanks.
-[explosion]
We've gotta get that
data disc before it melts away
any chance
at clearing Peter Parker.
Here, wouldn't want
you to lose this.
Come on!
[Daredevil] Why are you so
interested in helping Parker?
I like his work.
He always shoots my good side.
[explosion]
Uh-oh!
[grunting]
Daredevil, hang on!
I hate to leave you,
but if I don't get that disc,
Peter Parker will be cooked!
I hope this software
isn't soft-boiled yet!
Download complete!
-Yes!
-Get away from that computer!
He's done for!
Let's get outta here!
[dramatic music]
This time I'm getting
you out of here.
How? You can't see your way
through this smoke!
[Daredevil] Maybe some
of us look at the world
differently than others.
Thanks, you saved me!
Actually, I was
saving Peter Parker.
Excuse me?
You got that disc, right?
Oh, yeah, right, the disc!
This data will clear Parker.
Get it to your pal,
Matt Murdock.
I'm sure he'll be grateful,
as I am, for everything.
Hey, we're even.
[Daredevil] Since you and I
appear to be on the same team,
I should tell you who our
real adversary is in all this.
His name is Wilson Fisk.
The entrepreneur
and the philanthropist?
[Daredevil]
That's all a facade.
Fisk is really a devious
criminal mastermind
-who calls himself--
-[explosion]
The Kingpin.
Wilson Fisk?
Wait a minute,
that would explain
why the Hobgoblin
was after him!
My spider sense!
[Daredevil] What?
Federal agents, freeze!
Let's split up. Move!
Stop them!
[Spider-Man] It's time
to pack it in for the night.
Let's hope Daredevil
got away, too!
[sirens wailing]
Agent Choi, I need to you
talk about Peter Parker.
He is no traitor,
and you certainly can't
blame him for this.
I'm a little busy, Detective.
Have you followed up
on the other leads?
Who's the guy in the red suit?
-How are the Fisks involved?
-[engine starts]
Why are you rushing to judgment
before you've
fully investigated?
As far as I'm concerned,
this investigation is over!
All that's left
is capturing Parker.
You're out
of your jurisdiction here.
Now get lost or I'll have you
hauled in for a reprimand!
[somber music]
Every trace of the secret data
has gone up in flames.
And so has my building.
Yes, but my plan to frame
Parker is succeeding.
Wrong,
Peter Parker has escaped.
-What?
-Fools!
With Parker loose, the whole
scheme may be in jeopardy!
It's worse than you think.
Take a look at
what our security camera taped.
How did Spider-Man
know where to look?
[Fisk]
Who is leaking information?
This is all your fault!
It was your bad idea to frame
Parker in the first place.
But the feds were onto
our data smuggling operation.
It seemed
like the most elegant way
to throw them off our trail.
We're under even more
scrutiny now than before!
And at this moment,
Spider-Man may hold
the most incriminating
evidence against me.
-[reporter] May Parker--
-Wait, listen to this!
--the aunt of fugitive
Peter Parker,
reportedly collapsed
in her home.
She's been rushed
to Mercy Memorial Hospital.
Ah, a glimmer of light
through the gloom.
Should Parker be stupid enough
to visit his ailing aunt,
see to it that
we are there to welcome him.
We may have lost the data disc,
but we will have Parker!
[somber music]
Mr. Murdock?
Hmm, looks like I've got
the place to myself.
-[click]
-Let's see
what the news has to say
about tonight's little bonfire.
Parker's aunt collapsed and
was rushed to Mercy Memorial.
-What?!
-At this time,
there's no word on
how serious her condition is.
Aunt May!
-[elevator bell dings]
-Good news, Peter.
Daredevil has given us
the evidence we need
to appeal your conviction.
Matt, my Aunt May's
in the hospital.
I've gotta see her right away!
I'd have to advise
against that.
You're still and escaped felon.
It would be wiser to
cooperate with the authorities
and turn yourself in.
I can't waste
the time right now!
If anything should
happen to her...
You have no idea what it's
like to lose someone you love.
Maybe I know better
than you think.
As your attorney,
I must advise against this,
but as your friend,
I understand.
I'll take the disc to the feds.
Maybe I can persuade them
to suspend their dragnet.
Just be careful.
You're still a fugitive.
If anyone sees you,
they might shoot first
and ask questions later.
I won't be seen.
[suspenseful music]
[Mary Jane]
Will she be okay, Doctor?
Well, it's too soon to tell.
She's been under
a lot of stress.
I'll check back
in a little while.
That Peter, what he puts May
through is unforgivable!
I don't care
what trouble he's in!
His place is here
with his ailing aunt.
If I were Peter Parker,
wild horses couldn't
keep me away.
I swear, sometimes I think
May would be better off
if they caught Peter
and locked him up until--
Aunt Anna, that's enough!
I won't listen to this anymore!
What was that all about?
Mary Jane doesn't like hearing
bad things about Peter.
[Harry] You okay?
Not really, Harry, no.
It's Peter,
I'm so worried about him!
[Matt] The data on this disc
proves that my client
is innocent!
How did you get it?
Let's just say Peter has
people looking out for him.
I need a receipt.
It's the only copy.
Time is of the essence,
Mr. Murdock.
My people are tracking Parker.
They might shoot him on sight.
Point well taken.
I must make
immediate arrangements
to protect
and exonerate Parker.
[beeping]
-[line rings]
-[man] Yes?
I have the package you wanted.
[dramatic music]
[gasping] Peter!
What are you doing here?
There are police everywhere!
I need your help.
You haven't given
up on me, have you?
Never.
You can always count on me.
I'm sorry, I didn't mean to--
Harry and I are--
I know. Listen, I must get
in to see Aunt May.
Can you think of a way?
Leave it to me!
Oh, there you are, Dr. Peters!
Mrs. Parker's taken
a turn for the worse. Hurry!
[somber music]
Aunt May, can you hear me?
Peter, you-- you're here!
Everything's gonna be okay.
Mr. Murdock has evidence
that will clear me!
I told them you were innocent.
My Peter is a good boy!
She should rest now, Peter.
I'd better get out of here.
I may be placing
both of you in danger.
-[thinking] Now what?
-You!
Why, of all the nerve!
Anna Watson
activated my spider sense?
She must be really mad at me!
Oh, Anna, it's wonderful!
That nice lawyer, Mr. Murdock,
has proof
that Peter is innocent!
I'm happy to hear it,
Peter, really.
I've gotta go.
There are still a few people
who haven't heard the news.
I see. Then you need help
getting out of here.
Let me do what I can.
Why is my spider sense
still going crazy?
Oh, excuse me, Doctor,
have you seen
my niece Mary Jane?
It's sure nice of you
to help, Aunt Anna.
Oh, I'm not doing this
entirely for Peter.
-[spider-sense tingling]
-It's more for my own benefit.
[whooshing]
-[gasps]
-[Peter] Chameleon!
[both groaning]
[tires screeching]
[suspenseful music]
[Richard]
Nice work, Agent Choi.
My father knew his investment
in you would pay off.
[engine revving]
[keys clacking]
[beep]
Thanks for calling me
right away, Detective Lee.
That disc was Parker's
one chance to be exonerated.
There'll be the devil
to pay for this!
The data on this disc
could've destroyed my father.
He'll be pleased
with all we've done.
What is it, Richard?
Father, I have
the data disc and Parker.
I've taken care
of all your problems!
Splendid!
I shall await news
that you've eradicated both.
You see, Smythe?
My son has cleaned up
your mess.
How touching.
It is. I must say,
it pleases me greatly
knowing that my relationship
with my son
is nothing like I went through
with my own father.
Your father?
It occurs to me I know
very little about your past.
What was your father like?
What is the best way to say it?
I believe,
"small-time hood" sums it up,
but my father
wanted more out of life.
He wanted to become
a member of the Mob.
As for myself, I was lonely,
ostracized
because of my weight.
My father had great dreams,
but things never
went my father's way.
[men groaning]
Willy, what are you doin' here?
Come on, let's go!
[Fisk]
Whatever my father touched...
-[siren]
-turned positively putrid.
[wind whistling]
-[glass breaks]
-[alarm ringing]
Over the years,
I tried to join my father
in his business pursuits.
I wanted
to gain his acceptance.
-[sirens]
-I failed.
[straining]
[Fisk's Father] Sometimes
sacrifices must be made.
Sorry, son,
that's the way things are!
[siren wailing]
[guns cocking]
Young man, this court
is willing to show leniency,
but you must name
your accomplice!
[Fisk]
Now I was all alone.
I realized
I was going to have to
learn to survive
or be destroyed!
And I did learn.
By the time I got out, I had
acquired all the skills needed
to begin building
my criminal empire.
I even took a new name-- Fisk--
but I quickly became
known as the Kingpin.
I used my mastery
of technology to break
into the law enforcement
computer system
and to eradicate all records
of my pervious criminal
identity.
Only one thing remained
to link me to the past.
We found him for you, Kingpin.
It is you!
Nobody believed me,
but I knew the famous Kingpin
was really my boy Willy!
Wrong!
As far as the world must know,
Willy ceased to exist
when you left him in prison.
Now it's your turn.
No! Please!
Willy, don't do this!
I knew you were ruthless,
but this?
Sacrifices must be made.
[dramatic music]
Agh! Let her go!
You've got me!
[groaning]
[thinking]
It's hard to believe
after all the risks
I took as Spider-Man,
that Parker's gonna be
the one to take the fall.
If only I could save
the woman I love.
You've been here before.
This time,
I'll make sure it works.
It will all be over
in a matter of minutes.
Peter, what's going on?
[alarm beeping]
It's Terri Lee!
What's she doing here?!
We'll have to fight.
Police!
-[lasers blasting]
-Take cover!
[men grunting]
[men screaming and grunting]
The air!
I can hardly breathe!
Time to even the odds!
[heartbeats thumping]
[men grunting]
-Look out!
-[clink]
-[Peter wheezing]
-[Terri] Hyah!
[both grunting]
-[Mary Jane gasping]
-[Terri grunts]
Nice work, Detective.
I cannot bear incompetence.
Execute the contingency plan!
Take cover over here.
I'll be back.
[suspenseful music]
[webs whooshing]
[grunting]
[blows thudding]
With all that movement,
my spider-sense
can't lock in on who's who!
[groans]
[Spider-Man] No doubt now
who the imposter is!
Only the real thing could do
that with a billy club.
Catch ya later.
I've gotta check on a friend.
-[Mary Jane] Haah!
-[man groans]
Nice moves!
Hey, I'm a single woman
living in New York.
Self-defense classes
are a must.
-Unh!
-Going my way?
-[laser buzzing]
-Chameleon!
Book him.
-Up there!
-[helicopter whirring]
[Spider-Man]
I know this place!
I was here when a crook named
The Hobgoblin took it over!
Good, Since you're
familiar with the layout,
why don't you
keep security busy
while I settle
some unfinished business?
Uh, can you guys tell me
where the little spiders'
room is?
Where is the other one?
Right here, Kingpin,
and the name's Daredevil.
You would have to be
a daredevil to dare
to challenge me!
I'm taking your family!
The police have your son,
and I have you.
My son?!
-[both grunting]
-[thudding]
Hah! [growling]
Aah!
You are weak, useless!
You are weak, Willy, useless!
[grunting]
This time, the fight is mine!
Father, no!
[both yelling]
Now you're mine!
No, you're mine!
-[zapping]
-Aaah!
[Spider-Man]
Hold on, Moby Dick!
Time for me to reel you in!
-[punch lands]
-[Spider-Man grunts]
[web shooters hissing]
Empty? Not now!
[heartbeat thumping]
We can't let him get away!
[helicopter whirring]
Hang onto your cowl!
Take her down, pal!
The only thing
going down is you!
[Daredevil] Let's hope
he's good at blind landings!
[helicopter whirring]
[whooshing]
[groans]
[Spider-Man] Helpless
as a beached whale.
I'm afraid the Kingpin's had
the last laugh again.
[Spider-Man] Chameleon!
How did you guess?
I can see through disguises.
The real Kingpin
must've made the switch
back at Crime Central.
Well, at least
he's still got the CD-ROM
that proves Peter Parker
is innocent.
Wait a minute, if you can
see through disguises,
does that mean
you've seen through mine?
No, I have respected
your right to privacy.
I'm a big believer
in the Constitution
and the law.
This court finds
Richard Fisk, Susan Choi,
and the criminal known
as the Chameleon guilty.
[crowd gasping and muttering]
This court is willing
to show leniency,
but you must name
your accomplices, if any.
Sacrifices must be made.
[Fisk] Parker, I must apologize
for the trouble
you went through.
I did not realize my son
was stealing secrets.
[thinking] I can't believe
I have to swallow this,
but if I let on that
I know he's a criminal,
he can figure out who I am.
Apology accepted.
[thinking]
But watch it, Kingpin,
Spider-Man now knows the truth.
I've had it
with your bungling, Smythe.
Your days here are numbered!
Leave me!
[dramatic music]
Now how many days
shall I have to wait
for my son
to exact his revenge?
Jonah, I don't understand.
Why won't you let me
tell Parker
that you paid for his defense?
It'd spoil my image!
Besides, I don't want Parker
getting the idea I like him.
Which reminds me, Robbie,
who told you you could
offer Parker his job back?
That goofy kid couldn't focus
if his life depended on it!
[Spider-Man]
So, you're leaving?
Murdock's been called to D.C.
on special assignment
for the Justice Department.
It's up to you to hold
Kingpin at bay here
while Murdock and I gather
enough legal evidence
to put him behind bars forever.
You know, I just realized
that I don't know
much about you.
How did you and Murdock
first join forces?
It's unfortunate
that we masked men
must hide so much
from the world,
but there is one thing
you do need to know.
Behind this mask is
the face of a friend,
and a lifelong partner
in your war against Kingpin.
Thanks.
Goodbye, Daredevil.
Don't worry,
I'm going to fight the Kingpin
to the bitter end, so help me.
[upbeat rock music]
♪ Spider-Man, Spider-Man ♪
♪ Radioactive Spider-Man ♪
♪ Spider blood, spider blood ♪
♪ Radioactive spider blood ♪
♪ Spider blood ♪
♪ Spider-Man ♪