[Peter] Previously
onSpider-man.
Mariah Crawford was right,
I took her serum too soon.
MJ, I can't go out tonight.
I'm coming over right now.
-Peter!
-[Peter] Sorry, Aunt May.
Peter Parker doesn't
exist anymore.
I'll stay with you.
Whatever happens,
we'll face it together.
Please, help me.
Where are you going?
To Morbius.
I've got to help him.
But you're ill!
[gunfire]
[grunting]
[Spider-man] Who are you?
I'm The Punisher.
I punish those who
prey on the innocent.
You kidnapped that student.
[screams]
Put out an APB for Spider-man.
Now I'm going to take you
where you can get help.
No!
I'm not ready.
Felicia.
[screams]
[Robbie] Jonah, your mystery man
calls himself The Punisher.
[gunfire]
[Punisher] Gotcha.
Come on out, and I'll
make it quick and clean.
[growls]
["Spider-man Theme"]
♪ Spider-man, Spider-man ♪
♪ Radioactive Spider-man ♪
♪ Spider blood, spider blood ♪
♪ Radioactive spider blood ♪
♪ Spider-man, Spider-man ♪
[dramatic music]
-[crashing]
-[screaming]
[growling]
[explosions]
[growls]
Battle van, key on my location.
Go escape tactic.
Code 81452.
[growling]
[car screeches]
Open door!
Escape, code red.
[growls]
Engage autopilot return to base.
Go!
[crashing]
[screaming]
[car screeches]
[man] Frank.
Frank, do you copy?
Frank, are you there?
[Frank] Yeah.
[man] What happened, big guy?
I looked the devil
square in the eyes,
and I blinked.
It had ugly claws, six of them,
and it looked like something
out of a horror movie.
Let me see that.
[Officer] Lieutenant Lee.
Put out an APB for Spider-man.
Has Spider-man mutated into
some kind of man-spider?
Authorities are
wondering if there's
a connection between
Spider-man,
the mysterious plasma-draining
disease afflicting New Yorkers,
and stories of a
frightening spider monster
who's terrorizing the Empire
State University campus.
And if there is a
connection, what could it be?
Sergei, Spider-man has mutated.
He's dangerous.
You must come at once!
Please!
Frank, you've gotta drop it now.
Can't.
[laser gunfire]
But if Spider-man's turned
into some kind of monster,
this isn't your kind of fight.
We were just gonna do a
simple high-profile job
to get you in good graces
with the law, that's all.
Are you listening to me?
You're not in this
to fight monsters.
Wrong!
That's exactly what
I'm in this to fight.
Monsters.
I'm gonna hunt that
thing down and destroy it
before anybody gets hurt.
-Are you gonna help?
-Yeah.
Sure, anything you want.
It's gonna take hours
for us to prepare.
You think anybody will see that
man-spider in the meantime?
[Frank] Nah, if there's
anything left of his human mind
my guess is he'll
find someplace to hide
to avoid being spotted
in the daylight.
When the time
comes I'll find him
with that tracer I put
on his leg last night.
For now, let him get
his beauty sleep.
He's gonna need it, big time.
[ominous music]
[gasps]
Mrs. Parker.
I must have nodded off.
Mary Jane, dear,
you've slept all night.
It's morning.
Morning?
Where are you going?
To the police.
Peter never came
home last night.
What?
You know how Peter is.
Always following that
awful Spider-man around,
taking those pictures.
Now they say on the
news that Spider-man's
turned into a monster.
I'm so frightened.
Peter could be in horrible
trouble, or worse.
I'm going to the
police with you.
[May] No, you don't have to.
If anything's wrong I must know.
I care for Peter, and
if he's been harmed,
I don't know what I'd do.
[plane landing]
[sniffing]
New York.
I have worked all night
to create an anti-toxin,
but I must administer
it to him soon
or he will be that
man-spider creature forever.
Oh, Sergei,
I'm so glad you're here.
My Calypso, you must rest.
We have a long
night ahead of us.
While I do not have
the super strength
of a scientifically
created madman anymore,
I intend to be no less a hunter.
Sergei, did you bring your
ceremonial hunting garb?
Does the lion hunt
without his mane?
[dramatic music]
Got the anti-corrosive shield?
Yeah.
Frank, these are
awfully big toys.
You worry too much.
Maybe I'm getting
too old for all this.
I mean we've been
at it since 'nam.
Don't you ever get tired?
Never.
Then I guess I
can't quit either.
Somebody's gotta keep you alive.
Frank, be careful, okay?
I'll do what I have to.
War journal entry,
tracer's working.
Gonna see some action tonight.
I hunger.
Felicia, my love.
No!
I must keep trying to rid myself
of this horrible
need for plasma.
I must do this for you, Felicia.
And perhaps I need help.
[growling]
Hello?
Who's there?
[growling]
Help!
Please, help!
Hey, what's wrong with you?
That spider monster
people are talking about,
I think I just saw it
in the science lab.
Lady, that monster story
is just more garbage
cooked up by The Daily Bugle
to slam Spider-man.
Spider-man's a good guy, a hero.
So, what are you saying?
I'm seeing things?
Hey, you're the
beaker brain, not me.
Wait a minute, you're
that ESU football star,
Flash Thompson.
Please, hold the applause.
Well, if you're so great,
the least you can do is
escort me back inside.
Lady, I got places to go.
Huh, some big star you are.
You're afraid.
What?
Ah, come on.
In there.
[thunder]
It was the wind.
It knocked a few things over.
You must've imagined
the rest, lady.
I'm telling you, that science
stuff is bad for your brains.
Oh, really?
And how would you know that?
You jocks don't have any.
Huh, you're welcome.
Webbing?
Just what is going
on around here?
[dramatic music]
[growling]
[screaming]
[laser gunfire]
Battle van, glue shooter.
Key to my signal.
Compensate for wind.
[growling]
Made the glue
stronger, web-head.
This time I've really got you.
This is what I
live for, webhead,
to stop monsters like you
from harming innocent lives.
Say good night.
[growls]
I don't know who you are,
but you made a big mistake.
Who are you?
Someone who does not need
barbaric weapons to hunt.
[growling]
[Man] Debra, help me.
Thompson, knock it off.
[screaming]
No!
Hunger too strong.
I must feed.
-Forgive me.
-No!
[screams]
Get away from her!
[crashing]
[groans of pain]
Spider-man?
[growling]
No!
Leave him alone!
[alarm blaring]
[growling]
[groaning]
Blast!
On the television they
say you are a vigilante
who thinks he is above the law.
So what?
It is written that a
man may build himself
a throne of bayonets,
but cannot sit on it.
-Give up this hunt.
-[police sirens]
It is not about good or bad.
It is about life.
Don't know who you
are, jungle boy,
but if you get in my
way one more time,
the lion ain't going to
walk tonight, or ever again.
You understand?
A man that studieth revenge
keeps his own wounds green.
Francis Bacon.
Revenge is a foolish
reason to hunt.
Maybe, but it works for me.
[grunting]
[dramatic music]
[sniffing]
Hmm, you move
swiftly, Spider-man,
but I have your scent.
I will find you.
[doorbell rings]
Harry!
Thank heavens you're here.
I came as soon as
I got your message.
You're Peter's best friend.
You were the only
person I could turn to.
[computer beeping]
Computer, war
journal entry 1994.3
[phone ringing]
Yes, Sergei, what is the news?
I need you to come quickly.
I know where to find our friend.
And there's still no sign
of ESU student Peter Parker,
who's been missing
since yesterday.
[screeching]
Oh!
Is he, too, a victim
of this strange
man-spider creature who's
terrorizing the city?
Oh, dear.
I pray that's not the case.
Earlier tonight, a
student at ESU reported
sighting the creature
on campus.
Police are baffled.
[growling]
I'm worried, too, Mary Jane.
It isn't like Pete to
just up and disappear.
[screaming]
Please!
Stay back!
You leave her alone!
Don't hurt us!
Please don't hurt us!
[growling]
Remind me never
to do that again.
Harry, you brave fool.
Mary Jane, what made it go away?
I don't know, but
for a brief moment,
I had this strange
feeling that it knew me.
[growling]
[computer alarm]
What on earth?
[growling]
[crash]
[explosion]
[growling]
No! No!
[muffled groaning]
Shh! We would do well to
work together, yes?
Yeah.
No!
Do not vibrate the web!
[growling]
[dramatic music]
Do not hurt him.
I won't hurt him, I'm
going to disintegrate him.
Won't be any nerve endings
left to feel the pain.
Forget it, Gunga Din.
I drop this and we
all make the news.
[Mariah] Sergei!
Let him go!
[Frank] Who are you?
My name is Dr. Mariah Crawford,
and that creature down
there is my friend.
He needs my help.
Sorry, lady.
Not my fault if you
keep lousy company.
Wait! They say on TV that
you fight criminals
to avenge the loss
of your family,
that they were caught in a
cross fire between rival gangs.
Don't you know that
nothing you do now
can ever bring them back?
This man has a disease.
He's trapped in this
creature's body.
He's a victim, just as your wife
and two children were victims.
The only monster here is you.
I'm listening.
I must administer this serum.
I need for you and
Sergei to hold him down.
Hurry, lady.
There, it's done.
[growling]
Take your coat off.
Drape it over his face.
What?
The man wears a
mask for a reason.
We must respect his wishes.
[groaning]
Here, put this on him.
I found it.
Thought I'd keep
it as a souvenir.
Huh?
Easy, Spider-man.
We're all friends here.
This man helped save you.
I feel like a just woke
up from a nightmare.
Well, my little Calypso,
you have done it again.
Calypso?
In mythology,
Calypso was a goddess
who offered the gift
of life to Odysseus.
Well, then, I guess
you're my Calypso too.
Let him rest.
Then I will help you
carry him out of here.
Wait!
If it is any consolation to you,
Spider-man is innocent
of the kidnapping charge.
It isn't.
Huh.
World Trade Center
parking garage.
How did you know?
The gravel that I found
in man-spider's webbing,
it still had the
scent of gunpowder
from that bomb
explosion of years ago.
Clever.
I'm impressed.
[Sergei] We would be
magnificent together.
Thank you for giving
me back my life.
What a beautiful day
this is gonna be.
I feel lucky to be alive,
and lucky to be who I am.
Spider-man.
["Spider-man Theme"]
♪ Spider-man Spider-man ♪
♪ Radioactive Spider-man ♪
♪ Spider blood spider blood ♪
♪ Radioactive spider blood ♪
♪ Spider-man ♪