[upbeat rock music]
♪ Spider-Man ♪
♪ Radioactive Spider-Man ♪
♪ Spider blood
Spider blood ♪
♪ Radioactive spider blood ♪
♪ Spider blood
Spider blood ♪
♪ Radioactive spider blood ♪
[explosions booming]
[growling]
♪ Spider-Man ♪
[upbeat music]
[Spider-Man, thinking]
Mary Jane is gone. Gone!
She wasn't
the Gargan's real target.
It's all my fault.
Now I see her face
everywhere I look.
I need to talk to somebody
before I explode.
But who? Who can understand
the pain of this kind of loss?
Felicia! After what happened
to Michael Morbius,
she knows what it means
to lose someone you love.
I think we're great together,
so what do you say?
-Felicia?
-Hmm?
You weren't even listening.
I'm sorry, Brace.
I've got a lot on my mind.
What's wrong, darling.
We've gone out
several times,
and no matter what we do,
you always seem
to be somewhere else.
[John Hardesky]
Come in, Felicia.
What are you doing
up at this hour, hmm?
I like being up late!
That's when I get
to see you, Daddy.
We're very much alike, kitten.
We're both most comfortable
when we're wrapped in the dark
blanket of the night.
-[Brace] Felicia!
-Hmm?
You're home.
Oh, oh! Brace! I'm sorry.
I'm a little distracted tonight.
I'll call you soon.
Sure.
[Anastasia]
This is a nightmare!
A nightmare that won't end!
Haven't you done enough to me?
[Doctor Octopus]
What of all that I
have suffered
at your hands?
The loss of my funding?
Prison?!
You'll now compensate me
for all that!
Unless, of course,
you would like me
to divulge your connection
to the infamous theft
of the Ausbach Fortune.
All right! All right!
Just give me a little more time
to get the money together.
Mother! What's going on here?
Felicia! Stay away.
-Young Miss Hardy!
-[screaming]
How very nice to hold you
in my arms again.
-Aah!
-Don't hurt her.
I'll do anything you say.
Of course you will!
You're completely
at the mercy of Doctor Octopus!
Felicia will help me
deal with my grief.
I just hope I'm not
catching her at a bad time.
[Felicia] No!
Scream all you want, my dear.
No one can hear.
-Spider-Man!
-What?!
How could you have known
I was here?!
Must be my sense of smell!
Let us see how well-developed
your pain receptors are.
[grunting]
[glass breaks]
[Spider-Man] Just
a little short of the mark, huh?
-Wrong!
-[groaning]
[beeping]
Get away from that!
This little exercise
has succeeded
only in demolishing your home.
It changes nothing.
I have you
right where I want you.
[sirens]
I will not rest until I have
squeezed
the Hardy Foundation dry!
[laughing]
I don't understand why
they can't keep
a creep like him in jail.
Spider-Man, please,
don't leave us alone!
Don't worry, I won't.
Look, I'm sorry about the mess.
Maybe I can help you
clean things up.
[thinking]
Huh, I wonder who this is?
Felicia's father?
When are you ever
going to understand
that we
don't want your help.
Mother! Spider-Man
tried to save us!
How? By charging in
and ruining everything?
Why can't you just mind
your own business?!
What is going on here mother?!
Why were you bargaining
with that-- that lunatic?
Did she say bargaining?
With Doc Ock?
I don't want to discuss it.
Certainly not in front of him.
But, mother, I--
[sirens stop]
[Anastasia]
The police are coming,
and I have
to keep them out of this.
[Felicia crying]
Are you okay?
No, my world is
crumbling around me.
[crying]
[Spider-Man] Do you
want to talk about it?
The only good thing
in my life is you.
How did you know
to show up anyway?
Uh, I happened to be
in the neighborhood, and--
All right, then,
don't tell me.
But I'm still grateful.
What kind of deal was
your mother making with Doc Ock?
I-- I don't know.
They mentioned something
called the Ausbach Fortune.
-[sirens, tires screeching]
-Look, Felicia.
I'll do everything in my power
to get your mother out of this.
But right now, it's best if
the police don't find me here.
I'll see you later.
Sure. Later.
[sighs]
Why do I always
fall for mysterious men?
Jason.
Hm! Michael, Spider-Man.
Men who are wrapped in
the dark blanket of the night.
[Peter, thinking]
Maybe that Ausbach fortune
Octavius mentioned
will shed some light on--
Ah! Here it is!
It was a jewel theft
15 years ago.
A large cache
of diamonds was stolen.
The crime was attributed
to a mysterious burglar
known as The Cat.
Now lets see
if he was ever caught.
Got it! "Capture And Trial
Of The Legendary 'Cat.'"
-[beep]
-"John Hardesky."
Wait a minute,
I know that face.
John Hardesky
is Felicia's father!
So this is what Doc Ock
was up to.
He was probably threatening
to embarrass the Hardys
by telling the world.
[rumbling]
[surprised grunt]
-Who dares to--
-Freeze, freak.
What?!
[Doctor Octopus laughing]
[groaning]
[coughing]
[straining]
Who dares to abduct
Otto Octavius?
Such histrionics, Doctor.
Kingpin, what is this
all about?!
Your paltry blackmailing scheme
against Anastasia Hardy
has jeopardized
one of my long term projects!
I'm listening.
There will be
nothing else to hear
until you guarantee me
your cooperation.
I guarantee you nothing.
Your choice, Octavius.
Either fall in line,
or fall 70 stories.
Aaah!
Kingpin, I'm sure
we can work together
to some mutually
beneficial conclusion!
I knew I could count on you.
Landon, say hello
to our newest ally.
Ah, Octavius, how timely.
We're ready to communicate
with The Chameleon again.
The Chameleon?
But isn't he in jail?
Exactly, and because he is
such a danger to the world,
he was incarcerated
in the highest security prison
ever built.
A prison whose very location
is a military top secret,
just as I expected.
Then how--
how can you find him?
Watch.
When I allowed the authorities
to apprehend The Chameleon,
Landon here had already
infused him
with a techno-organic virus.
[Landon] It altered
his physiological makeup.
He is now part machine.
This allows The Chameleon
to have his morphing ability,
without the cumbersome apparatus
of his image-inducing belt.
It has one other benefit.
He is now biologically emitting
a powerful homing signal.
Imagine our surprise
when we first learned
that he was somewhere
in the air.
The air?
We're within range.
I'm activating
the neuro-optic imager.
Everything The Chameleon sees,
is now
instantly broadcast to me.
Incredible.
Chameleon,
show us your cell mate
in that highly guarded
security facility.
[Doctor Octopus] That man!
It's John Hardesky.
-The Cat!
-Exactly.
And if what The Chameleon
tells us is true,
Hardesky holds a secret
that is worth a king's ransom.
All we have to do is get it.
But where is
this prison in the sky?
That is my next surprise.
Have you ever heard
of S.H.I.E.L.D.?
[beeping]
Could this Cat
really be Felicia's father?
And if so, what became of him?
I can't find any record of
what prison they sent him to.
Another odd thing,
in most of the pictures,
there's the same guy
always near Hardesky.
Maybe if I enlarge
the shot I can I.D. him.
I know that face.
Yeah, it's Nick Fury,
the head of S.H.I.E.L.D.
What did he have
to do with all this?
If I knew that, I might
be able to help Felicia.
Wait, there may be a way.
[Nick] Welcome
to Supreme Headquarters
International Espionage
Law Enforcement Division.
We call it S.H.I.E.L.D.
Now, I need for you
to wear this.
If you see anything suspicious,
tap on this pin,
and undercover S.H.I.E.L.D.
agents will respond pronto.
I gotta to get that badge.
I'm in luck.
Jameson's on his way out.
So where does
a guy like Jonah keep
a little com badge
for a top secret agency.
He wouldn't frame it would he?
Wait a minute.
-[door opens]
-Uh-oh.
[Spider-Man]
If you want good reception,
head for the top
of the world,
or at least
the top of the city.
After all this,
it better still work.
[beeping]
Maybe they'll send one
of those flying limo's for me.
Yeah, now that's service.
[S.H.I.E.L.D. Agent] Spider-Man,
please surrender peacefully.
Surrender? Hey, I just want
to talk to Nick Fury.
Agent 13 is now
approaching you with restraints.
[Spider-Man]
This isn't going to work.
[groaning]
Look, don't you guys understand?
Immobilizer, five o'clock!
Fire!
[groaning]
I can't move!
Cables! Fire!
Now I know what it feels
like to be vacuumed packed.
At least I've gotten them
to take me
to their castle in the sky.
Here he is, Colonel Fury.
Well, long time, no see,
Spider-Man.
I thought you had
your fill of us
when we tackled The Chameleon
back at the U.N.
I need information
about a criminal named The Cat.
The Cat? This isn't
like ordering a pizza.
S.H.I.E.L.D. doesn't deliver
classified information
within 15 minutes or
the first state secret is free.
I regret that I can't
help you at all.
-But--
-Take him back and drop him off.
Gently this time.
Come with me, Spider-Man.
Sorry, I'm not ready
to leave just yet.
Don't force me
to get tough again.
Oh!
Well, that will cut down
on my webbing expenses.
I just have to download
a little info,
then I'll be out of your hair.
Let's see what S.H.I.E.L.D.
has on The Cat.
[engines roaring]
[lasers blasting]
[beeping]
Now comes the tricky part.
Getting out
of this flying fortress.
[explosion]
Uh-oh, now what?
I don't know who's behind this,
but it looks
like the agency just got caught
with their S.H.I.E.L.D. down.
I trust that you now appreciate,
the full genius of my plan.
This flying fortress is amazing!
My attacking stealth airship
could not of gotten close enough
without my cloaking technology.
But can you defeat
an enemy this well armed?
I don't have to defeat
S.H.I.E.L.D.
Just distract them.
Someone open this door! Now!
Colonel, how'd you get in there?
I was locked in there
by an escaping prisoner!
Find him!
Well done, Chameleon.
Now bring Hardesky
to the rendezvous site.
Where are you taking me?
All you need to know is
someone went through a lot
of trouble to spring you,
and it's not because
of your charm.
[groans]
How about my talent?
[Spider-Man] It's him,
Felicia's father!
He's alive!
What's he doing here?
Stand back!
The Cat is my prisoner!
[groans]
[gasp]
Aaah!
Excellent!
It will be hours before
those fools realize that I have
left them with a fake Cat.
-[handcuffs click]
-[Kingpin laughing]
Now for step two.
Doctor, there is someone that
I need for you to bring to me.
[Peter] I'd tell Felicia
her father's still alive,
but I need to get
all the facts straight first.
"Classified file.
John Hardesky, alias, The Cat.
1943." John Hardesky would
have only been a boy of 13.
Seems that his file
begins here,
with him creeping
into a top secret facility,
thinking that he'd been
hired by the government
to spy on Nazis.
Trained as an acrobat, the boy
possessed tremendous agility.
[scientist]
Gentlemen, it is time to unveil
the volunteer
for this top secret experiment--
Private Steve Rogers.
Young man, the risk you take
today could very well tip
the scales
of the war in our favor.
I pray it does, sir.
[power starts]
[Peter] But Hardesky
had one other important skill--
a photographic memory.
And with it,
he undertook the mission
of memorizing
a top secret formula.
[scientist]
It won't be long now.
This is only the beginning.
[Peter] That secret formula
held the key
to producing
an amazing transformation
in a normal human being.
Rogers is merely the first
of a new breed
of super soldiers,
who will free the world from
the tyranny of the Axis powers.
Gentlemen,
meet the new champion
of the Allied forces,
Captain America.
[Peter]
Young Hardesky realized
that what he had seen being
made that night was history.
It was also tragedy.
In the name of the Fatherland,
I will destroy
this American war machine!
[zapping]
Friend!
It's going to explode!
[men shouting]
[Peter] Hardesky escaped
from the exploding complex,
but there
were new realizations
that clouded the success
of his mission.
[Hardesky]
I'm here for deliveries.
[bartender] Storeroom.
Ah, Cat, you made it back.
Were you able to retrieve
the information?
I would expect nothing less from
the son of The Great Hardesky,
the finest escape artist
of our time.
I memorized the formula,
but there's something
I don't understand.
Why would Axis spies name
their agent Captain America?
[laughing]
They weren't Nazis, were they?
You're the Nazis!
You're trying to get me
to betray my country!
I'll never tell anyone
the formula! Never!
After him, you fools!
Don't let him escape!
-Unh!
-Oof!
[Peter] John Hardesky
grew up to be The Cat.
S.H.I.E.L.D.
took him into custody
to prevent
the super soldier formula
from falling
into the wrong hands.
Felicia's mom must
have changed their name.
But what do I tell Felicia?
"Hey, I've got some good news
and some bad news?
The good news is,
your father's still alive.
The bad is they've locked him
up and thrown away the key
because he knows too much."
-Nervous, Miss Hardy?
-[gasp]
You!
Aah!
What are you doing here?
Just picking up
a special package.
[Felicia] Noooo!
Felicia's been
through so much lately.
I'm not for sure how
she's going to take this.
Felicia!
Whatever happened here,
I'm too late! Again!
I vowed never to reveal
that formula to anyone.
I may of been a crook,
but I am not a traitor
to my country.
I don't care what you do to me.
Mr. Hardesky, I have
much more persuasive methods
at my disposal.
[Felicia]
Put me down, you big--
[Kingpin]
Impeccable timing.
Wilson Fisk?!
What is the meaning of this?!
One might say I have gone
into the business
of family reunions.
How long you enjoy
each other's company
depends on how well
you cooperate with me.
Felicia Hardy, allow me
to introduce you to your father.
[upbeat rock music]
♪ Spider-Man, Spider-Man ♪
♪ Radioactive Spider-Man ♪
♪ Spider blood, spider blood ♪
♪ Radioactive spider blood ♪
♪ Spider blood ♪
♪ Spider-Man ♪