[Mary Jane]
Previously onSpider-Man.
Toomes, you're leading
your company into ruin!
[Toomes] There is only room
for one bird of prey
in this company, and I'm it!
[Peter thinking]
Look at that kid,
not a care in the world.
Me, I can't survive without
the neogenic recombinator.
[screams]
It works.
[Spider-Man]
From roller blades
to geriatrics? But how?
Who is this flying flamingo?
Where'd he get
the razor-sharp wings?
No, not long enough.
What happened?
[screams]
[groans]
Who are you?
Much like yourself,
I'm a vulture.
[Peter thinking] Let's see
ifThe Bugle's data bank
can ID him.
Adrian Toomes?
It's a letter from my dad.
He wants me to meet him.
I need somebody to be with me.
I want it to be you.
I just saw some
creepy, giant bird
land on Toomes's penthouse.
[screams]
I've activated
a self-destruct bomb.
[screams]
Your super strength makes me
feel stronger than ever before.
Now, let's see
what you look like.
[upbeat rock music]
["Spider-Man Theme Song"
by Joe Perry playing]
♪ Spider-Man, Spider-Man ♪
♪ Radioactive Spider-Man ♪
[guitar break]
♪ Spider blood, spider blood ♪
♪ Radioactive spider blood ♪
♪ Radioactive spider power ♪
[guitar break]
♪ Spider-Man, Spider-Man ♪
-[fire crackling]
-[dramatic music]
[Vulture laughs]
Now, I'm the one
with the power,
more than
I've ever felt before.
Come.
Let's have a test flight.
Incredible.
I have new speed, new agility.
[gasps]
[crowd yelling]
[Vulture laughs]
[tires screeching]
Now, I know how you must feel.
Correction,
how you used to feel!
[Vulture laughs]
There's a word we old
aviators once said...
-Geronimo!
-[Spider-Man groaning]
[screams]
Did you really think
I'd let you go that easily?
You see, I'll be be needing you
and your strength
again and again and again!
[laughs]
Where do you think
you're going?
[loud crash]
No.
No!
Spider-Man, this was
not part of my plan.
Now, I have to move quickly,
while I still have your power.
[groans]
[screams]
Oh.
[gasps]
[Peter thinking]
Where can I hide
until this
transformation wears off?
[man] Hey, pal,
slow night for news, eh?
I mean, nobody cares what this
neogenic stuff's all about.
I care.
Neogenics is about
getting a second chance,
one last break to get
back into the human race
to be like everyone else again.
That's what neogenics is.
Hey, you didn't pay!
Hey!
Keep the change.
[Spider-Man thinking]
It's been too long.
Why haven't I become
my normal self again,
the way that guy
in the park did?
[Spider-Man groans]
My limbs feel like
they're lead weights.
I've got to get home
and think things through
where it's safe.
[Spider-Man groans]
Web slinging is agony.
I'm really losing it.
[woman] Help me!
Stop, stop!
[man 1] We don't want no lip,
just your purse, now!
[laughs]
[Spider-Man, muffled voice]
Leave her alone!
[Peter thinking]
Wow, even my voice is old.
It's Spider-Man!
I said leave her alone!
He missed.
Look, isn't there something
weird-looking about him?
Yeah, but I ain't gonna stick
around to find out what.
Here, lady, keep the purse.
Yeah, lay off, Spidey.
We were just kidding around!
[screams]
[Spider-Man thinking]
I'd hate to think
what would've happened
if they'd stayed to fight.
[woman] Thank you, Spider-Man.
You saved me.
[Spider-Man] Really,
it was nothing.
I guess we old folks
have to stick together.
I had no idea
you were a senior citizen.
[Spider-Man] It's the job.
It ages you.
[thinking]
I hope I don't have any more
spider action tonight.
I still can't believe I'm old!
Old.
My life as Spider-Man is over
if I'm trapped in this body
for the rest of my life.
I've got to do something.
I've got to fix this.
I feel so tired, so weak.
[bus squealing]
Hey, Mac, climb in.
It's OK if you forgot
your senior pass.
These streets
ain't safe at night
for an old fella like yourself.
We'll be landing at Oscorp
in five minutes, Mr. Osborn.
The sooner the better.
Good heavens! Look!
It's him!
-[Vulture laughs]
-Stop him.
Stop him!
[computer beeping]
[Vulture laughs]
[gun firing]
-[computer beeping]
-[Osborn] Finish him off!
Stop him!
Dive!
I learned that one
in my first dogfight.
Vulture laughs]
[screams]
Not so fast, Osborn.
I want to savor this.
[Osborn groans]
End game, Norman.
Who are you?
Your worst nightmare.
I am Adrian Toomes.
That's impossible!
It's a long story,
and I don't have time.
Neither do you.
No!
What's happening to me?
[loud growl, loud shriek]
[loud growl]
Help!
Help me!
[screams]
[Peter thinking] Good.
Aunt May won't hear me
come in.
[John] You tell Parker
I pay him to take photos,
not sick days.
That Vulture lunatic
just attacked
my good friend, Norman Osborn,
and we don't have any photos!
[Peter] All right, I, um,
when he's feeling better,
I'll give him the message.
Give him this message, too.
No matter what,
he's got a job to do
and he's expected to do it!
Who was that, Jonah?
Some relative of Parker's
calling in sick for him.
Robbie, why is it that having
no sense of responsibility
goes hand in hand
with being young?
[Peter thinking] I hate to
admit it, but Jameson's right.
I do have a job to do.
People are depending on me.
-I've got to do something.
-[phone beeping]
[Dr. Connors] What you're
telling me is unbelievable,
but maybe there's a chance
I can help you.
Can you meet me at
Toomes's neogenic lab
first in the morning?
Wouldn't miss it
for the world, Doc.
[phone beeps]
Help me!
Help me! [pants]
-He's gonna get me!
-[man 1] Easy, Dr. Stillwell.
-Easy.
-He's trying to get me.
[man 2] Sir, no one's
trying to get you.
[Farley]
You don't understand,
none of you do.
He's after me...
The Scorpion!
No!
Don't do this to me!
-[man 1] He's like this
every night.
-Please!
[man 2] What's his story?
-[man 1] Remember The Scorpion?
-[man 2] Yeah.
-[man 1] Well, Stillwell's
the one who created him.
No way, this guy?
[man 1] He was a genius.
Right on the cutting edge.
[man 2]
Well, he's over the edge now.
[Farley] No.
[Farley] No!
Please.
-Boo!
-[screams]
You, you're not real!
Oh, but I am, pally.
If I was a hallucination,
could I do this?
[whimpers]
Please, don't hurt me!
Stillwell,
I've had time to think
about what you've done to me,
and guess what I've decided.
Since I'm your creation,
I'm your responsibility.
Oh.
You got to turn me back
into the man I was!
I want to be plain
old Mac Gargan again!
What can I do for you here?
[Scorpion] Not here,
at Toomes Aerodynamics.
Who the...
Stop!
[groans]
Help!
Call the police!
Come on, Stillwell.
Now that I've got you,
I'm gonna make it
so both our nightmares
are gonna end.
[lightning crackling]
-[keyboard clacking]
-[computer beeping]
-Connors.
-What?
It's me, Adrian Toomes.
And it's time for you
to start earning
that grant I gave you.
These talons sucked
the youth force
out of Spider-Man
and made me young,
but there's something wrong.
I... [groans]
[screams]
No! No!
Not again!
Connors,
what's happening to me?
Why haven't I changed
back into my old self?!
This has to be the result
of your contact
with Spider-Man.
When you sapped his youth,
you must've also
absorbed his mutated DNA
and it's too unstable
to let you change back.
What?!
Spider-Man had a disease
that I was treating
with neogenics.
The only way to cure you
is to transfer the mutating DNA
back into him.
No other human
body can handle it.
It's too late!
Spider-Man's been destroyed!
But I just heard from him.
You did?
-When?
-[loud thud]
Farley Stillwell,
what are you doing here?
Oh, I was kidnapped.
-He--
-Quiet!
What's with them wings?
And how come you're wearing
that dumb green costume?
You some kind of a nut?
Who are you?
How dare you disturb us!
Now, tell me where
Spider-Man is!
[Dr. Connors] I don't know.
Where is he?
No!
I might need you later.
Aah! Scorpion, stop!
You'll destroy
the neogenic files!
You need them!
[Vulture] Fascinating.
You want the neogenic data,
and I want Spider-Man.
Who are you, anyway?
I can give you access
to the neogenic computers,
but you must help me
get Spider-Man.
[Scorpion] You need help?
I'm suffering from
a temporary ailment
that makes my powers
unreliable.
You can be my insurance
that Spider-Man
will pose no threat to us.
Do we have a deal?
I could make you do
what I want,
but I'd plan to squash
Spider-Man sooner or later
anyway.
It's a deal.
So, where is he?
He knows.
[Scorpion]
Better tell us, pally.
Huh, looks like
I don't have a choice.
He's due here any minute.
[Peter thinking] The
worst part of all this is
I can't be there with Mary Jane
when she meets her father.
But at least,
I'll leave her a note.
It's amazing how aging 50 years
can change your plans.
[Peter gasps]
Mary Jane.
You know me?
[Peter]
I'm, I'm making a big mistake.
Are you-- Who are you?
Are you my father?
Wait, don't leave me again.
[Peter thinking]
My own life's a mess,
and now, I'm ruining
Mary Jane's too.
Oh, what else could go wrong?
[horn honking]
Even my spider-sense is gone.
[Aunt May] Oh, you poor fellow.
Are you all right?
[Peter thinking] Oh, no.
Aunt May.
[Aunt May]
Have another, won't you?
[Peter thinking]
Oh, thank heavens,
she doesn't recognize me.
I'm grateful for everything.
Are you sure you're all right?
Absolutely, but I've
got to be going now.
[Aunt May] Wait.
I have something for you.
[Peter thinking] She's so nice,
even to a total stranger.
If I don't become
myself again,
she'll worry herself
sick about me.
And if I'm gone, who will
there be to take care of her?
Here you are.
You might need this.
Thank you.
It's my nephew Peter's,
but I don't think he'll mind.
I'm sure he won't mind.
And thank you for everything.
[Spider-Man] Doc.
It's great to see you.
[Scorpion] Is that Spider-Man?
He looks different.
Trust me, it's him.
[Spider-Man] I really
need your help.
Spider-Man, I--
[Spider-Man] Doc, what's wrong?
Surprise, web-for-brains!
[chuckles]
That was your best shot?
Enough!
Game time's over.
I owe you big time, punk!
Remember our deal,
he's yours
after I'm done with him.
[Spider-Man] I always thought
I could trust you.
I'm sorry, I...
[Vulture] Blast it, Connors!
You've been at this for hours.
How much longer will it take
to reconfigure the talons?
There, finished.
Now, you can use
the talons to transfer
your unstable mutagenic DNA
back into Spider-Man.
Fix him already, Connors.
Then you and Stillwell
can fix me!
Doc Connors, don't let him!
Fool, accept it.
[loud buzzing]
[groaning]
The Vulture seems to be
losing his youth force.
Connors, you've made a mistake!
No mistake.
Connors double-crossed me.
Stop him!
[screams]
[loud growling]
If Connors gave me back
my youth and powers,
did the transformation
work all the way?
Like a charm.
Scorpion, help me!
Make them change me back!
Hurry!
You might've
double-crossed The Vulture,
but you're not gonna
pull any tricks on me.
[Spider-Man] I'm back.
[Scorpion groans]
[screams]
[Dr. Connors] Farley,
what are you doing?
If I enter the right equations,
it'll overload
the recombinator's transformer
and it'll self-destruct!
I'll make sure that
monsters like The Scorpion
are never created
by neogenics again!
[Dr. Connors] You can't!
Too late, Connors.
It's going into
self-destruct mode now!
That data's my only
hope for a cure.
A cure? For what?
Oh!
-[Lizard growls]
-Good heavens!
[Scorpion]
Here's a little present, creep.
[Spider-Man] I sense hostility.
Go with your feelings.
Vent!
[Farley] Help!
-Oh, boy.
I don't want to hurt you, Doc,
and I don't know
if I could if I wanted to.
[growls]
-[spider-sense chimes]
-But I know this feeling.
[grunts]
[computer whirs]
[alarm wailing]
[Scorpion laughs]
[Farley] Everybody out, now!
The recombinator is
going to explode!
[alarm wailing]
[Spider-Man] Doc, are you OK?
[groans]
I think so,
but what about
The Scorpion and The Vulture?
[Spider-Man]
Doesn't look like they made it.
How are you feeling?
Terrific, better than
I've ever felt before!
That's because you're finally
cured of your disease.
I am?
But how did you do that?
When I caused your youth
energy to return to you,
I made the mutating aspect
of your DNA stay
in The Vulture.
You regained your
youth and superpowers,
but you'll never have
to worry about mutating
into the man-spider again.
So, the nightmare of neogenics
is finally over.
With the data destroyed,
the secret's locked
in here, forever.
But, Farley, I still
needed to cure myself.
I'm sorry, Connors,
but you were right
all those months ago,
the technology's
not worth the risk.
It is too unpredictable.
You can try to
recreate my work,
but this time,
you're on your own.
You'll never see me again.
[Vulture, muffled voice]
Destroyed.
Oh, destroyed.
I've got to hide
where no one can see me.
[screams]
I don't see anybody.
They're gone, all of them,
and so is my chance
to be normal again!
[screams]
No! No!
No!
[Peter thinking]
I still can't believe it.
Finally, I'm cured.
I don't have to worry
about that mutation
hanging over me anymore.
And now I can turn
my attention
to the woman
who needs me, Mary Jane.
I told her I'd be with her
when she meets her father.
Now, I can keep that promise,
if I'm not too late.
Peter, where are you?
You promised me.
[sighs]
You let me down again.
Big surprise.
-[metal clanking]
-[gasps]
Mary Jane!
She's gone, but--but how?
Where?
["Spider-Man Theme Song"
playing]
♪ Spider-Man, Spider-Man ♪
♪ Radioactive Spider-Man ♪
[guitar solo]
♪ Spider blood, spider blood ♪
♪ Radioactive spider blood ♪
♪ Spider-Man ♪