[upbeat rock music]
♪ Spider-Man ♪
♪ Radioactive Spider-Man ♪
♪ Spider blood
Spider blood ♪
♪ Radioactive spider blood ♪
♪ Spider blood
Spider blood ♪
♪ Radioactive spider blood ♪
[explosions booming]
[growling]
♪ Spider-Man ♪
[Peter] Life
is like a thunderstorm.
It's unpredictable,
uncontrollable,
sometimes even dangerous.
We like to think we
have a handle on life,
that we're in charge.
-Then, without warning...
-[thunder crashing]
...we find out how
wrong we really are.
[prosecutor]
This man has perpetrated
the most heinous crime
a citizen can commit.
He is a danger to the very
well-being of our society.
Therefore, I urge that there
be no bail for the defendant,
Peter Parker.
Your honor,
my client is innocent.
He demands his freedom
to prove it.
That's for a jury to determine.
-I order the defendant
held without bond.
-[bang]
-Bailiffs, take him away.
-[handcuffs click]
[Peter, thinking]
I can't believe
this is happening to me.
It's as if I stepped
into a Kafka novel.
I could use my powers
to break away,
but I'd have to reveal
that I'm Spider-Man.
That would be too dangerous
for Aunt May.
[Aunt May] Peter!
As if this hasn't
hurt her enough already.
[cameras clicking]
Parker, what made you think
you'd get away with it?!
[clicking]
[Mary Jane] Peter!
[dramatic music]
[helicopter buzzing]
-[explosion]
-[tires screech]
Now what's happening?!
It sounds like World War III
is going on outside.
[explosion]
[impostor]
What's the matter, kid,
haven't you seen
Spider-Man before?
[gas hisses]
[people shouting and screaming]
[gunshots]
[lasers blasting]
[dramatic music]
[pilot] J-3 Eagle to base.
I'm gonna try to get
closer and follow them.
A smoke screen! Aah!
[impostor] So, Parker,
wanna to take my picture now?
-[laughs]
-[guns cocking]
How about an interview?
[thinking]
I have questions all right.
Like who is this phony freak,
and how'd I get caught up
in this mess anyway?
I guess it started
when a man named Richard Fisk
called me out of nowhere
to offer me a job.
-Your a Physics instructor.
-I didn't know Richard Fisk,
but he sure knew
a lot about me.
Percentile of your class.
A winner of the prestigious
Dovale Science Award.
Mr. Parker, we are all
very impressed with you,
but there is
one achievement of yours
that dwarfs everything else.
-You saved my father's life.
-What?!
Mr. Parker,
my father, Wilson Fisk.
Greetings, young man.
[Peter]
Wilson Fisk! Of course!
He's the wealthy philanthropist
that the Hobgoblin
tried to assassinate.
I have been looking
for just the right way
of expressing
my gratitude to you.
-I think I have found it.
-[snip]
My son has come home
from Europe
to be the chairman of my newest
company, Fisk-Tronics.
The company will service
large computer systems.
I believe this is one
of your fields of interest.
Yes, it certainly is.
I will arrange
security clearance for you.
You are interested
in a work-study endowment,
are you not?
Interested? Are you kidding?
When do I start?
Immediately. Just place
your future in my hands.
[Peter] Those hands
could have held
ten people's futures,
or crushed them all
in the blink of an eye.
It was a great job.
Most of Fisk-Tronics' clients
were in defense,
and they used
the most cutting-edge
digital technology there was.
Not that I ever saw
anything really top secret.
As a systems operations
troubleshooter,
I just interfaced
the diagnostic machine
into the computer networks.
It gave me a disk pointing
out possible memory errors,
i/o conflicts, node failures--
routine stuff.
But the best part was
I made just enough money
to make an old dream come true.
Quit?!
You ungrateful upstart!
I took you in when you
were just a kid off the street!
I sweated blood teaching
you the news business!
And for all my troubles,
you do this to me?!
You can't quit.
You wanna to know why?
Because you're fired!
J.J., I'll never forget you,
no matter how hard I try.
You'll come crawling back!
Mark my words!
You'll be crawling
on your belly
just like all of them do!
Peter,
how'd he take the news?
I don't think he'll
be crying himself to sleep
over losing me, Mr. Robertson.
Don't be too sure.
Jonah doesn't know
how to show it,
but he does have a softer side.
I honestly think he likes you.
[Peter]
That was a surprise.
But I was in for a lot
of surprises from then on.
It was
all routine that next day.
The machine did its thing
and gave me a disk
with the diagnostic.
For once,
it seemed like my life
was finally starting
to come together.
One please,
with lots of mustard.
[thinking]
Man, why's my spider-sense--
-Don't move!
-So are you trying to tell me
this thing's bad
for my cholesterol?
[dramatic music]
He's getting away!
-Where'd he go?!
-I dunno.
We've got to get that disk!
[Peter]
My diagnostic disk?
Why would anyone want that?
[woman] We've got units
closing the streets.
He can't get away.
[Peter] I don't know
who these guys are,
but I'm sure gonna find out.
-Uh-oh, what now?
-[spider-sense tingling]
-[helicopter whirs]
-[laser blasts]
[man] It's Spider-Man!
He might be Parker's
accomplice!
[lasers blasting]
[Spider-Man]
Has the world gone crazy?
What's all this about?
[dramatic music]
I've lost them.
But the scary thing is,
they were originally after
Peter Parker, not Spider-Man.
[helicopter whirring]
-[Peter] Aunt May?
-Peter!
I didn't know
you were upstairs.
Aren't you home a little early
from your new job?
It's a long story,
but the important thing is,
-are you all right?
-Of course.
Why wouldn't I be?
-[crash]
-[gasps] Oh, dear!
Hold it right there, Parker!
[thinking]
I can't risk a battle here.
Aunt May could get hurt.
We'll see what the police
have to say about this.
Ma'am, we are the police.
Detective Terri Lee, NYPD.
Long time no see, Parker.
Allow me to introduce you
to Federal Agent Susan Choi.
Federal agent?
What do you want with me?
We want that computer disk
for starters.
But it's just diagnostic data.
Oh, really?
I say it's full
of classified defense plans.
We knew somebody
in Fisk's company
was selling government secrets.
Now we've finally
found the traitor-- you.
I don't know
what you're talking about.
I knew nothing about this.
[Choi]
Tell it to the judge.
Read him his rights.
Terri, you know me.
I wouldn't betray my country.
Parker, you better
get yourself a good lawyer.
[click]
[Aunt May]
Peter's a good boy!
There's got to be
an explanation!
For his sake,
I hope it's a good one.
[keys jingling]
[guard] Parker,
your lawyer's here.
You're my lawyer?
You sound surprised.
Uh, no, I mean...
I'm sorry.
I've just never met
a blind lawyer before.
Well, I've never met
an accused traitor before,
so we're even.
My name's Murdock.
Matt Murdock.
The famous
criminal defense lawyer?
But I can't afford you.
Well, somebody sent me
a big cash retainer,
so until it runs out,
I'm your man,
if you want me.
-Of course.
-Good.
They say justice is also blind,
so I like to think it gives me
a leg up on the competition.
Judging from what
you've gotten yourself into,
we're going to need
every bit of help we can get.
First of all, I need answers.
[helicopter whirs]
[Peter]
Up until this moment,
I had precious few to offer.
[thunder crashes]
That's why I've let
these creeps kidnap me.
But have I put myself
in even greater danger
than before?
[dramatic music]
Mr. Fisk,
what are you doing here?
Someone in my organization
made an awful mistake,
one which might have exposed
me to imminent prosecution.
I needed to find somebody
to take the fall, as they say,
and you are
that unfortunate person.
You're the one who framed me?
Yes, and I engineered
your escape,
so as to leave no doubt
in anyone's mind
that you are guilty.
You and Spider-Man.
Good work, Chameleon.
[Chameleon] My pleasure.
Unfortunately, as I no longer
have use for you,
I must be leaving.
Oh, please note,
not even your friend Spider-Man
could break out of this cell.
[heavy thud]
[panting]
There's no
air vent in here!
[Richard, on speaker] Note also
that you have only enough air
to last a few minutes.
Goodbye, Parker.
Goodbye forever.
[panting]
Not much air left.
Fisk was right about this door.
Spider-Man can't move it!
I'm done for!
[gasps]
Can't breathe!
[panting]
My father, the Kingpin,
will be pleased.
We've saved him
from federal prosecution.
How ironic that Parker
should be branded a traitor,
especially after what you've
told us about his parents.
[elevator hums]
[helicopter whirs]
[dramatic music]
[heart thumping]
-Huh?!
-[staff whooshes]
-[kick lands]
-Ooh!
[dramatic music]
-[hearts thumping,
guns cocking]
[laser blasts]
-Where'd he go?!
-[Daredevil] Right here.
[groaning]
[buzzing]
[henchman] What
happened to the lights?!
[henchmen groaning]
Can't... breathe!
Don't think I'm gonna make it.
[door whirs]
Murdock sent me to get you out.
Who are you?
I'm called the Daredevil.
Let's go.
What happened to these guys?
Me.
There's two men at the far end
of the roof, behind the sign.
One's out of shape,
he's breathing hard,
his heart's pounding.
This guy could
give my spider-sense
a run for its money.
[punches land]
[Peter] Daredevil, huh?
I like your style.
Murdock thinks
you've been framed.
You'll be safe here
until he can prove it.
Hold it, where are you going?
The night is young
and there's work to be done.
Wait a minute, where am I?
[dramatic music]
[click]
So, how did you
like my friend Daredevil?
Well, there's one thing
I'm still curious about.
Why am I helping you?
Maybe it's because
I know what it's like
when the deck's
stacked against you.
My dad was a fighter.
-[crowd cheering]
-[bell rings]
It's what he'd always been.
-He knew everything
about the business.
-[clang]
-[heavy punch]
-Except when to get out.
Dad's time in the ring
was over,
but he had a kid to support,
so he took a job
collecting money
for an up-and-coming mobster
and sold his soul.
[dramatic music]
[cans rattling]
[man] No! No, mister! No!
Here's the money.
[dramatic music]
[clank]
[Matt] I couldn't deal
with the shame
of what I'd seen my dad doing.
-It was the last thing
I ever saw.
-[horn blaring]
-[tires screech]
-[liquid splashes]
The stuff in the truck
was radioactive waste.
It was against the law to
transport it through the city.
Someone didn't
care about the law,
or about broken lives,
or about the value
of life at all.
That someone was a crime boss
who calls himself the Kingpin.
Dad made a vow that he'd pay.
He was on his way
to the police when--
[loud crash]
My dad was never seen again.
Do you know
who this Kingpin guy is?
I have my suspicions,
but since I have no evidence,
it's better I keep
my suspicions to myself.
But you think Richard Fisk
is working for him?
Yes, I'm sure of it.
The Kingpin's a dangerous man.
His influence is far-reaching,
but someday,
he'll meet his match.
Someday soon.
But I do go on.
You could probably
use some rest.
How about if I let you?
Thanks, Matt, for everything.
But there's
no rest for Spider-Man.
[thinking] I wish
I could have told you
the whole story, Parker,
told you about
how the accident changed me.
My blindness seemed to
enhance all my other senses--
smell, touch, taste.
Now I could see
better than before.
-[sounds enhanced]
-It was a kind
of a natural radar,
but it was so new,
it confused me.
Then I met a mysterious man
named Stick.
I wish the world could
know about all the effort,
all the long hours where Stick
took a lost
and lonely blind kid
and taught me to see in ways
I never knew existed.
That accident had changed me.
Was it the radiation?
Does it matter?
-Stick was my mentor.
-[thud]
He helped me to live up
to the nickname
the kids used to tease me
when they thought I was blind
and helpless, the Daredevil.
Now I am confident,
fearless.
[dramatic music]
And I'm close,
so close to confronting
my greatest enemy.
He'll pay for what he's done
to the innocent,
to the helpless,
to my father.
[dramatic music]
[Anna] Now, please, May,
let us make dinner.
You've got enough on your mind.
Why, Anna Watson,
you're being so kind,
you're embarrassing me.
But you win.
I am feeling a little tired.
Poor woman.
I never did trust Peter.
Always gone when May
needed him, and now this.
Aunt Anna, are you
saying Peter's guilty?
How can you even think that?
Mark my words, Mary Jane,
there's something odd
about that boy.
Shh, she doesn't
need to hear this.
May, you feel like having
brussels sprouts tonight?
May?
May, you look ill!
Mary Jane, call an ambulance!
Hurry!
Cop guarding the front.
In case I return, no doubt.
I hate the sewer.
Whenever I have to use it,
I'm eternally grateful
I wasn't bitten
by a radioactive rat.
I hope Aunt May is getting
a good night's sleep.
This has been
really tough on her.
My hunch is that if there's
any way in the world
to clear my name, I'll find
it here at Fisk-Tronics.
[dramatic music]
The whole Fisk-Tronics
system routes
through these mainframes.
Wait a minute,
this looks interesting.
[dramatic music]
[groaning]
Hey, I'm one of the good guys!
Then why'd you help Fisk
kidnap Parker?
[Spider-Man] Just my luck,
this guy thinks
I kidnapped me!
Look, I've been framed, too!
I need that disk
to clear myself!
Oh, really?
More likely you're planting
evidence against Parker.
[grunting]
I've got to stop
underestimating him.
He seems to have
a second sense
about everything.
[dramatic music]
[clank]
[Spider-Man] Listen,
I don't want to fight you,
but if you don't stop
swinging and start listening--
[lasers blasting]
That's it!
I've had it!
[dramatic music]
[staff thudding]
Start the timer, now!
That's what we came here for.
But what if all
our guys don't get out?!
You want to tell the Kingpin
we failed to blow
this place up?
[electronic ticking]
Now, you wouldn't be trying to
destroy evidence, would you?
And just who is this Kingpin?
Freeze, Spider-Man!
Nice! Not only
do we burn the evidence,
but you, too!
Spider-Man,
just stay right where you--
Oww!
-[ticking]
-Everyone get out of here!
The firebomb's gonna blow!
[Daredevil]
Maybe there's an override.
[gun cocking]
[Spider-Man] Look out!
[explosion]
[dramatic music]
[upbeat rock music]
♪ Spider-Man, Spider-Man ♪
♪ Radioactive Spider-Man ♪
♪ Spider blood, spider blood ♪
♪ Radioactive spider blood ♪
♪ Spider blood ♪
♪ Spider-Man ♪