[announcer]
Previously onSpider-Man.
The last few weeks have been
the best times of my life.
[Morrie] Let go of her!
[Mary Jane]
Leave my husband alone!
I'm taking you back to.
[Mary Jane screaming]
Mary Jane!
All that's left is her jacket.
I'm betting Bench passed
through M.J's jacket
during the abduction.
That's it!
I know where he's taken her.
Stay away from me.
Come back here Red.
It's time we had a little talk.
[Peter] That's the last of
my coagulating web fluid.
[Black Cat] Parker's
wife is missing.
I thought you'd be
looking for her too.
Run all you want Red.
Now I'm really steamed.
[Peter] Brilliant!
Mary Jane,
you've done it again.
Is it possible the lady's
trying to tell you something?
I'm sick of your interference!
[explosions booming]
This time I'm finishing
you off myself.
You can't do this to me!
[Peter] Mary Jane?
How on earth did you--
I don't know!
[theme music playing]
♪ Spider-Man ♪
♪ Radioactive Spider-Man ♪
♪ Spider blood ♪
♪ Radioactive spider blood ♪
[explosions booming]
[growling]
♪ Spider-Man ♪
[dramatic music playing]
[Mary Jane] Peter?
What's happening to me?
How did I turn into water?
[Peter] I don't know.
What did Hydro-Man do to her?
Cat, are you all right?
I'm okay.
As long as
sprinkler boy is gone.
How did you manage
to stop him anyway?
Well, uh--
I, uh--
Well--
[explosion booming]
We'll explain later.
Let's fly.
I guess we'd better take
Mrs. Parker back
to her husband.
[Peter] Huh?
I'm sure
he's been worried sick.
Look, I can get her back.
There's no need for
both of us to do it.
Fair enough.
Then I must get going.
I'll always cherish our
time together, Spider.
Cat, I--
Thanks for reminding me
that a superhero
must always have
a deep sense of commitment.
I made one to Morbius.
Now I have to keep it.
I'm going back to
join him in Europe.
I finally realized
that's where I belong.
Goodbye.
[clears throat] Hello?
For a minute it looked
like you forgot I was here.
What exactly is there between
you and this Black Cat?
She was once my partner
and she really helped me
through the time
that you were gone.
But we've got more important
things to worry about.
You're right.
And I just can't
shake the feeling
that when we find out
what's wrong with me,
it's going to lead
to my destruction.
[dramatic music playing]
[Terri]
So, the chemical factory
was the last place you
saw this Hydro-Man?
Yes.
Spider-Man saved me
then brought me home.
[gasps] Mary Jane,
you poor dear.
I can't believe you
had to go through that.
Oh, Anna, the worst is over.
And I'm sure detective Lee
will keep that awful
Hydro-Man away.
We'll do what
we can Mrs. Parker.
But this Hydro-Man's
a pretty elusive character.
[gasps]
You two are still
in real danger.
-Oh, dear.
-Now the best thing
for us to do is stay hidden
so Hydro-Man can't find us.
Please, do what you can.
It's all in your hands.
[Peter] And you don't
even know the worst of it.
Thanks for helping
us Doctor Connors.
We didn't know who
else to turn to.
Mary Jane's nightmare might be
a repressed memory
of where she was
when she disappeared
some time ago.
Maybe we can recover that
memory through hypnosis.
Are you ready Mary Jane?
Let's do it.
Relax completely.
[machine whirring]
Relax and go to sleep.
Let yourself go.
Mary Jane, can you hear me?
[Mary Jane] Yes.
[Curtis] Where are you?
[Mary Jane] I'm drowning!
[gasping] No!
I'm floating in water.
Someone else is here.
I can't see who
but he scares me.
[man] Come to me.
I am your father.
[Mary Jane] No, he's lying!
I must get away!
I hear a loud noise.
It sounds like train tracks.
Stop it!
[Mary Jane screaming]
I'm being chased by a clown.
You can't escape me.
[Mary Jane]
He has Morrie's voice.
No!
I smell something
baking in an oven.
I'm in my wedding gown
running up to the
top of a platform.
I love you.
You were made for me.
Me!
[Mary Jane screaming]
[Mary Jane] I'm falling.
The ground is sticky.
I see a man.
He says.
You can't go home.
[Mary Jane] Then he turns into
-a pirate.
-[man laughing]
I'm on his pirate ship.
[Mary Jane screaming]
No.
-Doc, what's wrong?
-No.
It's too much for her mind.
If I don't bring her out now
she might suffer a
nervous collapse.
-No!
-Mary Jane,
at the count of three
I will snap my fingers
and you must wake up.
You'll feel refreshed
and you'll remember
everything you've told me.
-One, two, three.
-[snaps fingers]
[gasps]
Oh, Peter.
You did well.
Those dream images may be
clues to your disappearance.
And we're gonna
track down every one
until we figure all this out.
[dramatic music playing]
[water splashing]
Professor, I never had this
much trouble reforming before.
I feel terrible.
Why is this happening to me?
I can't really say,
my dear boy.
Your constitution is still,
well, experimental
at this point.
I'll need to run a few tests.
It's going to take some time.
No! I can't wait!
Mary Jane is--
Mary Jane is not
important right now.
I must take time to
examine your blood sample.
And leave her in the
arms of Peter Parker?
Not a chance!
Sharp, come back!
Yes Anna, I have heard from
Peter and Mary Jane today.
I'm supposed
to keep it a secret
but they might go visit
the George Washington Bridge.
No, I haven't any idea why.
[Peter] Is this bringing
back any memories, M.J?
Any small clue?
[Mary Jane] I was on the ship
before I fell off this bridge.
-The pirate ship?
-Yes.
On the Hudson River?
Yes.
Oh, I know
what you're thinking.
It makes no sense at all.
But I-- [gasps]
Mary Jane.
What's the matter?
I suddenly felt really spacey.
As if I can't hold
my thoughts together.
It's probably the shock
of being back here
where it all started.
I remember suddenly
finding myself
at the bottom of the bridge
and seeing Spider-Man
battling the Green Goblin.
But I don't remember
falling off
or anything that
happened in between.
Oh, I hate this bridge.
Yeah, me too.
I always get the feeling
something bad is
going to happen here.
[Morrie] Kid,
you oughta become a psychic.
-Morrie!
-Stay back.
I don't know who's
more of a pain.
You or Spider-Man.
[Mary Jane screams]
Now then, we're together again.
Just the way I like it.
After all, we were
made for each other.
[water splashing]
[Mary Jane screaming]
Bench!
No.
[dramatic music playing]
Mary Jane.
Where is she?
They could be miles away.
My only chance of
getting Mary Jane back
is to keep following
the clues from her dream.
Somehow I think all the
answers will lead to Bench.
But where on earth am
I going to find a pirate ship?
Of course.
A theme restaurant.
[gentle music playing]
Well, hello Smiley.
I'm sorry sir.
A tie and jacket are
required after 5:00 pm.
[Peter] I'm not here for
the chicken a la Davy Jones.
I'm looking for
a woman whose life
may be in serious danger.
Oh yes, that poor child.
I was terribly
worried about her.
She appeared one night
and seemed very disoriented.
She was soaking wet
but it wasn't raining.
She said she wanted to go home
but I told her
you can't go home, dear.
Not until we get you
into some dry clothes.
I went back to see if we had
anything for her in
the coat check room.
And when I returned,
she was gone.
[Peter] Which way
did she come from?
From North, up the street.
[Peter] Thanks!
The bridge, the pirate ship,
the man with the mustache.
They're all real.
But what's next?
Hey, [sniffs] that
smells like cake baking.
[Mary Jane] I smell
something baking in an oven.
Wait a minute.
A wedding cake bakery?
Of course.
Mary Jane wearing
a wedding dress
and falling in goo.
It must be a dream image
inspired by these cakes.
[Mary Jane] I'm being
chased by a clown.
[Peter] A clown who
bangs a tin drum.
What could that be?
A circus?
A toy.
[toy robots whirring]
Hello.
This might be what
I'm looking for.
Now what?
[lasers zapping]
-Whoa!
-[explosions booming]
This is the one time
batteries not included
wouldn't have been a bad idea.
But why do I get the feeling
that Alistair Smythe
is now in the toy business?
Uh-oh.
[lasers zapping]
[explosions booming]
There's something back there.
Gotta move fast.
Thank you.
Oscorp?
What on earth is this?
Uh-oh, I'm outta here.
[wheels rattling]
The sound it's making
is what Mary Jane heard.
I'm on the right track.
Literally.
[Peter grunting]
[explosion booming]
I hope he only bought
a one way ticket.
Now where am I?
That light at the
end of the tunnel.
Could that be the big eye
Mary Jane saw in her dream?
This tunnel.
It's like the one
leading from Oscorp
to the Green Goblin's
underwater lab.
I thought I destroyed that lab.
But maybe somebody's
brought it back to life.
And if they did, why?
[Mary Jane coughing]
I never wanted you to have
to see this lab again, Red.
What do you mean again?
Wait a minute.
I remember this place.
[water bubbling]
This is where my dream begins.
What does it have
to do with you?
Like I've been saying
all along, Red.
We were made for each other.
Don't you understand?
You have no choice
but to be mine.
No, I hate the
sound of your voice.
I can't stand looking at you.
[yelps]
And let's not bring up
your personality.
I knew I could count
on you to find me.
-[water crashing]
-[Mary Jane screaming]
Why can't I get rid of you?
Mary Jane is mine.
[Peter] My suit, it's torn.
Mary Jane.
I can't reassemble myself.
I won't let you
terrorize me any longer.
Stop!
Please, stop!
I can't do it.
I can't destroy him.
Those water powers.
How do you even make
them happen at all?
I can answer that Spider-Man.
Who are you?
My name is Professor
Miles Warren
and I can actually
be considered
Mary Jane's father.
Miles Warren.
I read about you
in a science journal.
Your cloning experiments were
banned by the government.
True.
So I found it necessary
to continue my research
in secret on an
underground level.
Fortunately, there are
those who are willing
to pay for scientific
work like mine.
You're the one
who kept me here.
You gave me the power
to turn into water.
You have hydropower
because you and Hydro-Man
literally were made
for each other.
[Peter] What do you mean?
Perhaps it's best
if I explain everything
from the beginning.
I was set up in this lab
by an individual
who wished for me
to continue my research.
[Peter] Who?
He prefers to remain anonymous.
My early experiments
were unsuccessful.
The tissue wouldn't
hold together.
Then I happened upon an
article in the Daily Bugle
about Hydro-Man and
his viscous ability
to disassemble and
reassemble himself.
This might hold the key.
But Hydro-Man
evaporated on a rooftop.
[water splashing]
[Miles] So I had
read in the paper.
However, I hoped
there would still be
traces of his DNA at
the scene of his demise.
[Peter] And were there?
[Miles] Yes.
Enough to make a clone.
He was magnificent.
An exact duplicate
in looks, ability,
but also, unfortunately,
in memory and emotion.
[Mary Jane] Emotion?
[Peter] Are you
saying the clone
loved Mary Jane as much
as the real Hydro-Man?
[Miles] Exactly.
He threatened to destroy me
if I didn't help him find her.
I told him it was impossible.
Mary Jane was gone.
Hydro-Man was so
devastated by her loss
he insisted that I clone her.
[Mary Jane] How?
[Miles] All I needed was
a sample of your hair.
[Anna crying]
I fused the viscous properties
from Hydro-Man's cell structure
to Mary Jane's DNA to
insure the same stability.
It worked beautifully.
But just
as Hydro-Man's emotions
remained true to the original,
so did Mary Jane's.
She felt love.
Love for Peter Parker.
Peter, I've come back to you.
Mary Jane.
-[people cheering]
-[man] Hurray!
Hey!
[Miles] We had no
idea where she'd gone
until we read of
her marriage to Parker.
So what you're trying
to tell me
is I'm not the real Mary Jane?
I'm afraid that is so, my dear.
I would've come for you sooner
but I had to wait until
my powers grew stronger.
You're my Eve, Mary Jane.
You were made from
part of me for me.
[Peter] What?
I don't believe any of this.
It's not true.
It can't be true.
Oh, you know in
your heart it is.
You can feel it.
Why didn't you just
tell me I was a clone?
Because if you didn't know,
you'd be just like
the real Mary Jane.
How can I live
my life as a clone?
As a part of you?
I hate you!
Then you're just
gonna have to hate me
for all eternity
as my wife.
[Mary Jane gasping]
[clears throat]
I'm afraid I have
some rather unpleasant news.
The latest blood
test on Hydro-Man
show that the cloning process
has proven unstable.
You're coming apart just
like my first clones.
It has just taken longer
to happen this time.
According to my research,
neither of you
has much time left.
[Morrie yelling]
This is all your fault!
If you couldn't
do it correctly,
you should never
have done it at all.
[water crashing]
[Peter] Bench, stop!
You're destroying the lab.
No, it's happening too fast.
But I want you, Red.
I want you.
[screaming]
Mary Jane.
No!
It's too late.
I'm falling apart too.
We'll get help.
We'll, Warren!
Warren, where the
blazes are you?
Forget it, tiger.
He's gone.
Oh, dear.
Before I go, I want you
to know just one thing.
If any part of me is anything
like the real Mary Jane Watson,
she loves Peter Parker
more than anything
in the world.
More than anything.
No!
Mary Jane!
[water crashing]
[dramatic music playing]
Oh, Smythe, my dear fellow.
Sorry to bother you.
Tell Silvermane that I need
some repairs down here.
Perhaps soon I might make
some startling advances.
[dramatic music playing]
[Peter] What happened
to you Mary Jane?
I can't go on without knowing.
Not as Spider-Man.
Not as anyone.
[Madame Web] Oh, how
wrong you are Spider-Man.
As usual.
No, not you again.
I still have something very
important for you to do.
Have you forgotten
that I have been preparing
you this long while
for the most important
battle of your life?
[Peter] I remember
all of my encounters
with you Madame Web.
I want nothing to do with you.
But suppose I told you
I know where Mary Jane is?
And you will only find her
if you do as I command.
Leave me alone!
I cannot.
This is your
destiny, Spider-Man.
And now, the fate of mankind
rests on your weary shoulders.
[theme music playing]
♪ Spider-Man ♪
♪ Radioactive Spider-Man ♪
♪ Spider blood ♪
♪ Radioactive spider blood ♪
♪ Spider blood, spider blood ♪
♪ Spider-Man ♪