[Peter]
Previously onSpider-Man.
I've pinpointed the
doomsday complex.
Excellent.
Who are you?
Omar Mosley,
the real Black Marvel.
We have to stop Kingpin
from getting the keys.
Then we have to assemble
those of us who are left
and protect the site of
the doomsday complex.
This is a young person sport.
We all have one last chance
to prove ourselves again.
We shall secure the location.
[groaning]
What is the meaning of this?
[Rheinholdt] Father.
Rheinholdt, Chameleon, my sons.
[Rheinholdt] We are in this
doomsday complex you built.
We are destined to rule.
And we shall.
Free the others.
Right now, attack.
We must stop the Red Skulls.
Let's make the world
a safer democracy.
-We're losing power.
-This way, Rheinholdt.
Uh-oh.
I thought you were a mercenary.
I was continuing to hunt
German war criminals
when I stumbled onto
the doomsday plot.
Now I know you are a friend.
Between the two of us,
the Red Skull is finally
going to be history.
[theme music playing]
♪ Spider-Man, Spider-Man ♪
♪ Radioactive Spider-Man ♪
[guitar solo]
♪ Spider blood, spider blood ♪
♪ Radioactive spider blood ♪
♪ Spider blood, Spider blood ♪
[guitar solo]
♪ Spider-Man, Spider-Man ♪
Look!
No doubt about it.
The Skull and his
son went this way.
And then disappeared?
Spider sense, danger!
Ah, you have fallen
into my stasis trap.
Welcome to the heart
of my doomsday complex.
Why don't you give
this all up, Skull?
Your robots
have already failed.
They did what they
were designed for.
To safeguard this.
Witness as I transform my son
into fascism's
ultimate warrior.
Look!
He's changing.
Chameleon, when I am
done pulverizing you,
I look forward to doing
the same to your boss,
the Red Skull.
Spider-Man and Silver Sable
ran in here
after the Red Skull.
Come on, we have to get in.
We've got to stop
the Red Skull.
[woman] What's going on?
Stand back,
everybody, take cover.
[crumbling]
Look, someone's there.
What on earth?
Behold, my doomsday weapon.
A soldier
who can harness energy
and bend it to his will.
He is no longer my son.
Now you may call him Electro!
[laughing]
Do you mean to tell me
the doomsday weapon is simply
another Neanderthal
in a costume?
Don't underestimate
the Red Skull.
If he says he's created
something of great power,
there's only one
way to find out.
[groans]
Earth's mightiest
mortals fall before
our awesome power.
Our power?
[buzzing]
We will see how you feel
after you have
experienced my power.
Kingpin, no!
All of you,
your abilities are pathetic.
And mine are beyond
comprehension.
[gasping]
He has overtaxed himself.
His body has not adjusted yet.
I prepared this
emergency escape plan
all those years ago.
[exploding]
Now we know what
the doomsday weapon is.
Lucky us.
[sirens blaring]
Fisk, you'll be okay.
They'll get you to a place
where you can recuperate.
The mighty Kingpin.
Bah, there is no profit
to be made here now.
Let us get back
to our own lives.
The Kingpin and his men
have all been taken care of.
Now, what shall we do?
You should do nothing
more than wish us luck.
What?
Your people fought bravely,
but they are hopelessly
outmatched by Electro.
If you think for one second
that I'm going
to sit this out--
Sable, stop.
He's right and you know it.
It's our fight now.
I see.
One cannot afford
any liabilities.
Even well intentioned ones.
All right, we'll go.
But if you fail, I will be
back to take up the fight.
Wild Pack, assemble.
We're going home.
There goes one tough lady.
Spider-Man, what is this place?
This is the same part of town
where you fought the Red Skull.
But it's a wasteland.
What happened?
I think maybe we
hung up our tights
a little prematurely.
No kidding.
It looks to me like
America needs heroes
now more than ever.
Darn right it does.
So, what's our
next move, Captain?
It's hard to say this
to you, my friends.
Your powers are
five decades older.
The heck with that.
We're willing to
take our chances.
Well then, we need a
base of operations.
I can think of one.
I can't believe the
old Hall of Freedom
is still standing.
50 years.
I hope I'm not too out
of date to be of any use.
Cap, a classic is
never out of date.
I am glad that you had set up
a hidden retreat, Chameleon.
Father, what's happening to me?
Your body is adapting
to its fantastic power.
Soon, you'll be able
to control electricity
all over the entire world.
Yes, I can feel it.
You have shown strength,
my son.
And earned the place
in my new world order.
Your world order?
I spent my life
trying to free you.
But you were willing to risk
my life in that machine.
Ah, the risk was quite minimal.
Oh really?
It is I who has the power,
and I who shall rule.
I even sense the energy
in your body, brother.
I cannot be surprised.
And you, you'll never
control me again.
Do not despair, Chameleon.
The Red Skull
anticipates everything.
Ah, Jay Three Communications.
Just what I need to let the
world know of my arrival.
[gasping]
[intense music playing]
[Electro]
People of Earth, rejoice.
For a new age is upon you.
The age of Electro.
No force can withstand me.
No living thing can
exist without my energy.
I have willed the cessation
of all ground vehicles
in New York City as
a small demonstration
of what I can do.
This is only the tiniest
sample of my abilities.
I don't really control power.
I am power.
Our first task will be to
find out where they fled to.
We must find Electro.
Hey, my TV.
It just switched itself on.
All who oppose me
shall be destroyed.
I think we just found him.
Incredible, it's a miniature
transportable imaging device.
You United Nations delegates
are hereby instructed
to rectify
a declaration giving
me complete control
of all governments, citizens,
and property to
use as I see fit.
Submit now so I need not take
what is rightfully
mine by force.
I've got to get down there.
Peter's probably in
the thick of all this.
You can't put your
life in danger
just because of Peter's
disregard for his own safety.
Listen, Aunt Anna.
You're wrong.
Peter stands for everything
that's good in the world.
Well, it's just that
I love you so much.
Then that's something
you share with Peter.
He loves me too.
Any leaders who oppose
this oath of obedience
will be considered
traitors to the Earth
and will be
so merrily executed.
Huh?
[gasps]
[groaning]
Keep it up.
He's being distracted.
[mumbling]
[gasps]
Peter!
[groaning]
No! [screams]
Mary Jane!
[laughs]
Auf Wiedersehen,Spider-Man.
[groans]
You again?
It's time I showed the world
how futile your efforts are.
[laughs]
What have I done?
She's weak, Spider-Man.
We'd better get
her to a safe place
where she can rest.
It's my fault.
If she weren't married to me,
she never would've
been on that roof.
If I weren't playing hero--
[Captain America] I gather
that she's important to you.
But remember,
you're also important.
A lot of people are
counting on you.
People just like her.
I know you want to go with her.
If you do, she may not
have a world to wake up to.
That's the price you pay
when you do this job.
All right,
let's go stop that maniac.
[crumbling]
[Electro] Come, my friends.
[whirring]
I need to make a
memorable entrance.
[intense music playing]
[clapping]
The time has come.
Submission or oblivion.
The choice is yours.
He's 1000 times more
powerful than we thought.
And growing.
What hope do we have
of stopping him now?
I've spent the last 50 years
with the Red Skull's
hands at my throat.
I know how he thinks.
That mad man would
never allow someone
to be more powerful than he is.
The Red Skull must've prepared
some kind of fail safe device.
Some way to control him.
But what could be more
powerful than Electro,
the ultimate weapon?
The vortex.
The energy field that
kept Cap suspended in time
is self-perpetuating energy.
It's completely autonomous
from the Earth's
electromagnetic fields.
I get it.
The Red Skull must've
created the vortex
as a trump card.
Something to
threaten Electro with
if Electro got out of hand.
The rest of you, hightail it
over to the United Nations
and protect the delegates.
Spider-Man and I will
go after the vortex.
Let's move!
We've got to try to
keep Electro busy
until the Army arrives.
Not the Army.
This is just the kind of thing
S.H.I.E.L.D was designed for.
Well, what are we waiting for?
Invitations?
Ah, I sense Earth's mighty
heroes have arrived.
50 years too late.
My robots will keep
them duly occupied.
Now, let us get
back to the business
of electing me
ruler of the Earth.
[intense music playing]
What is that thing?
[man] It's S.H.I.E.L.D.
S.H.I.E.L.D Headquarters
in plain sight
of the whole city?
Preston must really be
taking this seriously.
Electro, we demand your
immediate surrender.
[intense music playing]
Signal the attack.
Attack hovercraft, move in.
Out on omega, delta.
[intense music playing]
[yells]
[groaning]
[intense music playing]
Our fighters are dropping out
of the sky like hailstones.
Revert to emergency
attack plan 814.
[intense music playing]
Use the motherships weapons.
Carrier turrets one,
three, and five.
Target only Electro.
Fire!
Colonel Fury, I think
we've stopped him.
Nice try.
Now, it's my turn.
Brace for attack.
No!
Ship weapons won't respond.
Hurry, Electro is
shutting us down.
S.H.I.E.L.D is going dead.
[intense music playing]
Deploy the emergency power.
Sir, there isn't
any emergency power.
Get everyone out.
Abandon ship.
-Sir, I--
-Agent, that's an order.
Now, beat it.
[alarm blaring]
[intense music playing]
[Agent] Colonel Fury,
are you all right?
Do you copy?
Yeah, I'm still alive.
For what it's worth.
He brought down
all of S.H.I.E.L.D
with only a gesture.
Heaven help us all.
Need I remind you what fate
awaits any who cast
their ballot against me?
How's it coming, Spider-Man?
Finished, I think.
Huh?
Spider sense.
Spider-Man, what--
[groans]
You've been here
the entire time?
Of course.
I knew one of you would deduce
the purpose of
the vortex generator
and return here to repair it.
Oh, great.
I just did the Red Skull's
dirty work for him.
[ominous music playing]
What is this feeling?
Some kind of new energy ripples
through Earth's
electromagnetic field.
An energy that rivals
my own in power.
Of course.
The vortex.
[groaning]
Look at them.
They've spent the last 50
years locked in combat,
and they still
refuse to give up.
[intense music playing]
[grunts]
No, Cap, don't do it!
I can't defeat
Electro without you.
You can do it, Spider-Man.
You're a hero.
First, last, and always.
Fight on, Spider-Man, fight on.
[screaming]
Cap!
[groans]
Bravo, Spider-Man.
You've managed to web
up my poor brother.
Let's see how you
do against someone
who has absolute power.
Got to get him
into that vortex.
Though I don't stand
much of a chance.
I've got to,
the world is at stake.
[intense music playing]
We did it.
We beat the robots.
I can hardly believe it.
We got to be heroes
one last time.
What a swell feeling this is.
[clapping and cheering]
Come on, we've got
to find out how
Spider-Man and Cap made out.
Your pitiful effort is wasted
on one
who is power personified.
[laughs]
If you're power personified,
why does the vortex
have you shaking
in your yellow booties?
I fear nothing!
Behold.
He did it. He actually bent
the energy beam.
Oh sure, you can
move it a tiny bit.
But what happens
when I do this?
I could destroy that
pitiful device with a foot.
But I shall prove to you
that even the vortex energy
has a master in me.
This had better work.
[Electro] Commencing all power.
All energy is mine!
What's happening to me?
The vortex is a
space time anomaly.
Its energy is
self-perpetuating, like a loop.
When you destroyed
the control panel,
you interrupted the loop.
Now all of the
power of the vortex
is feeding directly into you.
You wanted all
the power, Electro?
Well now you've got it.
[screaming]
This ought to pull the
plug on Electro for good.
The vortex was too
unstable to be controlled.
I did it, I won!
But now comes the hard part.
He was the definition of
a hero to the bitter end.
But now--
Now we're right back where
we started 50 years ago.
How do we deal with
the vortex generator?
Years ago, we did nothing.
This time has to be different.
It's what Captain America
would've wanted.
[crumbling]
F. Scott Fitzgerald once said,
"Show me a hero and
I'll write you a tragedy."
Cap's life was no tragedy.
It was an epic
story of a great man
doing great things
for the world.
As long as there are
heroes in the world,
you'll still be with us.
-Bless you, Cap.
-[camera clicks]
Well, if this photo
doesn't get me back
in Jameson's good graces,
I don't know what will.
I think I'll title it,
"The End Of A Golden Era".
[ominous music playing]
Peter?
Peter, did you win?
Is everybody safe?
Yes, Mary Jane.
Promise me that
you'll never quit.
That you'll always
be here for me
and for the world.
I promise.
And Spider-Man promises too.
That's just what we heroes do.
[theme music playing]
♪ Spider-Man, Spider-Man ♪
♪ Radioactive Spider-man ♪
[guitar solo]
♪ Spider blood, spider blood ♪
♪ Radioactive spider blood ♪
♪ Spider-Man ♪