[Anastasia]
Previously onSpider-Man.
-Leave us alone!
-I'll do anything you say!
Of course, you will.
What deal was your mother
making with Doc Ock?
Something called
the Ausbach Fortune.
[Peter, thinking]
It was a jewel theft.
The crime was attributed
to a burglar known as The Cat.
Felicia's father!
As a boy, he was tricked
into working for German spies.
He memorized a formula
that created Captain America.
The Chameleon?
But isn't he in jail?
[Kingpin] Chameleon,
show us your cellmate.
[Doctor Octopus]
It's Hardesky.
Hardesky holds a secret
that is worth a king's ransom.
Have you ever heard
of S.H.I.E.L.D.?
[Spider-Man] I need
information about The Cat.
I can't help you at all.
-[cannons firing]
-[explosion booms]
Now what?
[Kingpin] Well done, Chameleon.
I vowed never to reveal
that formula to anyone!
-I have more persuasive methods.
-[Felicia] No!
Fisk, what
is the meaning of this?!
Allow me to introduce
you to your father.
[upbeat rock music]
♪ Spider-Man ♪
♪ Radioactive Spider-Man ♪
♪ Spider blood
Spider blood ♪
♪ Radioactive spider blood ♪
♪ Spider blood
Spider blood ♪
♪ Radioactive spider blood ♪
[explosions booming]
[growling]
♪ Spider-Man ♪
[horns honking]
[thinking] Some superhero
I turned out to be.
First, I was helpless
to save Mary Jane,
and now I might
never see Felicia again.
She and her mother
have been missing for days.
Where could they be?
I feel like I'm losing everyone
in my life one by one.
[dramatic music]
[device beeps]
[soft scraping]
[device beeping]
-[device beeps]
-[alarm bell ringing]
Well, that's not exactly what
I had in mind for tonight,
but I guess I should respond.
-[spider-sense tingling]
-My Spidey-sense!
[Spider-Man groans]
I knew you would come, Spider.
[Spider-Man] Who are you?!
Just a stray Black Cat.
[Spider-Man] You're definitely
getting enough vitamins!
Silly Spider, cats always
land on their feet.
[groans]
Hey, I was just being curious.
I wanted to see
if I was as strong as you.
[Spider-Man] Well, you know
what they say about curiosity.
Indeed. I also know
the value of surprise!
-[smoke hissing]
-[Spider-Man coughing]
Sorry, Spider.
I want to know just
who's behind your mask.
[alarm bell ringing]
No, this isn't
what I want after all.
It'll be far more rewarding
when you take the mask
off for me willingly.
[doors thudding]
[officer] Get the door open!
Till next time.
[officer]
Come on, get it open!
[Spider-Man]
Whoever that woman was,
she gives new meaning
to the word "knockout."
Uh-oh!
I'm outta here.
Hey, it's Spider-Man!
Spider-Man's been sighted
in sector 814.
[Nick] Get him!
We've verified that the person
in Hardesky's cell
is really The Chameleon.
Hardesky's gone!
I want to know
Spider-Man's connection.
Is he trying to get
the Super Soldier formula?
I'll have all your heads if
it falls into the wrong hands.
[Kingpin]
Nervous, Hardesky?
You should be.
If our little test subject
has flown the coop,
it will be
very unfortunate for you.
Don't worry, Kingpin.
I've trained The Black Cat
to be unbeatable.
She should be returning now.
[Black Cat] Thanks
for the vote of confidence.
Spare me the theatrics.
How did the operation go?
Piece of cake.
Congratulations, Landon.
It appears you have
successfully recreated
the Super Soldier serum.
Recreated it?!
I have improved the formula.
Show Kingpin the new feature.
[high-pitched hum]
Ah, brilliant!
A built-in ability to hide
one's super identity.
And hide the shame I feel
to be carrying out
your wicked crimes.
As long as I keep
your father hostage,
you, my dear Black Cat, will
continue to do what I tell you.
Did you perchance encounter
that wall-crawling menace,
Spider-Man?
No, I didn't.
Pity.
I should like to have known
how your powers
would've measured up
against his.
Look, I'm exhausted.
If you're finished having me
jump through hoops,
I'd like to get some rest.
You are both dismissed, for now.
Take them back
to a holding cell.
The test went well,
but we'll need a few more days.
We must see if the formula
has any negative side effects.
You'd better get some rest.
I'm fine.
I just said I was tired
to get away from those two.
Between your coaching
and the formula,
Black Cat's
quite the feline felon.
Oh, I wanted something
better for you,
better than the life I had.
Daddy, this isn't your fault.
There was no way you
could've stopped The Kingpin
from giving me that serum.
Maybe, but what about
all the times you needed me
when you were growing up,
and I wasn't there?
Will you ever
forgive me for that?
That's all in the past.
Tell me, now
that you're all grown up,
is there anyone special
in your life?
Actually, there is someone.
He's a lot like you, mysterious.
And you have
strong feelings for him?
Yes, I'm afraid so.
Ah, family reunions
are so touching.
I shall miss this little family
after I have destroyed them.
And then she got
in a fight with Spider-Man.
Called herself The Black Cat.
I was hoping there
might be a file on her here,
but there isn't.
Do you know anything,
Mr. Robertson?
Sorry, I haven't heard word one
about a costumed adventurer,
but it looks like you've been
having adventures
of your own, Peter.
Huh?
How did that get there?
Peter, I need to talk
to you in my office, now.
Did he call me Peter?
Was that our J. Jonah Jameson?
Uh, what's up, Mr. Jameson?
You're friends
with Felicia Hardy.
Is she in some kind of trouble?
I'm not sure.
Why do you ask?
Not that it's
any of your business, Parker,
but Anastasia Hardy is
a guest at my penthouse.
Mrs. Hardy is staying with you?
She's afraid to go home,
but she won't tell me
what's wrong.
I tried all my other sources,
and now I'm reduced
to asking you.
I don't know
any more than you do.
Well, that's just dandy!
What are you wasting
my time for?!
Go back to your rooftops
and sewers!
[Peter] Right.
I can't believe it.
Jameson actually seems
to care about someone.
At least
that solves the mystery
of where Mrs. Hardy is.
-Nice view.
-[Anastasia gasps]
How dare you come here?
I'm concerned about Felicia.
Nobody's seen her, and--
She's not here!
And even if she were, my family
is none of your business.
Oh, no?
If Felicia's life's in danger,
shouldn't something be done?!
There's nothing anyone can do!
-Nothing!
-Mrs. Hardy, I'm begging you,
give me a chance to try!
I-- I can't!
Look, if you change your mind,
you can contact me with this.
Just press the center
to activate it.
I wish I knew what to do.
[loud whoosh]
Spider-Man?
[phone beeping]
Miss Grant, is Jonah there?
Well, when he gets in,
tell him I'm going home.
-[Felicia gasping]
-Shh!
Time to go, kitten.
Sorry, I'm sure
the cells are bugged.
I'm just glad we're finally
getting out of here.
There is no "we."
Only you have the super strength
necessary to escape.
No, I won't go without you.
Please, no arguments.
I haven't given you much,
kitten,
but I can give you your freedom.
Hurry.
[high-pitched hum]
Lead the way.
Where'd you get that?
Borrowed it from the lab.
[powder hissing]
Even at my best, kitten,
I never had what it'll take
to escape from this fortress.
I'm not sure I do, either.
You do. Trust me.
[door whirring]
John Hardesky,
I will come back for you.
-Mother?
-[Anastasia gasps]
Felicia, my darling!
Where have you been?
Are you all right?
Yes, and I've seen Daddy.
You've seen your father?
He told me everything.
I want to save him,
but I need help.
I suppose someone
has already volunteered.
[Felicia gasps]
I knew he wouldn't let me down.
Don't worry.
We'll take care of everything.
When I got
Mrs. Hardy's signal,
I assumed she was
in some sort of danger.
But why on earth
would she call me here?
Hey, Spider, care to dance?
Not this time.
-[Black Cat grunting]
-[Spider-Man groans]
What have you got
to do with the Hardys?
Cool it, Spider.
I'm on your side.
[kick thuds]
I need your help to save
another Cat, John Hardesky.
[Spider-Man] What's
your connection to him?
He made me the Super Soldier
I am today.
The formula,
you've actually taken it?
Ooh, smart Spider.
[Spider-Man] I'm smart
enough not to trust you.
I don't even know who you are!
I'm supposed to be
your executioner
if Kingpin has his way.
Kingpin?
If you work for Kingpin,
why don't you want to kill me?
Who knows?
Maybe it's
your animal magnetism.
-[spider-sense tingling]
-Now what?
Commander, it's Spider-Man.
-Get him.
-Fire!
Black Cat, save yourself!
[grunts]
Now we're gonna
I.D. him for sure!
-[Spider-Man grunts]
-It's no use.
-The mask's coming off.
-Is this private?
-[kick thuds]
-[agents shouting]
You really put your foot
in it this time, Spider.
[Black Cat grunts]
Stay with Spider-Man!
-[door thuds]
-Nice touch.
[groans]
[explosion booms]
[Agent X] After him!
This ought
to keep them in there!
Or maybe not!
Over here!
Need a lift?
I've got a feeling
I'm gonna need this.
[tires screeching]
You miserable thieves!
[Spider-Man]
We're not thieves!
Well, I'm not,
but her I'm not so sure about.
[tires screeching]
I hate to be a backseat driver,
but this is a one-way street.
[Black Cat]
Relax, I'm a New Yorker.
[Spider-Man]
"Relax" doesn't go in
the same sentence as "New York"!
Oh, big, big bus!
[bus horn honks]
You didn't take lessons
from a guy named Blade, did you?
Uh-oh!
[Black Cat] Ever hear
the phrase, divide and conquer?
Where'd he go?
-[man screams]
-I'm right here.
Cat!
Thanks for the ride.
All right,
now where were we
before I was
so rudely interrupted?
I was about to tell you
what a good team we'll make.
I don't team with anyone.
You'll have to if we're
going to save John Hardesky.
Look, I don't even know
who you are.
Like you, I have my secrets,
but that doesn't mean
you can't trust me.
All right, but we have
to return this bike first.
-No problem.
-And then let's discuss
this bad habit you have of
taking things that aren't yours.
[alarm beeping]
It's The Cat!
He got out of his cell somehow!
It would appear that
The Cat has lost his touch.
Or was this alarm deliberately
tripped as a diversion?
That would be just like you,
using surprise to help
your protégé escape.
The Kingpin does
not like surprises.
You had better hope that
your kitten is still with us.
[beeps]
What's up, boys?
With the formula a success,
I no longer have need
for either of you.
Guards! Dispose
of these two alley cats.
Landon, go to your laboratory
and manufacture enough serum
to make an army
of Super Soldiers.
With pleasure.
[computer beeping]
[alarm beeping]
What's happening?!
You, but you were
just taken away!
[The Cat]
When The Cat is involved,
one should never believe
everything they see.
Take this formula, for instance.
Now you see it...
[Landon] The formula!
-You're erasing it!
-[alarm beeping]
[The Cat] Exactly.
This is the only kind
of memory I ever trusted.
[Landon] You can't!
I guess the old Cat
hasn't lost his touch after all.
-[computer beeping]
-[Landon] No!
[Kingpin] As soon as you
get a respectable distance
from Crime Central,
finish them.
[Black Cat]
We have to stall.
He may need more time.
Aah!
-[kick thuds]
-[men groan]
Surprise!
-[kicks thud]
-[man groans]
[men groan]
Nice job, partner.
[gasps]
Doc Ock!
Surrender, Spider-Man,
unless you want to see
if this little Cat
truly has nine lives.
No! I can't risk
Black Cat's life.
Ah, how predictable.
Once again,
Spider-Man falls prey
to his pitiful weakness:
compassion.
We must find
the real Hardesky at once.
And, oh, yes, the prisoners
must be destroyed.
Before we go, there's one
last thing I have to tell you.
[Spider-Man] Yes?
-[guns firing]
-Duck!
[Spider-Man] Duck?!
Commander, the stealth sky ship
that attacked
S.H.I.E.L.D. headquarters,
it's finally showed up
on our sensors.
Tactical assault in progress.
Have you found John Hardesky?
Negative, but we've located
Spider-Man and his companion.
Bring every agent in.
Full attack formation!
Go!
[Kingpin] Look what they're
doing to my stealth sky ship!
Kingpin, I've bad news!
Hardesky was left behind,
hidden in my laboratory!
He has destroyed the formula!
What?! No!
-[guns firing]
-[explosion booms]
[Spider-Man] If we stay here,
we may take a hit
from either side, or both!
Personally, I like a little
more control over my destiny.
I'm with you, Spider.
Lead on!
-Not so fast, my pretty!
-[groans]
Hold it, Spider-Man,
or else she gets hurt!
[Black Cat] Doc!
Nice web shot, Spider.
[groans loudly]
We shall meet again, Spider-Man,
Black Cat, this I promise you.
[door thuds]
[computer beeping]
Hurry, I'm running out
of webbing again!
And this thing's
running out of gas.
I'm aiming it toward the river.
Time to abandon ship.
[Spider-Man] We all know
how cats feel about water,
but I think I can
keep your paws dry.
[Black Cat] Very impressive.
[Spider-Man] I'm getting
pretty good at this.
Hope old John Hardesky
took care of business
and got away safely.
[Black Cat] If there's one man
I'm sure I can count on,
it's John Hardesky.
Great working with you, Spider.
Don't be surprised
if I cross your path again.
Huh? What?
Hey!
What is it with me?
Why do women always
leave me high and wet?
Well, at least
when she wasn't looking,
I put a spider tracer on her.
Huh?
She put it back on me!
At least this time we
get to say goodbye.
[John] I hate to leave,
but there is no other way.
Twenty years ago,
we never had that chance.
I am sorry for that, Anastasia.
I can't let you leave me again.
I love you too much, Daddy.
I love you, too, kitten.
That's why I must go.
You can never lead
a normal life with me in it.
I know too much.
Oh, John, there's no place
where you'll be safe.
What kind of a life is that?
But you're forgetting,
The Cat has many lives.
Perhaps one of them
will be right for me.
Ready, Spider-Man?
Ready.
He's gone
from our lives once more.
[Anastasia] Yes, but thank
heaven he's alive and free.
[Spider-Man] Are you
sure you want to do this?
I don't want to, but I have to.
You see, I've got
a secret in here
that could destroy the world.
And there's only one place
where I'll be able
to keep it safe.
Then here goes.
Don't ever tell
Felicia where I am.
-I won't.
-And don't worry about me.
Now get out of here.
And thanks.
Commander Fury, it's Hardesky!
It looks
like he's waiting for us!
Well, what do you know?
Bring him in, and if you
see Spider-Man around,
tell him I said thanks.
Something tells me he had
his web-covered hand in this.
Before all this started,
I'd hoped to turn
to Felicia with my grief,
but she has more
than enough problems
of her own to deal with.
It looks like I'm alone again.
Or am I?
Have I found a kindred spirit
in The Black Cat?
I just wish I knew who she was.
[upbeat rock music]
♪ Spider-Man, Spider-Man ♪
♪ Radioactive Spider-Man ♪
♪ Spider blood, spider blood ♪
♪ Radioactive spider blood ♪
♪ Spider blood ♪
♪ Spider-Man ♪