[narrator]
Previously onSpider-Man...
Whoever conceives
the most original
neogenics experiment
gets the job as my assistant.
I thought you would be
my competition, Parker.
[Felicia screams]
-A bat!
-I am studying them.
[Peter thinking]
Better not take any chances.
What are you up to?
Parker's DNA might give
a person tremendous power.
I will expose this
to the neogenic process.
Get out of there!
No!
I hunger for blood.
[Spider-Man] Who are you?
[Michael] Blood made me
like the vampire bat.
[Peter] Morbius with a sample
of my blood?
He's headed back
to the university.
[Michael] I will feed on you.
[Peter] Incredible.
He's completely normal again.
[Felicia] I'm here
to see Michael Morbius.
He's gone.
-[police officer]
Somebody took him?
-Spider-Man.
[Peter] I'm mutating.
My serum seems to refuse
the mutation process.
Taking it could be a mistake.
[Peter groaning]
I thought that the serum
was going to help me.
[Peter screaming]
["Spider-Man Theme Song"
by Joe Perry playing]
♪ Spider-Man ♪
♪ Radioactive Spider-Man ♪
[guitar break]
♪ Spider blood ♪
♪ Radioactive spider blood ♪
[guitar break]
♪ Spider-Man ♪
[uplifting instrumental music]
Peter?
I--I heard a noise.
Are you in there?
[suspenseful music]
Oh, dear.
Peter.
Are you developing
your pictures?
[leaves rustling]
[May screams]
Honestly, May Parker.
You're jumping at shadows.
What would Peter think
if he saw you now?
[Peter thinking]
Sorry, Aunt May.
Peter Parker doesn't
exist anymore.
[man 1] A million bucks?
Never thought I'd meet a woman
who was worth that much.
Yeah.
Wish I was married
to a rich guy.
[man 2] You could be, baby.
Soon as her old man
pays me her ransom.
Especially after
that Columbian deal.
[woman] Is that a proposal?
[tires screeching]
[beeping]
[laughs] Big daddy,
you blow me away.
[explosion booming]
[gasps]
Who the heck is that?
Just waste him.
[woman yelping]
[grunts]
[lasers zapping]
[chuckling]
No!
Hey, I give up.
No, really.
I give up.
And then what?
Get some weasely lawyer?
Spend a year or two in prison
and then you're back
on the streets again?
Sorry. In this war,
there's no surrender.
Help me!
Please, somebody help me.
[crash]
[woman grunting
in muffled voice]
[woman]
Oh, thank you so much.
My pleasure.
[sirens wailing]
[Frank] Chip.
Frank, got another job for ya.
This isn't your
usual type of target.
-This is a special one.
-[beeps]
What do you know.
I was wondering when
he and I would tango.
I'll make dog meat out of him.
This is horrible.
Mariah Crawford was right.
I took her serum too soon.
[thinking]
Spider sense but why?
There's no danger.
Except to my brain.
It won't stop.
[phone ringing]
Hello? Who is it?
[Mary Jane]
You're in big trouble
if you can't guess, tiger.
Mary Jane.
You win the prize.
And for answering correctly,
I'm treating you to a nice,
new, romantic film tonight.
[Peter thinking]
I can't believe it.
Of all times.
MJ, [sighs]
I can't go out tonight.
Parker, what's with you?
You've been avoiding
me for days.
I thought you and I were...
I mean, last week
when we out at Coney Island--
I'm sorry.
It's just that my hands
are full at the moment.
-I've gotta go.
-Don't you dare hang up on me.
We need to talk about us.
I'm coming over there
right now.[hangs up]
[Peter thinking]
Any other time, I'd jump
at the chance to be with her.
But she can't see me like
this.
-I'm sorry, MJ.
-[doorbell rings]
[man] That's weird.
[man yells]
[Michael] Forgive me.
-[Peter] Doctor Crawford.
-[Mariah gasps]
Oh, Spider-Man.
Good thing I've gotten used to
you sneaking up
on me like [gasps].
Just as I feared.
The serum accelerated
your mutation
instead of retarding it.
Think it'll ruin my career
as a swimsuit model?
[yelping]
Please.
-Help me.
-Sit.
I need a blood sample.
[Peter groaning]
Pick an arm. Any arm.
[Mariah] When I heard what
you did to Michael Morbius,
I thought you'd
already mutated into--
Morbius? So you know?
How did you find out?
It's been on all the news.
They say you're responsible.
They'd blame me
for the common cold
if they could.
You mean it wasn't you
who kidnapped him
from the hospital?
Kidnapped?
Morbius is missing?
You didn't know?
And I'm here with the victim's
girlfriend Felicia Hardy.
Miss Hardy, why do you think
Spider-Man kidnapped
your boyfriend
rom this hospital?
I have no idea.
Heaven forgive me,
but I hate Spider-Man
for doing this to Michael.
I hate him
with all my heart and soul.
[crying]
People of New York,
haven't we had enough
of this wall crawling menace?
Surely there's some way
to rid ourselves of Spider-Man.
Some way we can
protect the lives
of innocent people
like Michael Morbius.
If ever there was a cue, Frank,
this is it.
If you bring
Spider-Man in alive,
it'd be a big step toward
redeeming yourself
in the eyes of the law.
That doesn't matter to me.
All I care about is
stopping the slime bags
who prey on innocent lives.
Fine. But as your partner
and your friend,
I care about you.
I don't want you to end up
in jail or worse.
Just do this one job
to patch up your reputation.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
And use the non-lethal
ordinance this time, OK?
All right.
Do it your way.
Just this once.
[John, on TV]
And so, people of New York,
lock your windows,
barricade your doors.
What?
One moment please.
Folks,
this is a breaking story.
Spider-Man has
apparently reappeared
outside the scene of the crime.
We go now live to
Manhattan Hospital.
Folks, it can only
be Spider-Man,
the wanted criminal himself.
[Spider-Man] That's Morbius.
[sirens wailing]
Felicia.
[Felicia] It's Spider-Man!
Who else could climb on
a building like that?
Stop him!
Where are you going?
To Morbius.
I've got to help him.
[Mariah] But you're ill.
So's he.
Thanks to me.
I have to help him.
Folks, there you see him live.
The menace himself.
Lieutenant Lee, he's up there.
What are you waiting for?
Hit the lights.
You?
What has happened to you?
Let's just say that
you don't own
the franchise on weirdness.
[both grunting]
Wrong arm.
There used to be a simple
choice of right or left.
[indistinct chatter]
Got him!
What in the name of?
He's turned into a freak.
[Spider-Man]
Can't sing, can't dance.
Time to get out
of the spotlight.
Six arms?
War journal entry 1195.3.
Spider-Man spotted
at 20:30 hours.
Doesn't matter
how many arms he's got.
I'm gonna take him.
Spider-Man, your days
of terrorizing the innocent
are over.
Don't tell me.
The Skull? The Cornea Line?
No, your name must
be Bone Head, right?
That was a bad guess.
Cool toy, but I'm out of here.
Battle Van, flare.
Place it 200 feet
above target being tracked.
[beeping]
[Spider-Man] Seems like
this guy wants to
light up my life.
Oh, out of web fluid.
Nice timing.
Battle Van, pantry
super-silicon projector.
Key on my signal and launch.
[pilot] G-3 Eagle to ground.
We've spotted unknown
figure with Spider-Man.
Can you identify?
Over.
[Spider-Man yelling]
[Peter] The pain, my sides.
Oh, why now?
That's right.
I said a skull on his chest.
[sirens wailing]
No, no, it's not a tattoo.
The skull's on his shirt.
I want him ID-ed pronto.
Larry, give me something
on this skull guy.
Anything, ASAP.
Battle Van, mini-stinger
with Teflon blade load.
Launch at my signal.
Heavy wind compensation
from aerial target.
Don't do it Frank.
Please, don't do it.
[Spider-Man grunting]
I'm a sitting duck up here.
I've got to move.
That psycho's aiming
a missile launcher at us.
-[Frank] Got ya.
-[launcher beeping]
[grunts] My gut's on fire.
Can't get away.
I'm pulling up.
[Spider-Man yelling]
[groaning]
See?
I got a web of my own.
[Microchip]
Nice and peaceful, Frank.
Had me worried
for a minute, big guy.
[grunting]
[Larry]
Jonah, your mystery man?
His name's Frank Castle.
He's a self-styled vigilante.
Calls himself The Punisher.
He's wanted by the FBI
and even the CIA want him
for questioning
in the disappearances of
various crime figures.
A crime fighter, huh?
And now he's after Spider-Man?
Maybe we can play up that angle
and turn him into a hero.
[Larry]
Not with this guy's M.O.
He's known for
using lethal force.
He shoots first
and never asks questions.
Hmm.
What about Parker?
Is he getting any
pictures of this?
- [Larry] I couldn't find him.
-[John] Typical.
[grunting]
About time these extra arms
came in handy for something.
[grunting]
Who are you?
I punish those who prey
on the innocent.
[grunts] Well what does
that have to do with me?
You kidnapped that student.
Next time, get the facts
before you decide
to punish someone.
This isn't the end
wall-crawler.
I'm coming after you.
And next time,
I'm using lethal force.
[jet pack engine stutters]
Oh, I'm so scared
I may start biting
my fingernails.
And man, have I got
fingernails.
Battle Van, escape item four.
Program two,
keyed on my signal.
[Microchip] Hang on, old buddy.
[Terri] Stop him!
[engine sputtering]
[Frank] Battle Van,
escape tactic, go!
[tires squealing]
[sirens wailing]
[nurse] What have you got?
Another victim of severe
plasma draining.
[Spider-Man] Morbius.
He's still out there.
I've got to find him.
[grunting]
The pain!
I need Doctor Crawford.
But I put myself first before
and Uncle Ben paid the price.
It was when I first
got my powers.
I became a costumed wrestler
to cash in and make big bucks.
[audience cheering]
[man] Hey, help!
Grab him!
Don't let him get away!
[Spider-Man ] Hey, sorry pal.
I'm a wrestler, not a cop.
I figured why should
I get involved?
But that night, the police
were at Aunt May's.
Bad news son.
[Spider-Man]
A crook had broken in.
My Uncle Ben tried to stop him
but the guy was armed.
The cop told me the creep
had been chased to a warehouse.
Whoever it was,
I wanted him first
and I got him, too.
It was the crook
from the arena.
Losing Uncle Ben was my fault
because I didn't
do what was right.
It won't happen again.
I've gotta get Morbius.
How am I going to find him?
His tape recording.
It's all I have.
[Aunt May]
But where could Peter be?
He's never out this late
without calling me.
I swear he was here,
Mrs. Parker.
I talked to him on the phone.
But why would he hide
from me and then leave?
It's just not like him.
Something's wrong.
I can feel it.
I'll stay with you.
Whatever happens,
we'll face it together.
[Spider-Man] I feel like a heel
but I can't let them
see me like this.
I'll have to do this quietly.
[grunting voice]
[Morbius] You're strong.
[Spider-Man]
Parker, you're a math wiz,
right?
- Spider-Man like strong.
-Now why don't you
use some of that
to solve this puzzle? Hmm.
-I battled Morbius here.
-[Spider-Man's voice]
Michael, you need help.
[Peter] Working
backwards on this tape
I need to find
a distinct noise.
-[upbeat rock music]
-There!
Now, I'll time how long
it takes
between that loud music
and my battle with Morbius.
[Frank]
Computer, activate transport.
War journal entry 1994.3.
Spider-Man is stationary
in residential
Queen's neighborhood.
Soon might be
permanently stationary.
[Spider-Man] OK.
I've pinpointed
some of the sounds,
estimated Morbius'
gliding speed,
and extrapolated the distance
he flew.
Well, math wiz,
here goes nothing.
[computer beeping]
-[computer beeping]
-Target's moving again.
Heading south, south east.
He's getting away.
[upbeat rock music]
[Spider-Man] This is it.
The loud music that
was on the tape.
OK, next sound.
Running water.
-War journal entry 19958.4.
-[beeping]
The web-slinger's
going in circles.
[water rushing]
[Spider-Man] Yes.
One more sound to pinpoint
and I should be able
to find Morbius' lab.
One last sound on the tape.
[screeching sound]
Rodents screeching?
No.
A rodent with wings.
A bat!
Any self-respecting bat
would go up high.
[computer beeping]
[Frank] He must've
lost his marbles.
[electricity buzzing]
[Peter] It's over, Michael.
Spider-Man!
How did you find me?
[Oh, let's say figuring
that out drove me batty.
Now I'm going to take you
where you can get help.
No!
I'm not ready.
[Spider-Man]
Well, ready or not.
You fool!
I was working on a cure.
Do you think I want
to be this way?
Now I'm doomed to
this gnawing hunger.
Unless I feed.
[both grunting]
I must stop myself.
I must!
Not the Bone Head again.
Not now.
[Microchip] Frank, you're using
lethal ordinance now,
aren't you?
Frank, do you copy?
Frank!
[screaming]
Aah...
-[Frank] Gotcha.
-[beeping]
[grunting]
Can't let it end like this.
Come on out.
I'll make it quick and clean.
[growling]
[Spider-Man theme song
playing]
♪ Spider-Man ♪
♪ Radioactive Spider-Man ♪
[guitar solo]
♪ Spider blood ♪
♪ Radioactive spider blood ♪
♪ Spider-Man ♪